<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416145249077872</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/venezuela-election-results-manipulated-by-at-least-1-million-votes-polling-company-says-20170802-gxo6yi.html</url>
  <title>Venezuela election results 'manipulated' by at least 1 million votes, polling company says</title>
  <content>
Caracas, Venezuela:  Election results decried by government opponents as a power grab were manipulated by at least 1 million votes, the company that provided Venezuela with its voting system said on Wednesday.
The disputed vote on Sunday elected 545 pro-government legislators who will sit in a new super-congress vested with vast powers. On Thursday, they are set to enter the neo-classical building in central Caracas that houses members of the opposition-controlled legislature elected in 2015.Photo: AP
Some opposition lawmakers have vowed to remain inside and stand their ground, sparking fears of a violent  confrontation. Last month, pro-government gangs, known as colectivos, entered the National Assembly and brutally attacked lawmakers and journalists.
That offered a taste of what may come on Thursday.Photo: AP
"They're expecting to come forcibly into the parliament and try to dislodge us," said Freddy Guevara, vice-president of the National Assembly. "And they're wrong if they think we're going to leave this palace. We don't have arms. They'll kick us out through bullets and rocks if they want to. But this assembly will continue in session."
The threat came as Antonio Mugica, chief executive of London-based Smartmatic, which has provided technology for Venezuelan elections since 2004, said it detected an inflated turnout figure on Sunday through the automated balloting system.

"With the deepest regret, we have to say that the turnout data presented on Sunday, July 30, for the constituent election was manipulated," Mugica said at a news conference in London.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

His company's analysis of the data, he said, suggested an inflated number of "at least 1 million" - a potentially important difference that would allow the government to claim a higher turnout than an opposition-held unofficial ballot last month.
The announcement adds to growing allegations of massive irregularities in Sunday's election, which was condemned internationally. The Trump administration, which slapped sanctions on President Nicolas Maduro on Monday, described it as a "sham election" that has turned Venezuela into a de facto dictatorship. A number of Latin American nations, including Brazil, Argentina, Peru and Colombia, have called the vote illegitimate.
The European Union on Wednesday issued a statement saying its members would not recognise the new constituent assembly.
Responding to the company's disclosure, Luis Almagro, secretary general of the Organisation of American States, tweeted: "The biggest electoral fraud in Latin America's history in percentage and in millions of votes is confirmed."
Senior government officials dismissed allegations of fraud as the rhetoric of socialism's enemies, both at home and abroad.
"They will always say it's fraud when it's about recognising the people," said Delcy Rodriguez, President Maduro's former foreign minister and now a newly minted member of the constituent assembly.
 Generating a high turnout in Sunday's vote was considered vital to proving public enthusiasm for the new constituent assembly, which gives the government effective control over all branches of government. Polls show the new body and Maduro are deeply unpopular.
The government claimed a turnout of 41.5 per cent - more than 8 million votes. That figure would be highly symbolic if true, as it is greater than the turnout for the unofficial ballot held by the opposition last month - in which it said nearly 7.6 million Venezuelans turned out to reject plans for the new, all-powerful legislature.
Washington Post
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Almagro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delcy Rodriguez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freddy Guevara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Assembly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Mugica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mugica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London-based Smartmatic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Organisation of American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
