<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416828148890908</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/mum-who-broke-down-at-boronia-intersection-overwhelmed-by-strangers-kindness/news-story/f0b64413bc81fe7793402ce491b57a1a</url>
  <title>Strangers rush to help broken down mum</title>
  <content>
BROKEN down at a busy Boronia intersection, Meaghan Rough had her three young children in the back seat, her hazard lights weren't working and howling winds meant she couldn't open the bonnet safely.
Mrs Rough, from The Basin, said she was doing her best not to "freak out" as cars narrowly missed her Kia Carnival in Dorset Square about 11.30am on Saturday, July 29.
But within half an hour of breaking down, she said she was crying tears of happiness because of the generosity of strangers.
A group of people helped push her car into the carpark while others looked after her children, aged 1, 4 and 6.
Ingrid Schoenfeld was one passer-by who stopped to help the family.
She bought Mrs Rough a coffee, got food for her children, waited with her for the tow truck to arrive and gave her money to help with car repairs.
Mrs Rough said she was amazed to meet someone so kind and helpful.
"She was so nice it just brought me to tears," she said.
"I still can't quite believe it."
Mrs Rough said Ms Schoenfeld kept insisting on getting things for her, even arranging the taxi and following them home to make sure they were OK.
Ms Schoenfeld said she was happy to lend a hand and said "if I see someone who needs help I'll do my best to help".
"That's just who I am," Ms Schoenfeld said.
"I don't think what I did was anything out of the ordinary".
Ms Schoenfeld credited the taxi driver, who drove the family home for free, and said Mrs Rough deserved praise for the way she handled the situation.
"I know how stressful it can be breaking down," Ms Schoenfeld said.
"She dealt with it so well and was such a loving parent; she was the epitome of grace and kindness and patience.
"Her children were so beautiful, they were looking out for the youngest one and sharing their food.
"When I got to their house they picked flowers from the garden for me and wrote me a 'thank you' card."
Ms Schoenfeld said she felt blessed to have met the family and said they would stay in touch.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Schoenfeld</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Rough</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meaghan Rough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingrid Schoenfeld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorset Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boronia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kia Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
