<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416789494184525</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/windows-10-insider-preview-build-16257-new-features-and-bugs/</url>
  <title>Windows 10 Insider Preview Build 16257 - New Features And Bugs</title>
  <content>
If you're living on the edge and running the Fast ring preview releases of Windows 10 for PC and mobile an update is available today. A bunch of features and enhancements have arrived including enhancements to everyone's favourite tool for downloading Chrome - Microsoft Edge - as well as a new Eye Control feature.

Eye Control

The centrepiece of this release is Eye Control.

Eye Control is focussed on people with disabilities operate an on-screen mouse, keyboard, and text-to-speech experience using only their eyes. It requires a compatible eye tracker.

As well as the applications for assisting people with disabilities I can imagine lots of other applications in UX design and gaming.

Refinement and tweaks

Microsoft Edge gets a number of updates including changes to the address bar, a fix for the bug where right-clicking an image and choosing "Copy" resulted in the image's URL going to the clipboard rather than the image, and issues with closing tabs when in full screen mode.

The Windows Console now supports a full 24-bit RBG colour palette and the default colours have been tweaked to make text easier to read on modern displays.

Windows Defender Application Guard receives some love with fixes for some known issues and new status messages to provide more information while it's running.

There's a lot more detail over at the . A

I run the Fast ring updates on my Lenovo Miix 510 and, while there are the occasional glitches (like invisible notifications) it's pretty stable.

But the old YMMV warnings apply. Don't run pre-release software on mission critical systems.

If you're looking for a new Windows Server Insider Preview build, you'll need to wait as that's not quite ready yet.

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft's Edge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defender Application Guard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windows Console</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windows Server Insider Preview</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Preview Build 16257</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eye Control</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windows 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEW FEATURES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YMMV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lenovo Miix 510</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chrome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
