<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416956997912321</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/the-gift-of-life-queenslanders-saved-by-selfless-decision-of-organ-donors/news-story/acaa331aad86315b06d9dce7ff7923f9</url>
  <title>"Their decision saved my baby's life"</title>
  <content>
KATE Phillips has just two words to say to a person she will never meet, but feels so connected to - "thank you". "I wish I could just give them a big hug."
Having suffered most of her life with congenital heart disease and pulmonary hypertension, an organ donor gave the now 31-year-old from Sherwood a life she never thought possible - being able to walk and talk at the same time without losing breath, lying flat in bed, and now competing in triathlons.
"Ever since I was 13, they talked about transplant because of the damage to my heart. It wasn't until I was about 18 that they started talking about heart and double-lung transplant."
In her 20s, a series of health scares made transplant the only option. At 23, she was doing a regular six-minute walk test at The Prince Charles Hospital.
"They say it's the safest way to test your pulmonary function."
"There's 30m measured out, and you walk up and back for six minutes with your physio while your heart is being monitored.
"I'm extremely competitive. I was feeling great and I said I was going to do a PB (personal best).
"I did my PB and at the end of that immediately suffered cardiac arrest.
"Still to this day, it was the most horrible thing I've been through."
Still to this day, it was the most horrible thing I've been through.

Kate Phillips talks about receiving the gift of life as part of Quest Community News' The Gift of Life campaign 2017. Video: Jamie-Leigh Mason

Kate Phillips talks about the gift of life.
She woke up in intensive care being told she would need a transplant sooner than originally planned.
"In January 2013, I had a six-minute walk test the next day so I went for a walk around the block to prepare for the next day,'' Kate said.
"I got home and the next thing I knew, I woke up on the bathroom floor.
"It was at that point, I knew I couldn't put transplant off any longer.
"About a month after I had gone on to the transplant waiting list, I slipped into heart failure.
"I was put on the National Emergency Register, which is reserved for critically ill patients. It's still not a guarantee.
"Thankfully, by some miracle, I got the call. Even though, technically, I didn't get the call, because I was in hospital." She received a double-lung and heart transplant in 2013.
"I was in hospital for six weeks post-transplant.
''I mean, when you're getting pretty much a brand new body, that's not bad."
.
SELFLESS ACT GIVES DAD CHANCE TO BE THERE FOR HIS CHILDREN
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Emergency Register</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quest Community News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KATE Phillips</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie-Leigh Mason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gift of Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT GIVES DAD CHANCE TO BE THERE FOR HIS CHILDREN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
