<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417257645627201</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/rendezview/lets-dump-girlboss-and-sheeo-and-mumpreneur-while-were-at-it/news-story/f0c5050623e1f9717b829b22c2130334</url>
  <title>Let's dump #girlboss. And sheEO while we're at it</title>
  <content>
THERE is a term flying around social media right now that makes my blood boil. Every time I see it, I close my eyes, take a deep breath and hope that it's the last time I have to lay eyes on the offending words.
And yet every day, more and more frequently, it continues to pop up on Facebook, on Instagram, on blogs and in magazine headlines and it needs to stop.
The term, or words, is "girl boss" or #girlboss.
Coined by author Sophia Amoruso when she released her memoir/self-help book #girlboss in 2014 (and then subsequently trademarked the name #GIRLBOSS), a social media movement was virtually spawned overnight.
Since then, the term has been used to tag almost seven million Instagram posts, accompanying pictures from everything including teenage girls to weight loss, weddings and, of course as the name suggests, young female bosses.
The Urban Dictionary definition of the term 'girl boss' is "a woman in control, taking charge of her own circumstances in work and life".
"A girl boss knows that if you don't have big dreams and goals, that you'll end up working really hard for someone who does."
To me, the term is not empowering - it's patronising. It has connotations that a female boss is "cute" and "special" and dumbs down the achievements of a women just because she's assumed the role of a boss against all the odds (surprise!)
A boss is a boss. The title isn't or shouldn't be gender-specific and does absolutely nothing to pave the way for females in top jobs. An example of this is my boss at The Advertiser happens to be a female but I don't refer to her as "my female manager", I call her "my manager".
You don't hear people calling Julie Bishop our "girl boss" Foreign Affairs Minister - thank gosh.
Not surprisingly, there are other just as condescending feminist words that have been coined in recent years.
'Ambitionista' is one. Another is 'SheEO', a term apparently needed to describe a female CEO and it's terrible. 'Mumpreneur' is a word used to describe an entrepreneur who is both female and a mum. Um, no thanks!
We're living in the 21st century but it's a well-known fact that there are still drastically fewer women in top jobs both in Australia and across the world.
According to latest stats from June this year, the percentage of women on ASX 200 boards was just 25.4 per cent and a total of 13 boards in the ASX 200 still do not have any women.
Our grandmas had it tough, as did our mums and even today, the struggle is still real for women trying to get ahead of men in the work force.
But, for me, gender-specific language does more harm than good in trying to break the glass ceiling.
We're beginning to crack the ceiling and it will be broken but these terms segregate us from men rather than put us on the same playing field - exactly where I want to be.
Not only that, but not every woman strives to be a "girl boss". And no one should make these women feel bad about that either.
Not every woman wants to follow the footsteps of Sheryl Sandberg, Chief Operating Officer of Facebook, billionaire, career-woman extraordinaire.
In fact, I've heard - and read - many prominent women, including doctors, lawyers and TV hosts, say that their biggest achievement in life is not the fact they're at the top of their fields - it is their achievements as mothers.
Some women make the choice to be stay-at-home mums and they should be applauded.
They too have important, full-time jobs raising children, wiping snot and shitty bums, cooking two-course meals, being a taxi service and cleaner - the job list is endless.
Some women choose to juggle it all. A full-time job, a family - everything. And my hat goes off to them, too.
It's about choice and no female should be ashamed or embarrassed about the choice they choose to make.
And for the record, if and when one day I become the boss, please don't call me girl boss. I'll be the boss thanks, plain and simple.
Katrina Stokes is an Adelaide Advertiser journalist.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Girlboss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumpreneur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Operating Officer of Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SheEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophia Amoruso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Affairs Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheryl Sandberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Advertiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Dictionary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katrina Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambitionista</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX 200</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
