<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417081551965592</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/movies/miff-2017-kriv-stenders-on-new-films-australia-day-and-the-gobetweens-right-here-20170802-gxnpit.html</url>
  <title>The hardest-working man in showbusiness, Kriv Stenders, brings two films to MIFF 2017</title>
  <content>
Judged by his own criteria, Kriv Stenders​ must be Australia's most successful filmmaker right now.
"To me success isn't really about 'critical success' or 'box office success'," the Brisbane-raised, Sydney-based director says. "Success is being able to work. That's how I look at it: if you're working you're successful, no matter what."

Up Next

Trailer: In a Heartbeat

00:25

More Trailers Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

01:53
Trailer: The Go Betweens: Right Here

Trailer: The Go Betweens: Right Here

The Go-Betweens were Australian indie rock trailblazers, leaving a legacy that's influenced everyone from Belle and Sebastian to Sleater-Kinney. This is their story, in their own words.

Up Next

Trailer: In a Heartbeat

00:25

01:21
Trailer: Romper Stomper

Trailer: Romper Stomper

The original 1992 film that tells the story of the downfall of a neo-Nazi group in blue-collar suburban Melbourne.

Up Next

Trailer:
It

02:23

02:23
Trailer: It

Trailer:
It

The new adaptation of Stephen King's iconic work. In Derry, Maine, seven friends come face-to-face with a shape shifter, who takes the form of an evil clown who targets children.

Up Next

Trailer:
Kiki, Love to Love

01:52

01:52
Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Trailer:
Kiki, Love to Love

Director Paco LeA³nas vibrant new comedy follows a collection of lovers through a series of intertwined stories, delivering an outrageously provocative take on what can happen behind closed doors.

Up Next

Trailer:
Thor: Ragnarok

02:25

02:25
Trailer: Thor: Ragnarok

Trailer:
Thor: Ragnarok

Imprisoned, Thor must battle a former ally and race against time to prevent goddess of death Hela from destroying his home.

Up Next

Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

01:54

Trailer: The Go Betweens: Right Here

The Go-Betweens were Australian indie rock trailblazers, leaving a legacy that's influenced everyone from Belle and Sebastian to Sleater-Kinney. This is their story, in their own words.

Stenders has two films opening at the Melbourne International Film Festival this weekend, both of them shot this year: the hyper-kinetic, gritty urban drama Australia Day and the tender music documentary The Go-Betweens: Right Here.
He's also just finished Wake in Fright, his mini-series take on Kenneth Cook's 1961 novel (famously and brilliantly filmed in 1971 by Canadian Ted Kotcheff​), which is due to screen on Ten later this year. Photo: MIFF
He's working on a documentary series with Sally Aitken (David Stratton: A Cinematic Life) and Sam Neill, retracing the three journeys Captain Cook made through the Pacific in the 18th century.
And we haven't even mentioned Red Dog: True Blue, Kill Me Three Times and the SBS series The Principal - all shot since 2014, along with some other directing work on series TV.

"It's my passion, it's also my living," Stenders says. When he started out, he made ads and music clips (including for the Go-Betweens). "It's how I used to make a living between films," he says. "I joke that I used to make TV commercials, now I make the stuff in between TV commercials."

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

New ways of watching

Australia Day follows three interlinked narratives over the course of one January 26, all of them involving a lot of running and a fair deal of violence.
Financed by Foxtel, the film premiered at the Sydney Film Festival in June, and after MIFF will get a small cinema release before making its way to the pay TV platform.
All of which is fine by Stenders, who is as pragmatic as he is prolific. "I'm not a cinema purist - I think any screen is a great screen."

Racial tensions abound in Australia Day. Photo: Vince Valitutti

The demand for content is at an all-time high, he believes, and only likely to increase, but new approaches to getting that content in front of people are essential.
I used to make TV commercials. Now I make the stuff in between TV commercials.
Kriv Stenders

"Anything that builds upon the crumbling ruin that was the exhibition system," he says. "It's all about moving forward and keeping this industry alive."
Looking back

If Australia Day is about embracing emerging models of finance, production and distribution, his Go-Betweens film is very much about looking back.
"It's a love letter to not only that band and their music, but also that time in my life - in all of our lives in that generation, that point in your life when you're young and you go on these adventures and you have these friendships and you make these bonds, and sometimes the bonds last and sometimes they don't."
The Brisbane band emerged in the late 1970s and attained cult status in the early 1980s. Around a nucleus of singer-songwriters Robert Forster and Grant McLennan and drummer Lindy Morrison, other musicians came and went until the band dissolved in acrimony in the late '80s. From 2000, Forster and McLennan resurrected the Go-Betweens and released three more critically acclaimed albums before McLennan died, aged 48, in 2006.

Grant McLennan, Lindy Morrison and Robert Forster in The Go-Betweens: Right Here. 

"There was something in the Go-Betweens' music and their story that has always haunted me," says Stenders, who first met them in his late teens. "There's always been a bitter-sweet quality about them, and I've always wanted to make a film about them.
"Originally I thought about making a fictional film about a band like the Go-Betweens, but there was just something inherent in that story about two guys who meet at uni and embark on this great adventure and build this family of artists around them that I just thought was really powerful. And there was a finiteness that happened to that story when Grant died, so there was a complete arc there."
Not your typical rock doc

The Go-Betweens were never a typical rock band, and so Stenders was determined to avoid the cliches of the typical rock doc. No mixing desks, no pubs, no stages with propped guitars in the background.
Instead, he interviewed the surviving band members in an old Queenslander house, owned by his sister in the hinterland behind Mt Tambourine.
"It's this amazing Arthur Dodson house, built around the turn of the last century," says Stenders, the son of an architect. The choice, he explains, "was partly pragmatic and partly creative. I wanted to get the band onto kind of neutral ground, and have them hostage so they couldn't go anywhere and be distracted.
"But also visually I wanted to create a sense of unity, I wanted to do something that was like the Go-Betweens, something cinematic and evocative and lyrical. And ultimately it also echoed Grant, in his upbringing in North Queensland, [the song] Cattle and Cane and the whole pastoral reference."
Fleetwood Mac minus the fame

The Go-Betweens famously seethed with relationship tension. Robert and Lindy were an item, and then they weren't. Lindy became a little infatuated with young violinist Amanda Brown and brought her into the group; Amanda and Grant became lovers, their relationship ending only when Grant announced he and Robert were leaving the band. They were like Fleetwood Mac, complete with the great songs and the drugs, only without the commercial success.
Remarkably, Stenders got them all to talk.
The key relationship, though, was always the one between Robert and Grant. Did Forster's recent memoir Grant & I help or hinder or in any other way inform the film?

Robert Forster (left) and Grant McLennan, in the post-2000 iteration of The Go-Betweens.

"I think the book works in parallel, it's a companion piece to the film," Stenders says. "I didn't want to make a film based on the book because I wanted to cover things it didn't. I wanted it to be everyone's story.
"But they're very different things. Robert's book is a memoir, and it's his story. 'This is what I remember.' The film is a little more democratic."
Australia Day screens on August 5 and 7.The Go-Betweens: Right Here screens on August 5 and 6. The Age is a Melbourne International Film Festival partner. 
Facebook:  
Twitter: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cinematic Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane-raised</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian Ted Kotcheff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kill Me Three Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>True Blue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLennan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenneth Cook's 1961</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindy Morrison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Valitutti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Tambourine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fleetwood Mac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant McLennan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stenders</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paco LeA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleater-Kinney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ragnarok</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Dodson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Dog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Forster</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIFF 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go-Betweens</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kriv Stenders</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne International Film Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trailers Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Stratton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Right Here</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIFF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiki</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Aitken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
