<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417347839941873</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/crime-and-justice/virtual-onthespot-domestic-violence-orders-deliver-clear-results/news-story/bdbed48292aed065ce325c3f12d03646</url>
  <title>'On-the-spot' DV orders boost results</title>
  <content>
THE number of police-issued orders to protect women and children from domestic violence has tripled under  delivered by the State Government.
Under legislation introduced in May, police can now issue virtual 'on-the-spot' domestic violence orders against alleged offenders.
The new laws have also been expanded to include, for the first time, alleged offences against children.
Since the introduction of the new laws, more than 1100 notices have been issued across the state - almost two thirds of the entire figure for the last financial year.
Speaking at a media conference on the Gold Coast today, Minister for the Prevention of Domestic and Family Violence Shannon Fentiman said the new laws had already delivered clear results.
"Police on the scene can now provide immediate legal protection for victims of Domestic Violence even if a perpetrator is not present, which was not possible before the changes took effect," she said.
"This tells us police are using these notices more often to keep women and children safe and the changes we have made have strengthened the protection police can put in place when called to domestic violence incidents."
However, she said more needed to be done to tackle domestic violence, which she called a scourge on society.
"It is absolutely abhorrent that this is still happening," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domestic Violence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prevention of Domestic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Violence Shannon Fentiman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
