<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417296300333553</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/football/qatar-buying-credibility-by-splashing-cash-on-neymar-latest-in-acquisition-of-expensive-assets/news-story/4376a8b6fd13ba0cefa6ba626b7a540a</url>
  <title>Qatar buying credibility by splashing cash on Neymar latest in acquisition of expensive assets</title>
  <content>
Neymar agrees to PSG deal
0:47

Football: Neymar has agreed to a five-year contract with French club PSG.

August 3rd 2017
4 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Football/

Neymar is reportedly set to join PSG from Barcelona.

AFPAFP

Share

THE soon-to-be world's most expensive footballer is the latest asset accrued by the tiny energy-rich emirate of Qatar who are desperate to stay relevant in the face of bad publicity.
By signing Brazilian superstar Neymar for its flagship sporting asset, French football club Paris St-Germain, Qatar is projecting a business-as-usual image to the world after two months locked in a bitter diplomatic dispute.
While a footnote in monetary terms in Qatar's wider investment portfolio, the immensely wealthy 2022 World Cup host nation has long used sports as a way to elevate its stature.

Neymar is reportedly set to join PSG from Barcelona.Source:AFP
Signing one of the most recognisable and marketable figures in the sports world would be an extravagant demonstration of that.
PSG will reportedly pay Neymar's $330 million buyout clause in the "coming hours". That would more than double the current transfer record set by Paul Pogba's $156 million move to Manchester United last year.
Then there is the player contract itself. Several media outlets are reporting that Neymar is expected to sign a five-year deal worth more than $818,000 a week. That's over $42m a year just in wages.
Doing the maths on actual numbers for the term of the contract, well, the numbers are simply mindboggling.
But Qatar likely sees this as absolutely necessary.

QATARI CASH SPLASH
The services of Neymar is just the latest high-profile asset snapped up by the oil and gas rich nation Qatar in the last few years. Here's an abridged list of what you can buy if you had billions of petro-dollars and a desperate desire for global legitimacy.  Paris St Germain purchased in 2012 for $170 million, The 2022 World Cup (price undisclosed)Harrods Department Store ($2.5 billion), A stake in Empire State Building of New York ($782 million)Valentino Fashion Group ($1,5 billion), Miramax Studios ($830 million), Paul Cezanne's "The Card Players" ($315 million),  Paul Gauguin's "When Will You Marry?" ($370 million), Mark Rothko "White Center (Yellow, Pink and Lavender on Rose)" ($92 million)
And they have fans. Manchester United manager Jose Mourinho actually sees it as good business.

"Expensive are the ones who get into a certain level without a certain quality," he said.
"I think that Neymar is the same (as Pogba). I don't think he is expensive.
"Neymar is one of the best players in the world, commercially he is very strong."
Qatar has been waging an international public relations offensive to fend off accusations by Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates, Egypt and Bahrain that it supports extremists.
Qatar strongly denies the allegation but their only land border has been sealed off.

Jose Mourinho with Paul Pogba who is about to the second most expensive player in the world.Source:AFP
Officials have made a point of saying that the vast construction project for the World Cup has been unaffected by the blockade. But they have acknowledged that import costs overall have risen dramatically for items such as food and medicine, which now need to be flown in or shipped by sea from points further afield.
While big-ticket assets like British department store Harrods seem more financially astute investments for Qatar, sports entities and events enjoy a higher profile.
Qatar hosted the 2006 Asian Games and the Asian Cup football finals in 2011, and stages annual tennis and motorcycle grand prix events.
All those will pale in comparison to its controversial hosting of the World Cup in 2022.
PSG has yet to win European football's Champions League title despite the lavish investment from Qatar Sports Investments.
Linked to the country's leadership, QSI describes itself as a "closed shareholding organisation" that is chaired by Nasser Ghanim al-Khelaifi, a Qatari former tennis player who is also chairman and CEO of beIN.

PSG president Nasser Al-Khelaifi is a former Qatari tennis player.Source:AFP
The sports network was caught up in the diplomatic dispute, too, with its signal along with that of Al-Jazeera cut for viewers in the boycotting countries. The UAE unblocked the network more than a week ago though to the delight of fans.
It will be through beIN that Neymar's matches from PSG are beamed onto screens across the Middle East if a transfer that would provide a potent example of Qatar's sporting firepower is completed.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will You Marry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose)" ($92</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Cezanne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Jazeera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar Sports Investment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrods Department Store ($2.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of beIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris St-Germain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Arab Emirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Mourinho</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Egypt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UAE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Gauguin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasser Al-Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentino Fashion Group ($1,5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pogba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QATARI CASH SPLASH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QSI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BeIn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pogba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasser Ghanim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Rothko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>York ($782</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bahrain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pogba's $156</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Card Players" ($315</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar's $330</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miramax Studios ($830</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Empire State Building of New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFPAFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
