<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416136659142909</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/royals/prince-philip-retires-from-public-life-after-royal-marines-parade-at-buckingham-palace/news-story/e2c7a9556a54ff0993a20a7a2c45e05e</url>
  <title>Prince Philip retires from public life after Royal Marines parade at Buckingham Palace</title>
  <content>
Prince Philip to retire on Wednesday
2:39

Prince Philip will attend his final official engagement during a parade at Buckingham Palace on Wednesday.

August 2nd 2017
13 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Britain's Prince Philip, Duke of Edinburgh will attend a parade of Royal Marines at Buckingham Palace, the last of 22,219 solo public engagements. Picture: AFP

Ellen Whinnett in London, staff writersNews Corp Australia Network

Share

THE Queen's husband, 96-year-old Prince Philip, has formally retired from public life, marking the event at a parade on the forecourt at Buckingham Palace overnight.
Prince Philip, the Duke of Edinburgh, announced in May that he would no longer undertake program of public events.
While he may appear with Queen Elizabeth, 91, from time to time, a parade by the Royal Marines marked his final royal appearance in his own right.

The Duke of Edinburgh attended a parade of Royal Marines at Buckingham Palace, the last of 22,219 solo public engagements since she ascended to the throne in 1952. Picture: AFP.Source:AFP
The Duke appeared at the parade, which started just after midnight Australian time, in his position of Captain General of the Royal Marines, a position he has held for the past 64 years.

Britain's Queen Elizabeth II with Prince Philip arrive by horse drawn carriage in the parade ring on the third day, traditionally known as Ladies Day, of the Royal Ascot horse race meeting. Picture: APSource:AP
He succeeded the late King George VI, Queen's Elizabeth's father, when the king died in 1952.
The Captain General's Parade last night was planned to mark the finale of the 1664 Global Challenge, a charitable event which saw members of the Royal Marines run 16.64 miles (26.77kms) each day for 100 days, totalling a distance of 1664 miles (2674kms).

After a lifetime of public service by the side of his wife Queen Elizabeth II, Prince Philip finally retires on August 2, 2017, at the age of 96. Picture: AFP.Source:AFP
Prince Philip performed the royal salute before meeting some of the Royal Marines runners, including two who completed the entire distance.

The Royal Marines offered three cheers for their retiring Captain General after the march had taken place.

Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip, Duke of Edinburgh, as they wave to supporters from the balcony at Buckingham Palace, following her coronation at Westminster Abbey. Picture: APSource:AP
In his 64-year royal career, Prince Philip has undertaken 22,219 solo engagements, made 637 solo overseas visits, given 5496 speeches, been patron of 785 organisations and authored 14 books.

Onlookers watch as Britain's Prince Philip, Duke of Edinburgh, in his role as Captain General, Royal Marines, attends a Parade to mark the finale of the 1664 Global Challenge on the Buckingham Palace Forecourt in central London on August 2, 2017. Picture: AFP.Source:AFP
His grandson Prince Harry, like his grandfather a war veteran, has replaced him as Captain General of the Royal Marines.
Since Prince Philip announced his plans to retire, other members of the royal family have taken on a greater load, including the heir to the throne Prince Charles, and the young royals Prince William and his wife Catherine, and Prince Harry.

Queen Elizabeth II sits next to Prince Philip in the House of Lords as she waits to read the Queen's speech to politicians in London. Picture: APSource:AP
Prince William and Catherine accompanied Prince Charles to Belgium this week for the centenary commemorations of the battle of Passchendaele.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke of Edinburgh</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Prince Philip</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Lords</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace Forecourt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladies Day, of the Royal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ascot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westminster Abbey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APSource</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain General of the Royal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth II</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Challenge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>writersNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain General's Parade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain General</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Passchendaele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Queen Elizabeth II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George VI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP.Source</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Marines</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellen Whinnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
