<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416789494184479</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/portugal-plane-crash-leaves-girl-8-and-man-56-dead/news-story/d99296b65da1d725b9d68f77efdea894</url>
  <title>Girl killed by plane while sunbaking</title>
  <content>
A YOUNG girl and man have been killed after a plane made an emergency landing on a beach in Portugal while the pilot was having a flying lesson.
The victims, aged 8 and 56, were sunbathing on Sao Joao beach near Lisbon when the horror unfolded.
A fuming mob on the packed beach branded the trainee pilot a "killer" and had to be held back by police,  reports.
Police chief Paulo Isabel confirmed the two men on board the plane, an instructor and his pupil, had been arrested and were being questioned.
Terrified holidaymakers were left running for their lives after the light aircraft landed on the beach and skidded across a football pitch where children were playing.
Witnesses claim the trainee, who was on a flying lesson with a 56-year-old pilot, was confronted by furious sunbathers after they realised the young girl and man had died.
One, known only as Mafalda, told a Portuguese paper how she was forced to grab her children and flee as the plane came down over the packed beach.
She said: "Those first moments were very tense. People wanted to attack the pilot and began to shout at him that he was a killer.
"Everyone was really disgusted."
Maritime Police Chief Pedro Coelho Dias, confirming the two deaths, said: "The victims are a man and an eight-year-old girl.
"They were hit by the plane and died at the scene."
The tragedy was on a stretch of coastline known as Costa da Caparica - a short drive from Manchester United coach Jose Mourinho's home city of Setubal.
Witnesses said the plane had approached the beach in silence so people only noticed it seconds before it came in to land.
Both the tragic youngster and the adult man are believed to be Portuguese - although there was no official confirmation of their nationalities - but not related.
The dead girl was with her parents, who were unhurt, witnesses told local television channels.
Shocking pictures show the aircraft in the sea surrounded by horrified onlookers.
The plane is said to have come from an air club in the Lisbon neighbourhood of Torres Vedras.
It was described as a Cessna-152 - capable of a cruising speed of 90mph.
Investigators are now believed to be probing a possible mechanical failure.
This article was first
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caparica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Setubal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Police Chief Pedro Coelho Dias</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Vedras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessna-152</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisbon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulo Isabel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sao Joao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mafalda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portuguese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
