<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416402947120719</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/lifestyle/food/full-set-of-penfolds-grange-to-break-australian-auction-records/news-story/5d0c6a8eeee2a15d7f8a64eccd3b6b34</url>
  <title>Iconic Aussie wine worth $250,000</title>
  <content>
ONE of the most spectacular sets of wine ever seen in Australia will go up for sale in Adelaide on Sunday - and it's expected to break all auction records.
The full set of Penfolds Grange, considered Australians most famous wine and in global terms one of the great wines of the world, has been valued at between $250,000 and $280,000 for buyers at du Plessis auction rooms in Adelaide's inner west.
The sale lot contains 62 bottles stretching from the first experimental 1951 vintage made by Grange's creator Max Schubert through to the latest release 2012 vintage made by current Penfolds chief winemaker Peter Gago and which was rated 99/100 points in the latest Halliday Wine Companion released August 3.
Many of the bottles have been signed by Penfolds' chief winemakers at the time of release, and also have been inspected by Penfolds' regular recorking clinics and marked as being in solid condition.
Auctioneer Mark du Plessis describes the set as being in excellent condition, having being pieced together over 25 years by an anonymous Adelaide building industry figure who is an avid collector and reportedly very particular about the storage and handling of the wine at all times.
Unbelievably, it is one of two sets owned by the vendor, though the second is still to be fully completed with some of the first and increasingly rare 1950s vintages.
The vendor is thought to have established the sets as an investment over time, which looks like coming to fruition on Sunday with keen interest already being shown from potential Australian buyers.
The price range potentially will be exceeded given that the most recent similar set went reportedly for more than $300,000 in December in a private sale brokered by Dan Murphy's.
The growth in the value of full Grange sets is difficult to track given their extreme rarity, though in 1988 a then set from 1952-1982 sold for a record Australian price of $16,500. In 2002 a full collection then from 1951-1996 vintages pulled $190,680.
Interest is expected to grow from international buyers before the auction as they spot the set's competitive price compared to another full set for sale in Dubai in recent years going for the equivalent of more than $600,000.
Investment interest has been sparked over the decades as even the rarest single bottles from better vintages have been doubling and tripling in price every two or three years. A recent sale in Victoria of the first vintage 1951 Grange Hermitage clocked more than $60,000.
"The potential buyers are keen because it is so hard to find a full set of Grange," Mr du Plessis said.
"We like to sell it in South Australia where the wine originates, and we'd like it to stay in South Australia," Mr du Plessis said.
"Penfolds Grange is not just an Australian icon, it's a South Australian icon. A set like this is of rare historical importance."
Details and photos of the set are available as Lot number 167 at duplessis.com.au
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Gago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plessis</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Schubert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halliday Wine Companion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penfolds Grange</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange Hermitage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
