<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416909753271304</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/jack-riewoldt-confident-of-taking-on-hawthorn-hawks-after-freak-eye-injury-20170802-gxo9hl.html</url>
  <title>Riewoldt confident of taking on Hawthorn</title>
  <content>
Richmond spearhead Jack Riewoldt is very confident he will be able to line up against Hawthorn on Sunday at the MCG after suffering a nasty eye injury last week.
Riewoldt was accidentally poked in the eye by teammate Mabior Chol in a freak training accident that saw the dual Coleman medallist require surgery.

Up Next

Sam Mitchell retires

02:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

Sam McClure previews all the footy action ahead of round 20 in the AFL.

As a result, the 28-year-old was forced to sit out the Tigers' 33-point win over Gold Coast on Saturday night.
But Riewoldt said the club doctor seemed happy with the way his eye was healing and the star forward would be surprised if he wasn't given the all clear to play this weekend.Photo: AAP
"I feel pretty strong that I'm going to be right and get up there for a big game against the Hawks," Riewoldt told RSN 927 on Thursday.
"It's a lot better than what it was at about 11 o'clock this time last week.

"Most of the blood has come out of it, I went and saw the club doctor yesterday about it, I've been getting daily check-ups, and he was really happy with it so I'll go and catch up with the eye specialist today and then hopefully get the tick off and then it's training tomorrow.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The main issues are I've got a cut on the eyeball which, as much as it sounds silly, it's a non-issue the cut on the white of my eye. It's more the cornea, I've got a little graze on that as well so that has got to be made sure that all the blood has dissipated from that and that's healed up enough to not re-bleed and that they feel comfortable that it's not going to reinjure from just running around in general."
Riewoldt said he experienced a "little bit of pain" immediately after the incident but that was replaced by a "weird feeling" soon after.
"I was looking to try and clear the eye, like when you get a little bit of dust or something in your eye and you blink a few times and try to clear it. I was just doing that but it wasn't happening," Riewoldt said.
"The sensation or the feeling or what I was looking at out of the right eye was just basically like a blood-stained frosted glass and I really couldn't see anything.
"It took me six hours before I had the surgery to come out of that and be able to see fairly clearly.
"So at the moment my right pupil is still fairly dilated just from the drops that you take, that's the healing process.
"The doctor did explain that I was probably a little bit unlucky with what had happened but also with those collision injuries, detaching at the back of the eye can be a real issue.
"I certainly realised how important sight is being debilitated for a week."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam McClure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mabior Chol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSN927</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
