<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416952702944992</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/amazon-to-open-first-warehouse-in-melb/news-story/ad6029ece2ad83cae2c51334bf44899b</url>
  <title>Amazon chooses Vic for first warehouse</title>
  <content>
Online retail giant Amazon will open its first Australian distribution warehouse in Melbourne's south eastern suburbs, in a move the company says will create hundreds of jobs.
Amazon has announced it will open a 24,000 square metre fulfilment centre in Dandenong South at the M2 industrial park.
The company's Australian director of operations Robert Bruce said "this is just the start" for Amazon.
"Over time, we will bring thousands of new jobs to Australia and millions of dollars of investment as well as opening up the opportunity for thousands of Australian businesses to sell at home and abroad through Amazon Marketplace," Bruce said on Wednesday.
He promised hundreds of thousands of products would be stocked at the new warehouse at low prices for Australian consumers.
Victorian Industry Minister Wade Noonan said it was the latest global company to choose the state for its Australian operations.
"The company's decision to locate its centre in Dandenong South will create hundreds of local jobs and open up retail opportunities for thousands of local businesses," Mr Noonan said.
The international giant has already started to recruit staff including operations managers, pickers, packers, systems technicians and HR specialist.
The company already has 1000 employees in Australia.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong South</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Industry Minister Wade Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
