<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417051487194144</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/holden-promises-to-change-ways-after-failing-custo/3208246/</url>
  <title>Holden promises to change ways after failing customers</title>
  <content>
HOLDEN acknowledges it failed to respond to manufacturing faults and deceived owners seeking fixes under warranty.
Some customers had been denied assistance because their vehicles had not been serviced by a Holden dealer or because it was bought second-hand.
, the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission has forced Holden "to comply with its consumer guarantee obligations under the Australian Consumer Law".
Investigations by the ACCC revealed Holden's responses to manufacturing faults was likely to have contravened the consumer law.
"Holden acknowledged that it misrepresented to some consumers that it had discretion to decide whether the vehicle owner would be offered a refund, repair or replacement for a car with a manufacturing fault, and that any remedy was a goodwill gesture," ACCC chairman Rod Sims said.
"Holden also accepted that some consumers were told that a remedy would not be provided because the vehicle had not been serviced by a Holden dealer or with sufficient regularity, or as the vehicle was purchased second hand.
"The Australian Consumer Law includes consumer guarantees that provide remedies for major and minor faults in motor vehicles. The consumer guarantees operate separately to the manufacturer's warranty, and cannot be modified to require consumers to have their vehicles serviced by authorised dealers in order to obtain a remedy."
According to the ACCC, Holden "has offered an undertaking that goes beyond ensuring compliance with the current consumer guarantee obligations and commits to measures in line with recommended changes to the law".
"These are great commitments that will have a significant and positive impact for consumers," Mr Sims said.
Among the Holden commitments are:
The ACCC's new car retailing study draft report will be released this month and will elaborate on the "widespread compliance issues we have encountered across this industry".
"As shown over the past week, the ACCC has a range of enforcement tools available to address unlawful conduct and we take a proportional response in addressing non-compliance. I urge all companies selling cars in Australia to get their consumer law compliance programs in order."
Holden is currently preparing to shut manufacturing operations in Australia.
A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Consumer Law</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Sims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
