<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416437306859606</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/melbourne-train-delays-due-to-massive-electrical-spark/news-story/1513dc6870dac0f6a8525370eadc60b4</url>
  <title>Explosion sparks peak hour train delays</title>
  <content>
A MASSIVE electrical spark has ground trains to a halt this morning near Flinders St Station.
Passengers on board the affected train were forced to jump off the train and walk along Batman Ave to the nearby station.
Metro spokeswoman Sammie Black confirmed an overhead power issue between Richmond and Flinders St station is causing delays of up to 45 minutes on the Sandringham line.
MFB crews were called to Flinders St station at 7.24am but confirmed it was a "false alarm" and there was no fire.
Crews left the scene a short time later.
Electricians are on site and Metro said they are hoping to restore power shortly.
Commuters are urged to check the Metro website for information about delayed services.
Motorists are also facing major delays this morning as four crashes within a one kilometre stretch of the Western Ring road caused traffic chaos about 7am.
The multi-car crashes, which occurred within an hour of each other, has traffic backed up Altona-bound between Airport Drive and the Calder Freeway.
The left lane remains closed at Airport Drive, due to two separate collisions.
There is also a third collision in the left-hand emergency lane Altona-bound.
Delays are currently back to the Tullamarine Freeway.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders St Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Altona-bound</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calder Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airport Drive</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Ring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sammie Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batman Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tullamarine Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
