<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416136659142876</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/football/ffa-cup-blacktown-city-beat-central-coast-mariners-32/news-story/bc275ef6762712f5c11ff52884d6d526</url>
  <title>Blacktown sink Mariners in Cup upset</title>
  <content>
From the 1100 fans crammed into a tiny ground to the emergency floodlights balanced on cranes, a night at Lily Homes Stadium in Seven Hills had all the hallmarks of the perfect FFA Cup night.
All we needed was a cup upset to complete the script, and Blacktown City found inspiration to deliver exactly that.
As the Mariners players slumped to the floor on the final whistle, on the wrong end of a 3-2 loss that kills their cup campaign at the outset, the strains of Dreams Can Come True echoed from speakers around the ground.
Thanks to two goals from a former A-League striker - and one born in Gosford to boot - Blacktown City can hope to host another of the nation's top sides in the Round of 16. They could win their minor premiership on Sunday too. Mark Crittenden's side could have quite a week.
For the the Central Coast Mariners it was another bitter FFA Cup experience, doomed to play the role of sacrifical lambs for the second year in a row after being embarrassed by Green Gully last year. Down 2-0 with barely a quarter hour on the clock, the visitors must have assumed the tide had turned their way when a pair of goals from Kwabena Appiah brought the tie level.
But Blacktown are not top of the NSW state league by accident, and in striker Joey Gibbs they have a player with nearly 20 A-League appearances - and remarkably, as a Sydney FC teenager off the bench, a title winner's medal. Now aged 25, Gibbs had already made his mark two minutes in with a well-placed freekick to give his side the lead.
When Roberto Speranza then played a one-two with Gibbs and sauntered into the Mariners box before driving home his side's second, the disbelief was not confined to visiting faces.
In truth the visitors hardly played badly - they moved the ball with precision and speed, and looked to work their way around City's packed lines of defence. Appiah's first goal was a moment of brilliance, capping a mazy run with a curling finish.
Soon after halftime he had another, bundling home the equaliser from close range, and the romance of the nght seemed elbowed aside by cold, hard professionalism. But the Mariners were careless with their finishing, and then, with eight minutes left, careless in defence once more.
Turned too easily on the left flank, the Mariners defenders stood and watched as Gibbs was fed just outside the box and placed the ball into the bottom corner. It sparked a furious onslaught from the Mariners, predictably, and yet their were few scares for Tristan Prendergast in the home goal until the final whistle sounded.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast Mariners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dreams Can Come True</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Gully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appiah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Crittenden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tristan Prendergast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey Gibbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lily Homes Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwabena Appiah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberto Speranza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gibbs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
