<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416136659142881</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/poisonous-relationships-between-adelaide-specialists-inquest/8768594</url>
  <title>Stroke deaths inquest told of 'poisonous relationships' between Adelaide specialists</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

An inquest into two men's hospital deaths has heard of "poisonous relationships" between Adelaide specialists, who might have been protective of their lucrative incomes.
Patients Michael John Russell, 60, and Leslie Robert Graham, 87, arrived at the Royal Adelaide Hospital on the same day back in April, each having suffered a stroke and needing emergency treatment.
On Wednesday the coroner heard leave had been granted for both the hospital's interventional neuroradiologists, Rebecca Scroop and James Taylor, with one overseas and the other fishing, south of Adelaide.
The court heard a specialist radiologist from another public hospital, Steve Chryssidis, was called in to perform the emergency treatment, but there were complications and both patients later died.
Asked why specialists from other hospitals could not be included on the on-call roster, acting head of radiology Jim Buckley told the inquest it was "controversial" and he agreed under cross-examination the specialists might be protective of their patch and incomes.
"This is the sort of situation that makes management very difficult ... with such poisonous relationships between different radiologists," Dr Buckley told the inquest.
He told the court he was aware the relationship between the RAH specialists and the FMC specialist "wasn't good" and said he did not know why, but agreed there may be a sense of protectiveness.
"I became aware of it, I think everyone did, it was common knowledge within the department and in Adelaide that there was not a good relationship between the three radiologists," Dr Buckley said.
He said he knew Dr Chryssidis well and "got on very well with him" and did not know how much of the difficulties were caused by "professional antipathy", "professional lack of respect" or "what part of it would be motivated by financial factors".
The court heard the two stroke specialists at the Royal Adelaide each earnt more than $1 million last financial year, including a large portion for after-hours calls.
to boost staffing, a move which had been recommended as far back as 2015.
He said a 24/7 service provided by only two people amounted to a "very fragile roster indeed".
Dr Buckley said a third specialist had since been appointed to help meet the workloads, but she could not work alone because of lack of experience.
The inquest, which resumes on today, is expected to run for at least a fortnight with a number of hospital department heads and radiologists to give evidence.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Scroop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Buckley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie Robert Graham, 87</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Chryssidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael John Russell, 60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Chryssidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FMC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
