<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416136659142896</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/that-thinking-feeling/how-many-of-our-bosses-would-have-aced-naplan-tests-20170802-gxo72j.html</url>
  <title>How many of our bosses would have aced NAPLAN tests?</title>
  <content>
In more than 25 years' of journalism, I've never interviewed a leader who topped his or her class at school.
Not a business leader like the steel-minded Gail Kelly or international scientist Professor Ian Frazer, whose science helped deliver the cervical cancer vaccine.Photo: Supplied
Not church leaders or politicians, merchant bankers. Not even Queensland's chief entrepreneur Mark Sowerby.
So why do we continue to push along - and judge our teachers - ? 

Yesterday's news was as tiresome as it was old. A mixed bag of results. We need to try harder. No real change in 10 years. The shock school that did well. 
It does not matter. I've learnt that a few times, starting when one of my daughters did off-the-chart well in year 3, but asked me should she have labelled herself Aboriginal or Torres Strait Islander.

Shouldn't knowledge of her background at least rival her maths?
I learnt it again, as a journalist when parents told me of their year 5 children dry-retching on the morning of the exam. Yes. Aged 10.Photo: Nic Walker
Now that's not an argument against testing - but for a dose of common sense around this.
What employer is going to demand a student's NAPLAN results, or increasingly even their academic results?
None. They want a quick learner, with a passion for the task. Someone who is loyal and hard-working, with an inner resilience and an ability to lead others.
Hold on. Not one of those traits is tested currently by our education system. Not one.
Schools, and the wonderful teachers who fill them, know that and find time in a crowded curriculum for everything from the dangers of social media to yoga, to critical thinking skills.
But it's more difficult for parents to value when our current system rewards an A in maths over astute emotional resilience and leadership skills.
And until we change it, and give equal weighting to the skills that will better dictate our life journeys, nothing will change.
But here's food for thought. Ms Kelly, the first female CEO of one of Australia's big four banks and listed by Forbes in 2010 as the eighth most powerful woman in the world, fell into banking.
She tried teaching first, and it didn't work out. Her grades were good, not great. She says leadership is as much about what you don't know as you do.
And what did she study at university? Latin and history. Not a single number. Go figure.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Ian Frazer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Sowerby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
