<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417433739289053</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/entertainment/all-set-to-smash-darwin/news-story/7f5eb0d2516f5575ab4189d0ce1f3ed9</url>
  <title>All set to smash Darwin</title>
  <content>
KITTY Flanagan enters new territory with her latest stand-up show Smashing.

The veteran Aussie comedian of stage and screen is talking about sex for the first time ever in her stand-up show which comes to the Darwin Entertainment Centre tomorrow night.

"I'm not comfortable talking about sex, but I'm going to overcome my fears," she said.

"(I've never spoken about sex) because it's personal and it wasn't really relevant - I didn't have anything funny to say about it but I've discovered some funny things about sex, mainly around the fact I'm bad at sex."

The realisation stems from the time Flanagan was told she was bad in the bedroom.

"At the time I think I just obliterated the comment and put it out of my mind, and then when I started to think about it recently, I thought that's really funny," she said.

But the show isn't all sex talk and the title Smashing is also unrelated to her sexual pursuits.

"Smashing is the only verb you need anymore," she said.

"It's always a bit of a challenged to come up with a title for a show but it seemed to be all around me.

"Everyone seems to be smashing everything these days. I heard someone smashing his burgers, smashing a coffee and I heard some girls talking about going to smash some cocktails."

Kitty Flanagan at the Darwin Entertainment Centre tomorrow at 8pm. Tickets $55/$50.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Entertainment Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flanagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KITTY Flanagan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
