<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417506753734789</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/brisbane-road-rage-death-probably-biggest-mistake-of-life-court/8770444</url>
  <title>Brisbane road rage death: 'Biggest mistake of his life' to pull over, court told</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A New Zealand man on trial over a fatal road rage incident made "probably the biggest mistake of his life" when he pulled over, a Brisbane court has been told.
Tamate Henry Heke, 38, has been accused of punching 50-year-old Shane Merrigan and causing him to fall into the path of a garbage truck on the Gateway Motorway at Eight Mile Plains on Brisbane's southside in December 2015.
Heke has .
In summing up the case, defence counsel Anthony Kimmins told the Supreme Court "there was aggressive driving on behalf of the deceased that afternoon".
Mr Kimmins said that included tailgating and that his client was effectively blocked for "the sin" of not increasing his speed.
"The Gateway Motorway as far as Tama was concerned turned into a version of The Fast and the Furious and at no stage was Tama in control," he told the court.
"Just stop and think if you were in his car that afternoon?
"You may well think that the deceased himself was committing a case of dangerous driving.
"It was probably the biggest mistake of his life [Heke] to pull over."
Mr Kimmins also told the court Heke was a hard-working man that had never been involved in criminal activity in his life.
"The prosecution says this person turned from an ordinary law-biding citizen ... to a killer ... deserving punishment," Mr Kimmins said.
"Looking at it completely you would not find that the prosecution have established beyond reasonable doubt ... that he turned himself into a criminal."
The altercation between the pair lasted just 20 seconds.
The jury is expected to retire later today.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateway Motorway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamate Henry Heke, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eight Mile Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Kimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kimmins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
