<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417639897722581</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/motorbike-rider-remains-critical-after-serious-crash-on-gold-coast/news-story/4bc4b4d26a2fd847a7c5a54845cf7b26</url>
  <title>'The most horrific thing I've seen'</title>
  <content>
GOLD Coast motorists have described the horrific moment they witnessed a  at Burleigh Waters yesterday.
Witnesses reported seeing a rider, believed to be the same man, travelling at high speed and zigzagging in traffic as far north as Logan.
It is understood the man's foot may have been severed in the high-impact accident.
A Gold Coast Bulletin follower shared a graphic image of the man lying on the road with a severed limb at least 20m ahead on the road.
The man, aged in his 30s, remains in a critical condition.
He was believed to be wearing just a singlet, pants, thongs and no helmet when he crashed metres before the southbound Bermuda St exit around 5.20pm yesterday.
Police and paramedics received multiple calls about the accident which delayed traffic for hours.
Witnesses believed the man was riding erratically and speeding along the Pacific Motorway at up to 160km/h.
Jillian Hodgkinson wrote on Facebook: "This guy rode past me at Helensvale! He was swerving over the (two) outside lanes. He even pulled his bag around to his front and grabbed a can of something, drinking it and threw it nearly hitting a car behind him. Was horrific to watch! I was just hoping he'd get pulled over or something. Not this."
Another witness, Karlene Michaelidis, wrote she saw him "driving like a crazy man", while Daniel Ftp Conway wrote: "Seen him on Logan Motorway doing 160 easy."
Other users expressed anger over the incident, with one Facebook user commenting: "Self inflicted. Feel sorry for the people who witnessed it however no sympathy for stupidness (sic). People like him gives us who do the right thing a bad name."
Witness Raema Dick described the smash "as the most horrific thing I have ever seen."
"I am physically ill," she wrote.
"No words could explain. I was in the car behind and watched the impact then him laying there on the road."
Police are continuing to investigate the accident.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raema Dick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helensvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Ftp Conway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bermuda St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karlene Michaelidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jillian Hodgkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
