<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417644192689947</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/the-retailers-most-vulnerable-to-amazons-australian-arrival-2017-8</url>
  <title>The retailers most vulnerable to Amazon's Australian arrival</title>
  <content>
UBS equity analysts have assessed which Australian retailers are most exposed to competition from Amazon.

The UBS team set out their buy/sell recommendations for Australian retail stocks, taking into account the Amazon effect.

The bank's forecast revisions to earnings for incumbent Australian retailers range between cuts of 1% to 20%. Here's the table:

The results show that UBS has reduced its price target for each stock on the list, but JB Hi-Fi is the only company with a change in rating - from Buy to Neutral.

The bank maintained its Buy recommendations for Harvey Normam, Super Retail Group and Woolworths. It stayed Neutral on Wesfarmers while maintaining a sell rating on Myer and Metcash.

UBS's forecasts factor in price competition as well as the costs of building new infrastructure to compete with Amazon's online service capabilities.

The bank's equity analysts said that the sectors most vulnerable to Amazon's market entry were electronics, sports and apparel/toys.

They said that the hardware, automotive and grocery sectors would be less impacted as they require a higher level of service and Amazon has an inferior product range in those areas.

"Of the listed retailers, we believe Myer, The Reject Shop, JB Hi-Fi and Super Retail Group are the most vulnerable to AMZN from both a 'sales' and 'cost' (need to invest) perspective," UBS said.

The analysts forecast that Amazon will generate sales of $3.5 billion by the 2023 financial year.

They looked at case studies of how Amazon has entered into other internatinoal markets, and the business model places a key focus on setting up Amazon's online presence.

This table shows how UBS expects Amazon to grow its online footprint.

Despite well-documented fears about the competitive threat from Amazon, UBS said there had been a market overreaction for some of Australia's listed retailers.

This chart shows which companies have seen an overreaction, as well as stocks more susceptible to direct competition from Amazon:

Stocks on the wrong end of the market overreaction were either more diversiifeid (Harvey Norman, which only derives 44% of revenue from Australian retail) or in retail sectors where the impact from Amazon would be less severe (sports and automotive).

UBS noted that the stocks in the under-reaction category, such as Myer and JB Hi-Fi, had seen significnat price falls, but the direct threat posed by Amazon mean that current valuations don't fully reflect the downside risks.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metcash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reject Shop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Hi-Fi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMZN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesfarmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Normam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Retail Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
