<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417438034256521</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/entertainment/television/james-weir-recaps-the-bachelor-australia-2017-episode-3/news-story/64e4e7189b141b2d2a2505401de0357d</url>
  <title>'God, don't cry': Bachelor villain's deception</title>
  <content>
IN A desperate attempt to earn sympathy, The Bachelor's villain has hatched an evil plan and emotionally deceived Matty J.
"Whatever it takes to win," Leah beamed before stumbling through a sympathy-grabbing backstory in an effort to get close to Matty J on Wednesday night's medieval themed group date. It was witchcraft of the modern age.
But before we delve into the twisted depths of Leah's mind, we must first get through the chapter entitled Laura and The Curious Case of The Kinky Brows.
Yes, we're treated to another private date that entails fanging around Sydney Harbour on a grey and overcast day. It's like these producers don't know their iPhones have a weather app. Wednesday night's recipient of the rather dreary experience is Laura.
As storm clouds loom overhead, they eat grapes and sip wine before Laura recounts the most stereotypically 20-something white girl anecdote ever. She shares her deep, life-changing, spiritual tales from her time spent in India.
After a ship to shore call for rescue from this story, we find ourselves back on land and sitting in front of two art easels.
Have you heard about those novelty artists who strip completely naked and use their penis dipped in paint to draw portraits at events? Well, that doesn't happen. But it would've been more interesting. Instead, we watch Laura and Matty giving each other side-eye for 15 minutes while they sketch.
"I like that Matty's hilarious and we both have a sense of humour," Laura says after a rather boring day where neither one of them has said anything remotely funny.
After an unnecessarily long time, we see their craft efforts.
Matty's actually does look like he sketched it with his penis.
"Matty's picture of me was possibly the most offensive thing I've seen in my entire life!" Laura gasps. But who is she to talk, hers looks like it was drawn with a penis too.
Afterwards, Matty not only identifies a rather unique quality in Laura, he also coins her new nickname.
"I kinda thought I did the eyebrows really well - they had this really beautiful kink to it. Because yours have a great kink," he observes.
For the rest of the date, Kinky Brows goes to great effort to arch her caterpillars even more to ensure their kinkiness is on fleek.
"So, why'd you pick me for this date," Laura asks, fishing for a compliment.
"You kind of just really stood out on the red carpet," Matty replies half-heartedly.
" ... Okay ..." she says, disappointed he didn't say it was because of her self-described sense of humour or her kinky brows.
As her brows go from kinky to furrowed, Matty moves in for the first kiss of the series. Maybe because he really likes her. Maybe because he got sick of staring at her with the severe afternoon glare in his eyes.
Matty tells her this was the "easiest first date" he's ever been on and, as someone who's been described as "easy on the first date", I know exactly how Laura's feeling.
We've had enough of Laura and her kinky brows,so we head off for a group date in ye olde England.
We arrive in a field where, PLOT TWIST, this broad is an unplanned intruder who jousts her way into Matty's heart.
"Henry VIII had six wives. So only six of you will have a seat at the table," Osher informs the ladies.
Henry VIII's second wife was also executed on false charges of incest, witchcraft, adultery and conspiracy against the king, so look forward to that rose ceremony my fellow dames.
Signing up to The Bachelor pretty much requires you to relinquish any sense of dignity, but for this date the producers have outdone themselves and concocted medieval tasks so humiliating that peasants in the middle ages would've offered to burn themselves at the stake instead of partaking in them.

Over the medieval dinner, Matty asks how the living situation in the mansion is going and Leah - the queen of drama - decides to talk about how awful all the other girls are and how selfless she is.
"I'm very protective - maybe it's the mother instinct in me," the single, childless 24-year-old informs Matty.
"I take on everybody else's feelings as if they're my own."
When Leah's not taking on other people's feelings, she's taking their private dates. She demonstrates this when she grabs a half-empty bottle of pinot grigio and trudges outside to interrupt the one-on-one time Matty's having with some other chick.
Somewhere between catching a pig and eating a comically-large turkey leg, she's hatched a plan to win him over. That plan basically involves making up a really sad-sounding backstory to try and get sympathy like all those losers on The Voice.
"I've never had an issue chasing after something I wanted in my life," she secretly tells us.
"Now that I've got Matty alone, maybe it's time to start playing a different game. I'm happy to play the 'sad, crying one' or be a little vulnerable if I need to."
In the dimly-lit backyard, grasping a wine bottle, Leah begins to stumble through this sympathy-grabbing ploy.
"I was raised by this amazing woman who taught me to care about everyone," she tells him. This opening sentence actually sounds rather serious. Matty looks concerned. Maybe I shouldn't have dismissed her so easily? Maybe it's real?
That's when Leah shoots this smug look at the camera just to show us she knows what's good.
"And I come from this background ... my mum. Oh god, do not cry," she continues, looking down at the ground and placing her palm over her forehead.
"She's a nurse. She takes care of kids. And I come from this background of absorbing people's problems. Because that's what she does. I think that's just in my nature. I care too much. That's just who I am."
Matty falls for it and pulls her in close for a hug. And Leah couldn't be more proud of her conniving efforts.
"Yeah I think that was like 10 out of 10 - come on! Whatever it takes to win," she beams to us afterwards.
And it works a treat. In the surprise rose ceremony, Leah breezes through. It comes down to Simone and Akoulina. And it's the one with the name like a pool detergent that is shown the door.
In keeping with the theme of the night, Akoulina is evicted on accusations of witchcraft and immediately locked in a limousine.
For more observations on witchcraft and how to achieve on fleek kinky brows, follow me on Twitter:
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeah I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leah</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Akoulina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PLOT TWIST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curious Case of The Kinky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry VIII</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kinky Brows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
