<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417532523538897</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:34</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/police-commissioner-to-baltimore-cops-please-dont-use-body-cams-to-falsify-evidence/</url>
  <title>Police Commissioner To Baltimore Cops: Please Don't Use Body Cams To Falsify Evidence</title>
  <content>
On Tuesday, the Baltimore Public Defender's Office released footage it says shows officers planting drugs and staging their discovery for body cameras,  to be released in the last two weeks. Prosecutors have now dropped  that relied on testimony from the officers seen in the videos.

Screenshot: Baltimore Police/

In response to the ongoing scandal, Police Commissioner  offered a simple message to officers in an internal memo yesterday: Please stop doing that. The Baltimore Sun (emphasis ours):

The video made public Tuesday depicts a November traffic stop during which officers arrested a woman for drug possession, claiming they recovered heroin and marijuana from her car. Footage, however, reveals the officers turned their body cameras off for 30 minutes during the stop (without explanation) before turning them back on, a violation of the department's policy.

In one officer's video, timestamped around 11:50PM, he searches the driver's seat of the woman's car, finding nothing. In another video, timestamped around 12:20AM, a second officer suggests searching the same driver's seat and immediately finds a baggie of drugs. The officers did not explain the 30-minute gap in footage. The charges against the woman have been dismissed and her attorney, Josh Insley, says he plans to pursue legal action against the department.

Last week, a similar video of Baltimore police  was released, showing Officer Richard Pinheiro planting a baggie of pills into a soup can, then turning on his camera (unaware it had saved the prior 30 seconds of footage) and recovering the drugs he'd just planted in the can.

Pinheiro is suspended pending an investigation and  because of the involvement of cops seen in either of the two videos. If the police commissioner himself has to warn against misusing body cameras to fake evidence, the issue may be more systematic than the department cares to admit.

[]

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner To Baltimore Cops</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltimore Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Use Body Cams To Falsify Evidence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltimore Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltimore Public Defender's Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Insley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinheiro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltimore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officer Richard Pinheiro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
