<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417429444321677</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/fresh-cheese-a-winner-with-brisbanes-foodies/3208191/</url>
  <title>Fresh cheese a winner with Brisbane's foodies</title>
  <content>
IT might be a small family-run business, but Woombye Cheese has proven itself as one of the most popular flavours in town.
Food and beverage companies from around the Sunshine Coast put their best food forward, showcasing the region to more than 100,000 consumers at the annual Regional Flavours, Brisbane's premier free food and wine event.
For the first time, the Sunshine Coast Council in partnership with Visit Sunshine Coast and Food Agribusiness Network (FAN) sponsored a 'Flavours of the Sunshine Coast' regional hub. The hub included 9 stallholders (all FAN members), a marketing display and a menu hub.
Sandra Cadby, one of the managers, said she was overwhelmed by how much they had sold.
"We sold everything that we brought and had to restock it all after just one day," she said.
"We were so lucky; the weather was beautiful and everything was on our side so it all added to a successful weekend - and it's good cheese of course.
"The cheeses we had were a triple cream brie, Blackall gold washed rind, a truffle triple cream brie, a camembert and our vintage cheddar.
"I think they were all equally enjoyed, but if I had to pick one I would say the Blackall cheese was probably the most popular and I think it sold out first."
The company, which first launched four years ago, was originally founded by Sandra's sister Karen and her brother-in-law Graeme.
Graeme passed away two years ago, and the sisters made the decision to continue his legacy.
"We promised him we would keep the dream alive, and that is what we are doing," Sandra said.
"He was the brains behind it... we are so lucky we have great staff and great support with our distributors; it makes managing it fairly easy.
"It is a small family business, we use only really good local milk from Maleny, and everything is made by hand... it gives you a chance to take a bit more care and attention to what's happening with the cheese.
"Graeme created a good recipe so it just works... we haven't changed his recipe since the first day we trialled it."
The Fresh Chai Co, QCamel, Pip's Real Food, Ten Acres, Kokopod Chocolate, Maleny Black Angus Beef, The Bear and the Ladle, Hum Honey and Hive Haven also featured at Regional Flavours.
Woombye Cheese can be purchased from a number of stockists around the region.
To read the company's full story, visit www.woombyecheese.com.
A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Ocean lovers take the plunge in daring shark net swim
Jetstar drops massive cut-price Sunshine Coast holiday deal.
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Acres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fresh Chai Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Flavours</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hum Honey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny Black Angus Beef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flavours of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Food Agribusiness Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCamel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woombye Cheese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pip's Real Food</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Cadby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokopod Chocolate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visit Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hive Haven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
