<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417682847396188</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4828734/dragons-searching-for-answers-to-inconsistency/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Dragons NRL finals hopes on the line against Rabbitohs</title>
  <content>
STILL LOOKING: Dragons veteran Jason Nightingale remains baffled by his side's inconsistency this season. Picture: AAP

VETERAN Dragons winger Jason Nightingale admits he's at a loss to explain the wildly fluctuating fortunes this season.
The past fortnight has told the story of the Dragons season, putting together a 30-point victory over the then third-placed Sea Eagles only to drop a game to the battling Knights a week later.

It leaves the Dragons hovering on the edge of the top eight and Nightingale said his side needs to find that elusive consistency or risk of slipping out finals picture.
"I can't really put a finger on it. If I could tell you why we wouldn't playing inconsistently,' Nightingale said.
"I'm sure every side in the competition has that battle through a 26-week competition. We're playing in patches and it's definitely a mindset thing more than a skill thing. 

"There's times we throw it around and complete at 90 per cent, and times where we throw it around and complete at 60 [per cent].
"I think it's the fact that we play that high-risk footy, but we need to make sure we're making the right judgement call on which pass to to throw and which one not to throw.
"That's probably the difference between us playing well and us playing poorly."
The loss to the Knights has pitched the Dragons into a finals battle with the fast-finishing Panthers while the Raiders could also make a run at unseating them.
It's a tight squeeze, but Nightingale said there is nothing to gain from ladder-watching.
"It's hard not to look at [the ladder] but it doesn't help anything," he said.

"Any loss puts a dent in your finals hopes. We're still looking finals-bound but that doesn't mean anything. I think the weekend was a good indicator of that.
"You've got to play every game with the right energy or you are going to lose whether they're coming 16th or 10th or fourth. It doesn't really matter.
"It's about making sure you put in a good enough performance to get a winning outcome and we didn't do that on the weekend.
"It's about winning and making sure that you put in consistent performances because, what's the point of getting to the finals if you're just going to turn up and play terribly?"
Nightingale was at the centre of some controversial calls that went against the Dragons last week, with coach Paul McGregor fined for his take in the aftermath.
It's served to keep the focus on the Knights loss but Nightingale dismissed the controversy as "an excuse."
"Refs shouldn't become part of whether you win or lose," he said.

"If we played the kind of footy we played a week earlier we wouldn't be talking about refs because it wouldn't have become a factor.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Nightingale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nightingale</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
