<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417429444321707</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/up-your-baking-game-by-embossing-your-pastries/</url>
  <title>Up Your Baking Game By Embossing Your Pastries</title>
  <content>
Have you ever stared at an empanada, willing it to tell you what delicious filling it contained within its pastry walls? If this scenario sounds familiar, I have good news: You can - as Twitter user @savelexi has shown us - emboss your pastry dough with identifying information, so you never have to wonder if you're reaching for chicken or beef ever again.

Photo by @savelixi via Twitter

My family is in 2037 y'all. They got their empanadas embossed w what meat is inside
- 🍋 (@savelexi)

I couldn't find an empanada-specific pastry press, but I did find , which lets you stamp whatever words and phrases you like onto cookies, fondant and pastry.

In addition to labelling tasty, meat-filled pies, you can use the letters to identify other ingredients, especially those that people might be allergic to or avoiding. Some ideas:

Stamp "VEGAN" onto a batch of vegan cookies, so you don't have to keep clarifying "yes, those are the vegan ones," at your next potluck.

Emboss all raisin-containing treats with "RAISINS UGH" so that they may be avoided.

Stamp top-crusted pies with the names of whatever fruit is inside them, so you don't end up with the wrong meat (a terrible tragedy).

Stamp "NUTS" into nut-containing foods, to warn those with allergies.

You get the idea. Of course, you don't have to limit yourself to identifying info. You can also use the stamps to put your name on every single thing you bake, claiming each cookie, cake and pie as your own.

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baking Game By Embossing Your Pastries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
