<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417511048702112</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/gay-marriage-postal-vote-option-to-be-dumped/news-story/1591cbe513d24516f9a9e55e9b9cd3e0</url>
  <title>Gay marriage postal vote to be dumped</title>
  <content>
THE threat of mail-early/mail-often sabotage is one of the reasons why Government MPs are next week likely to dump the idea of a postal ballot on same-sex marriage.
A national vote, essentially carried out by the Post Office, would be vulnerable to manipulation and delivery failures, those familiar with such ballots warn.
Election officials have documented how thousands of people could people have wasted their votes by using the mail, and ballot-stacking veterans scoff at the idea the system round be free of corruption.
The proposal by Immigration Minister Peter Dutton - intended to replace a hugely expensive plebiscite - appears doomed as Government MPs regroup to prevent the issue overwhelming the first party room meeting when Parliament returns next week.
A range of MPs including supporters of same sex marriage today are urging colleagues to concentrate on the fundamentals of the economy and family budgets, and the possible consequences of Labor's recently announced tax policies.
Queensland LNP member Warren Entsch today told Sky News the marriage equality matter should be settled in the Parliament so the Government can pursue other issues.
"We just need to put it to bed," he said.
Transport Minister Darren Chester, who also backs same sex marriage, told ABC radio today the plebiscite policy should be endorsed.
"Let's resolve this issue and get onto these other topics like national security and economic stability," he said.
It is possible Coalition MPs next week will be asked to support taking a plebiscite proposal to the next election scheduled for 2019 - the second time it would be put to voters - and holding it in the next term of government should the Coalition be returned.
This is unlikely to satisfy marriage equality advocates who see it as a delaying tactic.
The cost of a plebiscite, estimated to be as much as $160 million is being used as an argument for Mr Dutton's plan
Mr Dutton's counter proposal for a voluntary, non-binding postal vote of electors would cost around a quarter as much, but would have dubious credibility.
In March the ACT Electoral Commission reported hundreds of voters had been disenfranchised by failures of the mail system.
It found there had been 318 errant postal votes in the 2012 election, and in the 2016 poll the total reached 701.
That's a tiny fraction of the number of registered voters, but would be a considerable number if the same proportion applied to 16.5 million federal voters.
"This is a strong indication that the current postal service is not meeting the requirements for long distance postal voting," said ACT Electoral Commissioner Phillip Green "A significant number of electors were disenfranchised in 2016 as a result of their residency in an overseas location.
"There is genuine concern across Australian electoral jurisdictions that recent alterations to Australia Post's business model is resulting in increased delivery times for postal items and in turn is potentially increasing the likelihood that a postal vote may be rejected."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Darren Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dutton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Electoral Commissioner Phillip Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Post Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Electoral Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
