<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417476688963201</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/breaking-identities-of-accused-rocky-bomb-hoaxers-/3208316/</url>
  <title>Breaking: Identities of accused Rocky bomb hoaxers revealed</title>
  <content>
THE accused Rockhampton bomb hoax duo will appear in Rockhampton Magistrates Court this afternoon.

Gracemere's Kieren James Fyfe, 24, and Adam Clifford Ramm, 22, are currently in custody charged with two counts each of bomb hoax.

Earlier today, Fyfe appeared before Magistrate Catherine Benson, but his application for bail was stood down until 3pm.

Fyfe, sitting in the dock in a pair of board shorts and a tee shirt, listened, aIdentirms folded, as the court heard about an alleged hoax call on June 22.

Police prosecutor Clancy Fox said a JB HI-FI employee at Stocklands Rockhampton took a call about 7.50pm on the Thursday, which is late-night shopping at Rockhampton's busiest shopping centre.

Mr Fox said the 30-second call was made from Ramm's phone.

He said the employee was warned: "I have left a bomb in the DVD section...it goes off at 8.55pm."

Duty lawyer Axel Beard told the court Fyfe claimed to not be the one to make the call. However, Mr Beard understood both men were blaming each other.

"The pair were intoxicated and made the call together from Ramm's phone," Mr Beard told the court.

"They tried calling Project Mex and the United Service Station earlier that night. They were successful with United."

Police were able to use JB HI-FI's phone records to reverse call back to Ramm's device and subsequently made the connections.

"Stocklands management acted appropriately and dealt with the threat as they must," the court heard.

"It is a very large and very public place and they are very serious charges."

Both men are expected to appear in court today at 3pm.

A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Ocean lovers take the plunge in daring shark net swim
Jetstar drops massive cut-price Sunshine Coast holiday deal.
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Axel Beard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fyfe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramm</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Hi-Fi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>aIdentirms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Catherine Benson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Service Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clancy Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gracemere's Kieren James Fyfe, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Project Mex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Clifford Ramm, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
