<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417468099028433</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828195/stockland-green-hills-opens-new-stores-next-week-photos-video/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Stockland Green Hills opens new stores next week | Photos | Video</title>
  <content>
Lowes, Bed Bath N Table, Price Attack and Spendless Shoes are just a handful of the stores set to open next week when Stockland unveils stage two of its $412 million Green Hills redevelopment.

Stockland Green Hills opens new stores next week | Photos | Video

exit
Stockland has reported that it continues to make significant progress on the massive shopping centre project.
Stage two will also include the opening of another 350 rooftop car parking spaces.
Other businesses to open for trade will be Habitania, Darrell Lea, OPSM, Beautiful Hair, Helloworld, Escape Travel, IBrow Station, The Green Room, Laser Clinics Australia and Kards & Kandy.
A spokesperson for Stockland said it is great to see customers embracing the new centre so enthusiastically during its transformation into a vibrant, thriving shopping, leisure and entertainment destination.

As part of the next milestone Stockland will also celebrate the "topping out" of the centre, reaching the highest point of the development now at 34 metres.
So far 42,000 cubic metres of concrete has been poured, the equivalent of filling more than 17 olympic swimming pools, 45,000 kilos of glass has been used, the same weight as six elephants and 140,811 square metres of deck and wall ply, the same as 26 football fields, has been installed.
Next month Stockland will also deliver new "premium" bathrooms and a parents room including change tables, private feeding rooms, a microwave to warm bottles and a play area for the kids.
Disability amenities including an adult change room with a change table and assistance lifter will also open in September to assist carers and people with a disability.
In November, the centre will open a dedicated quiet room designed to create a safe place for parents carers and children with Autism Spectrum Disorder, providing a calm, low sensory environment which can be used as a retreat away from the busy shopping centre.
The redevelopment is on track to generate more than 2285 jobs, 1350 construction jobs, 1250 direct full-time jobs in retail, customer service and hospitality and about 1200 flow-on jobs for local suppliers.
On completion mid next year the centre will more than double in size to around 74,000 square metres and will feature the first new look David Jones department store in the Hunter, a new 900-seat Hoyts cinema and around 220 tenancies with a new dining and entertainment precinct that will be the biggest in the region.
RELATED CONTENT

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helloworld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoyt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IBrow Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beautiful Hair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland Green Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Autism Spectrum Disorder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darrell Lea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Escape Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laser Clinics Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spendless Shoes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kandy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bed Bath N Table</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OPSM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Price Attack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Habitania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
