<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417553998375737</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Mining</source>
  <url>https://www.australianmining.com.au/news/pybar-appoints-new-chief-executive/</url>
  <title>PYBAR appoints new chief executive - Australian Mining</title>
  <content>
Brendan Rouse

Latest News

PYBAR Mining Services has appointed Brendan Rouse, company co-founder and former chief operating officer, to the position of chief executive officer.
It follows the strategic decision by PYBAR co-founder and CEO Paul Rouse, to assume the role of executive chairman of the PYBAR Group.
Scott Todd, formerly manager of technical services - PYBAR Mining Services, has been promoted to the role of COO - PYBAR Mining Services.
Paul Rouse said the changes support PYBAR's nationwide strategy to deliver a leading underground mining contract service through a commitment to the company's values, performance, innovation and continuous improvement.
"The appointments of Brendan and Scott, with a collective 50-plus years' industry experience, facilitates the integration of our operations teams with our contracts and technical services teams, streamlining our service provision from tender through to project delivery and improving overall operational efficiencies for our clients," Rouse said.
"I would like to express my thanks to all our clients, suppliers and employees for their support. Under the leadership of Brendan, we look forward to building on our existing partnerships and continuing to deliver a safe, professional and value-adding service."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Todd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PYBAR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PYBAR Mining Services</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Rouse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Paul Rouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PYBAR Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
