<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417815991384348</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/the-games-remaining-in-2017-afl-home-and-away-season-that-will-shape-the-top-eight/news-story/627cbace9678ac73486c8b8fc14ef7c2</url>
  <title>Mini-finals: The games that will shape the eight</title>
  <content>
THE closest season in years is going down to the wire.
With a month to play in the home and away season, none of the places in the top eight are yet secure.
Adelaide may have the lead on top, but with a very tough run home, the minor premiership and, perhaps more importantly, a top-two finish is still up for grabs for at least five teams.
The top four is hotly contested too, while four teams are tied on 10 wins between sixth and ninth. Even Hawthorn, in 12th, remains a viable finals hopeful.
But there are some games that will matter more than most - the mini-finals, the proverbial eight pointers.
And thanks to Champion Data - who have taken each game in isolation and evaluated them for their individual impact on both teams' chances based on the result - we can put a number to just how important they are.

These are the games that will shape the eight, the top four and the top two.
MOST IMPORTANT MATCHES FOR THE TOP EIGHT
WITH an extra win and a heap of percentage between Port Adelaide in fifth and Sydney in sixth, there are seven contenders vying for the final three spots in the top eight.
The Western Bulldogs snuck into eighth for a few hours on Sunday, with West Coast's win over Brisbane knocking them back down into ninth. But the reigning premiers will play in three of the most important games left.
With a loss in any of their final three games - against GWS, Port Adelaide and Hawthorn - the Dogs would drop from approximately a 70 per cent chance of playing finals to a 30 per cent chance.
That last game in Round 23 is crucial for the Hawks as well, whose slim finals chances will drop to just 1 per cent with a loss.
This coming weekend sees a vital game as well with St Kilda hosting West Coast.
It is particularly vital for the Saints, who will have a 24 per cent chance of playing finals if they down the Eagles, but a two per cent chance if they lose. The visitors' chances would drop to 36 per cent with a loss, but be at 79 per cent with a win.
The most important game, though, is Melbourne against the Saints. The stakes for the Saints are similar to that as in the Eagles game, but the Demons will move to a 79 per cent chance of playing finals with a victory in Round 21. Their chances would be at 36 per cent with a loss.
MELBOURNE v ST KILDA, ROUND 21, MCG
Demons' top 8 chances: 79 per cent with win, 36 per cent with loss
Saints' top 8 chances: 24 per cent with win, 2 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 8 chances: 65 per cent
ST KILDA v WEST COAST EAGLES, ROUND 20, ETIHAD STADIUM
Saints' top 8 chances: 23 per cent with win, 3 per cent with loss
Eagles' top 8 chances: 79 per cent with win, 36 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 8 chances: 63 per cent
HAWTHORN v WESTERN BULLDOGS, ROUND 23, ETIHAD STADIUM
Hawks' top 8 chances: 21 per cent with win, 1 per cent with loss
Bulldogs' top 8 chances: 69 per cent with win, 28 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 8 chances: 61 per cent
WESTERN BULLDOGS v PORT ADELAIDE, ROUND 22, BALLARAT
Bulldogs' top 8 chances: 72 per cent with win, 33 per cent with loss
Power's top 8 chances: 100 per cent with win, 96 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 8 chances: 43 per cent
WESTERN BULLDOGS v GWS GIANTS, ROUND 21, ETIHAD STADIUM
Bulldogs' top 8 chances: 71 per cent with win, 34 per cent with loss
Giants' top 8 chances: 100 per cent with win, 97 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 8 chances: 40 per cent
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 20 PREVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
MOST IMPORTANT MATCHES FOR THE TOP FOUR
THE Cats' decision not to challenge Patrick Dangerfield's suspension makes a lot more sense when you consider the stakes of Round 21's clash with Richmond.
Geelong is rated as a 93 per cent chance of finishing in the top four if it downs the Tigers in that game - a near certainty - while it goes down to 61 per cent with a loss.
Richmond too faces a major test, as it would have a 79 per cent likelihood of earning a double chance with an upset win over the Cats, but that chance would drop to 36 per cent with a loss.
The Cats' clash with GWS in Round 23 is also vital, with the winner almost certain to finish in the top four.
The Giants' game this weekend against Melbourne is also vital. A loss and the Giants would drop to just above a toss-up in the top-four race, while the Demons would be considered having no chance if they lose.
But Melbourne would be given a one in six chance of earning a double chance if it downs the Giants - as would West Coast if it does the same in Round 22.
GEELONG CATS v RICHMOND, ROUND 21, SIMONDS STADIUM
Cats' top 4 chances: 93 per cent with win, 61 per cent with loss
Tigers' top 4 chances: 79 per cent with in, 36 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 4 chances: 75 per cent
GEELONG CATS v GWS GIANTS, ROUND 23, SIMONDS STADIUM
Cats' top 4 chances: 95 per cent with win, 70 per cent with loss
Giants' top 4 chances: 92 per cent with win, 62 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 4 chances: 55 per cent
WESTERN BULLDOGS v PORT ADELAIDE, ROUND 22, BALLARAT
Bulldogs' top 4 chances: 12 per cent with win, 0 per cent with loss
Power's top 4 chances: 80 per cent with win, 39 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 4 chances: 53 per cent
GWS GIANTS v MELBOURNE, ROUND 20, CANBERRA
Giants' top 4 chances: 87 per cent with win, 55 per cent with loss
Demons' top 4 chances: 17 per cent with win, 0 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 4 chances: 49 per cent
GWS GIANTS v WEST COAST EAGLES, ROUND 22, SPOTLESS STADIUM
Giants' top 4 chances: 88 per cent with win, 56 per cent with loss
Eagles' top 4 chances: 17 per cent with win, 0 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 4 chances: 49 per cent
MOST IMPORTANT MATCHES FOR THE TOP TWO
IT is all about Geelong and GWS in the race for the top two - with a bit of consideration to a massive Showdown.
The Cats-Giants clash in Round 23 looks likely to determine who earns a home qualifying final, based on Champion Data's simulations.
The loser's chances would drop by 50 per cent - Geelong from 72 per cent to 21, GWS from 61 per cent to 11.
The Cats also involved in the second-most dramatic game, with their top-two hopes dropping to 19 per cent if they were to lose to Richmond in Round 21. The Tigers' hopes would go from 34 per cent (with a win) to four per cent (with a loss).
The Giants' hopes of a top-two spot will fall by around 30 per cent if they lose to either West Coast or the Western Bulldogs.
This week's Showdown is also important. Adelaide would be a near certainty - 98 per cent - with a win, but would drop to 80 per cent chances of a top-two finish with a loss.
Port Adelaide's hopes would essentially vanish with a loss, but if they beat their archrivals, the Power would be given a one-in-four shot of finishing top two.
GEELONG CATS v GWS GIANTS, ROUND 23, SIMONDS STADIUM
Cats' top 2 chances: 72 per cent with win, 21 per cent with loss
Giants' top 2 chances: 61 per cent with win, 11 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 2 chances: 101 per cent
GEELONG CATS v RICHMOND, ROUND 21, SIMONDS STADIUM
Cats' top 2 chances: 59 per cent with win, 19 per cent with loss
Tigers' top 2 chances: 34 per cent with win, 4 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 2 chances: 70 per cent
ADELAIDE CROWS v PORT ADELAIDE, ROUND 20, ADELAIDE OVAL
Crows' top 2 chances: 98 per cent with win, 80 per cent with loss
Power's top 2 chances: 24 per cent with win, 2 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 2 chances: 40 per cent
GWS GIANTS v WEST COAST EAGLES, ROUND 22, SPOTLESS STADIUM
Giants' top 2 chances: 47 per cent with win, 16 per cent with loss
Eagles' top 2 chances: 1 per cent with win, 0 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 2 chances: 32 per cent
WESTERN BULLDOGS v GWS GIANTS, ROUND 21, ETIHAD STADIUM
Bulldogs' top 2 chances: 0 per cent with win, 0 per cent with loss
Giants' top 2 chances: 52 per cent with win, 21 per cent with loss
Combined swing on top 2 chances: 31 per cent
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cats-Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOP FOUR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong Cats</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballarat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champion Data</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champion Data</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mini-finals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOP TWO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOP EIGHT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMPORTANT MATCHES FOR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 20 PREVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 21</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 23</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
