<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417811696416982</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/politics/search-on-for-new-childrens-commissioner-after-mark-morrissey-quits-to-transition-to-parttime-work/news-story/7eea123a479180baf4f3fab6e4a6e522</url>
  <title>Commissioner for kids calls it a day</title>
  <content>
TASMANIA'S Children's Commissioner Mark Morrissey has announced his resignation as he "transitions to part-time work".
Mr Morrissey, who took up the role in late 2014, will be departing next month.
His sudden resignation comes at time when the State Government is under pressure over its handling of child protection matters and a revamp of the system.
In a statement issued today, Mr Morrissey urged government, agencies and organisations to work together to "improve outcomes" for children.
"Reflecting on my time as Commissioner, my lasting impression will always be of the many passionate and skilled people ... who every day strive to make a positive difference to the lives of our children and young people," he said.
"I would encourage all sides of politics to stay the course with the current set of reforms to the child protection and out of home care systems in Tasmania.
"I would like to emphasise the critical importance of promoting meaningful opportunities for children and young people to express their views and to influence decision making."
During his tenure Mr Morrissey worked on legislation giving the Commissioner new powers, produced several reports into the system and launched art-projects aimed at engaging with youth.
After more than three decades in senior leadership roles, Mr Morrissey said he would transition to part-time work
"I will continue to focus on the health and wellbeing of children and young people," he said.
Human Services Minister Jacquie Petrusma thanked Mr Morrissey for his work.
"Mr Morrissey has been an active participant in our reforms to the child protection system, helping to shape future services," she said.
"He has been a strong advocate for the need for these reforms and for the redesign of the system, and we thank him particularly for his work in this regard."
The Government will now look for a replacement.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Minister Jacquie Petrusma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrissey</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TASMANIA'S Children's Commissioner Mark Morrissey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
