<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417815991384392</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/two-headed-bat-baffles-scientists/3208372/</url>
  <title>Two-headed bat baffles scientists</title>
  <content>
THEY say two heads are better than one ...

Scientists have been left "completely astonished" after finding the perfectly preserved remains of dead conjoined twin bats under a tree in Brazil, reports .

It is only the third recorded case of conjoined bats and experts are now examining their remains to find out more about the phenomena.

The bats are believed to have been stillborn and still had the placenta attached when they were discovered under a mango tree in the southeast of the country.

Marcelo Nogueira, from the State University of Northern Rio de Janeiro, said: "We believe the mother of these twins was roosting in this tree when she gave birth.

"It is our hope that cases like this will encourage more studies on bat embryology, an open and fascinating field of research that can largely benefit from material already available in scientific collections."

Little is known about conjoined animals. Just one in around 200,000 human births involved conjoined twins.

Survival rates are around 15 per cent in humans but are thought to be much lower in the animal world.

An X-ray shows the male bats have separate heads and necks but their spines eventually merge into one.

They also have two separate but similar size hearts.

The total breadth of the twins, including wingspan, measures around 13cm.

Based on their physical characteristics the scientists determined they were most likely 'Artibeus' bats.

Little is known about conjoined animals. Just one in around 200,000 human births involved conjoined twins.

Survival rates are around 15 per cent in humans but are thought to be much lower in the animal world.

An X-ray shows the male bats have separate heads and necks but their spines eventually merge into one.

A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Accusations include woman being told "see a psychiatrist".
The assets could include his luxury 'toys' and 15 properties.
NAMBOUR residents have donated around 2000 knitted items.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janeiro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State University of Northern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Artibeus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcelo Nogueira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
