<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417854646090397</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/retail/amazon-to-create-hundreds-of-jobs-after-confirming-fulfilment-centre-20170802-gxo95d</url>
  <title>'This is just the start' - Amazon names Australian boss, launches warehouse </title>
  <content>
Amazon has ended months of speculation by announcing the name of its Australian country manager and confirming the opening of its first Australian fulfilment centre in Melbourne.
Amazon said on Thursday that its Australian operations would be led by Rocco Braeuniger, who will take up his new role in "coming months."
German-born Mr Braeuniger joined Amazon in 2006 and has held a number of roles during his 11-year career with the tech giant, including director of outdoor products and category lead in sporting goods and leisure. He is currently director of consumables at  in Germany and lives in Munich.
Before joining Amazon, the father-of-three worked in consulting. He has a Diploma from University of Bayreuth and an MBA from Babson College in Boston in the US.

Amazon also said it would create "hundreds of new jobs" after confirming it had signed a lease for its first Australian fulfilment centre, at Dandenong in Melbourne. The tech giant currently has more than 170 Australian jobs advertised on its website, split between its e-commerce and AWS cloud computing businesses.

Amazon's director of operations for Australia, Robert Bruce, said the online retail behemoth would begin recruiting immediately for a range of roles including operations managers, pickers, packers, systems technicians, and HR specialists.
Retail analysts say the e-commerce giant is also seeking buyers for branded goods, suggesting  it plans to launch its suite of retail products and services within months, rather than in 2018, when most retailers and analysts expect the group to start shipping goods locally.

Late last month property sources told The Australian Financial Review .

Mr Bruce confirmed the new 24,000 square metre site on Thursday, but did not clarify the timing of the retail launch.
"We are thrilled to be creating hundreds of new roles in Dandenong South," Mr Bruce said.
"This is just the start. Over time, we will bring thousands of new jobs to Australia and millions of dollars of investment as well as opening up the opportunity for thousands of Australian businesses to sell at home and abroad through Amazon Marketplace."
"This new fulfilment centre will stock hundreds of thousands of products which will be available for delivery to customers across Australia when we launch our retail offering," he said.

"We will be focusing on offering our Australian customers low prices on a great selection of products and can't wait to get started."
The fulfilment centre is located in the Pellicano's M2 Industry Park in Dandenong South, providing easy access to the South Gippsland Highway, Monash Highway and Eastlink. 
The building is also in close proximity to a wide range of amenities for employees. The lease of the centre was facilitated by CBRE's Industrial & Logistics business.
The Victorian Government has welcomed Amazon's investment in the state.

"Amazon is the latest global company to choose Victoria for its Australian operations," said Wade Noonan, Industry Minister for Victoria.
"The company's decision to locate its centre in Dandenong South will create hundreds of local jobs and open up retail opportunities for thousands of local businesses."
According to a landmark report by UBS ths week, , growing revenues from more than $400 million to about $3.5 billion by 2023 and crimping retailers' sales by around 2 per cent.
by prompting more consumers to shop online, where retailers' margins are thinner, by driving retail prices down significantly and by forcing retailers to invest hundreds of millions of dollars into e-commerce infrastructure which may take years to deliver returns.

UBS estimates that margins for major listed retailers will fall by between 100 and 200 basis points by 2023, dragging down earnings by as much as 20 per cent, with Super Retail Group, Myer and JB Hi-Fi the most exposed.
Amazon's pressure on retail prices will also have a major impact on the economy, slicing up to 0.25 percentage points from the consumer price index and putting further pressure on already weak retail employment, UBS says.
UBS expects Amazon to launch its retail products and services in 2018, although there is a chance it could launch towards the end of 2017, given current job ads for staff such as branded goods buyers.
Categories likely to be most exposed to Amazon include electronics, fashion, sporting goods and toys, while hardware, auto and groceries are likely to be least impacted. The initial impact will be felt by online marketplaces such as eBay and Catch.com.au.
While Amazon will have a material impact on earnings, UBS believes investors in retail stocks and REITs have over-reacted to the threat, although there may still be some downside risk for retailers such as JB Hi-Fi, Myer and Greencross.
Shares in major listed retailers and REITs have underperformed the market by 15 per cent and 16 per cent respectively since speculation about Amazon's intentions started building last November.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Bayreuth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>German-born Mr Braeuniger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pellicano's M2 Industry Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greencross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bruce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Hi-Fi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Babson College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocco Braeuniger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Gippsland Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong South</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Industry Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Retail Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBRE's Industrial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wade Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
