<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417635602755261</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/adelaide-symphony-orchestra-compensation-bid-on-hold/8770640</url>
  <title>Adelaide Symphony Orchestra compensation bid for forecast losses due to building works on hold</title>
  <content>
The Adelaide Symphony Orchestra (ASO) has had its bid for compensation for disruptions caused by extensive building works at the Festival Centre put on hold.
The centre is in the middle of a major refit, with the Festival Theatre closing last week for five months.
There are also other building works happening, including the rebuilding of the centre's car park, which have caused major disruptions to several arts companies and audience members.
The ASO has been forced to shift two productions, with its Movie Masterpieces show opening at the Adelaide Entertainment Centre on Friday night, while its co-production of Romeo and Juliet with State Theatre next month has been moved to the Town Hall.
The company had put in a compensation bid to Arts SA, with estimates it could lose up to $200,000 in production costs, having to change the cost of tickets and the number of tickets it will be able to sell.
ASO managing director Vincent Ciccarello said Arts SA wanted to see actual losses before handing over any money.
He said the company could carry the costs in the short term.
"We're in the fortunate position where we can wear that so to speak for the time being, but when the end-of-year result has to be finalised that's when the real impact is going to be felt, because it will have impact on our reserves," he said.
Companies told to make individual bids

The ASO had spent some time working with State Theatre and State Opera on a joint compensation bid but the companies were told to launch individual cases.
An Arts SA spokeswoman said it was "aware of companies predicting a shortfall in patronage and some potential increased costs, but as actual losses have not yet materialised, it will form the basis of further discussion if that becomes the case".
State Theatre said while the building and car park works would affect it, the company would not be putting its hand up for money.
State Opera said it had made a submission for compensation, but said its figure was less than the $200,000 the ASO had cited.
Mr Ciccarello said while he was disappointed the compensation bid had been put on hold, he understood.
But he said some state money would eventually be needed to compensate the company for losses this year.
"We'll need some compensation if we're not to post a loss as a direct result of the closure, but that's a conversation we'll have to work through with Arts South Australia," he said.
The Festival Theatre will reopen at the end of December, with an upgraded foyer, facility improvements and technical upgrades in the theatre.
The centre's revitalised northern promenade will also reopen in January next year, with a new Festival Theatre entrance, new dining and a Walk of Fame.
The car park will reopen midway through 2020.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Opera</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Festival Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walk of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romeo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Festival Theatre</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ciccarello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vincent Ciccarello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Symphony Orchestra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts SA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Movie Masterpieces</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Theatre</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juliet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aso</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Entertainment Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
