<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417820286351737</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/lovehacker-i-cant-make-my-fiancee-come-anymore/</url>
  <title>Lovehacker: Why Can't I Make My Girlfriend Come Anymore?</title>
  <content>
Dear Lovehacker, My girlfriend and I have been together for a few years and we're really happy. But for the past six months or so she hasn't been orgasming very often during sex and only when I'm rubbing her clitoris. I know that changing up routines can be helpful for long term couples, but she's sexually very shy and only really interested in the missionary position. What should I do? Thanks, B.

Hey B,

This is a great question, and something that more couples go through than you would think. There's possibly a few things going on here.

You're right in regards to mixing things up. It's absolutely possible to get bored of the same routine, even in a loving relationship. This doesn't mean that anyone is doing a bad job or that feelings have depreciated, it's just that you've gotten used to each other. That initial excitement and spark that comes with a new relationship and sexual experience fades eventually.

If your partner feels comfortable talking about it, consider exploring why she is only interested in missionary. There may be an underlying reason, such as performance anxiety or self-esteem issues.

Speaking from personal experience, I can become incredibly insecure about doing anything that doesn't involve hiding between the sheets. It tends to coincide with periods where I'm feeling negative about my body image. Even gaining a little winter weight can turn me completely off experimentation, or even just going on top. I don't feel sexy so I don't want to be seen.

As for performance anxiety, this can be common with women. Some of us are so preoccupied by how we look, if we're doing the right thing and if we can make our partner come that our own pleasure gets sidelined. We're not truly present in the moment.

It may be worth chatting to your girlfriend about why she isn't interested in trying new things, in a respectful and loving way.

You may find that there are things she wants to do but feels embarrassed about asking for them. Even in a committed relationship it can be difficult to be open about what are fantasies and desires are. It's scary to reveal that much of yourself to someone.

It also doesn't help that in the modern world we're exposed to institutionalised shame when it comes to sex. We're socialised to believe that it's is immoral, especially if you're a woman who enjoys it. We're taught to be ashamed of those desires from a young age, which can have a negative and lasting impact on our adult sex lives.

Dear Lovehacker, I've just turned 20 and I'm still a virgin and I've never had a serious boyfriend. Two of my bi guy friends and I have sometimes joked about having a threesome and I'm starting to consider it, just to get it over with. Is this a bad idea? Thanks, Third Wheel.

In regards to clitoral orgasms, you may have heard statistics citing that 75 per cent of women can't reach orgasm from penetration alone and 50 per cent of women can't orgasm at all. Sadly, it's tough to find the actual research behind these stats.

This tells me that there needs to be more importance placed on this topic so men and women alike aren't left in the dark. Female orgasms aren't the big cosmic mystery that they're made out to be.

revealed that only 15 per cent of participants had the majority of their orgasms via vaginal intercourse with no clitoral stimulation. 38 per cent also stated that not enough clitoral stimulation was a common obstacle in achieving orgasm with a partner.

And for the big one, only 57 per cent of participants orgasm most or every time that they're with their partner, versus 95 per cent who say that their partner orgasms every time.

What this and a handful of other studies tell us, is that it's simply more difficult for women to come then it is for men. And that clitoral-only orgasms are perfectly normal.

There can be a lack of balance when it comes to male and female pleasure during sex, and the fact that you know and care about what your partner likes is great.

Sexual compatibility is important. If variety and exploration is something you want, it's better to talk about it before it becomes an issue down the road.

No matter what she does or doesn't want to do, make sure you create a loving and safe environment for her to be honest about them with you, and vice versa. That may mean between the two of you, or even with a professional who can help provide the tools and discussion points so you can open up about sex and your relationship.
is a weekly relationship and sex column where our resident Agony Aunt answers your questions. Need help? Drop a comment below or .

Dear Lovehacker, My boyfriend has been on anti-depressants for about 6 months and they have improved nearly every aspect of his life. Except for one. They affect his ability to ejaculate.

WATCH MORE: Healthy Living News & Ideas

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Make My Girlfriend Come Anymore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Third Wheel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lovehacker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agony Aunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dear Lovehacker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Healthy Living News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
