<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417854646090444</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/cops-smash-drug-gang/news-story/2764a8e70c524245b3c476a65188a1f6</url>
  <title>How cops smashed drug gang</title>
  <content>
An almost year-long police operation has brought down a drug syndicate dealing in cannabis out of Ingham.
Operation Oscar Aurum began last October and culminated this week with detectives raiding homes in the Ingham area on Monday and Tuesday.
Detectives charged 23 people with 80 drug offences and seized more than $150,000 worth of drugs including ice, cannabis and steroids.
A number of "high quality" cannabis plants were found growing on properties around Ingham, along with about 4kg of drying cannabis and utensils.
Detective acting Inspector Jason Shepherd said most raids uncovered cannabis plants growing on rural properties, with several growers and dealers operating a drug syndicate.
"There wasn't a great number (of cannabis plants), but they were of a very good quality ... so there was a good quantity of cannabis being produced from the plants," Insp Shepherd said.
"Our aim was to disrupt the unlawful supply of dangerous drugs in Ingham and Townsville and I think this operation has been successful. "If there is information that comes out of this, that leads into a spider-web type of situation that branches off into other directions, then we will definitely follow those as well."
Insp Shepherd said the public played a crucial role in the operations, with the majority of information police acted on coming from the community.
"Information came in from members of the public and Crime Stoppers about the drug dealing that was occurring in the Ingham area," he said.
"Unfortunately drug dealers prey on any community, even close-knit, small communities like Ingham.
"Based on the information that we received from Crime Stoppers and other sources, I think the message was pretty clear the Ingham community didn't want drug dealers within the community."
Insp Shepherd said police did not uncover any labs producing ice.
"Sometimes we can be very lucky ... the day you hit, you may get a good stash, you may get a lab, it may just be that those drugs were transported the week before or the day before," he said.
Anyone with information about drug crime in North Queensland should call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingham</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Jason Shepherd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar Aurum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insp Shepherd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
