<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417734387004649</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-03/reid-revival-may-curb-pies-chase-for-boy-wonder</url>
  <title>Reid revival may curb Pies' chase for Boy Wonder</title>
  <content>
Ben Reid's move forward has transformed his career

BEN REID'S impressive second coming as a forward could influence Collingwood's off-season chase for a Robin to Darcy Moore's Batman in attack, coach Nathan Buckley says.

Reid began his AFL career as a forward, but has spent most of it in defence, including being an All Australian centre half-back in 2011.

Buckley dropped Reid for the Magpies' round 15 clash with Hawthorn and has deployed him as a key forward since he returned to the senior side, which has resulted in him kicking eight goals in four matches.

Out-of-contract Adelaide forward Mitch McGovern, who took the match-saving mark to secure a draw last week against Collingwood after the Crows trailed by 50 points, has been linked to the black and white.

"(Reid)'s looked really good the last couple of weeks since coming back - it looks like he's got a bit more spring in the step and ... he laid five forward-50 tackles on the weekend," Buckley told reporters.

"He had only six touches and kicked a couple of goals, but I think it was a really influential game as a key forward. You'd love 20 touches and six goals every week, but all we expect is for guys to play a role, and Reidy's influence was profound.

"A lot of what happens in the next month probably dictates ... the last 5 per cent of decisions you need to make on your list going into the next phase of the club's future."

Buckley declined to discuss recruiting specific players, such as McGovern or his in-demand Adelaide teammate Jake Lever, saying any talk at this stage was "disrespectful".

"They're decisions that happen at the end of the year and the life cycle of that happens behind the curtain, when we're in-season," he said.

"I do feel it's disrespectful to be talking about players from other clubs during the year, and we probably learned a bit from the Lin Jong situation last year (when the Bulldog's Collingwood meeting became public).

"It's not good for the player themselves or the clubs involved to get caught in that, so we'll let that happen behind the cloak."

More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lin Jong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Wonder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Moore's Batman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldog's Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Reid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
