<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417777336678272</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/innovation/tesla-is-burning-through-cash-and-some-investors-love-it-20170803-gxob5a.html</url>
  <title>Tesla is burning through cash, and (some) investors love it</title>
  <content>
Tesla is burning through cash with gleeful abandon. But for its long-term believers, it doesn't seem to matter.
Elon Musk's electric car, battery and storage company  it burned through a record $US1 billion ($1.26 billion) in the June quarter, during which it delivered 22,026 Model S sports cars and Model X SUVs to customers.

Up Next

Bitcoin splits in two

02:30

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Tesla's cash burn

Tesla burned through less cash than expected before rolling out the Model 3, giving Elon Musk some financial leeway to pull off his mission of bringing electric cars to the masses.

In response, the company's shares were up by more than 7 per cent in after-hours trading in the US, because of course they were.
It has been an eventful few weeks for Tesla, which delivered its first Model 3 car last week. Musk created headlines throughout Australia after being spotted at a Byron Bay music festival with his celebrity girlfriend Amber Heard.
In all seriousness, he captured the national spotlight after  to build the world's biggest lithium-ion battery storage project.
This facility will be able to provide "three times more power than the world's next most powerful battery storage installation", Musk said in a letter to shareholders, which is "enough power for more than 30,000 homes".

The South Australian government has not disclosed the size of this contract, infuriating some of its critics.
And neither has Tesla, but the contract win came in July, just after the quarter ended, so maybe we will learn more in a few months.Photo: Tesla
Tesla is a divisive company - and that predates it being caught up in Australia's incredibly tiring debate over energy policy. Investor opinion in the company is deeply split between staunch, almost cult-like believers in its admittedly enormous long-term potential, and aggressive sceptics who can't get past its shaky fundamentals.
At the moment, the blue-sky believers are winning. Tesla shares are up more than 1500 per cent since 2010. Yet, at the same time, lots of investors are betting that they will sooner or later crash back to earth.
Tesla is consistently among the most heavily short-sold stocks in the main US index, the S&P 500. (Short selling is when an investor borrows shares and sells them on the open market, hoping they fall and can be bought back more cheaply for a profit.)
Short selling

The Tesla short trade is even quite popular in Australia.
Just last week, a respected local fund manager, Antipodes Partners chief investment officer Jacob Mitchell, announced he was shorting Tesla.
"At its heart, we think it is a very small car maker, with a very large market cap," he said at a conference hosted by Livewire, an investment publication.
Mitchell noted that Tesla's valuation is currently above that of Hyundai, which makes 8 million cars a year, compared to Tesla's 100,000.
"They need to invest heavily to scale production. To compete long term, they have to get scale," he said of Tesla.
Cash burn

Which brings us back to the cash burn.
Tesla is spending aggressively to scale up production of its new, cheaper car, the Model 3, and to complete its gigantic battery production plant.
Despite the record cash bleed in June, it still has $US3 billion on its books. But the company has said it does not want its cash reserves to dwindle below $US1 billion.
"There is some wisdom in having a cash cushion for unexpected events," Musk told investors on the conference call on Thursday morning.
"You just never know when there's going to be some significant force majeure events in the world - [there] could be an earthquake in California, for example."
That leaves just $US2 billion to play with. At current pace, that would be wiped out in just six months.
'Promised land'

But Musk said that as production and deliveries for the Model 3 sped up, he expected the company's cash burn rates to decline. It is treading a fine line though, with little margin for error.
"So obviously, the nirvana is that we can make the car and get paid for the car before we have to pay our suppliers, which then the faster you grow, the faster your cash position grows. Obviously that's like, that's the promised land right there," he said.
If Tesla runs out of money, it would have to raise debt, or issue new shares.
Shareholders have been more than happy to stump up cash over the past seven years to fund Tesla's rapid expansion. But issuing new shares, in theory, weakens the share price. Which is what the short sellers are betting will happen.
So far, that bet hasn't really worked over the long term.
The potential of Tesla - which is rolling out solar roofs for homes and has plans to release an electric truck in addition to taking electric cars mainstream - is for Tesla fans, and some investors, proving irresistible.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model 3</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla's 100,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musk</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model X SUVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amber Heard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
