<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417450919158904</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/students-sleep-rough-as-part-of-vinnies-sleepout/news-story/e77215f769670d8e6d41d7ee97298cba</url>
  <title>Students sleep rough</title>
  <content>
STUDENTS at a college north of Brisbane will sleep rough to raise awareness of homelessness in Australia.

On Friday St Eugene College at Burpengary is hosting it's annual Vinnies Sleepout for students from Grades 7-12.

"Did you know that there are currently 105,237 people homeless in Australia? That number is

staggering," Assistant Principal of Religious Education Megan Kozak said. "As we go home to our warm houses and soft beds, there are children, teenagers, parents and grandparents currently living on the streets."

Mrs Kozak said throughout the week students and staff were making donations of non-perishable food, winter clothes and blankets to the Vinnies Winter Appeal and Rosies Friends on the Street.

"On Friday all students and staff are encouraged to wear a beanie and donate a

gold coin for the Vinnies Winter Appeal," she said. "Starting 4.30pm Friday afternoon and concluding at 8am on Saturday morning, it is an amazing evening of awareness raising and fun - with awesome games, homemade soup and sleeping on cardboard in Rodrigo Hall. This year we have two incredible guest speakers: Rochelle Courtenay (founder of Share the Dignity) and Olivia Skewes (St Vincent de Paul Society)."

Mrs Kozak said the school was also supporting Share the Dignity, which worked in conjunction with domestic violence shelters and homeless organisations to ensure that girls and women had appropriate access to sanitary items.

Year 12 students Matthew Breen and Nive Fonoimoana said they were participating in the sleep out to be the "the change that we need to see in the world."

"This year I have had the opportunity to be a part of Rosies Friends on the Streets program at

Caboolture, this has certainly raised my awareness to the difficulties that come with being homeless," Yr 12 Vice- Captain Ailish Rolston said

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Skewes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosies Friends</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Breen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vinnies Winter Appeal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Vincent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Kozak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodrigo Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday St Eugene College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Ailish Rolston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rochelle Courtenay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vinnies Sleepout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burpengary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nive Fonoimoana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Megan Kozak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Principal of Religious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
