<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417768746743412</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/gerald-ryan-targets-secondtier-sprints-with-tango-rain-to-dodge-10-million-everest-hopefuls-20170802-gxo7u5.html</url>
  <title>Gerald Ryan targets second-tier sprints with Tango Rain to dodge $10 million Everest hopefuls</title>
  <content>
Not every Sydney sprinter is going to end up with a slot in the $10 million Everest - and that suits Gerald Ryan just fine.

Up Next

Hooper steps up as Wallabies skipper

01:13

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Neymar leaving Barca, Spanish superclub confirms

Brazilian striker Neymar has informed Barcelona he plans to leave the club. The soccer superstar is expected to sign with Paris Saint-Germain (PSG) in a world record deal worth nearly $750 million.

Which may seem a strange school of thought, but while connections of some of the country's best speedsters become hypnotised by the big bucks on offer, the Rosehill trainer reckons he can nab a share of the second-tier spoils with Tango Rain.
"We'll stay up here and there's enough [races] in Sydney," he said of plans with the four-year-old entire, which resumes at Randwick on Saturday after a virus crippled his autumn carnival. 

"There's The Shorts and The Lightning which is on Everest day. There's enough good sprinters who will be running in The Everest and that Lightning is going to be worth good money [$500,000]."
Had fate figured differently, Tango Rain might have been spoken about as a prospective Everest candidate. But he's not. At least not yet.

Ryan's fickle autumn lost one of its leading lights when Tango Rain contracted a virus. It was enough to scupper a campaign aimed at the big three-year-old sprints after a couple of nice trials.
"He came back in the autumn, had two trials and then got a virus so we turned him out," Ryan said. "We were aiming towards the Arrowfield [Sprint], but we had to turn him out [and start again]. He did get crook for four or five days.Photo: Bradleyphotos.com.au
"His work [this time in] has been good and his trial was good. He's in a good frame of mind which is what we want. But we just need to get his ratings points up so we can aim at some of the better sprint races."
At least according to betting, Tango Rain's return will be a match race with Launch Code over the 1000-metre scamper in the Randwick eighth.
Both are having their first starts as four-year-olds in open company, but Ryan is not concerned about what he's going to see from his lightly raced sprinter which has a career-best performance of a close second to Star Turn in the San Domenico Stakes.
"It doesn't matter about the rain as he handles all ground and I didn't mind the [extreme outside] draw actually," Ryan said. "There is pace in the race, but that's just the type of race it is."
One of Ryan's other spring carnival big guns, Harper's Choice, will resume at big odds in the group 2 Missile Stakes just 40 minutes earlier after his autumn campaign ended with an Australian Derby placing behind Jon Snow.
"It's just a kick-off point for him and then we'll go to 1400 [metres] in a couple of weeks' time and then we'll decide whether we'll get him out to a mile-and-a-quarter or keep him [fresh] for the Epsom," Ryan said. 
"He doesn't cop a lot of work and he's a very clean-winded horse. He'll probably look the same on Saturday as what he did before the Derby - only stronger. His coat is like a mirror."
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tango Rain</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epsom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Domenico Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerald Ryan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arrowfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Turn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradleyphotos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper's Choice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launch Code</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
