<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417858941057785</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/golfs-battle-with-boobs-and-bums-blowing-up/news-story/8751375a4e5ebf34a2b373a1d8f8badb</url>
  <title>Golf's battle with boobs and bums blows up</title>
  <content>
WOMEN'S golf is ripping itself apart over new dress codes designed to make players less sexy.
Top players, including English star Charley Hull, have slammed the game's ruling body - the Ladies Professional Golf Association.
And the Women's British Open, which starts today at Kingsbarns near St Andrews, has been overshadowed by the row.
LPGA chiefs have told players that skirts must not be too short as to see the "bottom area" and that sports tops must not be too low-cut.
In an email sent to all players, part of the regulation states the "skirt must be long enough to not see your bottom area (even if covered by under shorts) at any time, standing or bent over".
But Hull, 21, and others fear such stuffy rules shows the game is stuck in the past and it will deter new, young players.
"A couple of weeks ago I, along with all the girls on the LPGA Tour, received an email explaining that as part of the new dress code, plunging neck lines, leggings and revealing skirts are now banned," she said.
"I don't wear any of them, so it doesn't really affect me. But I think it's a shame, as many people label golf old fashioned and we need to move away from that.
"Golf needs to be more original and athletic. If you look at most golfers, I don't think they look that good. If the clothes were cool, more people would play and watch it.
"I like what Jason Day wore on the first day of The Open this year - white high-top trainers and black tracksuit bottoms.
"Some people didn't like it, but that sort of outfit will attract younger fans."
Players will be given a $1000 fine for a breach which doubles with each offence and US Open champ Michelle Wie feels she is being targeted.
"It's something that I have been slightly fighting with them for the whole year," Wie said.
"We've been having a lot of discussions because a couple of outfits I have worn this year have raised eyebrows a little bit.
"So I can see where they're coming from, but I think it's a little bit unfortunate."
The most outspoken critic is Paige Spiranac, who regularly causes a stir with daring looks.
Despite not being on the LPGA Tour, she has spoken out at how some players are being body-shamed.
"Most likely, this edict was put into place to eliminate the presence of cleavage," the 24-year-old American said.
"In that case, a curvier, fuller-figured woman would be chided and fined far more often than a woman with a smaller bust."

Golf: Marcel Siem has come up with an inredible hole-in-one at the Porsche Open in Germany overnight.

Hole-in-one wins Siem a car

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LPGA Tour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsbarns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIEM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charley Hull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porsche Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LPGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hull, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladies Professional Golf Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paige Spiranac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Wie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's British Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcel Siem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
