<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417764451776076</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/technology/innovation/television-seoul-picks-quality-over-quantity-20170725-gxitmn.html</url>
  <title>Why South Korea is an Ultra HD wonderland</title>
  <content>
Broadcasters are embracing Ultra High Definition, with South Korea's major broadcast networks leading the charge, launching UHD channels to make the most of the new generation of super-sharp televisions.
While Australian broadcasters use their slice of the airwaves to offer multiple free-to-air channels, Seoul's three major networks only feature one or two channels each. They've already abandoned standard definition digital, instead using their allocated spectrum to simulcast in HD as well as UHD, which is four times sharper than Blu-ray.Photo: LG
Only five per cent of content is produced in native UHD, but this is set to rise to 50 per cent by 2023. This focus on quality rather than quantity means South Korean broadcaster MBC doesn't rely on foreign content or excessive reruns to fill its single channel.
"Less than 10 per cent of what MBC broadcasts each week would be repeats," said company broadcast engineer senior officer HeeJoon Kim.

"We don't dub or subtitle foreign content any more, because it's really niche content and people who want to watch that can find it online."
South Koreans can also watch MBC simulcast online and the network plans to upgrade this live-stream to UHD. Viewers will need download speeds of at least 16 Mbps, which doesn't present a problem in a city like Seoul with some the world's fastest home broadband services, including gigabit fibre to the premises.

Alongside terrestrial broadcasts, South Koreans can also sign up for traditional cable pay TV, while access to world-class broadband means they're spoiled for choice when it comes to online entertainment.

You will now receive updates from

Technology Newsletter

Technology Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In preparation for Netflix's arrival, MBC joined forces with the nation's other two major free-to-air broadcasters to launch  - a high-definition live-streaming and catch-up TV service. Meanwhile, the country's major broadband providers offer more than 200 IPTV streaming channels.
A keen adopter of new technology, South Korea is the first country to fully embrace free-to-air terrestrial UHD broadcasting after the government put aside the 700MHz band for television rather than mobile broadband services. The networks don't bid for spectrum or pay broadcast licensing fees, although they do donate to the Korean Broadcasting Development Fund. Viewers also pay an annual license of around $30.
The take-up of UHD televisions in South Korea is naturally high in a country which is home to electronics giants LG and Samsung, although early adopters require a new set-top box to watch free-to-air UHD. The free-to-air networks remain popular, despite the wealth of alternatives, although most viewers watch MBC through its broadband service rather than over the airwaves.
To further enhance the free-to-air picture, MBC aims to adopt High Dynamic Range (HDR) - offering more detail in the bright highlights and deep shadows. HDR is already used by Netflix and on Ultra HD Blu-ray movie discs, with MBC likely to adopt the Hybrid Log Gamma broadcast HDR format co-developed by the BBC and Japan's NHK.
"While South Koreans have many different ways to watch television, we see Ultra HD terrestrial broadcasts as an important part of the entertainment landscape," Kim says.
"Our viewers deserve the best picture quality and we're making sure they get it."
Adam Turner visited South Korea as a guest of LG.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MHz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBC</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultra HD Blu-ray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean Broadcasting Development Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mbps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HDR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blu-ray.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hybrid Log Gamma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UHD</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's NHK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Dynamic Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultra HD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seoul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HeeJoon Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korean</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultra High Definition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
