<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417777336678228</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/godolphin-glyn-schofield-takes-first-steps-to-james-cummings-reunion-20170802-gxo7uy.html</url>
  <title>Godolphin: Glyn Schofield takes first steps to James Cummings reunion </title>
  <content>
The Godolphin jockey merry-go-round? Glyn Schofield doesn't say it in these exact words, but you sense he'd like to climb aboard and ride the carousel for as long as he can.

Up Next

Neymar leaving Barca, Spanish superclub confirms

00:42

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Hooper steps up as Wallabies skipper

Michael Hooper has been appointed Wallabies captain, with long-serving Stephen Moore stepping down from the role ahead of his international retirement at the end of the season.

Who knows how many of Sydney's riding ranks are going to be thrown the royal blue in the next few months and asked to do a job for his highness? Schofield doesn't. But when the chances come, he knows he had better take them.
James Cummings is the season's premiership pacesetter - after the first meeting anyway - and he has made no secret that his team will use whatever jockeys they need before making a call on whether they want to rejuvenate the retained rider concept. It will make the hoops hungry at the least. Horses for courses and all that.

But when Schofield, such a steady hand for Cummings in recent years as he ventured out on his own before signing on to be Sheikh Mohammed's top man in Australia, was asked to ride odds-on pop Alizee at Warwick Farm on Wednesday, everything old was new again. And he backed up on Thursday with three bookings for Godolphin at Hawkesbury.
Perhaps spying an opening at Godolphin?

"Well, I used to ride a lot for James when he was on his own - for Gooree and his other clients," Schofield said. "It was nice to get my first ride for him as a winner; I can only ride the horses I'm presented with. I've got one on Saturday. He's a very good trainer and that's why Godolphin got him."
Which is undisputed. But just who will be asked to do the steering on a semi-permanent basis? Corey Brown has one ride for Godolphin on Regimen in the first at Randwick on Saturday, Schofield on Ghostly in the last.Photo: AAP
The new racing season has been the first time he has pulled on the Godolphin colours successfully since he rode Beautiful Romance to victory in last year's Sandown Classic.
On Ghostly, Schofield said: "I don't know much about him, but he looks to have good ability."
Same can be said perhaps  about the horse Cummings most reluctantly had to part with, Launch Code, which goes around in the eighth.
The trainer has always spoken glowingly of the Gooree speedster. His new trainer Kris Lees already has. But Schofield just wants to temper the enthusiasm for now.
"I think it's a little bit too much hype," Schofield said. "The horses he beat in his maiden, a five-horse field ... [it] was not the strongest form race. The way he did it was nice; likewise over the 1000 metres at Wyong.
"Obviously he has shown he has got good potential, but like any horse he's got to produce it on race day.
"He showed, even though it was just a provincial race, the promise he has displayed to his previous trainer, and his current trainer Kris Lees. He ran some slick sectionals to win quite comfortably. He's drawn soft again and we'll ride him in a similar fashion with cover and hopefully he can reproduce."
A horse Schofield is all too familiar with will hopefully land him the first group race of the new season, the Missile Stakes, as the unofficial start to the Sydney spring carnival is ushered in.
The Lees-trained Le Romain is a commanding favourite in the group 2 dash, but faces the prospect of racing back in a field featuring blistering pace.
"He's a proven group 1 horse and clearly he's trialling well, his work has been a treat and he's come back well," Schofield said.
"A little bit of rain won't do him any harm. I'm really looking forward to getting back on him. It will be a similar sort of spring, and if he can have the same sort of results in a few of the big ones he contests it will be happy days for everybody."
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lees-trained Le Romain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandown Classic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glyn Schofield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schofield</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cummings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheikh Mohammed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godolphin</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gooree</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkesbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Lees</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beautiful Romance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alizee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cumming</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
