<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417854646090365</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/country-dancers-earn-roles-in-victorian-state-ballet-production/8770228</url>
  <title>Victorian State Ballet gives country kids a chance to fulfil their dancing dreams</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Nathan Zappia's dream of having a dance career is taking a big step in the right direction, with 13-year-old from Robinvale, in north-west Victoria, about to perform in a professional stage production.
The Victorian State Ballet will bring its classic fairy tale Cinderella to the Swan Hill Town Hall on Friday night, and Nathan will be playing the role of the young prince.
"Living in a small country town, this is really big and exciting," he said.

"We don't get a lot of opportunities here, so having to dance with the Victorian State Ballet is a good opportunity and I can't wait."
Nathan began dancing in 2012 and enjoyed it at home, so he decided to follow a cousin off to dance classes.
He loved it so much he is now participating in classes four days a week, ranging from ballet to hip hop, jazz and tap.
"I really enjoy dancing. That's probably the main reason that I'm doing all these classes," he said.
"I hope to pursue a dance career, so the more I learn and the different genres I can do, that will help."
However, travel time is a factor for Nathan and his parents, as they clock up about 600 kilometres a week driving to Mildura, with only one dance session in their home town.
"I'm really thankful and grateful to have supportive parents who drive me up to Mildura and back," Nathan said.
The audition process

Auditions for local dancers were held in mid-July, with the roles of the young stepsisters, young Cinderella, young prince and fairies all being offered to talented youngsters.
Nathan found the auditions were quite relaxed, and was surprised he was not nervous.
"We just went in, did a warm up, learnt a few exercises," he said.
"I learnt a little bit of the prince role and we had to perform that in front of the people who were choosing the parts."
Nathan was at school when he discovered he had been selected for Cinderella.
"It was recess and I was playing with my friends and one of them noticed that my dad was standing at the fence, so I went up to the fence and I was really excited when he told me I was going to play the young prince," he said.
Nathan travelled to Melbourne for a rehearsal a few weekends ago, and since then he has busy practicing at home.
"I can't wait to meet the Victorian State Ballet dancers and I'm going to have fun dancing with them on stage, because I have the opportunity to dance with the king and queen," he said.
"I think most of my family is coming and I know a lot of my teachers and friends want to come as well, so I think most of the audience will be from Robinvale."

Company identifies talented dancers

Victorian State Ballet artistic director Michelle Sierra said she had been impressed with some of the dancers in Swan Hill.
"The standards are very good and the level of training, concentration, focus and commitment is wonderful," she said.
"We have seen some lovely talent and we're really keen to follow up. There's a couple of youngsters that have really bright futures."
The company provides opportunities to young dancers four or five times a year.
While Swan Hill is the furthest location in Victoria the company has been to so far, it visited Tasmania last year.
Ms Sierra said working with young artists was part of the state ballet's mission.
"[We do it] not only to bring high standard ballets to regional Victoria, but also to invest into the generations of tomorrow for our ballet companies and the arts in Australia," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinvale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Sierra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian State Ballet</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sierra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan Hill Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cinderella</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Zappia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mildura</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
