<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417725797069944</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/parallel-universe-for-turnbull-in-wa/news-story/1b86c38bad178f3bec6d9b2eacbe3b46</url>
  <title>Parallel universe for Turnbull in WA</title>
  <content>
Greg RobertsAustralian Associated Press

Share

Malcolm Turnbull says parallel universes must exist in Western Australia because of the warm welcome he has received, in contrast to hostile media reporting about how he won't lift the state's GST share.
The prime minister met with WA Premier Mark McGowan for 90 minutes but as expected failed to resolve the issue of the state getting by far the lowest GST share in the nation.
WA has received the lowest share of GST revenue for several years, but the state government this week asked for intervention.
It claims that new census population estimates would lead to a further $1.9 billion drop in GST revenue, on top of the billions of dollars it loses each year from what it raises.
"I have met with hundreds of West Australians this week ... and the reception I have had could not have been warmer, more positive, more welcoming," Mr Turnbull told ABC radio.
"I listen to you (media) about how angry people are, how furious they are, they wish I wasn't coming and so forth and it's a completely parallel universe between what the media are saying and what people I am meeting in the real world are saying to me.
"I recognise there is an unfair distribution of the GST and I am seeking to resolve it."
Mr Turnbull could be heading for an election loss according to a Galaxy newspaper poll published earlier in the week, which predicted four Liberal-held seats in the west would fall to Labor.
It is the PM's first trip to Perth since February, and the entire cabinet met on Tuesday.

Mr McGowan and Mr Turnbull opened a six-kilometre extension to Perth's Mitchell Freeway on Thursday morning, but avoided an awkward press conference together.
Mr Turnbull left without taking questions ahead of a trip to the north of the state.
"It was a direct, open and constructive conversation with the prime minister," Mr McGowan said after the meeting.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg RobertsAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth's Mitchell Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal-held</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
