<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418026444784984</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/levi-casboult-hit-left-geelongs-tom-lonergan-worried-about-his-good-kidney-20170803-gxoj06.html</url>
  <title>Levi Casboult hit left Geelong's Tom Lonergan worried about his 'good' kidney</title>
  <content>
Geelong defender Tom Lonergan admitted he was "worried there for a while" after he got kneed in the back by Carlton forward Levi Casboult in a marking contest on Saturday night.
Lonergan has played without his right kidney since 2006 when he was involved in an horrific on-field collision which almost cost him his life.Photo: AAP
Casboult's knee hit him on his "good side" where he still has a functioning kidney and the hit saw Lonergan leave the field for an extended period of time.
Losing both kidneys would force an individual to spend the rest of their life on dialysis and the potential severity of the situation wasn't lost on Lonergan.
"That was the first really big knock I've had since my accident back in 2006," Lonergan said.
"It was on my good side so I was a little bit worried there for a while but I went down into the rooms and had the ultrasound and the doc gave me the all clear so I was pretty happy with that."

Lonergan said the clash with Casboult made him think about his football mortality.
"Obviously when things like last weekend happened, you get the knock in the back, it does cross your mind," he said.
Coincidentally, the upcoming round of AFL matches will be dedicated to raising awareness for organ donation and it's a cause that Lonergan is passionate about.
"It's a fantastic cause and we just encourage all family members to have that discussion, have the conversation and hopefully we can all contribute and save someone's life," Lonergan said.
"You just want all kids to be happy and healthy ... We all can make a difference, we can register and we can help."
Of more immediate concern for Lonergan is a looming match-up with his old sparring partner Lance Franklin on Friday night when the Cats do battle with the Swans in a top-eight blockbuster at Simonds Stadium.
Lonergan is one of the few backmen in the competition that regularly does a good job on the brilliant Sydney forward and the premiership Cat is excited about locking horns with him again.
"I love playing Sydney, they're a great football organisation, a great team and we've got a few down, obviously Pat (Dangerfield) is missing, and we're all going to have to step up to match it with those guys," Lonergan said.
"He (Franklin) is certainly a guy I love playing on, he's probably the best forward in the competition and has been for a long period of time so I enjoy coming up against the best, it's just another good opportunity."
Lonergan is out of contract at the end of the season but the 33-year-old said discussions about his playing future beyond 2017 won't be had until later in the year.
"We've got a big finals campaign coming up and it's so even so I'll wait until after the season to have those discussions."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casboult</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Lonergan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Tom Lonergan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonergan</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi Casboult</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
