<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417944840405007</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/13/57/naplan-negative-impact-on-teachers-union</url>
  <title>'Too much store' placed in NAPLAN results will have 'dramatic, negative effect' on teachers: union rep</title>
  <content>
The NSW union for teachers has warned excessive emphasis on the NAPLAN results will have a dire impact on the curriculum.
Speaking to Nine.com.au, president of the NSW Teachers Federation Maurie Mulheron said there is "too much store" placed in the NAPLAN results.
"We've got to understand the NAPLAN test itself is a pretty imperfect test, it's a pretty blunt instrument," he said.
"We place far too much store in the results. It's not a particularly well-constructed test, it has some limitations," he said.
point to small gains across the board in reading and numeracy since 2008 and a drop in writing results since 2011 when the test format changed.
Mulheron said the issue of "teaching to the test" has become a "massive problem" for the education system.
"does not test anything that the children have been taught - it's not a test of what they have been taught at their state-curriculum level or at the national-curriculum level. It's divorced from what's happening in the classroom," he said.

Related Articles

Mulheron said teachers in NSW are telling the union due to the emphasis on NAPLAN, the curriculum is becoming narrowed to "mind-deadening worksheets around NAPLAN".
"We're diminishing our support for creative and performing arts, sport, physical education, extracurricular activities - all the things we know engage and educate the whole child to fulfil not just their intellectual needs, but their emotional, social and physical needs," he said.
"We see the emphasis on having a dramatic, negative effect on what is expected of teachers.
"Far too much pressure is being placed on teachers to bump up test scores. Lifting test scores is not the same as lifting student outcomes - they are very different things.
"Anyone can lift test scores - rote learn, teach to the test, do a hundred practice tests, you'll lift test scores but have you lifted student outcomes? Have you improved their literacy and numeracy? Have you improved their critical thinking skills? No, you haven't. That's where teachers get very concerned with the over-emphasis on NAPLAN."

The Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority (ACARA) asserts it "actively discourages teaching to the test".
Dr Stanley Rabinowitz, ACARA's general manager of assessment and reporting, said: "NAPLAN simply tests what is taught in the curriculum. Teachers don't need to
do anything other than teach the Australian Curriculum in their classrooms".
He argues the test is now "mainly seen as a routine, but important, part of the school calendar".
"However, year on year we continue to hear the same NAPLAN myths repeated by various sectors," Dr Rabinowitz said.
"NAPLAN is a very valuable tool, it tells us how we are going at a national level in the important areas of literacy and numeracy. It gives teachers, parents and students important information about how a student is doing, highlighting areas where a child is doing well, but also any areas for development. The question is why would you not want to know this information
"NAPLAN is best used alongside local assessments and teacher judgment-not as a substitute for either, but as an external check to ensure all students, regardless of where they attend school, are held to the same expectations defined by the Australian Curriculum.'
While yesterday's results of the test suggested writing skills have dropped, Mulheron claims the writing element of the NAPLAN test is "shoddy".
"It is an appalling test. And how we mark the writing is also shonky," he claimed.
"It's a shonky test and it's marked in a shonky way. I don't place much store in the writing component of NAPLAN and it needs severe improvement."
However, according to Mulheron, improvement is not in sight with the unionist asserting ACARA want to transition the writing component of the test to automated testing.
"They want to see all student's extended writing marked by a laptop, marked by automated robots not by human beings," Mulheron said.
"This is a significant concern for the community and the profession is steadfastly opposed to it and we will fight it tooth and nail to ensure that does not come in.
"You can't just create an algorithm that is somehow going to assess how kids write - it can't assess logic, it can't assess sequencing or relevance, it can't assess humour or irony or the variation of tone, or the level of persuasion or the complexity of organisation."
Mulheron asserts if the writing test is marked in an automated fashion, it will force teachers "to teach students to write in a conformist way to suit the algorithms of a laptop".
ACARA confirmed NAPLAN online will use automated essay scoring.
Dr Rabinowtiz disagreed with Mulheron's claims about the automated process' ability to mark the test.
"Multiple studies have shown that this automated essay scoring is as reliable as human markers when applied to NAPLAN writing," he said.
"In 2018, all NAPLAN Online writing tests will be double-marked by both the automated system and human markers, with any differences resolved by a human marker. Automated essay scoring enables faster turnaround of results, allowing the results to get back to students, parents and teachers within weeks instead of months.
"This will help teachers and schools to respond more quickly to identify student learning needs."
The Federal Minister for Education Simon Birmingham's office referred Nine.com.au to previous comments by the Minister when approached for comment on the matter.
"NAPLAN's an important tool to get an assessment of the basics - of reading, writing, numeracy skills. And they're really important foundation skills upon which all the rest of student learning depends," the Minister said.
"Now, NAPLAN is not the be-all and end-all, it's not the only assessment tool that schools should use - far from it. There are many things that schools should use, and the judgement of teachers is essential to that.
"But NAPLAN is important, and it's important to give us a guide as to whether we're getting those foundational skills right upon which we can then build more complex skills."
Nine.com.au has also approached the NSW Minister for Education Rob Stokes for comment.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Teachers Federation Maurie Mulheron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Stanley Rabinowitz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Rabinowtiz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reporting Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACARA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN Online</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulheron</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Ministers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Curriculum</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Rob Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Rabinowitz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
