<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417901890731384</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/gold-coast-titans/ash-taylor-signing-race-shapes-as-a-watershed-moment-for-gold-coast-titans-20170803-gxoe78.html</url>
  <title>Ash Taylor signing race shapes as a watershed moment for Gold Coast Titans</title>
  <content>
There are high stakes for the Brisbane Broncos as they face the Titans on Saturday night but the future direction of Gold Coast halfback Ash Taylor remains inescapable ahead of Queensland's only regional derby.
Paul White, the Broncos chief executive, insists rivalry in rugby league hasn't gone the way of the dodo, even if he and his Titans counterpart Graham Annesley were on the most friendly of terms when they appeared to together in front of the beach at Southport on Thursday.

Up Next

Neymar leaving Barca, Spanish superclub confirms

00:42

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Plays of the Week

Nail-biting finishes, ripping yorkers and hat-trick heroes, these are the plays of the week.

That relationship might go substantially south if Brisbane were to regain the rights to Taylor, the brilliant young playmaker that left Red Hill as a rookie in search of regular top grade football but could be the subject of a targeted raid as he plans his future.
Taylor has a year to run on his current Titans deal but will start weighing up his options from the start of next season. With Ben Hunt on the way to the Dragons, Brisbane will turn to Kodi Nikorima to guide them in the number seven jumper.Photo: AAP
But players of Taylor's quality and upside rarely surface on the market and Nikorima can play anywhere. Wayne Bennett has made no secret of the fact that if Taylor was interested in shifting back up the M1, they would be highly accommodating.
It all shapes as a watershed moment for the Gold Coast, who already lost damaging centre James Roberts to Brisbane, although they did gain Origin prop Jarrod Wallace.

Annesley has made it clear they see Taylor as the man to build a team around and they now need to prove they can provide an attractive offer to future stars. If they don't, suggestions that they have become an expensive feeder team for the Broncos would only grow louder.
"We've got Ash Taylor up until the end of next season. Under the NRL system players can look at their future in the final year of their contract. Ash is a very, very important part of our club going forward. He's aware of that. We are talking to him and his management at this stage," Annesley said.
"Any player is entitled to see who is interested in their services but we'll be doing everything we can to keep Ash on the Gold Coast. We see the future as building a team around him and we'll be doing everything we can to keep him.
"The Broncos let Ash go because of their roster. We picked him up and he's gone on from being a rookie to an established member of our team and one of the real prospects of being one of the great players in the game.
"He's still got a lot to do but he shows all the hallmarks of being around for a long time. We'd like to see him on the Gold Coast."
The timing of Bennett's comments have raised some eyebrows but he was only responding to questions. And this rivalry needs all the help it can get, with the Titans without a win against Brisbane for three seasons.
It's also given the Titans a timely crack with the persuader to start performing towards the end of the season. Annesley said he was well aware players, especially a potential million-dollar one like Taylor, need to see a light at the end of the tunnel.
"I think players want to go to clubs where they see a strong future. Players know whether clubs are on the improve or on the downwards spiral. I like to think our club is on the improve.
"We need to retain the basis of our team. Of course it's important that if we're not going to be in the eight, that the players feel this club has a future."
White said his immediate job was to finalise deals with stars like Darius Boyd and he hadn't considered where Taylor might fit in to their cap scenario. But all's fair in love and war and there's little doubt Brisbane would feel like the cat that ate the cream should they jag the Gold Coast young gun.
"Our immediate priority is finalising our current roster, we've still got Darius Boyd contract negotiations to be finalised. That's our number one priority at this stage," White said.
"The salary cap equalised the competition. We have seen guys like Jarrod Wallace and Ashley Taylor travel down to the Titans because they can get regular first grade. You're always limited to what you may offer. The player marker has been pretty fluid but I think it's been pretty difficult for all clubs. We're still operating with an unknown cap."
Both clubs were on hand to raise awareness and support for the Thomas Kelly Foundation, which aims to provide a responsible drinking culture among young Australians. Kelly died as the result of an unprovoked one-punch attack in Kings Cross in 2012.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikorima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Kelly Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Annesley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kodi Nikorima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Taylor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darius Boyd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Wallace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annesley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
