<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417987790078732</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/casey-residents-planted-more-than-12000-indigenous-plants-in-just-two-hours-during-the-national-tree-day-event-on-july-30/news-story/9f048445e1fa9027ac57c4abe4760835</url>
  <title>Casey gets muddy for tree planting day</title>
  <content>
CASEY residents planted more than 12,000 indigenous plants in just two hours during the National Tree Day event on July 30.
Close to 250 people got their hands dirty at the City of Casey's Plant Your Roots event at Hessell Rd in Harkaway, before sharing a multicultural lunch to celebrate their efforts.
The council has been holding tree day events for several years.
Casey city planning manager Nicola Ward said the city was thrilled to see so many people take part in the worthy cause.
"Our community planting days not only achieve improved environmental outcomes, but also foster community spirit and pride and help educate the community about the importance of native vegetation within Casey," Ms Ward said.
"The participants were such a diverse mix of ages, faiths and backgrounds.
"My hope is that the young people of Casey who were there can bring their own children and grandchildren to the park in the future and share the story about how they planted the trees.
"The City of Casey thanks all the individuals, families and community groups who volunteered their time on the day to help Council achieve a significant environmental goal and create Casey's next bushland forest."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harkaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicola Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plant Your Roots</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Tree Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITY of Casey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hessell Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
