<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417944840405038</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/workplace-relations/unions-fined-430000-over-strikes-20170803-gxoiu9.html</url>
  <title>Unions fined $430,000 over strikes</title>
  <content>
Illegal strikes involving about 600 workers at three major Queensland government projects have resulted in two construction unions being fined $430,000.
The Federal Court imposed a $300,000 penalty on the Construction, Forestry, Mining and Energy Union, while the Communications, Electrical and Plumbing Union of Australia was ordered to pay $130,000 over the May 2011 strikes.Photo: Bradley Kanaris
Union officers encouraged hundreds of workers across several construction sites, including the Lady Cilento Children's Hospital, to down tools to campaign against "sham contracting".
The court found the CFMEU was liable for $1000 for each of the 605 workers its officers encouraged to unlawfully strike while the CEPU was ordered to $800 for each of the contraventions it was involved with.
Both aggregate fines were reduced by 50 per cent, due, in part, to co-operation and admissions from the unions.
When proceedings between both unions and the Fair Work Building Inspectorate, which is now the Australian Building and Construction Commission, commenced in May 2013, it was admitted the industrial action was illegal.

"The industrial action by the building workers was unlawful industrial action under the Building and Construction Industry Improvement Act 2005," Thursday's judgment stated.
The reasons it was deemed illegal rely on interpretations of "a labyrinthine series of complex definitional provisions," the justices said.
They centre around whether action was industrially motivated, constitutionally connected and not excluded under provisions of the act.
"The unlawful industrial action by the employees was aided, abetted, counselled or procured by the union officials," the judgment said.
"The conduct of the officials was taken to have been engaged in by their respective unions, and that the unions thereby contravened (the act)."
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forestry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Building Inspectorate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plumbing Union of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Industry Improvement Act 2005</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Kanaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEPU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Building</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Cilento Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
