<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417639897722637</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/health/2017/08/03/12/34/antibiotic-overuse-warning-as-superbug-spreads</url>
  <title>Antibiotic overuse warning as resistant superbug spreads into community</title>
  <content>
Australia's healthcare safety watchdog has issued a warning about the overuse of antibiotics in the community.
A new report from the Australian Commission of Safety and Quality in Health Care found a strain of the antibiotic resistant superbug 'Staphylococcus aureus' that causes bloodstream infections is now more commonly caught in the community rather than hospitals, raising concerns about its spread.
The latest figures show almost half of the Australian population were prescribed antibiotics once in a given year.

Only 23.5 percent of patients prescribed antibiotics had a reason recorded on their health record .
Of these people, around 60 percent were reported to have colds or upper respiratory tract infections, where antibiotics are not generally recommended.
Commission Senior Medical Advisor Professor John Turnidge said antimicrobial resistance was "one of the most significant challenges for the delivery of safe, high-quality health services, and has a direct impact on patient care and patient outcomes".
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Commission of Safety</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commission Senior Medical Advisor Professor John Turnidge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health-care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staphylococcus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
