<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417987790078756</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/mark-thompson-questions-whether-north-melbourne-should-give-coach-brad-scott-a-contract-extension/news-story/9846491f31b09268cd4abff312225dd6</url>
  <title>'He's done an average job at an average club'</title>
  <content>
FORMER Geelong and Essendon coach Mark Thompson says he holds doubts over North Melbourne's decision to enter contract negotiations with coach Brad Scott.
Scott - who is contracted until the end of next season - has led the Kangaroos to the finals on four occasions during his eight-year stint at the helm of the club, including back-to-back preliminary finals in 2015 and 2016.
But speaking on Fox Footy's AFL 360 on Wednesday night, Thompson questioned whether Scott's record warranted a new deal.
"I don't know whether they should or not, because he's done an average job at an average club," Thompson said.
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 20 PREVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
"The critical moment for me - and the thing they'll have to think about - is after eight years, halfway through 2016 after coming fourth and sixth and then having 13 wins and no losses, they've decided they're going to rebuild in a year that they probably topped up.
"And they're going to appoint a coach now who is probably going to take three years? That's 11 years without being successful. I won a premiership in my seventh year, which was a record then, so they're going to break all records."

On Wednesday, club chairman Ben Buckley told SEN Breakfast that the club would wait until the end of the season before approaching Scott over a new deal.
"Brad is contracted for another year, he's doing a really, really good job. We've been very happy with the performance of the team this year," Buckley said.
"He and others were very key to laying out a plan for the next two to three years and I think we're on track with that plan and I think he's coaching extremely well.
"We'll sit down at the end of the year and start to review not only next year but the years ahead and I'm sure at that point in time we'll have some discussion about the coaching position.
"He's contracted for the next year. I think he's enjoying what he's doing, he's very happy with the performance of the coaching staff and the team."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 20 PREVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
