<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417463804060989</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/mile-jedinak-set-to-miss-socceroos-world-cup-qualifiers/8770554</url>
  <title>Mile Jedinak set to miss Socceroos' World Cup qualifiers because of groin injury</title>
  <content>
Captain Mile Jedinak's hopes of appearing in a Socceroos shirt for World Cup qualifiers with Japan and Thailand appear dashed.
Jedinak is still troubled .
The combative midfielder, who turns 33 today, will miss Aston Villa's Championship season opener with Hull City this weekend.
Villa manager Steve Bruce confirmed Jedinak would be out for "a couple of weeks".
A club statement said Jedinak was "in light training but is still approximately two weeks away from being available".
Given Socceroos coach Ange Postecoglou must name his squad at least two weeks before the August 31 qualifier with Japan, Jedinak is in grave doubt of missing the cut.
Australia currently sits third in its World Cup qualifying group.
The top two places progress to Russia, while a third-place finish would send the Socceroos on a tricky repechage pathway.
Jedinak was last sighted in club colours in April in Villa's 1-0 win over arch rivals Birmingham City.
With their season petering out, Villa then allowed Jedinak to rest for a busy June of national team action.
Jedinak returned to help Australia defeat Saudi Arabia in its must-win qualifier but was subsequently ruled out of the Confederations Cup in Russia.
He made the trip back to England and had groin surgery in early July, missing Villa's preseason.
Postecoglou's selection mantra to be tested

Jedinak's rehabilitation timeline leaves Postecoglou in a tricky place.
Postecoglou has been a firm adherent to his "form and fitness" mantra, which gives credence to players firing at club level ahead of reputation.
But Postecoglou could be light on players for the matches against Japan and Thailand.
He has already signalled he is unlikely to pick any A-League players for his squad given the long off-season break.
But Tim Cahill and Mark Milligan, recently signed by Melbourne Victory, are likely exceptions to this rule.

When Jedinak does return to fitness he is expected to fill a crucial role at club level.
Villa are the favourites to be promoted to the English Premier League this season, having signed former England captain John Terry to bolster their title hopes.
Bruce suggested the cost to add Terry to their squad would mean losing "one or two" players, but it is unlikely Jedinak would be one of those.
AAP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Milligan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos' World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confederations Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Victory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Cahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Postecoglou</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birmingham City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ange Postecoglou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hull City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aston Villa's Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jedinak</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mile Jedinak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
