<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417940545437624</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/sa-racing/bordertown-racing-club-to-build-1m-facility/news-story/2e6f4f2d2b3a7bc805cfea162e46a6a2</url>
  <title>Million-dollar boost for country race club</title>
  <content>
IN another boost for South Australian country racing, the Bordertown club will develop a $1 million multipurpose facility.
The racing and community/function centre at Bordertown will provide new race day facilities for stewards, jockeys and patrons.
The two-storey complex will also have the ability to cater for non-race day sit-down functions for up to 150 people upstairs and 75 people downstairs.
The announcement comes hot on the heel of news earlier this week that the Mount Gambier racetrack will be completely revamped at a cost of $3.3m.
The Federal Government has committed $400,000 to the project through the Building Better Regions Fund initiative, with the club funding $519,000 and Thoroughbred Racing SA providing the remaining $70,000.
"This is wonderful news for the community and, following on from the Mount Gambier announcement, TRSA is delighted that the Federal Government has once again recognised the importance of the racing industry in regional South Australia," TRSA chair Frances Nelson said.
TRSA chief operating officer Nick Redin joined Federal Member for Barker, Tony Pasin MP, in Bordertown on Thursday to announce the development.
"We congratulate the club for its ongoing vision and the development of its facilities in a planned and considered manner," Redin said.
"We're extremely grateful to the Federal Government for its commitment and thrilled that we're able to make this project a reality.
"We anticipate the project will take approximately 12 months to complete from commencement and the industry will now work with the Club and local participants on the timing of when this project will be done."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Gambier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bordertown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Pasin MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRSA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Redin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thoroughbred Racing SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Better Regions Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frances Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
