<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418030739752437</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65456/bmw-announces-2018-3-series-changes-ahead-of-november-arrival</url>
  <title>BMW Announces 2018 3 Series Changes Ahead Of November Arrival</title>
  <content>
has detailed a range of changes for the 2018 3 Series range, bring new technology, minor specification changes, and light cosmetic tweaks to the medium sedan and wagon range.
The changes are accompanied by range-wide pricing increases, with between $800 and $1300 added depending on the variant for a range that starts from $57,300 plus on-road costs for the entry level 318i sedan and tops out at $91,200 plus on-roads for the 340i sedan.
The latest iDrive 6 infotainment system makes its way into the 3 Series range with a new app-style interface, and a choice of voice, touch or dial operations. A 6.5-inch display comes standard on the 318i, 320i and 320d ranges, while the 330i, 330e and 340i step-up to an 8.8-inch screen that's optional on lower grades.

A multi-function display which displays specific information for all driving modes is optionally available across the range, while BMW's Speed Limit Info system is included as standard.
Sport Line trim features as standard on the 318i, 320i, 330i and 330e while 340i buyers can choose between Luxury Line or M Sport packages, with the high-grade package optionally available across the rest of the range.
BMW has reworked the steering for the 340i making the previous variable sports steering optional and instead equipping fixed-ratio power steering as standard.

Buyers that add the optional Innovations Package will gain access to additional tech depending on model grade.
On the 318i it adds navigation, parking assistant, multi-function display and extended smartphone connectivity. While the 320i and 320d includes those features plus active cruise control with Stop & Go capabilities.
Adding the Innovations Package to the 330i it adds everything 320i except for the navigation, while the 330e mimics the 330i except for the multi-function display as it uses it own hybrid-specific display.

The updated 3 Series range will arrive in Australian showrooms from November.
Pricing

318i sedan - $57,300 (+$800)
320i sedan - $63,400 (+$900)
320d sedan - $65,800 (+$900)
330i sedan - $70,900 (+$1000)
330e sedan - $73,900 (+$1000)
340i sedan - $91,200 ($1300)
320i Touring - $67,500 (+$1000)
330i Touring - $75,000 (+$1100)
Manufacturer's list price, excluding on-road costs.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luxury Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Touring - $67,500 (+$1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovations Package</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDrive 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW's Speed Limit Info</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Touring - $75,000 (+$1100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW Announces 2018 3 Series Changes Ahead Of November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
