<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418026444784859</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/earth-overshoot-day:-today-the-earth-goes-into-the-red/8770040</url>
  <title>Earth Overshoot Day: We used a year's worth of resources in seven months</title>
  <content>
There is a date every year when the world's resource bank goes into overdraft.
This year, Earth Overshoot Day is marked globally on August 2. For the rest of year we're in the burning red.
It's the point when the amount of natural resources - think trees, fish and water - humanity takes from the Earth reaches the total that can be regenerated over the entire year.
It's when the amount of carbon emitted reaches the amount the forests and oceans are able to absorb.
This year it happened in seven months, according to the Global Footprint Network.
That's the earliest it's ever been and it's no thanks to Australia.

If every country in the world lived like Australia, Earth Overshoot Day would have been on March 12.

If you reckon that's not your debt, you can calculate how you are personally tracking via the  and then compare it to the national date.
We were at a break-even point in 1971 and even had a surplus before that (the UN started collecting this data in 1961).
Since then, the date has been creeping further from December - we're demanding more from the Earth while reducing its capacity to regenerate.
The Global Footprint Network calculates each year's overshoot day.
The equation has four main factors:
How much we consume
How efficiently products are made
How many of us there are
How much nature's ecosystems are able to produce.
According to their calculations, we're using the resources of 1.7 planets every year.
To reign in our ecological spending, we'd need to push Earth Overshoot Day back 4.5 days each year to be living within our single-planet means by 2050.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Footprint Network</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earth Overshoot Day</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
