<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417992085046057</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65461/2018-jaguar-xf-sportbrake-pricing-revealed-ahead-of-australian-launch</url>
  <title>2018 Jaguar XF Sportbrake Pricing Revealed Ahead Of Australian Launch</title>
  <content>
will offer a station wagon variant of its XF sedan for the first time in Australia later this year, announcing the first firm details of the XF Sportbrake ahead of its arrival in November.
The Sportbrake will be tasked with breathing life back into the dwindling 'estate' segment, and will compete with a growing selections of more popular SUVs, as well as long-roof versions of the  and .
The four-variant XF Sportbrake range will start from $90,400 before on-road costs for the entry-level XF R-Sport 20d, powered by a 132kW/430Nm 2.0-litre four-cylinder turbo diesel engine with drive delivered to the rear wheels via an eight-speed automatic transmission.

The next step up in the range, the XF 25t will be the sole petrol version offered to Australian buyers, priced from $91,400 with a 2.0-litre turbocharged four-cylinder engine producing 184kW and 365Nm.
The most powerful Sportbrake is the XF S which generates 221kW and a hefty 700Nm from a 3.0-litre turbo diesel V6, priced from $123,450 plus on-road costs. Alongside the XF S Jaguar will also offer a First Edition model with the same mechanical specification but extra equipment for $137,300 before on-roads.

The more flexible XF Sportbrake features a 565 litre boot, which can be expanded to 1700 litres with the rear seats folded down. Access to the rear cargo bay is via a gesture-controlled powered tailgate to allow for easier loading.
The XF Sportbrake also boasts a 2000kg braked towing limit for diesel models and 1900kg for the petrol variant. Jaguar's Tow Assist technology helps prevent trailer sway without driver input.
Inside the XF Sportbrake comes equipped with Jaguar's 10-inch Touch Pro touchscreen infotainment system, while customers can also option a 12.3-inch digital instrument display, wearable Activity Key, and panoramic sunroof with gesture controlled blind.

The XF Sportbrake also features a range of active safety technology like autonomous emergency braking, adaptive cruise control, blind spot warning and rear cross traffic alert.
Further specifications will be revealed closer to the XF Sportbrake's November launch.
Pricing

XF Sportbrake 20d - $90,400
XF Sportbrake 25t - $91,400
XF S Sportbrake - $123,450
XF S Sportbrake First Edition - $137,300
Manufacturer's list price excluding on-road costs. Overseas model shown.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF S Sportbrake - $123,450</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF Sportbrake 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF Sportbrake 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaguar's Tow Assist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF Sportbrake</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF R-Sport 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaguar XF Sportbrake Pricing Revealed Ahead Of Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Touch Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF S Jaguar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Edition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF Sportbrake's November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Activity Key</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF S Sportbrake First Edition - $137,300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sportbrake</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XF 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
