<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418035034719765</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65455/honda-jazz-tweaked-for-2018-price-and-features-for-australia</url>
  <title>Honda Jazz Tweaked for 2018 - Price And features For Australia</title>
  <content>
has spruced up its Jazz light hatch for the 2018 model year with a fresh face and new infotainment systems.
Visually the Jazz picks up a new front bumper and grille design, and newly designed alloy wheels on the mid and high-spec the VTi-S, and VTi-L model lines.
The Base VTi variant receives a multi-angle reversing camera, a 7.0-inch touchscreen comes with Honda's flexible magic seats which allows 18 different configuration for the multi-folding rear seats. Other standard equipment includes cruise control, 15-inch steel wheels, four-speaker audio, and fabric seat trim.

Jazz VTi pricing is unchanged, available with a five-speed manual for $14,990 plus on-road costs, with the CVT automatic VTi priced from $16,990 before on-road costs.
The Mid-range VTi-S builds on that list with satellite navigation, LED headlights, power-folding mirrors, front fog lights, a leather wrapped steering wheel, tailgate spoiler and 16-inch alloy wheels. The auto-only VTi-S rises by $200 to start from $19,990 plus on-road costs.

The flagship Jazz VTi-L comes with leather-appointed seat trim, heated front seats, keyless entry and ignition, bi-LED headlights and daytime running lights, six-speaker audio a rear seat armrest, rear park sensors, climate control, and steering wheel paddle shifters.
The VTi-L is priced from $22,990, which represents a $500 price rise over the outgoing model.
A new Phoenix Orange pearlescent paint steps in for the previous Attract Yellow hero colour, with seven other paint shades to choose from. An optional Luxe Pack can be added to all variants for $1498 adding black alloy wheels, door visors, bonnet protector, alloy pedal, carpet mat and luggage tray.

All models are still powered by the same 1.5-litre four-cylinder petrol engine that produces 88kW and 145Nm. The Jazz also features Honda's recently announced five year warranty.
The 2018 Honda Jazz will arrive in showrooms during August.
Pricing

Jazz VTi manual - $14,990
Jazz VTi CVT - $16,990
Jazz VTi-S CVT - $19,990
Jazz VTi-L CVT - $22,990
Manufacturer's list price excluding on-road costs. Jazz VTi-L shown.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attract Yellow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazz VTi-L CVT - $22,990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazz VTi CVT - $16,990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazz VTi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honda Jazz Tweaked</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mid-range VTi-S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VTi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazz VTi-S CVT - $19,990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honda Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luxe Pack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VTi-S</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VTi-L</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazz VTi-L</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Orange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Base VTi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CVT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
