<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418030739752349</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/russias-sexiest-motorcyclist-dies-in-tragic-crash/news-story/158dc9fa278fd645157c1d06da53d0b7</url>
  <title>Russia's 'sexiest motorcyclist' dies in tragic crash</title>
  <content>
Olga's death is not being treated as suspicious. Picture: Instagram

Ed Wright and Richard WheatstoneThe Sun

Share

A FEMALE biker dubbed Russia's sexiest motorcyclist has been killed in a horror crash while racing down a motorway.
Olga Pronina was racing through the city of Vladivostok in Russia when she lost control of her BMW motorcycle and ploughed into a side railing on Monday evening.

Olga Pronina died while racing through the city of Vladivostok.Source:Instagram
The 40-year-old mum-of-one, who was known as Monika to her legion of fans on Instagram, was thrown from the bike and died before the emergency services could reach her.
The daring brunette who had more than 150,000 followers on the social media site was described by friends as an adrenaline junkie who loved riding at high-speed.

She won more than 150,000 followers on Instagram.Source:Instagram
In one of her last videos posted on Instagram last month, the thrill-chasing biker - who also worked as a hairdresser - is seen straddling a motorcycle sideways and drinking from a straw while riding at high-speed.

One of the wheels of her bike was found more than 600 yards from the scene.Source:Instagram
And she warned her followers: "By the way, doing 250kmph and holding one hand is very uncomfortable. I do not recommend. But I got my adrenaline dose."
According to local reports, Olga had clocked up dozens of speeding offences.

Olga was said to have clocked dozens of speeding offences.Source:Instagram

Olga was a hairdresser who became an Instagram star.Source:Instagram

Hundreds of fans have paid tribute to her after the tragedy.Source:Instagram
Shocked pal Eduard Hasanov told local media: "She was breaching every rule of safety and riding at high-speed pretty often. Her death is incredibly tragic."

Olga was Russia's most famous motorcyclist.Source:Instagram
Another friend who arrived at the scene 10 minutes after the accident said: "She was high-speeding and the rear wheel of the bike was lying 600 metres from the scene.

Olga was pronounced dead at the scene of the crash.Source:Instagram
"We tried to find her action camera, but could not find it."
Police are not treating her death as suspicious.
Devastated fans have been quick to react.

The Instagram star regularly spoke of the adrenaline rush she got from bikingSource:Instagram
Writing on her Instagram page, GNK_77.1 posted: "Condolences to the family and friends, this is huge tragedy. Sleep calm, crazy girl."
Fan aaterihoff wrote: "I wish you good roads in heaven."
And katilda__in__law posted: "She got her adrenaline dose all right, once and for all ..."

The 40-year-old won legions of fans with her racy Instagram posts.Source:Instagram

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olga</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladivostok.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olga Pronina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard WheatstoneThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>bikingSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladivostok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eduard Hasanov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GNK_77.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>17</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
