<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417820286351728</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/music/justin-bieber-confirms-career-break-i-want-to-be-sustainable-20170803-gxobwp.html</url>
  <title>Justin Bieber confirms career break: 'I want to be sustainable'</title>
  <content>
Justin Bieber has confirmed he is taking a career break in order to focus on living a more "sustainable" lifestyle. 
The pop star abruptly cancelled his Purpose World Tour last month "due to unforseen circumstances".

Up Next
The Bacherlor 2017:
The first kiss

02:18

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Bitchiness on The Bachelor, Dr G Yunupingu's marvelous career, talk shows take on Trump's transgender ban, fans' anger at Australian Ninja Warrior and Ringo and Paul back together again.

The announcement came just weeks after Bieber attended a Hillsong conference in Australia, with rumours swirling that the 23-year-old wants to take a step back from music in order to focus on his faith and potentially start his own church. 
In an emotional message to his fans, Bieber wrote on Instagram that growing up while touring the world hasn't been easy, but "knowing I'm not alone has kept me going".Photo: AP
"I have let my insecurities get the best of me at times," he said. "I let my broken relationships dictate the way I acted towards people and the way I treated them. I let bitterness, jealousy and fear run my life." 
The Canadian pop star said he hoped putting his career on hold would allow him to become face up to his past mistakes and learn from them. 

"I want my career to be sustainable, but I also want my mind, heart and soul to be sustainable," he said.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"[This is] so that I can be the man I want to be, the husband I eventually want to be and the father I want to be. I'm not expecting anyone to understand, but I do want people ot have an opportunity to know where I am coming from."Photo: Instagram/@brigggiesmalls
Earlier this year Bieber was criticised for his unenthusiastic performances in Australia - as well as his . 
While Bieber cut his latest world tour short, he told fans the shows he did play were "unbelievable" and taught him "so much". 
"I am reminded of how blessed I am to have a voice in this world," he said. "I've learned the more you appreciate your calling, the more you want to protect your calling." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Purpose World Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Bieber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillsong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitchiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bacherlor 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bieber</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
