<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417940545437681</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/race-watch-brad-davidsons-extended-preview-and-tips-for-royal-randwick/news-story/46bf51c482158de76b7b9f162ff361b8</url>
  <title>Race watch: Davo's tips for Randwick</title>
  <content>
THE Daily Telegraph's Brad Davidson runs the rule over every race, including speed maps and suggested bets for Royal Randwick on Saturday.ROYAL RANDWICK
Track: Soft 6. Rail: True position.R1 (11.50am): WWW.WALKING2HELP.COM.AU SPRINT (1200m)
OVERVIEW: Two nice colts go head-to-head here in Brave Song and Addictive Nature. Both were pretty impressive winners last start and I wouldn't be surprised to see them come away and fight this out. Maybe Addictive Nature has more upside second-up when compared to Brave Song third-up but Brave Song has already proven he handles wet ground. Wild Heart (blinkers on), Regimen and Solar Patch, who has come back a better horse as a gelding, on the next line.
SPEED MAP: Addictive Nature can hold the fence if he wants with Regimen up there as well. Brave Song should be midfield. Speed looks even.
DID YOU KNOW: Addictive Nature's winning time on debut was more than one second quicker than what Akasaki ran when winning a Benchmark 67 over the same trip (1100m) on the same day.
BETTING STRATEGY: Not much between ADDICTIVE NATURE and BRAVE SONG. Just watching this.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Brave Song $4-$3.20 ($1,000 @ $4, $300 @ $4, $1,050 @ $3.60, $1,000 @ $3.20, $500 @ $3.20)R2 (12.30pm): #THERACES HCP (1800m)
OVERVIEW: Two promising mares look to dictate this upfront and it will just come down to whether they run out the 1800m. I speak of La Chica Bella and Long Time Ago and both have been racing well. La Chica Bella got her own way in front when winning over the mile last start, while Long Time Ago looked gone over 1500m last start but really came again on the line and is bred to get 1800m. Shanakee's two runs back from a spell haven't been that bad and the sting out of the track suits her. She will be strong late. Labdien, Diapason and Wahng Wah also have claims too.
SPEED MAP: La Chica Bella and Long Time Ago should control it upfront. Labdien and Diapason should be in the next line. Speed looks moderate at best.
DID YOU KNOW: Long Time Ago's mother Once Were Wild won an Australian Oaks over 2400m. Also, La Chica Bella's full brother Player One won up to 2100m.
BETTING STRATEGY: Very small each-way play SHANAKEE at $23 (1 x 4).
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Diapason $4.80 unchanged ($980 @ $4.80, $200 @ $4.80)R3 (1.05pm): CINDY SULLIVAN MEMORIAL HCP (1400m)
OVERVIEW: King Darci interests me third-up at his right distance. Adam Hyeronimus replaces an apprentice and he might have just been a bit flat second-up. The 1400m suits as does the sting out of the track. Francesco was super at this track last start and he was three-wide without cover before still running on for third. He looks over the odds. Imperator Augustus just loves his home track, while Dane Thunder has been racing well in Melbourne and must be respected.
SPEED MAP: King Darci and Imperator Augustus should take it up with Muraqaba and He's A Given handy.
DID YOU KNOW: The last race King Darci contested has produced seven subsequent starters for two city winners and three minor placegetters.
BETTING STRATEGY: KING DARCI to win. Saving on FRANCESCO.R4 (1.40pm): TAB HIGHWAY SUPPORTS JOCKEYS TRUST (1400m)
OVERVIEW: I like the set up for Gitan here off a solid third at Canterbury behind Awoke and The Pharoah, who have both run well since. He has won three from five starts at 1400m, beat Imperator Augustus on a heavy track last prep and gets a positive jockey change with Tim Clark going aboard. Makfi Lass savaged the line at Scone last start and she can finish full of running again with no weight on her back. Care To Think is flying in Queensland but he has a wide gate, big weight and may be better on top of the ground. Superstar Bob was good fresh in a stronger race and just has to run out 1400m on a testing track.
SPEED MAP: Solid speed with Mister Marmalade, D'Beak, Puzzling Wonder and Gitan all up there. Every horse should get their chance.
DID YOU KNOW: Care To Think is yet to win on four starts on soft tracks.
BETTING STRATEGY: GITAN to win.R5 (2.15pm): JOHN & DENISE COBCROFT RECOGNITION HCP (2400m)
OVERVIEW: I like the look of Go Benny. He was just half a length off Sayed three back at 2400m and his two runs back in distance since have been super. He did his best work late over the 2000m last start and a wet track is no worry. Sayed is racing in great form and wet tracks are no concern for him either, he is just a bit skinny at $2.80. Celestial Choice won at big odds last start and can run another cheeky race at even bigger odds, while Get On The Grange is airborne and looks next best.
SPEED MAP: Solid tempo with Life O'Brien, Ashlee Marie, Celestial Choice, Global Gentl and Get On The Grange all up there.
DID YOU KNOW: Go Benny meets Sayed (2kg) and Celestial Choice (5kg) better off at the weights compared to last time he raced against this duo.
BETTING STRATEGY: GO BENNY to win at $10.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Sayed $2.80 unchanged ($500 @ $2.80)
R6 (2.50pm): JOCKEY CELEBRATION DAY HCP (1600m)
OVERVIEW: Hard to go past Invincible Knight and he put a gap on most of his rivals here last start. All of his runs this time in have been super and he will be hard to hold out. Admiral Jello ran a blinder fresh after being snagged back from the wide gate and the only query is whether the stayer can reproduce that at the mile second-up. Steyne started under the odds the other day but was held up at a crucial stage and can improve. So Willie the other main chance.
SPEED MAP: Tempo looks even with Gold Ambition, Zin Zan Eddie and Zayam all up there. Every horse gets their chance.
DID YOU KNOW: Steyne has attracted bets of $500 and $250 at $4.40 with TAB in early betting.
BETTING STRATEGY: INVINCIBLE KNIGHT to win.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Steyne $4.40 unchanged ($500 @ $4.40, $250 @ $4.40)R7 (3.30pm): MISSILE STAKES (1200m)
OVERVIEW: The race all comes down to how Le Romain parades. If he strips fit enough and isn't overdoing it in the parade then he is clearly the best horse in the race. He is a multiple Group 1 winner and has beaten Chautauqua at Randwick. The Monstar went well on an unsuitable dry track in the Ramornie and the key is he gets back to a track he loves, on rain affected ground and he is rock-hard fit. Invincible Gem has trialled well twice and she is so underrated. It wouldn't surprise me at all to see her win this. Tycoon Tara won a Group 1 in Queensland last start but she got a cheap lead that day and the set up looks different here.
SPEED MAP: Speed looks very strong with Tycoon Tara and Jungle Edge kicking up from the inside and That's A Good Idea and Memes pressing on from out wider. Le Romain probably has to be ridden cold to get in.
DID YOU KNOW: Tycoon Tara won this race by half-a-length last year.
BETTING STRATEGY: THE MONSTAR the value at $10.

Missile Stakes (1200m)

HorseTrainerJockeyBarrierWeight
1. LE ROMAINK LeesG Schofield858.5kg
2. JUNGLE EDGEM BellK Forrester458.5kg
3. THE MONSTARB CavanoughJ Adams558.5kg
4. BOSS LANER QuintonA Adkins (a)358.5kg
5. THAT'S A GOOD IDEAP & P SnowdenT Angland758.5kg
6. HARPER'S CHOICEG RyanJ Collett258.5kg
7. TYCOON TARAP & P SnowdenK McEvoy156.5kg
8. INVINCIBLE GEMK LeesC Brown656.5kg
9. MEMESJ CoyleMs R King (a)956.5kgR8 (4.10pm): TAB.COM.AU HCP (1000m)
OVERVIEW: I can't let Pro Consul go around without me at $31 and back on a wet track at Randwick suits. He is flying and I'm happy to be with him at the price. Salerno is also big odds at $16 and he has won his past two at this track in commanding fashion. I'm respecting the money for Tango Rain, and the recent trial was super. He is probably the best horse in the race and even though there is a heap of speed inside him, he is a very quick animal and will probably still cross these. He is first-up in a year off one trial though and that's the query. Launch Code was dominant at Wyong last start but this is much tougher.
SPEED MAP: Strong speed here with Tango Rain likely to cross from out wide. Lion Couchant, Johnny Roo Boo, Gendebien and potentially Cudabeen are all up there.
DID YOU KNOW: Tango Rain missed the autumn due to a nasty virus.
BETTING STRATEGY: PRO CONSUL each-way (1 x 4) at $31.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Tango Rain $3.80-$2.90 ($400 @ $3.80, $625 @ $3.20)R9 (4.50pm): SCHWEPPES HCP (1200m)
OVERVIEW: I have to stick with Argent D'Or, he overcame a slow early tempo to win well last start. There's more speed here and he has drawn ideally. Spending To Win gets a nice little weight swing on Argent D'Or from last start and should get every chance, while Kings Of Leon is airborne and just has to overcome the wide draw. Mana loves the sting out of the track and won on an unsuitable good surface last start, while Clipper is flying and beat all bar Missile Stakes contender Memes last start. Denpurr flies fresh but doesn't want it too wet.
SPEED MAP: Solid speed with Clipper, Mana and Spending To Win all up there. Every horse should get their chance.
DID YOU KNOW: Spending To Win gets a 3kg swing in weights on Argent D'Or from last start but goes from Hugh Bowman to James Innes Jr.
BETTING STRATEGY: ARGENT D'OR to win.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Kings Of Leon $9 unchanged ($1,000 @ $9, $200 e/w @ $9/$3.05)TURF TALK
Brad Davidson and Shayne O'Cass discuss their best bets for the weekend.
Davidson: Any new season resolutions, Shayne?
O'Cass: To offload the wooden spoon in the office tipping competition would be a start!
Davidson: Don't worry, Ray Thomas isn't back from holidays for a few weeks yet and we'll make sure he is a long last after the first furlong.
O'Cass: In all seriousness, it's going to be a great season - Winx going for her third Cox Plate and the inaugural running of The Everest, which will be won by Russian Revolution.
Davidson: Hang on a minute, he needs to gain a slot first!
O'Cass: I'll buy one if he doesn't get a spot in the 12-horse field.
Davidson: Where are you going to get $600,000 from? You were asking for 20 cents from me for the vending machine the other day.
O'Cass: Enough gibber, onto more serious things, please.
Davidson: Spring is not far away with the Group 2 Missile Stakes the feature at Randwick on Saturday. Le Romain is back - does he just win or is he vulnerable fresh?
O'Cass: I think you're half right - Kris Lees will win the race but it will be with Invincible Gem.
Davidson: Her trials have been super and Kris did mention she is a bit more forward than Le Romain, although he is still leaning towards the latter as his best chance. I went with The Monstar just with race fitness on his side but it's not a race I am keen on.
O'Cass: How good are the new season three-year-olds lining up in the first? Addictive Nature could be a Golden Rose horse but you and I are both big Solar Patch supporters.
Davidson: He is in my numbers but I couldn't go past Addictive Nature. I won't be playing in that race either though.
O'Cass: So what race are you playing in then?
Davidson: I think Go Benny (Race 5) is the best play on the program at $10 and I will also be having bets on Gitan in the TAB Highway and Pro Consul at $31 in Race 8. What about you my friend?
O'Cass: My good thing is Sayed (Race 5), who is just a fit Waller stayer in form. My other main play is Alluvion in the last at $26. She is on the back-up and should be ready to rock and roll third-up.
Davidson: I went with Argent D'Or in the last but it's a cracking race. Finally, have you got us a tip for the first Friday of the new season?
O'Cass: Saint Denis - Race 3 at Goulburn.
Davidson: I made him my best, too.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TARAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sayed</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tango Rain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celestial Choice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soft 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care To Think</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharoah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STAKES (1200</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R7 (3.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R1 (11.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THERACES HCP (1800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brave Song $4-$3.20 ($1,000 @ $4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celestial Choice (5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Romain</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cudabeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makfi Lass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Oaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tycoon Tara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P SnowdenK McEvoy156.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COM.AU HCP (1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TURF TALK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LE ROMAINK LeesG Schofield858.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DENISE COBCROFT RECOGNITION HCP (2400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWW.WALKING2HELP.COM.AU SPRINT (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Time Ago</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chautauqua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Revolution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph's Brad Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mister Marmalade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R3 (1.05</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CELEBRATION DAY HCP (1600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labdien</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davidson</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R6 (2.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIGHWAY SUPPORTS JOCKEYS TRUST (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P SnowdenT Angland758.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MEMESJ CoyleMs R King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sayed $2.80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gitan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Idea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steyne $4.40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diapason $4.80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muraqaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salerno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Gentl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion Couchant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Benny</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Akasaki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Player One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wahng Wah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCHWEPPES HCP (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Of Leon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diapason</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro Consul</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S A GOOD IDEAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wild Heart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashlee Marie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Ambition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benchmark 67</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Chica Bella</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanakee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramornie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHAYNE O'CASS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sayed (2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spending To Win</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Roo Boo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steyne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Darci</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARKET MOVERS</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HARPER'S CHOICEG RyanJ Collett258.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EDGEM BellK Forrester458.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argent D</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Get On</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tango Rain $3.80-$2.90 ($400 @ $3.80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday.ROYAL RANDWICK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kgR8 (4.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Hyeronimus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Admiral Jello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zayam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jungle Edge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brave Song</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monstar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denpurr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CINDY SULLIVAN MEMORIAL HCP (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GEMK LeesC Brown656.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FRANCESCO.R4 (1.40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Lees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperator Augustus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Innes Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clippers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONSTARB CavanoughJ Adams558.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R5 (2.15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox Plate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAB Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint-Denis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 2 Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francesco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HorseTrainerJockeyBarrier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addictive Nature</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gendebien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R2 (12.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LANER QuintonA Adkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Cass</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R9 (4.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puzzling Wonder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zin Zan Eddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solar Patch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Gem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alluvion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
