<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417429444321640</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/andrew-faulkner-communities-crying-out-for-ratecapping-as-councils-spend-profligately/news-story/539523bc7a813e96ff7f9319fb04eecc</url>
  <title>Communities crying out for rate-capping</title>
  <content>
COUNCILS say they are the closest arm of government to the people.
This is true, as you have to get very close indeed to reach into a victim's hip pocket.
The "closest to the people" line is among the paternalistic sophistry emanating from the Local Government Association's Frome St palace.
(Paid for by you, just as you are paying for the LGA's campaign to make you keep paying exorbitant rates.)
The LGA says our libraries are under threat from the Opposition's rate-capping pledge. According to the LGA libraries are "discretionary spends".
We'll forgive the heinous use of "spend" as a noun, but we won't forgive the blatant - albeit feeble - bid to pass off libraries as luxuries. Running libraries is one of the things councils actually do well, so good luck selling closing the library to the community.
LGA chief executive Matt Pinnegar told ABC radio recently that "sporting facilities, local jetties, parks and gardens ... these are all the things that are at risk".
It's supposed to be a scare campaign, but it's about as scary as an eight-year-old saying "boo" after springing out from behind an expensive piece of council-commissioned modern art at one of the soon-to-be-closed playgrounds.
If the nasty Liberals won't consider the kids, won't they think of the volunteers? Yes, rate-capping will stop you giving up your time to volunteer in your community.
"The experience interstate is very clear that progressively you see councils doing less, maintaining less, you see infrastructure backlogs (and) you see less opportunities for volunteers to work with councils," Mr Pinnegar said.
Infrastructure backlogs? Councils have been doing a fine job of building them up on their own, even after years of exponential rates rises.
As for the "experience interstate" argument, according to the Opposition, South Australians pay about $150 more in council rates per capita than "any other state".
But it's always the libraries, playgrounds and ovals. Not the legal fees, conga lines of consultants and overseas conferences.
With wages growth stagnating, and lingering job insecurity, communities are crying out for rate-capping, and the more the better.
Andrew Faulkner is a journalist and author.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Faulkner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pinnegar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Pinnegar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government Association's Frome St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
