<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417940545437594</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/one-trapped-one-fights-for-life-after-plane-crashes-in-melbournes-southeast-20170803-gxodr3.html</url>
  <title>Two flown to hospital after plane crashes in Melbourne's south-east</title>
  <content>
Two people have been flown to hospital after a light plane crash in Melbourne's outer south-east on Thursday.
Paramedics were called to the accident about 10.40am in Clyde North, Ambulance Victoria said in a statement.Photo: Twitter/@dougalbeatty
One person is in a critical condition, but no details of their injuries have been released.
They are being taken by air-ambulance to The Royal Melbourne Hospital.
An Ambulance Victoria spokeswoman could not confirm the gender or any other details about the person.
A man believed to be in his 20s was initially trapped in the plane, but has now been freed.

Paramedics believe he has suffered facial, chest and spinal injuries.
He is in a serious but stable condition, and will be flown to The Alfred hospital.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The area is regularly used by light planes, including pilots in training.
Four people died in two separate crashes in the same area little more than a year apart in February 2007 and May 2008.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clyde North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambulance Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Melbourne Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
