<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417442329224057</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/kyah-simon-says-matildas-will-put-on-a-cracking-show-against-brazil/news-story/48a64364785570867dbf9ed580d42f77</url>
  <title>Matildas to put on 'cracking show'</title>
  <content>
FOOTBALL star Kyah Simon has promised the Matildas will put on a 'cracking show' when they take on the team which destroyed their dreams of a historic medal at last year's Olympics.
Simon says the quarter-final loss to Brazil in Rio was still felt by the team but would be channelled into positive motivation ahead of their two matches against the South American side in Australia next month.
"It's still a soft spot for us, the Olympics,'' Simon admitted.

"It does still hurt. Big losses on big stages don't escape you.
"But I feel as a professional athlete these moments can define you You use the heartbreak and emotion as new motivation.
"As a collective group we felt like it was a missed opportunity.
"But we have high goals and we use the loss as a positive.''

Football Australia recently announced Australia would play Brazil in two internationals in Sydney in Newcastle in a major boost for the women's side of the game.
The Matildas have an ever-growing support base with top quality matches hopefully enticing new supporters and backers to the team.
"This is huge and hopefully it does bring more people to the game, being able to watch such a high-level game,'' Simon said.
"And we will make it a cracker.''
The Matildas created history in late July when they scored their first every win over football super power, the US.
The Matildas and Brazil will meet on Australian soil in a two-match International Series at Pepper Stadium, Penrith, on September 16 and McDonald Jones Stadium, Newcastle, on September 19.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyah Simon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pepper Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
