<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417854646090384</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/books/michael-connellys-new-book-is-his-30th-and-its-mostly-boschfree-20170802-gxo9lq.html</url>
  <title>Michael Connelly's new book is his 30th, and it's (mostly) Bosch-free</title>
  <content>
Twenty-five years ago, a Los Angeles Times crime reporter published his first novel, a gritty police procedural called The Black Echo and featuring a jazz-loving LAPD homicide detective named Hieronymus - Harry - Bosch.
For its author Michael Connelly, it was the start of an astonishingly successful new career in crime fiction. This month brings a remarkable milestone: his 30th book, The Late Show.Photo: Ian Spanier
"I have a hard time believing it myself," says Connelly. "I wasn't even contemplating (writing 30 books) when I started out on this path, so it's pretty cool."
Though Harry Bosch has featured in most of Connelly's books, he's introduced other lead characters as well: attorney Mickey Haller (who debuted in The Lincoln Lawyer), journalist Jack McEvoy (The Poet), retired FBI profiler Terry McCaleb (Blood Work), professional thief Cassie Black (Void Moon).
The Late Show brings the debut of a new one: LAPD Detective Renee Ballard, who works the night shift at Hollywood Station - called "the late show" by those who work it.
The inspiration for Ballard, said Connelly, "just sort of fell into my lap". For his 30th book, written just after he turned 60, he wanted to do "something a little different, maybe challenge myself in some way". As part of his Amazon series Bosch, he came to meet several LAPD detectives as consultants. One of them, Mitzi Roberts, was a veteran of "the late show" and had plenty of stories to tell.

"I knew I wanted to write about somebody on the late show because it's so entertaining," Connelly said. "When you're a detective on the midnight shift, you don't have a specialty, you roll on any time they need a detective, whether it's big or small. That variety really appealed to me.
"The more I talked to (Detective Roberts), got to know her, saw her in court a couple of times, in crime scenes, I was inspired by her personally, because she's a very determined and fierce detective. Those are the words I was hoping to get into the character of Renee Ballard."
Ballard shares many of Roberts' qualities - including, said Connelly, the real-life detective's habit of going paddleboarding at dawn after finishing her shift, with her dog watching over her belongings on the beach. But the character has her own backstory, one Connelly says he's still developing.
As is his habit for an introductory novel, Connelly focuses The Late Show solely on Ballard. "My history is that I will create a character and they will have a book to themselves, and then I'll integrate the character into the larger world of all my books," he said. (Look closely, though, and you'll find a sly peek of Bosch - or, rather, of the TV show named for him.)
He's thinking, though, that Ballard's path might soon cross with his other characters. A new Bosch book, Two Kinds of Truth, will be out in November, and "I've planted a seed in it for a Ballard book to come afterwards", he said. "If I choose to go in that direction, it would definitely connect the people in the Bosch universe with the Ballard universe. That might bring Haller into it as well."
The Seattle Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bosch-free</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAPD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry McCaleb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Two Kinds of Truth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballard</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bosch</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-five</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lincoln Lawyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hieronymus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Void Moon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Bosch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitzi Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAPD Detective Renee Ballard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Spanier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mickey Haller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connelly</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Connelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Late Show.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassie Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Late Show</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Echo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Ballard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blood Work</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
