<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418159588773226</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/nsw/charges-to-be-laid-over-sydney-terrorist-plane-plot-as-airport-threat-downgraded-20170803-gxoji1.html</url>
  <title>Charges to be laid over Sydney terrorist plane plot as airport threat downgraded</title>
  <content>
Members of a Sydney terrorist cell accused of plotting to blow up a plane will be charged after police gathered "very substantial" evidence about the thwarted attack.
The sweeping operation that let to the arrests of four men on Saturday prompted a bolstering of security measures at Australia's major airports and lengthy passenger delays.Photo: AAP
Speaking in Perth on Thursday, Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull said security measures would return to normal following an assessment by ASIO that there was no longer an active threat to the aviation industry.
"They have uncovered this plot, they have disrupted it and they have contained it," he said.Photo: AAP
Mr Turnbull said "enhanced" security measures would remain in place but travellers would no longer need to arrive two hours before domestic flights and three hours before international flights.
People should follow the directions of their airlines, he added.

"There will be continued enhanced security measures. Some of them will be visible to travellers, some of them will not," he said.
The emergency arrangements that were put in place last week following the counter-terrorism arrests led to chaotic delays at Sydney Airport, with queues snaking out the doors of the terminal.Photo: Supplied
The heightened security measures came after police interrupted a plot to smuggle an improvised explosive device onto an Etihad flight from Sydney to Abu Dhabi.
Khaled Merhi, Khaled Khayat and Mahmoud Khayat remain in custody after the Federal Court granted a police application to keep the men detained for seven days.Photo: Brook Mitchell
Abdul Merhi, 50, Khaled's Wiley Park-based brother,  without charge on Tuesday night.
Police have spent the past few days searching the homes of these men in Punchbowl, Lakemba, Wiley Park and Surry Hills.
A domestic meat mincer turn into a home-made explosive, which could explode or leak poisonous gas, was a suspected weapon.
Mr Turnbull said the Australian Federal Police informed him that "very substantial evidence" had been uncovered.
"The Federal Police Commissioner, Andrew Colvin, has advised me that the investigation efforts are proceeding very successfully in terms of the gathering of evidence," he said.
"And that I should expect, and Australians should expect, charges to be laid in due course."
Hours earlier, NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller said he believed the three men still in custody would be charged.
"The evidence gathered is very strong," he said.
Mr Fuller said police had mobilised quickly to stop what could have been a horrible crime.
"Terrorism is very different to other crimes; you cannot wait until you have the perfect brief, you cannot wait until you have all the pieces of the puzzle because you cannot afford to let the criminal act happen," he said.
"When we go early to protect the community, it gives us an opportunity to make sure we gather all the necessary evidence.
"I think in the coming days, as this matter progresses, and, in my opinion, people will be charged and the facts are tendered ... you will understand about the police operation more holistically."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Police Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOK MITCHELL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled's Wiley Park-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
