<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418159588773201</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/uk-based-expats-were-so-keen-to-secure-this-brisbane-home-they-bid-at-auction-sight-unseen/news-story/6b4c2954fef444e9d519a93b03e7e2fc</url>
  <title>UK based expats were so keen to secure this Brisbane home they bid at auction sight unseen - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
UK based expats were so keen to secure this Bulimba home they bid at auction sight unseen.
The home at 43 Waterline Crescent, sold under the hammer on Thursday for $2.266 million.
There were three bidders, including those on the phone from the UK and bidding started at $2.2 million.
The home was previoulsy owned by Cara and Ben Graham.

43 Waterline Cres, Bulimba

Marketing agent Sarah Hackett of Place Bulimba said the Brisbane riverfront market was the strongest she had seen since 2007.
"The timing has never been better for the high-end riverfront market,'' she said.
"We're seeing a combination of local buyers upgrading and overseas interest. There have also been some expats particularly looking to move back to Brisbane.

43 Waterline Cres, Bulimba

"Today, it was an Australian couple living in the UK who purchased 43 Waterline Crescent over the phone at the Place in-room auctions. They hadn't inspected the home, but they knew the opportunity wouldn't last long."

43 Waterline Cres, Bulimba

Mrs Hackett said there was very little stock on the market and that was something that helped keep price levels strong.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulimba</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterline Cres</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterline Crescent</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Hackett of Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hackett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
