<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418206833414284</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/brazilian-president-michel-temer-survives-vote-on-corruption-trial-20170803-gxodf3.html</url>
  <title>Brazilian President Michel Temer survives vote on corruption trial</title>
  <content>
Curitiba: Brazilian MPs have voted to spare embattled President Michel Temer from standing trial on corruption charges, choosing to keep the deeply unpopular leader in place and avoid yet another round of political turmoil.   
Temer, who needed at least 172 MPs to back him or abstain from voting to avoid prosecution, reached that threshold during a marathon congressional session on Wednesday, Brasilia time, that underscored Brazil's political polarisation. He won the final vote count 263 to 227.Photo: Eraldo Peres
Several lawmakers who sided with him said nothing about the accusations, justifying their votes by saying Brazil could not afford more political upheaval. But opponents said allowing Temer to stay amounted to an endorsement of the culture of impunity that has made corruption in Brazilian politics pervasive.
Temer came nearly a year after Congress impeached his predecessor, Dilma Rousseff, for diverting money from state-run banks to conceal budget shortfalls before her re-election in 2014.

When the top prosecutor charged Temer in June with accepting a $US152,000 bribe ($192,000) from a food industry magnate, Brazilians faced the possibility of losing a second president in two years.
Prosecuting a sitting president in Brazil requires that two-thirds of the lower house of Congress formally send the case to the Supreme Court. If enough MPs had voted against Temer, he would have been suspended for 180 days and potentially put on trial, much like Rousseff was.

But many lawmakers, including some who are also under investigation for corruption, have argued that the country and its aching economy need stability, not more political turmoil.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Temer is separately under cloud after he was caught on tape seemingly agreeing to a bribe scheme by meat giant JBS owners Joesley and Wesley Batista to keep jailed politicians from handing over information to corruption investigations.  Batista recorded his meeting with the President as part of a plea bargain.
More than 80 per cent of Brazilians favoured suspending Temer and putting him on trial, according to a poll conducted late last month; 73 per cent of respondents said that any MPs who blocked the charges did not deserve to be re-elected.
Temer's approval rating sank to 5 per cent last month, according to the poll, which was conducted by the research company IBOPE and had a sampling error of 3 percentage points and included 1000 respondents. That makes him even less popular than Rousseff at her low point in late 2015, when 9 per cent of Brazilians supported her.
Hundreds of lawmakers are under investigation in a series of sprawling probes into kickback schemes at Brazil's state-controlled oil company, Petrobras, and global construction giant Odebrecht and other scandals.
New York Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temer</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joesley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ibope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US152,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eraldo Peres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dilma Rousseff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesley Batista</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brasilia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrobras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rousseff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian President Michel Temer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Michel Temer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CURITIBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batistas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Odebrecht</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
