<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417463804061015</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4831022/new-townhomes-at-the-waterfront-shell-cove-unveiled/?cs=298</url>
  <title>New townhome designs unveiled for The Waterfront, Shell Cove</title>
  <content>
OFF THE PLAN: The homes are located about 150 metres from the marina edge and 300 metres from the future town centre. Pictures: Supplied

New townhome designs have been unveiled for The Waterfront, Shell Cove and will be available for purchase off the plan. 
Fourteen new townhomes will be released on August 17. Prospective buyers can lodge their interest via online registration. 

Prices range from $890,000 to $1.135 million. 
The new four and five-bedroom townhomes include a selection with in-ground pools.
The Sails release is located along The Promontory Drive. The homes are located about 150 metres from the marina edge and 300 metres from the future town centre.
All 14 of the double-storey designer townhomes feature four or five bedrooms, three bathrooms, double garages, north-facing living areas, covered alfresco areas off the main living area and rear-lane access.
Each home also has a fully landscaped garden and courtyard.
The five-bedroom Odyssey townhomes are located on corner lots and feature eight-metre frontages, with some also featuring in-ground pools. The four-bedroom Sails townhomes will have 7.5-metre frontages.

"These large contemporary homes will be in a prime location just a short walk to the future town centre and harbour edge, and will appeal to anyone who desires plenty of space and a combination of indoor and outdoor living," Glenn Colquhoun, development director Shell Cove, Frasers Property Australia said.

Shell Cove is a joint development between Shellharbour City Council and Frasers Property Australia.

Work will reportedly soon begin on stage one of the new town centre, which will include a retail precinct anchored by a Woolworths.

Click  for more details. 

READ MORE: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frasers Property Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Colquhoun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Odyssey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shell Cove</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Promontory Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
