<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418112344132233</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4831437/tk-maxx-first-retailer-to-open-near-new-david-jones/?cs=300</url>
  <title>TK Maxx first to open in Wollongong Central near new David Jones</title>
  <content>
New shopping experience: Brittany Carradine, of Shellharbour, was among the first customers at the new TK Maxx store at Warrawong Plaza when it opened in early May. Picture: Greg Ellis.

is confirmed as the first major new retailer to open in the new look Wollongong Central this month.

The international fashion and retail chain is presently moving into the redeveloped lower ground level site formerly occupied by Rebel sports store. 50 staff are presently being employed and the doors will open on August 31.

Warrawong store manager Jenna King has been promoted to the larger store and will be looking to employ even more casuals leading up to Christmas.

Australia spokesperson Tessa Buenen said at 2000 sqm the Wollongong outlet will be a full service store. And as with all new store openings there will be many one off intriguing items when the doors open at 9am on Thursday, August 31.

"The Wollongong store is quite a large store and will have our full offering," Mr Buenan said.
offers thousands of brands under one roof. The stock changes rapidly to create a treasure hunt style shopping experience. Ms Buenan said TK Maxx buyers travel the world to find the hottest products of the season from major labels, high street brands and up-and-coming designers, all with amazing savings. 

TK Maxx first retailer to open near new David Jones

exit
She said the company was delighted to be expanding its presence in Wollongong, following its recent conversion of 34 Trade Secret stores to TK Maxx. 

"We have been thrilled with the response to that. We see a lot of potential in the Wollongong market. There are a lot of savvy shoppers in the area".

Ms Beunan said TK Maxx was excited to be part of the redevelopment going on in Wollongong Central which was providing a modern new look retail area. It is also excited to be the first retail outlet to open. GPT expects the new look David Jones and other new specialty stores will open in early October ahead of the busy Christmas trading period. 
Ms Beunan said the new larger Wollongong store will have a different offering and will service a slightly different market. But she does expect people will shop at both.
"We are thrilled to bring local shoppers another opportunity to enjoy the exciting TK Maxx shopping experience," she said.

"Every TK Maxx store offers a different assortment of brands and products and the selection changes rapidly. That's why it will be beneficial for shoppers to visit both of our Wollongong stores."
Ms Buenan said customers can expect to see a vast product range at TK Maxx Wollongong Central.

The range will included women's, men's and kids' fashion, shoes, accessories, luggage, beauty, toys, lingerie and homewares for every room.
Ms Beunan said Wollongong Lord Mayor Gordon Bradbery will cut the ribbon at 9am on opening day and everyone was invited to come join in the opening day celebrations.

TK Maxx will also be setting up an activation area manned by staff at the Eat Streets Markets on the first two Thursday nights of trade.

It will have a relaxinf lounge where people can come and ask staff questions about the new store and even apply for casual work.
"We're always on the lookout for great people to join the TK Maxx team as the business grows, and would love to hear from job seekers."

There will also be entertainment on the first day and a Hidden Hangar competition with $2,000 in gift cards.

Trading hours:

Monday to Wednesday & Friday - 9.00am to 5.30pm

Thursday  - 9.00am to 9.00pm

Saturday -  9.00am to 4.00pm
Sunday & Public Holidays -  10.00am to 4.00pm
Related stories:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Lord Mayor Gordon Bradbery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Buenan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trade Secret</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TK Maxx Wollongong Central</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brittany Carradine, of Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Beunan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Buenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eat Streets Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Holidays -  10.00</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrawong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hidden Hangar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tessa Buenen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenna King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TK Maxx</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday -  9.00</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday  - 9.00</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Central</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrawong Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday - 9.00</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
