<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418116639099617</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/how-married-at-first-sight-bride-sharon-sabotaged-her-relationship-with-nick/news-story/1fcaf190478e9412ec37a5f883b6d33b</url>
  <title>How Married At First Sight bride Sharon sabotaged her relationship with Nick</title>
  <content>
MAFS couple Nick and Sharon reveal they got matching tattoos
0:18

Nick and Sharon from Married At First Sight' reveal they got matching tattoos on a recent trip to NZ. Courtesy: Channel Nine/Married At First Sight

April 6th 2017
4 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Married At First Sight's Sharon admits she didn't truly love Nick.

Share

THEY seemed like the perfect couple when they were matched on controversial Channel Nine series Married At First Sight.
But just a few weeks after announcing she's split from her television husband Nick Furphy, Sharon Marsh has admitted she was never truly in love with the 30-year-old Melbourne carpenter.
They were the only couple on the series to stay together after filming wrapped. They got matching tattoos and Furphy encouraged the Perth-based blonde to move across the country for him. But, in an interview with OK! magazine, Marsh said she subconsciously sabotaged her relationship by making excuses.
"I made excuses [as to] why I couldn't move over to Melbourne straight away. My business, I needed to rent out my house, I'd miss my family and friends, my dog ... Bullsh*t!" she told the magazine.

Married at First Sight couple Nick and Sharon fell hard and fast on the series.Source:News Corp Australia

The couple decide to stay together in the final episode of the show.Source:Channel 9
She added: "I realise if you are truly in love with someone and want to commit to them, you will make it happen."
Talking about the recent breakup, she said they remained friends but they're "not in love with each other".

A post shared by Sharon Marsh (@shazzimarsh) on

Their split last month came as a shock to fans of the show. Marsh told New Idea she needed a "deeper love".
"I love Nick, but after moving to Melbourne eight weeks ago to be with him, I soon realised that I'm not in love with him," she told the publication.
"I've shed many tears over this, because I really wanted it to work. I wanted the butterflies and roses - but I also needed a deeper love.

"I had a constant ache in my chest and it didn't feel like I'd made the right decision. I missed everything about home - my dog, my sister, my parents."
Talking about Marsh's decision, Furphy told the magazine: "It broke my heart. I started to shake and couldn't believe what I was hearing."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Furphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Marsh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine/Married At First Sight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAFS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Sight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marsh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Idea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Sight's Sharon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Married At First Sight</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
