<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417592653081849</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/heavenly-brighton-hideaway-to-answer-buyers-prayers/news-story/86c2b4f73b44d5076ce01d95674d8fae</url>
  <title>Heavenly Brighton hideaway to answer buyers prayers - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, has lofty price hopes of $3.75-$3.95 million.

A SOARING tower extends this new home inside a century-old church up to the heavens.
Kay & Burton's Bert Geraerts said the Tower Residence at , was one of three homes built into the former St Luke's Anglican Church as part of a recent development by The Belgrave Group and architects A Genser and Associates.
RELATED:

The project modernised the church's interior.

The home's three levels are connected by a lift.

The project modernised the church's interior but kept its divine heritage facade intact.
"It's something really different and one of a kind for Brighton," Mr Geraerts said. "You see (church conversions) all the time in the inner-city, but there's nothing like this in the residential part of this suburb."

A spiral staircase inside the tower, which also offers city views.

It is one of three homes built into the former St Luke's Anglican Church.

The home's three levels are connected by a lift, and a spiral staircase inside the tower, which also offers city views.
The ground floor features an open-plan living and dining area that is designed to capture natural light and features a marble kitchen with Gaggenau appliances and an integrated Liebherr fridge and freezer.

The plunge pool is north facing.

The deck is perfect for entertaining.

It opens out to a north-facing plunge pool with a cascading water feature and two outdoor entertaining areas.
Three bedrooms - all with ensuites and the main with a dressing room - occupy the next level up, and the top floor offers a retreat or "meditation space" as well as a reading loft.

The property goes under the hammer at 2pm, August 19.

A garage for two cars completes the home, which Mr Geraerts said was already being eyed by locals and buyers from further up the bay in Albert Park.
The property, which is going under the hammer at 2pm, August 19, has price hopes of $3.75-$3.95 million.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Luke's Anglican Church</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heavenly Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liebherr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgrave Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tower Residence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Geraerts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burton's Bert Geraerts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaggenau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
