<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418206833414329</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830477/where-are-your-phones-and-wallets/?cs=300</url>
  <title>"Where are your phones and wallets?"</title>
  <content>
Two men impersonated police officers while committing a robbery while armed with a hammer, police alleged in Wollongong Bail Court on Thursday.
Richard Anthony Mitchell, 33 of Warilla and Michael John Zeiser, 26, of no fixed address, appeared before the court charged with two counts of impersonating police officers, as well as armed robbery and robbery in company.

Police facts allege that on August 1 at 11.15pm the pair were closely following a car on The Esplanade at Oak Flats.
They allegedly flashed a bright, white strobe light at the car "causing the victims to believe they were being signalled by police to pull over".

The car pulled over and Mitchell approached it and allegedly told the trio of men inside, "I'm a cop. My name is Officer Brown ... from Lake Illawarra police station".

Police allege he also identified Zeiser as an officer.

"What have you boys got on you?" Mitchell allegedly asked.

"Any drugs or alcohol? Where are your phones and wallets?"
The victims asked to see some police identification and then called triple 0.
Mitchell then allegedly punched one of the victims and took his phone.

The victim allegedly replied "Look, I know I'm getting robbed, don't attack me. Here, take my watch".
Police allege Mitchell then punched another occupant of the car and stole his phone.
Zeiser allegedly hit the third victim in the shoulder with a hammer twice before grabbing his phone and smashing it to the ground.

After this the pair drove away and the victims reported the incident to police.
Police soon believed the same pair may have been responsible for an alleged robbery on July 31.
The pair have been charged over that incident too, where the police facts alleged they approached a man in a car at Boonerah Reserve in Mt Warrigal and identified themselves as NSW Police.
They allegedly stole a sports bag containing khaki pants and running shoes.
On August 2, police went to a house in Lobelia Street, Albion Park and allegedly spotted Mitchell through a window.
When several people came but he remained inside, police surrounded the house.
Nearly an hour after police arrived, Mitchell left the house and surrendered.
A search of the house allegedly uncovered a phone belonging to one of the victims from the alleged Oak Flats offence.

Mitchell was also allegedly wearing pants the Boonerah Reserve victim identified as his.
In court on Thursday bail for both Mitchell and Zeiser was formally refused.

Both men's cases were adjourned until September 13.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boonerah Reserve</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zeiser</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Anthony Mitchell, 33 of Warilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael John Zeiser, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officer Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Warrigal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Bail Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lobelia Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oak Flats</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
