<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418198243479502</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/cricket/cricket-australia-and-players-sign-peace-deal-to-end-pay-war-20170803-gxokfe.html</url>
  <title>Cricket Australia and players sign peace deal to end pay war</title>
  <content>
Australian cricket's long and ugly pay dispute is finally over, with Cricket Australia and the players finally agreeing on a peace deal on Thursday afternoon.
After 10 months of butting heads, the sports' worst industrial crisis in 40 years had accelerated towards a resolution following a threat last week by CA chief executive James Sutherland to have the matter ruled upon by independent arbitration. Photo: Daniel Pockett
The negotiating teams from CA and the Australian Cricketers' Association had worked long in the night throughout this week to settle their remaining differences in the drafting of a heads of agreement, as the troubled talks threatened to go off course again. They were at last able to find middle ground on Thursday. An announcement in a media conference is expected this afternoon at 4:30pm in Melbourne.
The long-awaited deal on the game's next five-year memorandum of understanding between the governing body and players arrives just in the nick of time to save this month's two-Test series between Australia and Bangladesh. It also ensures that this summer's Ashes series in Australia will go ahead, as will an Australian limited-overs tour of India in October.
Steve Smith's squad is due to assemble in Darwin for a training camp next week before taking off to the subcontinent for a series that they were refusing to play in had there not been a new MOU agreed.
The members of the Test team are among 230 players who have been out of contract and not paid since the last agreement elapsed on June 30.
​MORE TO COME
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
