<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418198243479552</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/world/guntoting-tennessee-bride-arrested-after-pulling-pistol-on-new-husband-20170803-gxofnw.html</url>
  <title>Gun-toting Tennessee bride arrested after pulling pistol on new husband</title>
  <content>
Chicago: The honeymoon did not last long.
Just hours after saying "I do," a Tennessee bride pulled a 9mm pistol from her wedding dress, pointed it at her groom and pulled the trigger, according to court documents and media reports.
Kate Elizabeth Prichard, 25, of Kenton, Tennessee, faces a charge of aggravated domestic assault. Her husband, James Burton, was not injured in Monday's incident.
"Responding officers let the husband know the honeymoon was over and his new wife was going to jail," Sergeant Kyle Evans of the Murfreesboro Police Department told WTVF-TV.
Prichard was still in her wedding dress when she was arrested, Sergeant Evans said.
The incident followed an argument with Burton at the Clarion Inn motel near Murfreesboro, according to court documents.

Prichard at first pointed the gun at her new husband's head, and pulled the trigger, but no shot was fired. She then loaded a round into the gun chamber and shot it into the air, the court documents show.
It is not known if Prichard was aware there was no bullet in the gun when she first pulled the trigger.
Police arrived at the scene after a call said a woman had threatened to shoot her husband for pushing her against a wall. The pair were uncooperative and denied the allegations, the records show.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Neither Prichard nor Burton could be reached for comment.
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WTVF-TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Burton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prichard</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Kyle Evans of the Murfreesboro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MURFREESBORO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Elizabeth Prichard, 25, of Kenton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarion Inn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennessee</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
