<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417429444321619</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/inspirational-speakers-give-students-a-step-in-the/3208319/</url>
  <title>Inspirational speakers give students a step in the right direction</title>
  <content>
JAMES Peterson goes from school to school speaking to students as part of his quest to make sure every young person has the tools and knowledge to look after their mental health.
It's a topic close to Mr Peterson's heart after his father took his own life in 2013 following a long battle with depression and anxiety.
Driven by a burning desire to build awareness and make a difference, he started a mental health charity later that year to help educate and encourage people to live mentally healthy lifestyles.
Since founding breakingFree, Mr Peterson has spoken and delivered workshops to thousands of high school students across Australia.
Mr Peterson shared his inspirational story at the USQ Student Leadership Conference at USQ Springfield this week (August 1).
Organised by USQ's Phoenix Central, the Conference themed Taking the First Steps included keynote speakers who have taken risks in life to achieve their goals.
"When I started breakingFree, I was only 18 and had absolutely nothing," Mr Peterson said.
"No one believed in me and everyone thought there was no way I could make it happen.
"But I had a very clear vision of what I wanted, which was to provide mental health education in high schools because it wasn't being provided.
"I'm a true believer that your mindset determines where you end up, that's why the best advice I can give, is that you must believe in yourself if you want to be successful.
"If you have the vision, passion, patience and stay focus, eventually you will reach your goals."   
Little Tokyo Two's Mike Danielli shared his broad understanding of business and the skills he had learnt in his role looking after the day-to-day operations of the innovation hub.
"How you achieve success is entirely up to you and figuring out the right way to do it," he said.
"People work in their own time zones, so don't envy those who are ahead of you and don't mock those behind you - your time will come."
To learn more about student leadership at USQ, visit .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>USQ Springfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Steps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Peterson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo Two's Mike Danielli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USQ's Phoenix Central</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USQ Student Leadership Conference</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>breakingFree</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JAMES Peterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
