<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418206833414345</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/new-book-delivers-glimpse-into-history/3208196/</url>
  <title>New book delivers glimpse into history</title>
  <content>
TERRY Fewtrell was always interested in his family's history.
Now, through a new book, readers can take a trip back in time and learn about this history of Palmwoods and the man many referred to as the father of the town.
'George, Elise and a mandarin-identity in early Australia' will be launched at the Palmwoods Memorial Hall on Saturday, August 5 by Federal MP Ted O'Brien.
"There was always some key elements of the story that were passed down in the family, mainly to do with my great grandmother as she had a particularly tragic time getting to Australia and then her early years here... what she went through was courageous," Mr Fewtrell said.
"Then she married George and things went from there... we knew they were early settlers in Palmwoods, but that was about it.
"What I set out to do was discover more about these people... the more I knew, the more I wanted to tell their story.
"What I've written is a social history, so it tells their story in the context of what was happening in the world at the time."
The book recreates life in early Palmwoods and details the town's role in the early citrus industry.
George Fewtrell was particularly active in the community and was an orchardist, developing a popular variety of mandarin known as Fewtrell's Early.
Mr Fewtrell said while this was his first book, he had always been interested in history.
"I find it more interesting than fiction, to be honest," he said.
"This was a story that just had a compelling appeal to me and I wanted to tell the story... I am very interested in the issue of national identity."
The book will be on sale at the book launch available for ordering through major bookshops and at Berkelouw's Eumundi, The Bookshop at Caloundra and The River Read at Noosaville.
The book will also be available, along with an e book version, via  and at Amazon and Book Depository websites.
Why our federal MPs want a plebiscite on same-sex marriage
Accusations include woman being told "see a psychiatrist".
The assets could include his luxury 'toys' and 15 properties.
Coast in grip of influenza
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fewtrell's Early</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Fewtrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TERRY Fewtrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal MP Ted O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berkelouw's Eumundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Book Depository</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods Memorial Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fewtrell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
