<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418288437794439</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/business/companies/veteran-political-reporter-laurie-oakes-announces-his-retirement/news-story/6ac90a8c6e57feadd5c4ba43d05a4ef2</url>
  <title>Laurie Oakes announces his retirement</title>
  <content>
NINE News veteran Laurie Oakes has shocked the political and TV industries with his latest scoop - he is retiring.
The 73-year-old Canberra stalwart likened his decision to the famous election slogan: it's time. He will officially retire on August 18.
The network's political editor and a journalist of 50 years standing has been a fixture on Nine's news coverage of Federal Parliament, with his most recent exclusive - revealing Malcolm Turnbull's parody of Donald Trump at the Press Gallery's midwinter ball - made global headlines.
Over his award-winning career, Oakes also laid claim to exposing the Kirribili leadership pact between Bob Hawke and Paul Keating; leaking the entire 1980 Federal Budget; as well as the travel rorts scandal of 1997 which cost three ministers their jobs.
While keeping mum on his sources, Oakes - also a columnist for News Corp - revealed to ninenews.com.au how he orchestrated the Budget scoop, which he claimed was his greatest coup.
"I met a contact in a hotel carpark on the Sunday morning.
"He handed over the Budget speech and gave me 15 minutes to read it.
"So I gabbled the whole lot into a tape recorder while he went in and had a quick drink, and then I transcribed it back at the office.
"That evening [then treasurer] Mr [John] Howard was at home with toddler daughter Melanie on his lap watching cartoons on TV.
"Then the news started and I came up blowing every detail of his Budget speech."
In a tribute following the announcement, the Nine network described Oakes as Australia's "best political mind".
"With 50 years' experience covering politics, Oakes is Australia's best political mind and unrivalled in his ability to break news and offer expert analysis.
"His grasp of the Australian political scene is without parallel among Australian journalists."
The Nine journalist hasn't been shy about setting the political agenda over the years. He made headlines in June after publishing leaked footage of Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull's off the record Midwinter Ball speech, which showed him poking fun at US President Donald Trump.
Oakes defended his decision, saying: "The PM presumably thought that Mr Trump would never find out because journalists attending the ball agree not to report what happened. But I don't go to the ball and audio just happened to leak plus a sample was posted on Instagram."

Tributes from friends and colleagues started pouring in soon after the announcement.

A true great of Australian journalism ... announces "It's time" . Laurie is retiring & my goodness, we will miss the great man.

kept the bastards honest for decades. What a role model for aspiring journalists. Hope he has a long healthy retirement. 'NO GREATER CRUSADER FOR JOURNALISM'
Remembering Oakes' time in the job, Nine News director Darren Wick said there had been no greater crusader for the cause of journalism in Australia.
"There is an old Samurai saying that a person will only be as long as their life, but their name will be for all time," he wrote.
"At Nine News, that name is Laurie Oakes.
"To borrow the catchcry from Gough Whitlam's 1972 election campaign, Laurie has simply decided, 'It's time'.
"It's with a touch of sadness that this day has finally come. However, it's also with immense pride, admiration and gratitude that we thank Laurie for his contribution to Nine.
"He's a perfectionist who sets the highest standards for himself. And, by way of his actions, he passes those ideals and a tremendous work ethic onto his colleagues. He has always led by example. No-one has been a better master at breaking news.
"He's a father figure to the Canberra Bureau team and a ferocious defender whenever they've come under attack. Many a politician and their minder have been sent from the Bureau with tails between legs after foolishly daring to challenge the veracity of a report on Nine News.
"Occasionally sent packing with colourful language about sex and travel that we couldn't actually bring you on Nine News."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Keating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midwinter Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine News</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Budget</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakes</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREATER CRUSADER FOR JOURNALISM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gough Whitlam's 1972</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Wick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Press Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melanie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirribili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
