<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418241193153388</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/breaking-news/aust-needs-more-climate-scientists-report/news-story/d39e88cf0f797ff2ac29ef7657c5845a</url>
  <title>Call for Aust climate research overhaul</title>
  <content>
Australia's climate agencies need to be overhauled and about 80 new research positions created because the country is falling behind the rest of the world, a new report says.
An Australian Academy of Science review of climate research has called for the creation of a new overarching body - or the beefing up and overhauling of existing organisations - following cuts to the CSIRO's climate team.
The review has also recommended about 80 new research positions, including roughly 30 scientists and modellers, be created over the next four years.
"Australia's climate research sector is a fraction of the size of those in America or Europe, but we cover most of the Southern Hemisphere in terms of climate modelling and understanding," Professor Trevor McDougall, who led the review, said on Thursday.
"Many of our universities are considered to be world-class in this effort, but as a country we are falling behind in areas such as climate modelling."
The academy suggested the creation of a new office of climate research, outside of the environment and energy department, or establishing one or two new national bodies to oversee existing research capacity.
Other options include streamlining all climate research in the Bureau of Meteorology or CSIRO to reduce inefficiency.
The review did not advocate for any one option and said that regardless of the future shape of Australia's climate research sector, current climate modelling capacity was lacking.
"If these gaps are not filled, the effects will not be immediately catastrophic, but Australia will increasingly be less and less able to have a sufficient level of information to make informed decisions," the report said.
Environment and Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg said he would consider the report as part of the government's National Climate Science Advisory Committee.
Labor's science spokesman Kim Carr accused the government of inflicting "extraordinary vandalism" on the CSIRO through previous budget cuts.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Climate Science Advisory Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSIRO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Hemisphere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Trevor McDougall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Academy of Science</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
