<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418288437794396</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/business/breaking-news/holden-makes-warranty-pledge-to-accc/news-story/2640eefa9cb216244c3ed9191b18ee9b</url>
  <title>Holden makes warranty pledge to ACCC</title>
  <content>
Holden has promised the competition watchdog it will review and refund customers who were issued warranties that failed to deliver the guarantees they are entitled to under consumer law.
The Australia Competition and Consumer Commission investigated the car manufacturer after receiving complaints about its response to a manufacturing fault.
"Holden acknowledged that it misrepresented to some consumers that it had discretion to decide whether the vehicle owner would be offered a refund, repair or replacement for a car with a manufacturing fault, and that any remedy was a goodwill gesture," ACCC Chairman Rod Sims said.
The company also accepted that some customers were told the company would not repair the fault because their car had not been serviced by a Holden dealer, or because it was bought second hand.
Holden has accepted its conduct is likely to have contravened consumer law, and committed to meeting its obligations to customers.
That includes the engagement an external reviewer to follow up on any complaints made since January 1, 2016, and provide a remedy to consumers where appropriate.
"Rather than make an example of them in court, we've let them set an example out of court," Mr Sims said.
The watchdog will publish a draft report into car retailers next week, which will elaborate on widespread consumer law issues.
Car owners do not depend on the generosity of the retailer for a repair, refund or replacement, and are entitled to the guarantee of the law for major and minor faults, Mr Sims told AAP.
"The consumer guarantees operate separately to the manufacturer's warranty, and cannot be modified to require consumers to have their vehicles serviced by authorised dealers in order to obtain a remedy."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC Chairman Rod Sims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1, 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
