<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418327092500675</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/markets/raghuram-rajan-on-the-fault-line-that-threatens-the-world-economy-20170803-gxoakk</url>
  <title>Raghuram Rajan on the 'fault line' that threatens the world economy</title>
  <content>
After a three-year stint as governor of the Reserve Bank of India, Raghuram Rajan is back where he feels most comfortable: at the top of the ivory tower of academia.
"I foray out from academia for a few years at a time and I'm always happy to return," he says from the University of Chicago Booth School of Business, where he has been a long-time professor of finance. In addition to his time at the RBI, which ended in September of last year, his previous "foray" was as chief economist at the International Monetary Fund between 2003 and 2006.
What he thinks about being  will sadly have to wait a few more months: Rajan has made a commitment to "not talk about India" for 12 months following his departure.
Rajan was at one stage an outspoken critic of what he called "competitive monetary easing" by central banks, warning that it was pushing more debt into the global financial crisis and causing investors to "crowd in" to risky assets.

In 2014, at a Brookings Institute event, Rajan wondered, "If the policy hurts the rest of the world more than it helps the United States, should this policy be pursued?" .

Central bankers in a 'hard place'

Out of the crucible of monetary policy making, Rajan appears to have toned down that fiery rhetoric. He now concedes that "it has been a tough place to be" running a central bank in an industrial country in recent years.
"On the one hand during the crisis and immediately post-crisis I thought they did a fantastic job in preserving the system and repairing markets and essentially insuring we didn't get the kind of collapse that was at one time imminent," he says.
"At some point I think their focus turned to how we stimulate the system to get back to those levels of growth and I think that's where the jury is more ambivalent, because it's not clear that the instruments have had much traction."

But Rajan does note that it was "paramount" for central bankers to continue to maintain confidence by pledging to do whatever it took to support growth and fend off a damaging bout of deflation.
"Given that they all had inflation mandates which [required] also being above the lower bound of the mandate, none of them could throw up their hands and say, 'well we've done pretty much all we could, there's little more that we can do'."
"They were trapped in a hard place, so I think I would fault not so much the central bankers, after all, they have to say what they have to say, given the alternatives."
Time to tighten

Despite the inevitable risks, Rajan believes it is now "appropriate that accommodation be steadily withdrawn, especially by countries that seem to be growing pretty much at potential".
"Whenever you start [removing monetary stimulus] it's going to be a threat, so better to start doing it and be vigilant for the possibilities, because, as I said, I believe the benefits of continuous accommodation are getting more and more limited, while the costs are rising in terms of price distortions and risk taking behaviour and so on."
As governor of the Bank of India, Rajan was particularly outspoken around the collateral damage to emerging markets as a result of central bank decisions in advanced economies. Is it still something which vexes him as the monetary policy cycle turns towards tightening?
"I think many of them [emerging economies] have had an enormous amount of time to prepare, so hopefully they are in a much better position than they were in 2013 when the 'taper tantrum' started.

"I mean, look, it's never going to be easy, but I think at least some I think withdrawal is necessary because if it's not easy today, it's going to get even worse tomorrow."
Political paralysis

While Rajan is happier these days to take a more sanguine view on central bankers, he is much more critical of politicians for "not stepping up and doing what was needed" in the post-crisis years, an outcome that he partly blames on "political paralysis", particularly in Washington.
"It is important for the political establishment to step up and do what is necessary to strengthen the potential growth of the economies, and that means structural reforms, of which we have seen very limited evidence," Rajan says.

In reflecting back to his award-winning book of 2010, Fault Lines, Rajan sees growing inequality as the primary underlying "fault line" that continues to run through advanced economies. Digging into the root causes of this rising inequality will be a focus of his future academic research, he says.
"Primarily in the United States, but also certain areas in Europe, a growing part of the industrial workforce has essentially not been able to adjust to global competition, to the increase in technology and the displacement by new technology," he says.
"Especially the areas hit by trade competition have really become hollowed-out communities, and those areas - I think to some extent what people call the Trump voters - haven't really obtained the policy focus that they need.
"In a sense the risk is that their social concerns are being addressed by the administration without any attempt to address the economic concerns, and that in the long run could prove very detrimental."
The need for reform

Rajan believes, among other reforms, that a focus on education as a tool to reform the workforce should be a focus for policy makers.
"Certainly education is part of the answer, we have been talking about this for a long time and we need to understand why some of the interventions haven't worked so well. I think it needs more than just money, it needs a much broader focus within the community on making it work."
Surely, then, the emergence of Donald Trump as US President and the distractions of a dysfunctional White House must be a major setback to the cause of long-term reform.

"I don't think you can pin it on the new administration," Rajan demures. "Political consensus has been eluding the US for some time. The polarisation in Congress has been going on for almost 10 years now - since 2010 I guess many people would date it. I think the administration is more a symptom rather than a cause. The polarisation has been there for some time and we need to think about why this polarisation is there and what can be done to remedy it."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brookings Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Monetary Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raghuram Rajan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rajan</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Booth School of Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
