<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418327092500728</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/technology/australianmade-app-designed-to-be-linkedin-for-hollywood-launches-50000-film-funding-prize/news-story/d30e31e02133b6bfea345097929e8767</url>
  <title>Aussie app 'LinkedIn for Hollywood'</title>
  <content>
AN AUSTRALIAN app designed to be the LinkedIn of the film industry is launching a  judged by one the executives behind Game of Thrones to entice new users.
The free app, called Green Room, is already being used in more than 50 countries and its maker says it's designed to help get TV and film productions made in an industry plagued by "outdated modes of networking".
Green Room co-founder and independent filmmaker Kosta Nikas said he teamed up with Peter Lord to create an online network for workers in creative industries as they were currently ignored or under-served by social networks and agency databases.
"Right now there's no efficient means of networking in the sector and it's hurting the most disadvantaged groups," he said.
"There are 100 productions going on in Sydney right now and there's no way to find out their status or where they are."
Green Room users can look up job postings, search for productions by city and type, and make connections within the free app.
Projects currently listed on its network include a Sydney comedy film called The Citizenship Test starring Acropolis Now actor George Kapiniaris and an LA-based romance called Detours.
Filmmakers who join the app and list their production can also apply for a share of a $50,000 film fund, with winners to be judged by a six-member industry panel including HBO Television media and production vice-president Stephen Beres and Red Dog director Kriv Stenders.
The Green Room's launch in and stores followed the release of a Victoria University report , which found job insecurity, low wages, and financial pressures were rife among film industry workers.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Kapiniaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kosta Nikas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Lord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO Television</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Room</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Dog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Beres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citizenship Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kriv Stenders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LinkedIn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acropolis Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
