<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418245488120741</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/tennis/fans-boo-nick-kyrgios-off-the-court-at-the-washington-open/news-story/2de8e7688594c61eacd5c14584124313</url>
  <title>Fans boo Nick Kyrgios off the court at the Washington Open</title>
  <content>
Sunrise hosts argue over Kyrgios going to a nightclub
3:44

Natalie Barr and Mark Beretta argue over Nick Kyrgios' behaviour going to a nightclub while injured at Wimbledon. Courtesy: Sunrise/7 News

July 6th 2017
a month ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Nick Kyrgios' rough trot continues.

Share

FANS have booed Nick Kyrgios off the court after the Aussie tennis star retired in the second set of his match against Tennys Sandgren at the Washington Open because of a shoulder injury.
The 22-year-old was losing 6-3 3-0 to the world No. 106 American on Thursday (AEST) when he pulled the pin after being in obvious discomfort for the duration of their second round match.
Kyrgios first called for the physio after he went down 3-0 in the first, but at least his pain was relatively short-lived as he lost the opener in just 20 minutes.
The physio worked on the Canberra product's right shoulder in the break, but it didn't help as he called it quits after losing the first three games of the second set.
Kyrgios told the trainer: "I'm done," before congratulating Sandgren on advancing to the third round. Despite his physical problems, Kyrgios' reputation for not always giving his best likely made things worse as those in the stands booed him when he declared his retirement, and again as he trudged off the court.
A hampered Nick Kyrgios retires as  moves into the R16 leading 6-3 3-0.
Kyrgios gets booed by some fans as he exits the court after retiring with an injury

Monitoring the Citi Open for  and Nick Kyrgios is, um, not giving his best effort. Not the first time that's happened.

That Kyrgios was playing a local meant he was always going to have trouble endearing himself to the crowd, but the manner of his exit only made things worse.
According to New York Times tennis writer Ben Rothenberg, the ATP gave Kyrgios less than two minutes to address the media after the match.
Press was cut off by ATP after less than 2 min, but Kyrgios said physical struggles hurt his prep. Also obvious off court mental struggles.

It was Kyrgios' first tournament since he retired during the first round of Wimbledon last month because of a chronic hip injury.
He reached the second round in Washington after a bye in the opening round.

Meanwhile, Aussie Jordan Thompson came frustratingly close to upsetting world No. 8 Alexander Zverev in the pair's second round encounter.
The 23-year-old Thompson lost 4-6 6-3 7-6, leading the third set tiebreak 5-4 before conceding the final three points of the match. Two points away from one of the biggest victories of his career, Thompson put a routine backhand into the net and then double-faulted.
Zverev put away the match with a cross-court forehand.
Thompson, ranked 75th in the world, earlier broke his German opponent twice to take the opening set of the pair's first meeting.
Zverev rallied in the second, taking advantage of the weaker service game of Thompson who won only 36 per cent of points on second serve in the set. "I'm just happy to get through that one, 7-6 in the third is always something very nice," Zverev said.
"You feel good about yourself. Hopefully I can do it better the next match."
Zverev, the winner of three titles in 2017, will face Sandgren in the third round.
Earlier, Australian Marc Polmans lost his second round match to American Jared Donaldson in straight sets.
The 20-year-old Polmans was beaten 6-2 6-3 by the world No. 69. Tenth-ranked Canadian Milos Raonic also advanced by defeating Nicolas Mahut 7-6 (7-2) 7-6 (10-8).
Raonic, the 2014 Washington Open champion, next faces veteran Marcos Baghdatis.
- with AAP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zverev</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian Milos Raonic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunrise/7 News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennys Sandgren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Zverev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Jordan Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wimbledon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Beretta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Open</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rothenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrgios</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marc Polmans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Kyrgios</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Barr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polmans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Jared Donaldson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raonic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcos Baghdatis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandgren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
