<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417730092037293</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/music/tours/justin-bieber-reveals-he-cancelled-the-rest-of-his-world-tour-to-stay-sustainable/news-story/d023751827fc43099097cfe9f7256244</url>
  <title>Justin Bieber reveals he cancelled the rest of his world tour to stay 'sustainable'</title>
  <content>
What's Justin Bieber's Next Career Move? -JS
5:00

After cancelling the remainder of his 'Purpose' world tour for religious reasons, Justin Bieber must look ahead to the next chapter in his life. Where will he go? What will he do? What do you mean? Let us know what the Biebs' next move should be in the comments below.

August 2nd 2017
a day ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Justin Bieber explains why he abruptly cancelled his world tour. Picture: Lionel Cironneau

NY Post

Share

IS IT too late now to say sorry?
After abruptly cancelling the rest of his world tour, Justin Bieber apologised to his fans in a typo-filled Instagram post.
"Im so grateful for this journey with all of you.." he started.
He reflected on his issues and continued, "Im VERY aware Im never gonna be perfect, and I'm gonna keep making mistakes but what I'm not gonna do is let my past dictate my future . What I'm not gonna do is be ashamed of my mistakes."
Bieber also said that he's taking this time to be "sustainable."
"I want my career to be sustainable, but I also want my mind heart and soul to be sustainable," he wrote. "So that I can be the man I want to be, the husband I eventually want to be and the father I want to be."
He finished his post in all caps, writing, "THIS MESSAGE IS IS VERY GRAMMATICALLY INCORRECT BUT ITS FROM THE HEART. BUT I THINK THERES SOMETHING SPECIAL ABOUT IMPERFECTIONS!!"

on

Bieber's tour was cancelled in July and his manager asked that fans note that the singer's "soul and well being" are more important than concert dates.
originally appeared on The New York Post and has been republished here with permission.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Js</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NY Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Bieber</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Bieber's Next Career Move</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MESSAGE IS IS VERY GRAMMATICALLY INCORRECT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THINK THERES SOMETHING SPECIAL ABOUT IMPERFECTIONS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Im VERY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biebs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bieber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LIONEL CIRONNEAU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
