<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418284142826956</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4831796/new-housing-trust-ceo-is-appointed/?cs=300</url>
  <title>The Housing Trust appoints new CEO Michele Adair, is a finalist for state award</title>
  <content>
HOUSING TRUST: Their Central Gardens development in Shellharbour has been shortlisted for the Excellence in NSW Regions Development and Excellence in Affordable Development Awards. (Inset) Michele Adair.

The new CEO of The Housing Trust says she wants to ensure the company delivers more safe and affordable homes.
- David Campbell
Michele Adair has been appointed CEO of the Illawarra community housing provider. 

Ms Adair has a background in corporate strategy and organisational performance, and experience across health and social needs portfolios. 

"My life and career have provided me with a wealth of opportunities to understand the importance of collaboration and what people can achieve with the right support," she said.
"I understand the needs of our ageing population, the financial hardships faced by so many people in our community and how difficult it can be for people living with chronic illness or disability.
"With The Housing Trust I can take all of that knowledge and help create communities where people can build the life they choose.

"The best starting place for that is a decent home for everyone."
The Housing Trust chair David Campbell said Ms Adair has both the intense management skills and social awareness needed to fulfill the company's purpose of building homes and communities that create opportunities and enrich lives.
"Michele has held national leadership roles at The Smith Family and Mission Australia and led the merger of Cystic Fibrosis NSW and CF Victoria to create Cystic Fibrosis Community Care, so her understanding of processes and ability to implement policy is second to none," he said.
"We consider her appointment as CEO to be a major coup for the region and we are looking forward to seeing what she achieves in coming years."
Meanwhile, The Housing Trust is attending the Urban Development Institute of Australia (UDIA) NSW Awards for Excellence, where the organisation is a finalist in two development categories.

Their Central Gardens development in Shellharbour is shortlisted for the Excellence in NSW Regions Development and Excellence in Affordable Development Awards.
State category winners have the chance to compete for the National Award.

The award winners are scheduled to be announced on Friday night (August 4).
Housing Trust is a not-for-profit community-based organisation that began in 1983 with an aim to prevent homelessness by providing community homes.

READ MORE: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UDIA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Affordable Development Awards</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Trust I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Michele Adair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith Family</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Campbell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CF Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Development Institute of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Garden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cystic Fibrosis NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Adair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michele Adair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cystic Fibrosis Community Care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Regions Development</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Trust</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of The Housing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of the Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
