<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418241193153373</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4831785/parking-reprieve-for-watt-street-businesses/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Parking reprieve for Watt Street businesses</title>
  <content>
PARCHED FOR PARKS: Watt Street in June. Picture: Max Mason-Hubers

BUSINESSES caught in the hub of Newcastle's east end construction have been given a parking reprieve from the council. 
Newcastle City Council will let businesses facing Watt Street seek a two hour free parking permit for customers and clients for the nearby King Street parking structure. 
The provision is designed to help offset the loss of parking outside their premises as work continues, and requires users to get their parking validated. 
Interim chief executive Jeremy Bath said the council has spoken at length with the affected businesses. 
"Some businesses asked for reserved on-street parking spaces on surrounding streets, but this is not legally possible," he said.

"The only place where the council can provide parking spaces close to Watt St is our King St car park."
"We hope this will provide some relief to Watt St business owners affected by the current upgrades, but also attract more people to the precinct to shop and do business."
The measure could be permanent, with Mr Bath saying it will assessed after construction is complete. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watt St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watt Street</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Bath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
