<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418455941521632</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/husband-and-wife-team-at-dandenong-north-primary-school-have-together-notched-up-95-years-in-education/news-story/e71789180047ad791d02a1ff4dd54c29</url>
  <title>School principal, 73, still loves the job</title>
  <content>
KEVIN Mackay is 73-years-old but still leading the charge at Dandenong North Primary School.
One of Victoria's oldest school principals, Mr Mackay has notched up 55 years in education.
And, keeping it in the family, his wife Jenny Mackay - deputy principal at the school - was recently recognised for her 40 years in teaching.
The couple has spent their entire married life working at Dandenong North, wedding in 1986, the year Mr Mackay took the reins as principal.
"I've been at 10 different schools in my career but landed at Dandenong North in 1983," he said.
"We now have 51 different cultural backgrounds of students at Dandenong North - when I arrived it was only 3-4."
The principal said he'd seen many changes throughout the years and is certain the education system is better than it's ever been.
"In my first year of teaching I remember a travelling salesperson came to the school with all this equipment that was new at the time - overhead projectors and electronic photocopiers - it was all hugely expensive," Mr Mackay said.
"I remember saying no primary school would ever be able to afford this sort of equipment ... now you see the technology we have with interactive whiteboards and computers.
"Kids are much better educated these days."
Mrs Mackay said four teachers on the staff were once pupils at the school and said Mr Mackay's doctor is also a past student.
"'She came into our school and my class from the independent system when she was in Year 4," Mrs Mackay said.
"She had become disengaged with school, although I didn't know that at the time.
"She returned to visit me with a large box of flowers after finding out she had been awarded a place at Monash University in Medicine, to thank me for encouraging her and getting her re-engaged in school.
"It's a great feeling to know you made a difference in someone's life."
Mr Mackay said there had been many memories over the years that would stick with him when retirement eventually comes but there are no plans for that anytime soon.
"I can remember watching the moon landing at Humphrey St Primary School in Ballarat - that school is now an antique shop," he said.
"I'm still loving every day and being rewarded by the job."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong North</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong North Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mackay</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humphrey St Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballarat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Mackay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KEVIN Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
