<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417596948049156</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830995/illawarra-has-a-healthy-music-scene-says-melbourne-band/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Illawarra has a "healthy" music scene says Melbourne's The Ocean Party</title>
  <content>
The Ocean Party: All band members play equal roles in writing songs so the creative juices are always flowing. Their latest album Beauty Point was partly recorded in Stanwell Park.  Picture: Supplied

The Ocean Party are a hard-working bunch of musicians having released seven albums in about seven years - the latest partly recorded in Stanwell Park.
The six-piece hail from Wagga Wagga but are now Melbourne-based, but are signed to Illawarra label Spunk Records.
Guitarist and vocalist Lachlan Denton said over the years they've come to make friends with a lot of creatives in the northern suburbs which led them to record a number of songs for Beauty Point in the basement of a giant share-house on Lower Coast Road.

The Ocean Party. Picture: Supplied
Having played a number of times in the region, Denton said the music scene was thriving in the Illawarra though wasn't sure if it was something in the water or simply the fact the idyllic environment prevented creatives from moving away.
"For a place it's size it's unbelievable really, there's so many great bands coming out of there," he said.

"It's also so close to Sydney, so because of that it's nurtured this really healthy music scene."

Denton said venues could always to more to be supportive of live original music though he feels bands have been "making do" with the amount of Illawarra venues willing.
The Ocean Party are on tour this month: Music Farmers in Wollongong on August 22 and Franks Wild Years in Thirroul on August 23.

 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spunk Records</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franks Wild Years</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beauty Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Coast Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanwell Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ocean Party</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga Wagga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
