<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418374337141709</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/nsw-act/news/nsw-weather-rain-to-hit-sydney-for-evening-commute/news-story/a29c73fb100c5dcccf835a38a8d8a092</url>
  <title>NSW weather: Rain to hit Sydney for evening commute</title>
  <content>
It's been a while since Sydney had scenes with such soggy pedestrians.

Share

AS if thirsty Thursday wasn't a good enough reason to log off and leave work early, there's this - storm's coming, boss, and I gotta get to the pub, er, I mean, home.
Sydney has a 95 per cent chance of rain later in the afternoon, becoming heavy later on, according to the Bureau of Meteorology website.
And true to August, strong winds are on the way, as well, with warnings put in place for coastal areas of Sydney, Hunter, Macquarie and Coffs.

Rains this time last year had Sydney mostly surrounded. Picture: BOMSource:Supplied
Sydney's temperature will also slide, going from 18C at 3pm to 15C by evening.
Rain will become intermittent around midnight before clearing into Friday.
The wet stuff falling from the sky will be quite welcome considering a dearth of it lately, last Monday notwithstanding.

When it used to rain in Sydney - when people wore summer clothing.Source:News Corp Australia
With high-pressure systems having the most influence on NSW weather for the past two months, the seemingly endless blue-sky days have come at a cost.
June was the driest in the state for 15 years, coldest in a decade for overnight minimums but the warmest for nine years considering maximums.
July gave NSW its lightest rainfall for 15 years. Except for far southern ranges, less than 20 per cent of average rainfall for the month fell in the majority of the state.

Nationwide, July was the warmest on record by maximum temperatures and the driest in a decade.
Central West centres such as Mandurama, Parkes and Orange had their driest July ever.
So if you didn't bring a brolly to work, too bad. If you did, keep an eye on it :-)
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandurama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOMSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
