<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418163883740584</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/world/australian-nurse-tammy-davischarles-sentenced-to-18-months-jail-in-cambodia-20170803-gxofsl.html</url>
  <title>Australian nurse Tammy Davis-Charles sentenced to 18 months' jail in Cambodia</title>
  <content>
Phnom Penh: Australian Tammy Davis-Charles wept today after being sentenced in a Cambodian court to 18 months' jail for paying Cambodian women to have surrogate babies for Australian couples.
Two Cambodians who worked with Ms Davis-Charles in the surrogacy business were also convicted and jailed for 18 months.Photo: Cambodian National Police
The sentence will begin from when they were arrested in November last year.
Judge Sor Lina said there was sufficient evidence to prove that 23 Cambodian women were paid $US10,000 each to have surrogate babies and that the couples paid an average of $US50,000 for each baby.

The Judge said evidence showed that money was paid illegally to obtain birth certificates for the babies so they could be taken out of Cambodia.
Davis-Charles, who was wearing an orange prison uniform, was teary-eyed when the guilty verdict and sentence were handed down. She hung her head and wept openly when taken to a holding room for prisoners.

On July 17, Davis-Charles pleaded with the court for leniency, saying she had lost everything and was suffering from cancer.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I lost 20 kilos. I have left eye cancer. My youngest sons said they didn't see their mother coming home," Davis-Charles told the court.Photo: Craig Skehan
Police allege Davis-Charles, a 49-year-old mother of six from Melbourne, falsified documents, including birth certificates, to smooth passage of surrogacy paperwork through Cambodia's murky legal system and the Australian embassy in Cambodia.
For more than a year, Davis-Charles ignored warnings from the Australian government that commercial surrogacy was illegal in Cambodia.Photo: Facebook/Lux Clinic
Davis-Charles' lawyer, Chheang Sophoan, asked the judge to drop charges against her, saying the evidence was unclear.
Davis-Charles told the court her company Fertility Solutions PGD was only responsible for caring for surrogate mothers and another company was responsible for screening and preparing paperwork, such as the contracts between intended parents and surrogate mothers.
But in a statement, prosecutors called for Davis-Charles to be convicted.
"She became an intermediary to recruit the Khmer women to become surrogate mothers," they said.
"She has been involved in the process of paperwork from the beginning until the day the surrogate babies were taken out the country, with the aim of making profit."
Police alleged Fertility Solutions PGD signed at least 23 surrogacy agreements, most of them with Australian biological parents.
Davis-Charles was arrested with the two Cambodians as police cracked down on more than 50 surrogacy clinics and brokers in Phnom Penh.
The crackdown sent hundreds of surrogate mothers into hiding, fearing arrest, where many were not able to receive medication and treatment.
Many surrogates travelled to Thailand and Laos to give birth to their babies.
The Cambodian government called on intending parents, including about 70 couples from Australia, to come forward and abide by temporary rules that would allow them to take their babies home.
Few if any identified themselves.
The rules stipulated the parents must sign a contract agreeing to provide a once-a-year report on the children's mental and physical development in their home countries. A Cambodian court would have to approve the intending parents taking custody of a baby after strict vetting.
Davis-Charles appeared emotional during court hearings after being brought from Prey Sar, a notoriously harsh prison on the outskirts of Phnom Penh.
Witnesses told the court surrogate mothers went to the Australian embassy in Phnom Penh to finalise paperwork that would give custody to the biological parents, but that Davis-Charles usually stayed outside.
, said she did not understand official proceedings at the embassy because no interpreter was present. She said after giving birth her baby girl was taken from her and she did not see her face until meeting with the Australian biological father at the Australian embassy.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook/Lux Clinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tammy Davis-Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prey Sar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fertility Solutions PGD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Sor Lina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chheang Sophoan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodian National Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phnom Penh</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodian</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$50,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davis-Charles</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Skehan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$10,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Davis-Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Tammy Davis-Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodia.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
