<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418417286815353</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/how-the-justice-system-is-failling-vulnerable-australians/8770292</url>
  <title>160,000 people turned away: How the justice system is failing vulnerable Australians</title>
  <content>
All Australians have the right under the law to seek justice. Yet this right means little when you cannot exercise it because you can't get the help you need.
That's the problem now facing countless Australians, and it's getting worse.
Tens of thousands of those who need help most are slipping through the cracks of our justice system every year.
Australians facing complex social and economic challenges encounter more serious legal issues, typically including dealings with government agencies, the health system, consumer issues and spiralling debt.
Yet without the means to afford legal advice most of these issues are left to slide.
Twenty years of steady cuts to the legal-assistance sector mean that free advice is harder and harder to access. Community legal centres are turning away 160,000 people a year due to lack of capacity, while an additional 10,000 people a year are facing the courts alone due to cutbacks.
More than 13 per cent of the population live under the poverty line, yet legal aid is only available for 8 per cent of Australians.
Resources in the Family Court and Federal Circuit Court are so scarce that wait times for final hearings are pushing three years in some registries.
A case related to the permanent living arrangements of a child may take years to reach final resolution, compounding the pressure on families already under the strain of separation.
Minor matters grow to major headaches

Many of the legal issues encountered by people who experience significant disadvantage are tremendously important. They involve, for example, people's access to a secure income, to secure housing, to safety and protection, to the fair resolution of claims and to a fair trial when accused of a crime.
Over time, even minor unresolved complaints can mutate into more complex matters, clogging up the courts and creating enormous personal stress and serious social and economic consequences.
Accumulation of fines, for example, can reinforce poverty, increasing the risk of homelessness or contact with the criminal justice system.

A major driver of the catastrophic imprisonment rates of Indigenous Australians, particularly Aboriginal women, is unpaid fines.
Ms Dhu, an Aboriginal woman who died in custody in 2014, .
Over recent decades, new policies, including those that aim to be "tough on crime", have driven up legal need and exacerbated access to justice problems for people who are already having difficulty negotiating a complex system.
"Tough on crime" policies and laws have typically been developed without consideration of the ripple-on effects.
This puts untold pressure on legal assistance services and the court system, and heaping pressure on health care, housing, and child protection services.
Equality is fundamental

As a society we accept that equality before the law and access to justice are fundamental to the rule of law, which in turn underpins the quality of our economy and society.
Yet we have watched as a person's formal right to seek justice has been rendered useless as that person's effective access to legal remedy has eroded.
The Australian legal profession has laboured for years to mitigate this crisis by working for free.
On average, each Australian lawyer contributes one week of pro bono work each year.
Yet this year the legal profession decided it needed to do more, and that is why the Law Council of Australia is undertaking .
Tell your story

Under the guidance of a steering committee led by former chief justice of the High Court Robert French, a comprehensive national investigation into access to justice for people who experience significantly disadvantage is currently underway.
After months of research, the project has released new consultation papers relating to groups identified to be at a significant social or economic disadvantage: older Australians, young Australians, LGBTI people, homeless persons, recent arrivals, those in regional, rural and remote areas and others.
This research will be distributed widely for public comment and, over the coming months, the Law Council will take the project on the road, through dozens of discussions Australia wide.
The aim is not to tell disadvantaged groups what they need, but to allow those affected to share their personal perspective of the justice system.
The aim is to take our access to justice crisis out of the realm of numbers and into the realm of lived experience, examining the system using a people-centred perspective based on everyday legal problems and the system's response.
We are also identifying what is working well and demonstrating the considerable innovation that exists within the justice sector, despite the pressures it is under.
At the end of this year, the Justice Project's interim report will suggest evidence-based approaches for achieving access to justice that will both reduce costs to the community and overcome the barriers that vulnerable people face.
Australia can and should be a nation that prides itself on the fact that we are all equal before the law.
We have a long way to go from here, but, through the individual contributions of many, the Justice Project can show us how to get there.
Fiona McLeod, SC, is president of the Law Council of Australia.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Council of Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Project</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona McLeod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court Robert French</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Circuit Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Dhu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
