<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418417286815401</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/west-beaches/new-fruit-and-veg-retailer-moves-into-the-port-to-fill-the-void-left-by-farmer-joes/news-story/1205c93eaf71a61866534f3988ca2627</url>
  <title>Meet the fresh face of fruit and veg</title>
  <content>
HAPPILY for the Port, the closure of Farmer Joe's has not spelt the end of local produce in Port Adelaide.
Former Semaphore fruit and veg vendor Lloyd McPhee is moving in to fill the void left when the Port stalwart shut its doors two weeks ago after 23 years of trading in Quebec St.
Mr McPhee - who ran the People's Market for five years on Military Rd and then for the past few months in a carpark in Queenstown - has leased a vacant block down the road from Jaffers Furniture on St Vincent St from Roger and Heather Jaffer at a reduced rate.
Mr McPhee said finding an affordable local site was essential if he was to be able to compete with the large supermarket chains in the area.
"When we first went to move nine months ago, the rents were outrageous," Mr McPhee said.
He said he was grateful to the Jaffers for allowing him to run his open-air market on their block and to Mayor Gary Johanson for recommending the location.
"With Farmer Joe's closing that's opened a door we are hoping to jump through.
"I've been passionate about the Port for 30 years and watched it evolve," he said.
"I supplied the fruit and veg from the beginning at the Red Lime Shack, Dutch Coffee Lab and Folklore cafe."
Mr McPhee said in order to survive when up against nearby supermarket giants he would emphasise the community charm inherent in the People's Market.
"We will be initiating a 'click and collect' service as well as expanding on our uniqueness for being simple, fun, family-friendly and affordable.
"We do things differently like playing old songs in our first van, which is now a jukebox playing classic (songs) from the 60s.
"Our helpers, aged from 13 to 72, carry the boxes to your car - we are becoming bag-free in our efforts to avoid a plastic planet."
Red Lime Shack cafe owner Steph Taylor said she loved the People's Market and was thrilled it was coming to the Port.
"We are so relieved that he will continue and (be) much closer than ever," Ms Taylor said.
Mr McPhee's produce is largely sourced from the Adelaide Hills, the Adelaide Plains and the Riverland.
The market opens for business next Friday, August 11, and will trade 10am - 4pm from Friday to Sunday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McPhee</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Vincent St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Gary Johanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmer Joe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch Coffee Lab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Lime Shack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's Market</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd McPhee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quebec St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaffer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Military Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heather Jaffer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaffers Furniture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
