<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418455941521621</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/personal-finance/shares/us-housing-market-has-room-to-run-20170803-gxojp4</url>
  <title>US housing market has room to run</title>
  <content>
by
Greg Smith

D.R. Horton, the largest home builder in the US, has posted a quarterly profit that was ahead by double digits, beating Wall Street expectations.
We believe "Dr" Horton provides an attractive exposure to the US housing market with an excellent land bank, a diverse product portfolio (spanning price points) and a wide geographic footprint. We believe the US housing market has further to run given the strong jobs market, robust consumer confidence and low housing inventory. Although we expect interest rates to rise again this year, they remain low from an historical perspective.
The company mostly sells single-family homes and offers a range of dwellings, from Express Homes as the most affordable, through to luxury homes under the Emerald Homes banner. Sale prices range from about $US100,000 ($126,000) to more than $US1 million, with an average closing price of $US295,200 in the nine months to June 30. Third quarter revenues increased 17 per cent year-on-year to $US3.7 billion.
About  89 per cent of the company's home sales revenues in the nine months to June 30 came from the sale of single-family detached homes. 

Homes sold in the quarter rose 16 per cent year-on-year to 12,497 homes. While a 2 per cent increase in average selling prices was a modest improvement, it reflects the strong growth of the new Express Homes business segment. This division offers a lower-priced product targeting entry-level buyers and was introduced in  2014.

Solid growth in Express Homes brand

Express Homes has grown quickly to become a significant part of the sales mix, although its share has stabilised in the past couple of quarters.
Express Home sales accounted for 33 per cent of homes closed in the quarter and 25 per cent of home sales revenue. The product has been popular with first time home buyers trying to "get on the ladder".
D.R. Horton has continued to do a good job of preserving margins even as sales of the relatively lower priced Express Homes brand have grown. The gross margin on home sales of 19.8 per cent in the third quarter was just 0.5 percentage points lower than a year earlier. Notably, D.R. Horton has been consistent in maintaining its gross margin at about 20 per cent during the past four years.

Gross profit from home sales came in at $US725.4 million in the quarter, increasing 15 per cent from a year ago. Consolidated pre-tax income rose 17 per cent to $US445 million as the pre-tax profit margin edged up 0.1 percentage points to 11.8 per cent.
Strong cash flows have seen the company further bolster balance sheet strength by buying back shares, with 1.85 million shares repurchased during the quarter.
Despite also paying some $US350 million of principal on its senior notes, D.R. Horton ended the quarter with $US460.8 million of unrestricted cash and a home building debt to capital ratio of just 24.8 per cent.
Trading outlook strong

The trading outlook also looks strong, with net sales orders for the quarter increasing 11 per cent year-on-year to 13,040 homes and by 13 per cent in value to $US3.9 billion. With tailwinds on several fronts, D.R. Horton looks well placed and is attractively priced in our view. The shares trade on 13 times 2017 forecast earnings, dropping to 11.5 times the following year. 
Interests associated with the author and Fat Prophets declare a holding in D.R. Horton.
Greg Smith is the head of research at investment research and funds management house Fat Prophets.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US445</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US725.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US295,200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US100,000 ($126,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D.R. Horton</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fat Prophets</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US460.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Express Homes</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emerald Homes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US3.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US3.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
