<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418335682435485</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-03/morris-keen-to-play-on-if-dogs-want-him-to</url>
  <title>Morris keen to play on if Dogs want him to</title>
  <content>
Morris' day over with serious arm injury
Western Bulldog Dale Morris has gone down to the rooms clutching his arm after falling awkwardly in a marking contest

Veteran defender Dale Morris is keen to play on

VETERAN defender Dale Morris is keen to play on next season if the Western Bulldogs see him as part of their future.

With the 34-year-old touch and go to play again this season after breaking his arm in round 18, Morris could join fellow club greats Robert Murphy and Matthew Boyd in finishing up at season's end.

While Murphy and Boyd are yet to disclose whether they want to play on, Morris said he'd love extend his career into a 14th season.

"I've said all along that if the club want me and there's a role for me there, then I'll keep going forever," Morris told Fox Footy on Wednesday night.

"But we'll have those discussions in due course and work all that out.

"Except for my chalky bones, yes, I feel great."

Broken bones have restricted Morris to just nine games this season, with a fractured leg in round one sidelining him for eight weeks.

With an inability to keep up with the pace of the game usually a sign a veteran's days are numbered, Morris has no concerns as he is still one the of the Dogs' most dependable servants.

But if the club does decide to go in another direction, the All Australian will be shattered and accepting of the decision at the same time.

"So, if the club turned to me and said, 'that's it', I would be upset, and probably devastated," he said.

"But I understand where things are at, I understand how lucky I am and I've been there - I've been up the top, we've won the premiership and I've been a part of a successful club, I've been a part of a club that's not so successful.

"So, it is what it is (and) a lot of this stuff's out of my control unfortunately - I can't be out there playing footy but I'll keep fronting up."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Morris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldog Dale Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morris</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
