<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418412991848012</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/latest-news/nsw-terror-charges-in-due-course-pm/news-story/fe0b9dfa89f743a584c8be3f19bc21bc</url>
  <title>NSW terror charges 'in due course': PM</title>
  <content>
The evidence against three men detained over an alleged Sydney-based terror plot to bring down a plane is "very strong" and charges will likely be laid "in due course", the prime minister says.
The men remain in custody following weekend raids across Sydney prompted by the discovery of the alleged conspiracy to down a Gulf-bound aircraft.
Malcolm Turnbull on Thursday cited advice from AFP Commissioner Andrew Colvin that charges are expected.
"(Mr Colvin) has told me the investigations have proceeded very well in terms of uncovering evidence," the prime minister told reporters in Perth.
"They've got very strong evidence and I should expect charges to be laid in due course."
NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller earlier on Thursday said he also believed charges were likely.
"As this matter progresses, and in my opinion people will be charged, and the facts are tendered, you will understand about the police operation more holistically," he said in Sydney.
"AFP have the lead in the matter but, from my perspective, the evidence gathered is very strong."
Mr Turnbull said the aviation threat level had returned to "possible" after it was raised to "probable" when authorities on the weekend thwarted the alleged terror plot.
The PM said the threat of Islamist terrorism was a global one.
"There are no guarantees in a dangerous world - we all understand that," Mr Turnbull said.
"But we are focused, always, on protecting Australians."
Investigators have combed through homes in Lakemba, Wiley Park, Punchbowl and Surry Hills since the arrests.
Under terror legislation, police are able to hold suspects without charge for up to a week. That period is due to end on Sunday evening.
A fourth man, 50-year-old Abdul Merhi, was also detained but released without charge on Tuesday evening.
Little has been officially confirmed about the alleged conspiracy but police have said it involved an intention to "bring down" a plane and an "improvised device".
One theory is that a chemical bomb was to be hidden inside a meat grinder.
Mr Merhi's solicitor, Moustafa Kheir, wants to review "what basis police had to do what they did".
Mr Fuller welcomes that scrutiny.
"Oversight and people reviewing police action is totally fine," he said.
"But at the same time I've got the challenge of protecting the people of NSW.
"I've been given strong powers, strong legislation, I'll use those."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP Commissioner Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulf-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moustafa Kheir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
