<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418382927076513</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/preview-boomtown-rat-ready-to-rock-for-rookie-trainer-edward-orourke-at-wyong/news-story/1fa1918d3a6b1d41b062a1bdd0119122</url>
  <title>Preview: Boom time for rookie O'Rourke</title>
  <content>
IF things go well, both horse and trainer will post their first win today at Wyong.
Superbly-bred three-year-old Boomtown Rat makes his debut in the Bishop Collins Maiden Plate (1350m). The gelding will be only the third horse saddled-up by one of the newest additions to the Sydney training ranks, Edward O'Rourke.
RACE WATCH:
CHARGED:
The 32-year-old Irishman was granted his trainer's licence recently, taking over the Randwick stables of Michael Freedman, now in Hong Kong, where he had been working as stable foreman.SHAYNE O'CASS'S BEST BETSWYONG
BEST BET: STONE (Race 2, No. 4)
Has raced three times, all of them in town against superior opposition to what he meets here. Stone ran well last start against Siege Of Quebec, who looks a Golden Rose candidate, and that form reads well for a provincial maiden.
NEXT BEST: WANDER (Race 3, No. 4)
Another of the James Cummings-trained string, this son of Lonhro is a half brother to Group 2 winner Gallatin. Hit the line extremely well at his last trial. Bold bid expected.
VALUE BET: GONE WITH THE WIND (Race 5, No. 1)
Can take control of this race and hopefully dictate terms to ensure that he has something in reserve for the late challengers. Layout suits.
JOCKEY TO FOLLOW
Two-time Melbourne Cup-winning jockey KERRIN McEVOY has a great book of rides - two each for Chris Waller and Joe Pride, while his other one, for David Pfieffer (Crafty Tycoon), can win race seven.
SUGGESTED BETS
Exacta: Race 2, No. 4 to beat No. 1
Daily Double: 1st leg: 1, 2nd leg: 5
QUADDIE
Race 5: 1,2,3,4. Race 6: 1,2. Race 7: 1,3,7,8. Race 8: 3,5.GOULBURN
BEST BET: AALTO (Race 6, No. 10)
A $340,000 yearling on debut. Superbly bred by Pierro out of Miss Mooney Mooney and has trialled nicely for this without being shown up.
NEXT BEST: SAINT DENIS (Race 3, No. 3)
Will benefit from his narrow second at Newcastle over 1400m. Finished off strongly and the mile will suit him, while Jeff Penza is in the saddle again.
*****
O'Rourke inherited a number of Freedman-trained horses, including the Golden Slipper runner-up Frolic, as well as the one-time boom filly From Within (formerly with Chris Waller).
Boomtown Rat was purchased by Freedman for NZ$110,000 at the New Zealand Bloodstock Ready To Run Sale after the horse breezed up over 200m in a slick time of 10.66s.
Boomtown Rat is a son of New Zealand 2000 Guineas winner and NZ Derby runner-up Rock 'N' Pop and is a half brother to Group 1 Telegraph winner Irish Fling.
"He is well-bred and he has shown us a lot for a stayer in some 900m trials, so he has sprinted quite well, which normally stayers can't do,'' O'Rourke said.
"Obviously we didn't want to start him off over 1200m because we know he wants to get over a mile-plus, so we expect him to be competitive. It's not a big field but it's a good field. He's got a nice draw and should improve again from (Friday's run). He is still quite immature through the neck and the shoulder so once he has a bit of time under his belt, he'll be a nice city horse.''
Meantime, two-time Melbourne Cup-winning jockey Kerrin McEvoy has five major chances at Wyong, one for David Pfieffer and two each for Chris Waller and Joe Pride.
McEvoy's engagement for Pride are the Proven Thoroughbreds pair of Masterati and Tamarack. Both are first-up in their respective races and in desperate need of a firm track.
"Masterati is a galloper that Joe has always liked,'' Proven Thoroughbreds founder Jamie Walter said. "He was disappointing behind Russian Revolution on debut on a wet track so we gave him a decent spell. He came back and was wide but well beaten at Gosford after he was gelded so we were pretty disappointed in that, but subsequently we found that he had a little bit of a back issue which has been addressed.
"His trials have been good and Joe's very, very happy with him.''
Stablemate Tamarack has drawn barrier three.
"He was really impressive at his first two runs then he had three weeks between runs and we stepped him up to a mile on a heavy track and he failed,'' Walter said. "Then we gave him another three weeks off and kept him to the mile on a good track and he was fair.
"So he's on a bit of a redemption course but it would want to be a pretty dry track for him to run otherwise we will keep him for another day.''GOULBURN
CANNY Lass descendant Saint Denis may never get a better opportunity to shed his maiden status than Friday's Australian Stockyard Co Maiden (1600m) at Goulburn.
Saint Denis was formerly trained by James Cummings but relocated to John Sargent's stables when Cummings took over as head trainer at Godolphin last month.
Saint Denis has had two runs for Sargent, both at Newcastle, finishing second in a 1200m maiden first-up before his solid third over 1400m, again in maiden company.
The son of Show A Heart has been ridden in all four starts by NSW's leading jockey of the 2016-17 season, Jeff Penza, who will be in the saddle again on Friday.
"Saint Denis challenged like he was going to win at Newcastle but he just stayed the same pace,'' Sargent said. "I was speaking to Jeff and I said, 'Look, we'd better get him up to a mile where he can run on the speed and then keep increasing it'. He's bred to do that and the way he has been working, he should be able to be prominent around a mile at Goulburn and put a staying test to them.''
Sargent will use the Goulburn meeting to kick-off the careers of two of the stable's unraced residents in The Big Boss and the British import High Tranquility, who goes around in the opening race over 1300m.
"High Tranquillity is very promising mare. She was born in England and brought out here by the same man that I trained (Queensland Oaks winner) Quintessential for,'' he said.
"We've just taken her time with her, she's settled in now and has got good ability and I think she'll run a very good race. The track is going to be rain affected but High Chaparral's usually don't mind that.''
Al Maher three-year-old The Big Boss was beaten 1 1/2 lengths by possible The Everest contender Pariah in a recent barrier trial at Royal Randwick.
"Michael Walker rode him for me at his last trial and said he's still green and will probably be like all Al Maher's and end up in blinkers,'' Sargent said. "He'll probably go back a bit from the draw, it'll be a learning day out for him, but will give a good account of himself.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward O'Rourke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonhro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Rourke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin McEvoy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crafty Tycoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHAYNE O'CASS'S BEST BETSWYONG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Chaparral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Cup-winning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Double: 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Revolution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gone With</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race: 2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pfieffer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Mooney Mooney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ$110,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aalto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1 Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cummings-trained</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Pride</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Tranquility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamarack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siege Of Quebec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulburn</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedman-trained</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Waller</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N' Pop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Penza</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishop Collins Maiden Plate (1350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godolphin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Bloodstock Ready To Run Sale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Slipper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exacta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterati</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Walter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Freedman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pierro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irishman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish Fling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Show A Heart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday's Australian Stockyard Co Maiden (1600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Sargent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boomtown Rat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand 2000 Guineas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallatin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Maher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Proven Thoroughbreds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Oaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cumming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUADDIE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Boss</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint-Denis</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sargent</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
