<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417511048702121</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/politics/axed-mayor-peter-coad-throws-his-hat-into-state-election-ring/news-story/432e3b432c91a6ac35fba0a29ca2a2b9</url>
  <title>Coad throws hat into election ring</title>
  <content>
FORMER Huon Valley mayor Peter Coad says he is "very keen" to run in the impending State Election.
Mr Coad was sacked with the rest of the Huon Valley Council last year, following a damning Board of Inquiry report which exposed deep-seated divisions and dysfunction.
Mr Coad said he had since been asked on several occasions to run as a candidate for Franklin in the State Election.
"Yeah, more than a couple of people have asked me," he told the Mercury. "I'm not too sure to be honest if I will, but I am very keen to stand. I'm not too happy with what the State Government has done with TasWater and the local government reforms."
Mr Coad said the one sticking point would be costs, as he would run as an independent candidate.
"It can cost a lot of money ... but I would be interested in standing, it would be more likely I do than I don't."
Speculation is rife that suspended Glenorchy mayor Kristie Johnston will run in Denison, with the backing of popular federal MP Andrew Wilkie.
But when contacted by the Mercury, Ms Johnston, while not ruling out such a move, said she was just focused on the Board of Inquiry into the council, which is still to be made public.
"That's No. 1 priority," she said. "There are just too many uncertainties at this moment to think about other things."
Meanwhile, the Australian Recreational Fishers Party will not run candidates in the State Election. But party secretary Kevin Harkins said they would back any candidate who shared their views.
"That will be irrespective of the party, we will back any individual candidates who share our views," Mr Harkins said.
The Greens have said they would campaign hard on fish farming in Lyons where Tassal's proposed Okehampton Bay fish farm has caused much community angst.
"Salmon farming is one issue," Mr Harkins said. "There are many issues on recreational fishing that we don't agree with the Greens on."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Harkin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Recreational Fishers Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Coad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Election</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristie Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasWater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Andrew Wilkie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Board of Inquiry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okehampton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Coad</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Harkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huon Valley Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenorchy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
