<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418374337141809</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/margot-robbies-high-school-yearbook-photos-prove-she-was-destined-to-be-a-hollywood-star/news-story/1dfe929d6e39e6fc4012069107170743</url>
  <title>Margot Robbie's high school yearbook photos prove she was destined to be a Hollywood star</title>
  <content>
Is Margot Robbie the next Bond girl?
1:11

Herald Sun Confidential's Jackie and Nui discuss how our own Margot Robbie has a shot at becoming the female lead in the next James Bond movie

July 28th 2016
a year ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Photos from Margot Robbie's high school yearbook prove she was always a star.

Share

MARGOT Robbie's high school yearbook photos prove the Aussie stunner was always destined to be a Hollywood star.
The photos, which have resurfaced a decade after they were taken, show the 27-year-old as a 17-year-old student with dark hair in her senior year at Somerset College in Mudgeeraba, Queensland.
In one snap, Robbie is seen on stage acting in a school play alongside her classmates - one of whom has his face painted black for the performance.

Margot Robbie performs in a play during her final year at Somerset College.Source:Mega
In another photo, the star is seen posing as a bride for a mock wedding. The A-lister wears a white wedding dress and veil as she stands alongside a "groom" and "bridesmaid" in the photo. She's also shown posing in her blue and white uniform for her official class photo in the yearbook.

Margot Robbie dresses up as a bride for a mock wedding with her classmates.Source:Mega

Front and centre ... the A-lister poses for her class photo at the Mudgeeraba college.Source:Mega
One year after graduating from the Mudgeeraba high school, Robbie landed a guest role as Donna Freedman on Neighbours in 2008 before turning into a permanent castmember on the series. Leaving the soap in 2010, the blonde made the jump to Hollywood before scoring her first major role in Martin Scorsese's 2013 hit The Wolf of Wall Street.

Margot Robbie attends the 88th Annual Academy Awards in 2016.Source:Supplied
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annual Academy Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Scorsese's 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somerset College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mudgeeraba</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolf of Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun Confidential's Jackie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margot Robbie</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Freedman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somerset College.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
