<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418327092500717</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/icacs-report-is-written-by-someone-who-wasnt-there-20170803-gxoii1</url>
  <title>ICAC's report is written by someone who wasn't there</title>
  <content>
Barry O'Farrell was absolutely certain that he : he hadn't seen it, his wife hadn't seen it, even Oscar his 14-year-old cocker spaniel apparently hadn't come across it.
The  by O'Farrell's successor, Premier Mike Baird, to replace the head of the Independent Commission Against Corruption, Megan Latham, with three new Commissioners has put that forgettable bottle of Grange into eternal limbo.
ICAC's long-delayed release of the report into the public hearings of Operation Credo, which focused on lobbying by Australian Water Holdings of Labor and Liberal governments, has a basic flaw: it appears to have been written by someone who wasn't there.
The report was submitted to parliament on Thursday by Acting Commissioner

Reginald Blanch, QC. But who actually wrote it?

ICAC

An ICAC spokeswoman said only that it was a report of the Commission.

"Findings are based on the evidence that was given and not on the demeanour of the witnesses," she said.
ICAC has been able to make  against former Labor Ministers Eddie Obeid, Tony Kelly and Joe Tripodi, with recommendations for prosecution, on the back of documentary evidence and multiple witness accounts.
These are important findings which underline ICAC's essential role. But in any area which required observing the evidence that witnesses gave, and to allocate weight to it, the anonymous writer of the report is unable to proceed. There is no possibility of making findings as to credit.
For example AWH chief Nick Di Girolamo gave evidence that in May 2011 he asked the then AWH chairman Arthur Sinodinos, to lobby the new Premier, O'Farrell for a Public-Private Partnership (PPP) with Sydney Water Corporation.

Sinodinos later told him he spoke to the Minister for finance and services, Greg Pearce, who told he would "direct" Sydney Water Corporation to "undertake a negotiation process with us re: Package 2 & the PPP"
.
Di Girolamo had a file note of this conversation, but both Sinodinos and Pearce denied any such promise was made. Without having heard their evidence to judge their credibiilty, the report writer had no option but to accept that Di Girolamo's file note must be wrong.
To be clear, this is not to suggest that either Sinodinos or Pearce misled ICAC. It's just that having someone write a report three years after the hearings inevitably raises a credibility issue over the findings.
This is nowhere clearer than when it comes to Barry O'Farrell's no good, very bad day, back on April 15 2014, and the earthquake it produced the next day when the Premier resigned because of his mistaken testimony.

The ICAC report covers it in a brisk page and a half, noting that O'Farrell testified he didn't remember receiving a $3000 bottle of Grange which was couriered to his home by Di Girolamo, and "there is no evidence to the contrary.
The Commission is satisfied that there was no intention on Mr O'Farrell's part to mislead the Commission on either occasion that he gave evidence".
It was all a mix-up then. All a bit of a misunderstanding and no need to resign after all. Does O'Farrell feel silly about that, or what?
It's a finding which contains little of the drama, the passion and the underlying mystery that swirled around the hearing room that day.

Di Girolamo gave evidence in the morning that he had couriered the 1959 bottle of Grange to O'Farrell's house and that night O'Farrell called to thank him.
ICAC had the sale receipt, the Direct Couriers despatch record for Job #9600 which notes it was left by the door, and a telephone record that showed O'Farrell called Di Girolamo for 30 seconds that night.
But O'Farrell repeatedly testified that he was certain he never got the bottle because he would remember it. Twice he referred to his wife also not recalling it, with the implicit suggestion that ICAC could question her as well.
He described how he packed up the wine store in the laundry cupboard when they moved house three months later, and the arrangements with his dog ("I should tell you about Oscar").

His vehemence was mystifying. He left himself absolutely no wiggle room. A month before, the Daily Telegraph had asked him if he ever received a bottle of wine from Di Girolamo, and he had said no.
Now he seemed determined to obliterate any possibility that he got the wine. He walked so far out on to the ledge that when Di Girolamo's lawyers produced O'Farrell's handwritten note of thanks for the wine, he had nowhere to go but down.
The ICAC report accepts this as an honest mistake by O'Farrell. Arguably, Mike Baird's decision to replace Commissioner Latham has meant there was no other possible finding.
This is not to suggest that it was anything improper. But was O'Farrell set up by unknown parties? The mystery of the wine bottle remains.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Sinodinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Ministers Eddie Obeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acting Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Girolamo</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 15 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does O'Farrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Job #9600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation Credo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Water Holdings of Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Water Corporation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Private Partnerships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Farrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sinodinos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Di Girolamo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mike Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Latham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Independent Commission Against Corruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Latham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry O'Farrell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Direct Couriers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Farrell</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reginald Blanch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tripodi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
