<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418455941521645</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/13/23/australian-mother-smoked-cannabis-while-pregnant</url>
  <title>WA mother-of-two had 'healthy' babies after smoking marijuana while pregnant</title>
  <content>
A West Australian mother who smoked cannabis throughout her two pregnancies said the criminality of marijuana caused more issues for her children than their exposure to the drug.
Stacey, who asked not to be identified, has smoked marijuana just about every day for the last 40 years.
The 56-year-old said she continued smoking throughout her two pregnancies and produced two "beautiful, healthy and intelligent" children - neither of whom are "pot heads".
"Both of my daughters are above average intelligence and rated in the top 20 percent of their classes," she told nine.com.au
"My oldest is a store manager and my youngest is learning to be a nurse."

Do you think it's okay to smoke marijuana while pregnant?

While never smoking with her children, Stacey remained open with her two daughters about her drug use growing up, particularly after she was busted with 11 plants and found herself unable to find work.
"I started smoking a very long time ago for fun and found out early on that anytime you feel sick, you need one small puff to control the nausea," she said.

Related Articles

"It is gone in an instant - it's like a miracle. So if I had morning sickness, tell me why would I got to the doctor when I had cannabis in my cupboard?"

Stacey said she never liked pharmaceutical drugs.
There are expectant and new mothers across the globe who prescribed to the  - which argues while they take a calculated risk exposing their children to pot they believe it is the best way to medicate themselves for a range of ailments.
Stacey acknowledged her decision to continue smoking throughout her pregnancies came far before she learned of the medicinal benefits.
"I smoked because I was a smoker," she said.
"I never thought much about [the medical side of it] but I had to hide it from people once I fell pregnant."
She admitted  though doing no research before deciding she would continue to smoke throughout her pregnancies.
"Google wasn't there back then and I didn't feel like I could approach a doctor. I suppose I just went on how I felt within my own body," she said.
"I didn't feel like I was damaging myself and being calm around my baby was better than being strung out."
The only issues that arose, she said, stemmed from the drug's illegality.
"It pushes you into this grimy world of unsavoury people where there are far more dangerous drugs available," she said.
As a result Stacey said she stayed in a destructive relationship for much longer than she should have as he used to help her "score".
"If I could go down the street and buy cannabis like I can buy a bottle of vodka I wouldn't have to interact with these people. They wouldn't have that power over me."
In an effort to withdraw from the "dodgy characters" in the drug dealing world, Stacey started to grow her own stash.
This led to her being charged with three different drug offences over ten years - two of which were for the more serious offence of supply.
"I had 11 plants, some still baby plants, but more than 10 is deemed a supplier which means they thought I was sharing it around and could charge me for it."
Stacey said she was never "up at the high school pushing it on anyone" and felt the "serious" criminal charges unjustly tore her life apart.
"It has really hurt my life and my children," she said.
"I can't get a job. Not in the government or at a bank - even cleaning someone's house."
Stacey said she used to work in administration and is "reasonably intelligent" but that didn't stop her being "pushed out" of work.
"I am a very capable and honest person yet I've got this wall up: 'You can't do this; you can't do that.'"
Stacey was put on a 12-month supervision order and forced to undertake drug tests every fortnight.
She said this was the only period she was clean since she started smoking.
"My friend just got clean urine off someone and cheated. I wish I had done that," she said.
Stacey believes around $30,000 was wasted by the government during her "rehabilitation" taking into consideration police man hours charging her, the five times she appeared in court, her probation officer's wage and the cost of pathology for her urine tests.
"And after all that I still smoke," she said.
Stacey said her daughters were old enough that they were not at risk of being taken by child protective services when she was busted for supply in 2014.
She empathised with mothers of younger children who faced the prospect of losing their child if they decide to medicate with cannabis.
"If I was faced with that problem today I think I would cheat [on a drug test]. There is no way I would have let them take my kids from me for that."
She said violent drunks or gamblers pose a far greater risk to their children than "stoner parents".
"If you go to a BBQ people get so drunk they fall off their chair or get violent. The people smoking pot are not the trouble makers. They sit back and have a laugh instead." 
The self-employed mother-of-two likened smoking cannabis during pregnancy to "drinking ten cups of coffee".
"There are a whole heap of risks for pregnant women we don't really look at or police," she said.
"You find pregnant people stuffing themselves with McDonalds instead of eating fresh veggies, or people dosing themselves up on sleeping tablets. What is the difference?"
Stacey argued if these mothers were able to take a calculated risk with their children's lives, she should be entitled to do the same.
"I was upset that I did not have a choice. I am a grown woman who knows my body," she said.
"If I feel stressed I am allowed to drink alcohol. I am allowed to kill myself from drinking so much but if I smoke I am demonised."
Despite her pro-cannabis stance, Stacey condemned images of young mother's smoking bongs while holding their newborns, or breast feeding in a cloud of smoke.
"That girl smoking that cone with the baby in her arms was stupid ... It is just wrong."
"I smoked around my kids because I didn't see running and hiding behind the toilet as a good idea.
"It sets them up to see you as a liar. I was always very up front because I didn't see anything wrong with it myself."
She does however acknowledge cannabis can have different effects on different people.
A friend of Stacey's youngest daughter smoked "a lot of pot" and committed suicide.
"She and her mother both had mental issues but she also used the synthetic stuff.
"It does show cannabis can trigger things in some people, but I see that as the same as sugar triggers diabetes in some and not others."
Stacey said around 90 percent of her friends would share her outlook on cannabis consumption.
"That large segment of the population is overlooked because we aren't allowed to have a voice, or a choice for that matter."
The mother-of-two said her drug use had not turned either of her children into addicts.
Her eldest daughter does not smoke, although she did try cannabis when she was around 17.
"My eldest was apparently pinching it from me when she was a teenager but she doesn't smoke now. She doesn't like drugs - she likes Jack Daniels and coke."
"My younger one likes to experiment a bit but I have been able to show her how to smoke responsibly.
"I am able to say to her, 'This is the story, these are the risks'. The same I do with amphetamines."
Stacey believes this openness fosters trust which makes it far more likely for her daughters to believe her advice when it comes to harder drugs.
"Because I am not lying about cannabis she knows I am not lying about ice."
Stacey argued it is damaging for politicians to be so quick to lump stimulants like amphetamines, or methamphetamines, in the same category as cannabis. 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonalds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stacey</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Daniels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
