<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418455941521605</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/chemotherapy-under-dosing-three-times-worse-than-first-thought/8771256</url>
  <title>Chemotherapy under-dosing in bush three times worse than first thought</title>
  <content>
The number of people in western New South Wales affected by the chemotherapy under-dosing scandal is more than triple originally thought, new documents have revealed.

Key points:

Chemotherapy dosages some of John Grygiel's patients received are again being scrutinised
Probe into clinical records found an extra 58 patients were given off-protocol doses in western NSW
Dr Grygiel settled an unfair dismissal claim with Sydney's St Vincent's Hospital in March

A NSW Government inquiry last year found 28 patients who were treated by doctor John Grygiel during fly-in, fly-out visits to Bathurst, Orange, Dubbo, Parkes and Cowra
Documents obtained by the ABC under Freedom of Information laws show that number to be much higher.
A probe into clinical records held in Western NSW Local Health District and Pharmaceutical Benefits Scheme (PBS) data has found an extra 58 patients received low doses of chemotherapy.
It also found one extra patient was identified as receiving a 100 milligram flat dose of the drug carboplatin.
The inquiry investigated cases between 2010 and 2013, and found in NSW, more than 100 cancer patients treated by Dr Grygiel received off-protocol doses of chemotherapy.

Dr Grygiel in March
Among the patients treated by Dr Grygiel was Kevin Swindle, whose 55th birthday would have been this week.
The father-of-five from Parkes was diagnosed with bowel cancer and died six years ago.
His son Craig said the latest revelations have left his family with more questions around their father's chemotherapy treatment at Orange Base Hospital.
"He mightn't be here now but we would've had longer with him if he'd stayed on the treatment that he was on," Mr Swindle said.
"It would've shrunk the cancer, so if he stayed on that it maybe he would've stayed a bit longer."

'We suspected this all along'

Shadow Health Minister Walt Secord, who has been calling for a special commission of inquiry into under-dosing in the central west, said he was not surprised the figure was much greater than initially thought.
"We suspected this all along, that the numbers the State Government was telling us was a dramatic underestimation," Mr Secord said.
"With the new evidence that's come to light, I think the case for a special commission of inquiry is overwhelming.
"The inquiry by the State Government was inadequate and it didn't even compel witnesses. We know that there were witnesses in the central west that were not forced to give evidence.
"We need to get to the bottom of this, we owe it to the families. Sadly, many of the patients are no longer with us."

Greens MP Jeremy Buckingham, whose late mother-in-law was treated by Dr Grygiel in Orange, said it was vital the government provided a "robust" health system for regional communities.
"We've had a State Government that's more intent on protecting its own reputation than protecting the integrity of the New South Wales health system," Mr Buckingham said.
"It shouldn't be up to the ABC to dig these documents out. I'm incredibly alarmed and I'll be referring it to the Minister and also raising it in State Parliament."
Health Minister Brad Hazzard has been contacted for comment.
The NSW Chief Cancer Officer Professor David Currow said the original government inquiry into the issue had acknowledged the number 28 was incomplete.
"Section 122 inquiry was clear in its background, its recommendations and the patient flow that more cases were expected," Professor Currow said.
"The PBS data was identified as the source for identifying these people and the work of reviewing these cases has now been completed by Western New South Wales Local Health District."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Currow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Grygiel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western New South Wales Local Health District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedom of Information</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Swindle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharmaceutical Benefits Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Walt Secord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Chief Cancer Officer Professor David Currow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Swindle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens MP Jeremy Buckingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orange Base Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Grygiel</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western NSW Local Health District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's St Vincent's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Buckingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Secord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Brad Hazzard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
