<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418541840868865</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/15/59/woman-sentenced-over-terrifying-melbourne-crime-spree</url>
  <title>Woman sentenced over terrifying Melbourne crime spree</title>
  <content>
Tammy Phillips was using one gram of methamphetamine and drinking up to three bottles of spirits when she went on a four-day crime spree that included pressing an imitation gun to the face of an elderly woman.
The crime spree started when Phillips brandished an imitation handgun when she set upon Mavis Dillon, as she put her walking frame in her car.
She pushed 87-year-old great grandmother over, fracturing her eye socket and wrist.
Ms Mavis had to roll away from her car as Phillips snatched her keys and drove away.
Two days later, Phillips targeted a 74-year-old woman who had her three-year-old grandchild with her in a shopping centre carpark.
Phillips jammed a fake gun against the woman's cheek and threatened to harm the little girl if she didn't hand over her purse.
The court heard that victim has since suffered severe depression and has been admitted to a psychiatric unit for treatment.

Related Articles

The 34-year-old made full admissions to her crimes upon her arrest and pleaded guilty.
In sentencing, the Judge Elizabeth Gaynor noted Phillips is illiterate and has such a profound intellectual disability she was unable to comprehend what was being said in court.
Judge Gaynor said told the court "(Phillips) broke the face bone of an 87-year-old lady. Another lady is living in a mental asylum because of what you did to her."
The court was told Phillips has endured a tough life, leaving school at aged 13 and becoming a prostitute, hooked on heroin.
She has three children, who have never been in her custody.
Phillips broke down as she was sentenced to serve a minimum term of three years and 10 months before being eligible for parole.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tammy Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillips</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mavis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Gaynor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Elizabeth Gaynor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mavis Dillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
