<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417562588310395</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829554/connor-watson-why-im-joining-the-knights/?cs=303</url>
  <title>Connor Watson: Why I'm joining the Knights</title>
  <content>
Connor Watson leant on a former teammate already at the Knights and another about to tread the same path to the Hunter before conceding the lure of playing No.6 and leading a Newcastle rebuild was too much to resist.
The Roosters utility, a shining light for Trent Robinson in a season that still promises so much, used new Knight Shaun Kenny-Dowall and Tricolours back-rower Aidan Guerra as sounding boards before signing a three-year deal with Nathan Brown's NRL strugglers.

SIGNED: Connor Watson
It was only after the Roosters snared NSW and Tigers ace James Tedesco that Watson knew his goal of cracking the starting side on a permanent basis in 2018 was not going to be met at Bondi, spurning interest from the Tigers to fill Tedesco's shoes at Concord.
And Newcastle coach Nathan Brown can thank Kenny-Dowall and Guerra, who will also add experience to a side finally showing signs of emerging from back-to-back wooden spoons.
The Newcastle transition for Watson - who famously said as a child on The Footy Show he wanted to play for the Knights when he grew up - will be made easier given the mini-Rooster hunt Brown has embarked on, as a trio of Robinson's stars swap one red, white and blue for another.
"I wouldn't say they were in my ear, but I spoke to both of them about it," Watson said. "I spoke to Skidsy [Kenny-Dowall] a little bit and he was just telling me about the facilities and the area, what the boys are like.
"I did speak to [Guerra too], but they didn't push it on me. They sort of just said, 'We'd love to have you up here and it would be good to play with you again.' They were just there when I needed to ask a few questions about the place."

Watson has seamlessly filled Michael Gordon's boots at No.1 for the Roosters during the past month, as Robinson's side eyes another minor premiership after a horror 2016. The Roosters are still hopeful Gordon can play a part in their finals push.

It was the same position that Ivan Cleary wanted to groom the livewire to play for the Tigers, but Watson had his sights set on a five-eighth role.
He had already told Robinson he craved a permanent spot in the run-on team by 2018, but conceded the Tedesco, Luke Keary, Mitchell Pearce, Jake Friend spine was always going to be a mountain too high.
"The club has been so great to me for the last couple of years, but when we signed Tedesco [the writing was on the wall]," Watson said.
"When I re-signed last year, Robbo and I spoke about playing the utility role this year and I told him I was happy to play that this year, but I wanted to be in a starting spot next year. I didn't know what position that was going to be, but I wanted to work into a position I was starting next year.
"With the new signings and boys playing some great footy this year - Luke's playing really good, Mitch is playing really good and so is Friendy - it was hard for me to get into a position where I would start. Those players have five or six years left in their career. It's a long time for me.
"I thought the opportunity is here now for me to go. I had to take it if I see myself being a starting player in the future.

"At the Roosters here, I haven't trained pre-season in one position, and that's what I'm looking forward to the most, going up there and training in one spot and looking forward to be the best player I can be in that position."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny-Dowall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Cleary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footy Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Concord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aidan Guerra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Watson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown's NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tedesco</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skidsy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Friend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Keary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight Shaun Kenny-Dowall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guerra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Tedesco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
