<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417691437331017</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-03/eade-hopes-gaz-return-ends-conspiracy-talk</url>
  <title>Eade hopes Gaz return ends conspiracy talk</title>
  <content>
Gary Ablett and Steven May will be back for the Suns in Perth this week

GARY Ablett will play Fremantle on Saturday, and Gold Coast coach Rodney Eade hopes the champion's return from injury quietens the conspiracy theorists.

Ablett has missed the past two matches - and four of the past six - with hamstring problems but will board the Suns' flight to Perth on Thursday afternoon.

With the 33-year-old not ruling out retirement or again requesting a trade to Geelong at season's end, some have speculated in recent weeks he was opting to just play matches at Metricon Stadium.

"I think going to Perth puts to bed that theory that he just wants to play at home," Eade said. 

"I'm fairly confident, unless he gets a new injury, that he'll play (the last four matches)."

Eade said he hadn't spoken to Ablett - or any other player - about their futures, but believed the dual Brownlow medallist could maintain his excellent 2017 form for a few more seasons.

"You've got to judge what's his best form.

"He's 33, so his best form, when was that? When he was 29 or 30 years of age? 

"He's probably not going to play to that level, it's very hard for anybody, but the form he's displayed this year, if he has a reasonable run of injuries, you think he'd be able to maintain what he's been able to do this year.

"I think he'd be really high on our best and fairest, there's a fair chance he can win that. 

"His output, except for early in the season when he was criticised, has been very high."

Ablett is not the only big-name inclusion in a decimated Gold Coast team.

Co-captain Steven May will also return against the Dockers after missing a fortnight with a hamstring problem. 

The Suns need to make a fistful of changes, with Jarrod Witts (shoulder), Callum Ah Chee (shoulder), Brayden Fiorini (hamstring) and Ben Ainsworth (knee) all injured in last week's loss to Richmond.

Veteran Michael Rischitelli is being rested after playing three matches in his comeback from a knee reconstruction. 

Dan Currie will replace Witts, while Josh Schoenfeld, Trent McKenzie and Mitch Hallahan will also come into the extended squad. 

"We're going over there to win, that's our mindset," Eade said. 

"Fremantle are playing some kids and they've got some injuries as well.

"It's on their home deck, so they've got an advantage there, but from our point of view, we're going to win and that's the mindset we've got."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eade</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Ablett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-captain Steven May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ablett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Ah Chee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Hallahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Schoenfeld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Currie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Witt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metricon Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Witts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brayden Fiorini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Rischitelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Ainsworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
