<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418245488120732</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/art-and-design/melbourne-arts/joelpeter-witkin--the-controversial-us-photographer-who-uses-human-remains--opens-first-solo-australian-exhibition-20170802-gxo086.html</url>
  <title>Controversial US photographer Joel-Peter Witkin opens his first solo Australian exhibition</title>
  <content>
Joel-Peter Witkin lives on a ranch in Albuquerque, New Mexico, but his accent is still that of the kid raised in 1940s Brooklyn. He often describes a childhood moment in which a neighbour returning from the Pacific theatre crouched down to say hello. The young Witkin saw the hole left by the bullet that had miraculously passed through the man's neck. "I said, in child's talk, that I'd like to put my finger in the hole in your neck. I don't know. That may well be the beginning of my investigation into darkness and light."
Most of Witkin's photographs couldn't be published on this page. A cornucopia of fruit spills from the hollow of a dead dog's guts. A reclining nude absent-mindedly strokes the erect penis of a suspended horse. Two halves of a severed human head are locked in a kiss. All of these are rendered in the faded silvers and sepias of the earliest forms of photography, lending an otherworldly aspect to the (very) still lives and posed tableaux.Photo: Joe Armao
Witkin's work can seem grisly, obscene, perverse, abject. On the eve of his first Australia solo show, the 77-year-old artist says that some people who encounter his images unaware of his intent "presume that I'm some sort of ghoul and have no moral boundaries. The total opposite is my reality. My work is a form of sacred work. In fact I really think what I do is a form of contemporary religious iconography. I think that's very lacking in contemporary art because most of it is about escapism and not facing harder realities."
Witkin is a practicing Catholic, which informs his relationship with mortality. "I look forward to death as a Christian because my belief - and I love that belief - is that it's the beginning of everlasting life."A History of the White World New MexicoPhoto: Courtesy Baudoin LeBon
Does that mean the cadavers and body parts he photographs are just so much meat to him? "Oh no, no, no, that would be unkind. That would be tabloid photography," he says. "I see it as very reverential work ... If I could explain it I wouldn't do it, it would be over with, but it's a form of reverence. I see myself in them."
There are rules Witkin imposes on his work. "Medical ethics and morality play a big role in photographing death. I would never photograph human remains unless I knew from an authority that that person or part was unclaimed."

In recent years he has moved away from the use of deceased bodies - or parts of them - but in the past sourced materials through doctors and hospitals. He generally found more success doing so via Mexico than in the US.
Though his subjects can be discomfiting, their capturing via outmoded forms of photography - such as daguerreotypes and tintypes - removes them from time. "They're of a time that doesn't exist, so they become precious. They represent all the people that lived in that time and all the physical and internal realisations that existed."Imperfect ThirstPhoto: B. Huet-Tutti courtesy Baudoin LeBon
It's more than stylistic flourish. In the late 19th century, post-mortem photography was commonplace, with the bodies of recently deceased loved ones arranged for portraits that today might be considered macabre. These were often the only visual record of a lost family member.
They also speak to a culture in which death was not invisible. "In those times we were born and died at home. Now we're institutionalised. When we're in a hospital we're separated. We have visiting hours, whatever, and then usually we're not there when a person dies so we get that essential life information second- hand."La GiovanissimaPhoto: Courtesty Baudoin LeBon
Witkin's second wife died last year after six years of cancer. For the last six months he was her caregiver. "That was an experience of humility and devotion and love. That's the way I see all the photographs I make and participate in."
As confronting as his images can be, it only takes a short while speaking to Witkin to grasp how even the most abject subjects are for him opportunities for growth. Forging his way into uncharted territory is his role as a kind of "visual Columbus", in the same way an explorer might climb a mountain or sail an unknown sea. "That person's hope is to discover something that they can't fathom but hope to see. Because of that it's a very encouraging and loving and hopeful way to live."
I'd like to put my finger in the hole in your neck
Joel-Peter Witkin, as a child

Witkin accepts that many people will never get what he does or why. "I think this whole conversation can be compressed into one thing. It's that life is joyous and wonderful and it's meant for us to grow as individuals, as citizens, as human beings and spirits. The terrible thing is that we have a choice and usually the negative choice is the easy way. That's what we regret because we know we've harmed and we're not meant to harm. We're meant to heal and grow and share and if I had a knife at my neck or a gun to my head I'd say the same thing."
He's always said he's been an artist from the egg. His role - or rather his vocation, as he sees it - is to observe "what people do in life in order to elevate or diminish love." You can write that on his tombstone, he says, before a chuckle rasps its way out. "Although I'm not going to be buried. It's too expensive."
Joel-Peter Witkin - Photographs 1980-2016 is on at William Mora Galleries until August 25. Witkin will present a free artist talk at NGV International on August 5.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>B. Huet-Tutti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albuquerque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baudoin LeBon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Mora Galleries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Armao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ThirstPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Columbus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGV International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel-Peter Witkin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>History of the White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World New MexicoPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtesty Baudoin LeBon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Witkin</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La GiovanissimaPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
