<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418374337141716</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/breaking-news/nz-dollar-extends-decline/news-story/a78c607d843e4bc340b84d8150247766</url>
  <title>NZ dollar extends decline</title>
  <content>
The New Zealand dollar fell to a nine-day low on Thursday on growing expectations that the central bank will shift to an even more neutral stance at next Thursday's policy review and signal interest rates will be on hold for longer.
The kiwi traded at US73.99c at 5pm from 74.28c Wednesday,
In its forecasts, the central bank has signalled that it expects to begin lifting New Zealand's record-low interest rates in September 2019.
However, given weaker inflation data, softer housing and jobs data and the recent strength of the kiwi dollar "I think the market is leaning toward the idea that we might see the profile toward the end of the forecast period flattening out, ie a more neutral style policy stance coming through," said Robert Rennie, chief currency strategist at Westpac.
ANZ chief economist Cameron Bagrie said he expects the central bank to keep rates on hold at 1.75 per cent "with the tone of the accompanying statement, projections and press confidence to reinforce the RBNZ's cautious, watchful and neutral stance".
In fact, according to Mr Bagrie "a case could be made for moving to an easing bias," given core inflation has softened, housing market momentum has slowed, financial conditions have softened, the dollar has strengthened and "global inflation has rolled over".
Mr Rennie said the kiwi is also losing ground on the back of some US dollar stability as US President Donald Trump's administration appears to be shifting its focus onto a tax plan.
The kiwi traded at A93.23c from A93.33c, and at 4.9780 Chinese yuan from 4.9957 yuan.
The local currency traded at 55.96 British pence from 56.23 pence, ahead of the Bank of England's rate decision. The kiwi was down to 62.46 euro cents from 62.80c and traded at 81.90 yen from 82.34 yen.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US73.99</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Bagrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Rennie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBNZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bagrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rennie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
