<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418546135836180</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/2017/08/03/vince-colosimo-court-case/</url>
  <title>Vince Colosimo a court no-show, magistrate bemoans adjournments</title>
  <content>
Australian actor Vince Colosimo wasn't in court to hear a Melbourne magistrate's frustration over delays in his drug-driving case.
Mr Colosimo is charged with driving with drugs in his system and being behind the wheel while suspended after being stopped by police recently.
Mr Colosimo was charged with the offences in July this year.
The Underbelly actor's matter was mentioned by the Melbourne Magistrates' Court on Thursday but Mr Colosimo was not required to appear in person and was interstate.
The 50-year-old's case was adjourned a month ago and on Thursday defence counsel Tara Hartnett asked for it to be adjourned again, saying Mr Colosimo wanted to appear in person.
Magistrate Ross Maxted expressed frustration over the delay.
"That's the problem with this court, there are too many adjournments," Mr Maxted said, according to .
"This is a relatively straightforward matter. I am wondering why it is so complex."
The case was adjourned to November 3.
In January this year Mr Colosimo plead guilty to one charge of possessing methamphetamine and was placed on a 12-month good behaviour bond without conviction.
He called the charge "a wake-up call" at the time.
Mr Colosimo, who has two children, had been dating actress Diana Glenn for eight years but unconfirmed reports from July this year suggested the pair had split.
In 2014, Mr Colosimo was fined $1000 after he was caught driving while suspended.
- with AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana Glenn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Ross Maxted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Maxted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Colosimo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Colosimo</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Hartnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
