<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418460236488991</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/malcolm-turnbull-calls-crisis-meeting-on-samesex-marriage-20170802-gxo82b</url>
  <title>Turnbull calls crisis meeting on same-sex marriage </title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull has called a special meeting of federal Liberal MPs on Monday afternoon to try and end the crippling dispute over same-sex marriage before Parliament resumes the next day.
MPs will be free to say their piece and, if they agree, hold a secret ballot on which policy option to purse to determine exactly where the numbers stand.
The outcome of that meeting will then be put to a joint party room meeting the next day, which includes the National Party.
Mr Turnbull had party whips summon MPs to the meeting as the issue continued to spiral out of control on Thursday.

Rebel MPs threatening to cross the floor to force a debate and a vote on a private member's bill to legalise same-sex marriage have had their preselections threatened and the whole saga is eroding Mr Turnbull's leadership.

Senior sources say even if this issue can be settled and the moderates placated, the party will plunge headlong into another split, this time over energy and with the conservatives leading the revolt.
Tony Abbott is marshalling forces to fight plans to introduce a clean energy target, as recommended by Chief Scientist Alan Finkel, dismissing such policy this week as "green theology".
 The Coalition's policy on same-sex marriage is that there be no parliamentary vote without a plebiscite first.
 MPs Warren Entsch, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans, Jason Wood, Trent Zimmerman and Senator Dean Smith say the obligation towards a plebiscite was discharged after the Senate blocked legislation for a February plebiscite.

They want the issue resolved. Their push has split the party. It is likely that on Monday, the Liberals will consider a plan in which the government tries again top pass legislation to establish a plebiscite. In the likely event that is rejected again, the government will hold a non-compulsory postal plebiscite which it believes does not require legislation.
Both sides of the debate have already indicated they will not respect the outcome of a postal ballot, given it would not be representative of the population's view due to the lack of proper methodology.
But sources say it would satisfy the election promise that there would be no vote in Parliament without the people being given a say first.
more to come...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Scientist Alan Finkel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
