<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418249783088129</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/new-york-slice-has-best-announcement-toowoomba/3205392/</url>
  <title>New York Slice has best news for Toowoomba</title>
  <content>
IT IS one of the most popular pizza franchises in the state and it's coming to Toowoomba. 

New York Slice is famous for its extra large serving sizes. There are already five stores at the Sunshine Coast and Brisbane, with the business now expanding to the Garden City.

New York Slice is expected to open late August, operating out of a site fronting The Chronicle Arcade at 189 Margaret St.

Its slices are made in the traditional New York style - thin base and lightly topped in tasty flavours.

The slices are twice the size of a regular pizza slice, making them a meal in themselves.

Diners can order a favourite from the menu or build their own pizza and have it within minutes.

Franchise Retail Brands director Sean Corbin said New York Slice would deliver a great value, high quality pizza to Toowoomba.

"It is well-known for its traditional American offering and point of difference in the Australian pizza market - providing big, bold slices with a thin base, and honest New York style toppings," he said.

"New York Slice pizza brings quality ingredients, a Neapolitan dough, rolled fresh in-store, traditional Italian tomato sauce, and a low price point to match.

"By bringing New York Slice into the Franchise Retail Brands group, we are able to leverage supply chain agreements with multiple suppliers to further improve the excellence of our ingredients, meanwhile reducing the price to consumers.

"We've also been able to expand our footprint and open a store in Toowoomba, which we are particularly excited about."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Corbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retail Brands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neapolitan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franchise Retail Brands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Slice</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chronicle Arcade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garden City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
