<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417815991384366</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/sorry-gen-ys-we-cant-all-be-exceptional-leaders-of-tomorrow-20170802-gxnnhj.html</url>
  <title>Sorry, Gen Ys, we can't all be exceptional 'leaders of tomorrow'</title>
  <content>
Shockingly, I seem to have reached my thirties without becoming a household name (if you don't count the other Jill Murphy, famous author). This has prompted me to wonder: is this it?
From childhood, Gen Ys have been encouraged to believe that we can be anything we want to be. Our schools and universities assured us that we would become "the leaders of tomorrow" in our chosen careers, going on to be successful and/or famous. But what if we end up being neither?Photo: Thinkstock
I like my work - I'm a counsellor - but I'm not sure that it's the best fit for me. I have a vague yet persistent feeling that I should be doing something else; that I must have latent talents just waiting to flourish, like a nascent flower preparing to bloom. This isn't a unique experience. Many of my friends are in jobs that they don't particularly like, but can't think what exactly they want to do instead. We feel like our calling is just waiting around the corner - if only we knew which corner. We joke about it. "I don't have a dream!" we cry, or "I don't know what I want to be when I grow up!"
Perhaps we Gen Ys are just ungrateful, not content with what we have. We're certainly stereotyped as job-hoppers, always on the hunt for something better. The myriad occupations these days contributes to this endless search. At school, we thought of careers in terms of teachers, doctors, tradies ... We could not have conceived that some of us might become social media managers or events planners (I'm fairly certain the events planning in the town I grew up in was competently executed by the selfless ladies in the CWA).
Online journalism doesn't help our feeling that there must be something better out there. We're inundated with articles entitled things like "Ten things you should look for in an employer", or "Five ways to find a job you love". The media also constantly highlight people who have done something extraordinary, like write a bestseller in 10 minutes or build a penthouse out of paperclips, and they make it sound like we can do it too. These exceptional people inevitably write memoirs or self-help books destined to make the rest of us feel bad for our continuing mediocrity ("I used to be like you: stuck in a dead-end job, miserable and unhealthy, until one day...").
All of this contributes to Gen Ys feeling like we should be AWESOME. We're not going to be ordinary, and put up with nine-to-five drudgery that we're not passionate about.

I didn't want to be the one to break the bad news to my contemporaries, but here it is: we won't all have brilliant careers. We can't all be successful, or famous, or rich, or even love our work. For someone to be exceptional, they have to actually be the exception; we can't all do it.
I ran into one of my high school teachers recently, who eagerly asked me what I was up to these days. I told him that I'm a counsellor, and his disappointment was palpable (I could vent my rage here about why choosing to help vulnerable people is not seen as "successful" in our society, but that's another issue). I don't want to pass on this weight of expectation to my children, nor my sense of unrealised potential. Obviously, I don't want to stamp on their hopes and dreams if they tell me they plan to cure cancer - incidentally, when I was five I went around saying I wanted to be a bushranger, and still no one told me it wasn't a good idea - but I would like them to understand that while they may have amazing careers and love their work, equally they may have boring desk jobs and never really be sure what they want to be. They may train to be barristers but prefer to be baristas. They may, like me, discover that they are not ambitious, preferring to work to live rather than live to work.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

While I was pondering this, my three-year-old daughter told me that she was "going to work" in her toy car. "Oh," I said with interest, "What kind of work do you do?" To which she replied excitedly: "I clean toilets, Mummy! I make them all lovely and clean!" Which is, I think, an admirable and achievable aspiration. I don't care whether she's completely ordinary or indeed extraordinary; I just want her to feel good about it, free from a niggling suspicion that she should be doing something else.
Jill Murphy is a writer and family counsellor.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thinkstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Ys</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
