<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417949135372392</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/tycoon-tara-heading-for-stud-as-tony-krushka-pays-tribute-to-peter-and-paul-snowden-before-missile-stakes-defence-20170803-gxoezw.html</url>
  <title>Tycoon Tara heading for stud as Tony Krushka pays tribute to Peter and Paul Snowden before Missile Stakes defence</title>
  <content>
Tony Krushka had to wait 20 years to win as an owner-breeder the group 1 he should have won as a trainer. He was even told so by an itchy-fingered apprentice who now admits he counted a little too quickly.

Up Next

Hooper steps up as Wallabies skipper

01:13

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Neymar leaving Barca, Spanish superclub confirms

Brazilian striker Neymar has informed Barcelona he plans to leave the club. The soccer superstar is expected to sign with Paris Saint-Germain (PSG) in a world record deal worth nearly $750 million.

"I thought I'd won one as a trainer and I got pipped on the line," Krushka laughed about Haltemann getting nabbed in the shadows of the post in a 1998 major at Caulfield at huge odds.
"He shot clear four or five lengths in the straight and [Luke] Currie rode it. He said to me a while back, 'If I knew what I knew now I would have won that race'. He was only an apprentice then and he was heading for home."

It's lucky Kerrin McEvoy didn't make the same mistake twice, by his own admission not being at his best on Tycoon Tara during the winter until her Tatt's Tiara win.
Which is what Krushka kept telling to Peter Snowden, the reluctant trainer of perhaps the most improved mare in Sydney racing in the last 12 months. The Warrnambool small-time trainer and breeder wanted another shot at stakes level. Snowden was thinking stud.

It's about the only time the trainer and his son Paul may have slightly erred with the mare, which returns to defend her Missile Stakes crown as a last-start group 1 winner and a year on from joining Sydney's powerhouse stable.
"Peter and I had discussions and every time we had a discussion I would tell him all the positives - and he would tell me all the negatives [about racing on]," Krushka said. "I could find excuses with every run and reasons why we weren't in the finish leading up into the [Tatt's Tiara].Photo: AAP
"The Snowdens have taken her to the next level. I always knew she had a lot of ability, but she needed someone with that expertise to get her to the next level. She deserved a chance with someone like that."
So Krushka begged. And the Snowdens relented. Since then Tycoon Tara has won a Missile Stakes, Show County, Golden Pendant and crowned her career in the Tiara to become one of the most valuable broodmares in waiting.
Krushka promises the third foal of Mosstara is going to stud this spring and will be covered by Zoustar. But how good would a farewell win in the Missile Stakes be?
"[Peter] is just such a quiet, unassuming gentleman and he would spend a lot of time looking at his horses," Krushka said. "Condition is the most important thing. When she went up there he said, 'Look, I can't race the horse in the condition it's in'.
"He took that time and even before she ran [first-up for the Snowdens in last year's Missile Stakes] I looked at her and she had never looked better in her life."
Tycoon Tara will join another ageing star, That's A Good Idea, in a two-pronged Snowden attack on the Missile Stakes which is headed by multiple group 1 winner Le Romain. Sentiment will rest with Tycoon Tara, who figures to be chasing a hot speed in a small but zippy field.
"It's always a positive going into these spring races [having residual fitness from winter]," Krushka said.
"If you've got a horse that has had a few runs in the winter you've just got that edge on the horses that have just been trialling. She's a very clean-winded horse and once they get fit they can maintain that fitness," he said.
On That's A Good Idea, Paul Snowden said: "The horse is going really well, we can't fault him. Obviously we don't want the rain and he's not getting younger. It's just a question of whether he's sharp enough now and he may be better over seven [furlongs] than six [furlongs] as they all lose that dash eventually."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Krushka</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Romain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoustar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tycoon Tara</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haltemann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Idea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snowden</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Snowden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mosstara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Pendant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Krushka</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Snowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatt's Tiara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
