<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418241193153404</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/police-target-troublemakers-in-frankstons-transit-precinct-for-operation-rickman/news-story/c346b1b5ca71b1f22c05571d5fe782d7</url>
  <title>Police swoop on troublemakers at train station</title>
  <content>
SEVENTEEN people were arrested, a missing person found and warrants for more than $130,000 in outstanding fines issued during a swoop on the train station on Tuesday.
Police and the sheriff's department targeted the transit precinct as part of Operation Rickman; a crackdown aimed at deterring troublemakers.
Police issued 92 infringement notices, arrested two people for carrying weapons and 15 for outstanding warrants.
They also found a missing person.
Authorised Officers from the Metro Multi Modal unit issued 75 infringements while Sheriff's officers executed 311 warrants totalling in just under $130,000 in outstanding fines.
Local Area Commander for South Transit Safety Division, Inspector Martin Hardy, said he was rapt with the outcome.
"Operation Rickman is just one great example of law enforcement agencies working together to ensure community safety and security on the public transport system," he said.
Trader Lucky Ferraro, who runs Lucky's Deli, said the operation had made a huge difference.
"The elderly and young people feel more confident with the increased police presence," he said.
Frankston Labor MP Paul Edbrooke said the operation sent a clear message to those who engaged in anti social behaviour.
"I have been working with local police command to ensure that policing operations like this send a clear message that we encourage people who abide by the law to visit and enjoy our beautiful city," he said.
"But if you are here for the wrong reasons you are simply not welcome."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Transit Safety Division</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucky Ferraro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Area Commander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Martin Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rickman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Labor MP Paul Edbrooke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation Rickman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro Multi Modal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LUCKY'S DELI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
