<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418421581782733</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/paint-fumes-force-adelaide-state-library-evacuation/8771136</url>
  <title>SA State Library evacuated due to paint fumes, two taken to Royal Adelaide Hospital</title>
  <content>
South Australia's State Library, located in the Adelaide CBD, was evacuated and two people taken to hospital after paint fumes drifted into the building during renovations.
Dozens of people were evacuated from the library building in North Terrace about 12:30pm.
Metropolitan Fire Service (MFS) and SA Ambulance crews attended the scene, and the main part of the library was later reopened.
"Apparently there was some sort of chemical scare," ABC Radio Adelaide presenter Peter Goers, who was heading to a football exhibition at the library, said.
"There's a smell of ammonia in the building, apparently, I'm told by people leaving."
SA Ambulance confirmed two people were taken to the Royal Adelaide Hospital in a stable condition.

Part of the building is being renovated, with extensive scaffolding in place around its Mortlock wing.
Library representative Beverly Scott said workers had painted window frames during the morning.
"[That] caused some fumes ... to enter the building in the first instance into the Mortlock chamber," she said.
Ms Scott said a security guard was among those affected by fumes.
"Visitors to the library ... say they were duly treated by the ambulance people," she said.
The Mortlock wing remains closed, but Ms Scott said people had now been able to return to the Spence wing, which is the main part of the library complex.
She said MFS was working to rid the building of paint fumes.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Ambulance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan Fire Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA State Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mortlock</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Goers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia's State Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beverly Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Terrace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
