<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418245488120721</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/how-do-councils-get-lord-mayor-status/8771060</url>
  <title>What is the difference between mayor and lord mayor? It's a right royal subject of debate</title>
  <content>
There's no extra chains, robes and just a little pomp and circumstance, but the title of lord mayor, as opposed to mayor, is a sought-after status though one not frequently bestowed.
There are only four councils in New South Wales with a lord mayor - City of Sydney, Parramatta, Newcastle and Wollongong.
Now Liverpool Council has applied to the Premier for the honorary title change.
"Liverpool is the fourth oldest city in Australia, and all three older cities including Parramatta and Hobart have a lord mayor," council chief executive Kiersten Fishburn told .
"With our rapid growth and change, with the release of a Western Sydney airport in our local government area, universities coming to town, new release areas and the excitement of being in Liverpool right now, it's really timely to make an application for a lord mayor."

What does it mean?

Being lord mayor of a local government area does not come with any extra powers or privileges.
The honour can only be granted by the monarch, via the governor's office, as a result of a significant event.
One caller to ABC Radio Sydney thought the status was bestowed only if the city housed a cathedral.
The Office of Local Government advises that: "Although there is no specific qualifications required for such bestowal, it appears that the local government area would need to have a very special significance in the history and geography of the state."
In 1988 for example, Elizabeth II elevated the position of mayor to lord mayor at Parramatta Council to mark its bicentenary.

In a letter signed by then premier Nick Greiner, the following message from the Queen via the governor said:
"It is an established practice, that a mayor of an important city is raised to a lord mayor only to mark some very special national or local event.
"The City of Parramatta's own bicentennial in Australia's bicentennial year, seems to meet that criterion most aptly ... "
'Good for public perception'

Ms Fishburn said having a lord mayor was important for the area and acknowledged that the process could take some years.
Wollongong Council first applied for lord mayor status in 1951, and despite subsequent applications the honour was only granted in 1969.
"In practical terms, it doesn't really change anything, it's an honorary title," Ms Fishburn said.
"But in terms of public perception, when people hear that a city has a lord mayor, they do perceive it as a more significant place. They see it as a higher status.
"We think that's important as we negotiate on the global stage with the airport coming in.
"It's important for a community with people immigrating, and a lot of people who make Liverpool their first home in Australia, I think it gives it a little bit more stature to the city for them."
Former Liverpool mayor Nick Mannoun, however, has been scathing about the application, posting on Facebook that the council was "wasting their time".
"What do you think is important for the mayor and council to be discussing and fixing? Better train services, increased funding for CCTV, better parks, more jobs?" he wrote.
"Instead they are wasting their time (and your money) discussing the importance of changing the tittle of the mayor to lord mayor."

External Link:

Nick Mannoun FB post

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Local</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fishburn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Greiner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Mannoun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Mannoun FB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiersten Fishburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
