<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418636330151038</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/news-and-current-affairs/laurie-oakes-retires-and-tv-news-loses-a-trusted-voice-20170803-gxomta.html</url>
  <title>Laurie Oakes retires, and TV news loses a trusted voice</title>
  <content>
It's a hoary old cliche: they don't make them like they used to.
And yet, in the case of Laurie Oakes, the veteran political journalist, and wiser mind than most, it is true.

Up Next

Charges to be laid over Sydney terrorist plane plot

01:17

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Laurie Oakes announces retirement

Bringing to an end a 50-year career, an "absolute giant" of journalism, Laurie Oakes, announces his retirement. Video courtesy Nine News.

Oakes, 73, announced his retirement today and Australia's political life, and the fabric of its journalistic culture, will be lessened by losing him.
To the untrained eye, Oakes leaves behind a world of television news which is in disarray, under siege from budget cuts, a news cycle which resembles a mouse wheel and the now ubiquitous groan of "fake news".

But within that maelstrom the value of trust has never been greater.
And those, such as the legendary Oakes, who are able to engender it in an ever more sceptical audience, never more necessary.

As young reporter in the 1960s, Oakes was christened in a journalism world which would both baffle and amuse its young practitioners today: one of rotary dial telephones, manual typewriters and telex machines.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

There were no mobile phones, no internet, no Google.Photo: Andrew Campbell
You simply had a notepad, a pen, a tape recorder and whatever chutzpah you could muster in pursuit of a story.
If you didn't have the office clips library - a musty and arcane old vault of newspaper clippings and bound volumes - handy, you had to rely on your memory.Photo: Graham Tidy
Remember that?
It was in that world, and armed with what seems now to be so little, that Oakes flourished: the Melbourne Sun's Canberra bureau chief by 25, and not long after a rising star in television, working for Ten, Seven and finally Nine where he is considered "the king" of the Canberra press gallery.Photo: Fairfax Media
In person he cuts a formidable figure, and in cultural presence he curiously straddles two worlds, illustrated by nothing more perfectly than the Gold Walkley and TV Week Gold Logie which bear his name.
In the last decade, as the smoke and mirrors of politics have given way to a more calculated art of deception, it has been Oakes' cut-to-the-bone analysis which has helped keep the bastards honest.
In interviews he takes no prisoners, a delicious style which has seen him at odds with prime ministers, senior political figures and indeed presenters from his own network.
He is the man who stuck it to former prime minister Julia Gillard with the words "doesn't this convince people that you're all just the same?"
And to another former prime minister, Paul Keating, "aren't you concerned that the government looks sloppy?". (Keating replied that he was.)
The journalistic landscape Oakes leaves today is one of multiple rolling news channels, where digital crawls have replaced telex machines and for every talking head you once saw, there are now dozens, if not hundreds, more.
But if we're honest, in some ways little will change.
Nature abhors a vacuum and the absence of Oakes' voice will give rise to others. As it should.
But he will be missed. For his skill. For his wisdom. And for his indefatigable determination to hold truth to power.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Photos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Keating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Tidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV Week Gold Logie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakes, 73</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakes</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Sun's Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Walkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
