<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418206833414296</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/federal-politics/political-opinion/a-political-trick-as-old-as-it-is-transparent-when-in-political-trouble-blame-the-media-20170803-gxoaom.html</url>
  <title>A trick as old as it is transparent: when in political trouble, blame the media</title>
  <content>
When Malcolm Turnbull was asked about Donald Trump's attacks on the media earlier this year, he offered the US President some advice.
"A very great politician, Winston Churchill, once said that politicians complaining about the newspapers is like a sailor complaining about the sea," Turnbull said.
"There is not much point. That is the media we live with and we have to get our message across and we thank you all in the media for your kind attention."
The Churchill quote is one of Turnbull's favourite phrases to trot out, outdone only perhaps by describing something as a "penetrating glimpse of the obvious".  

This week he threw his own words of wisdom overboard.
At a press conference in Perth, Turnbull grew exasperated as reporters peppered him with questions about same-sex marriage rather than the government's internship program.

"Can I tell you - I've been in WA now for a couple of days, I have met with hundreds of people from the Mindarie pub to community meetings to schools to the train down to Mandurah - only one person has raised this issue with me," he said. 

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"So this is an issue of enormous interest to journalists.Photo: Andrew Meares
"I think there are a lot of parents watching us today who will be really wondering why it is that not one of the journalists here has got any interest in a program that is going to give up to 120,000 young people on welfare an internship and a job.
"They'll be really wondering, really wondering, what the priorities are of our friends in the media here versus the government."
It's a trick as old as time and as transparent as cling film: when in political trouble, blame the media.
What the PM left out is that at least five MPs have spoken out against the government's plebiscite policy and argued for a free vote. Liberal senator Dean Smith, who has announced he is drafting a private members' bill to legislate same-sex marriage, wrote two op-eds on the issue this week. Warren Entsch wrote of his own; Trevor Evans and Tim Wilson have given multiple interviews. They have been upfront about their plans to overturn party when the Liberal party room meets next week. 
On the other side of the debate, Peter Dutton went on radio and television to argue for a postal plebiscite. Craig Kelly called for the government to test the numbers again in the Senate. Tony Abbott warned of a "dramatic loss of discipline inside the government" if MPs break ranks.
Despite this, Liberal MPs have valiantly tried to accuse reporters of making the whole thing up.
"The media's not interested in issues that other Australians are interested in," complained Liberal MP Jason Falinski.
​"How is this news? Seriously!" 
Colleague Craig Laundy said the issue had "grown a life of its own according to the media".
"I, to be brutally honest, think that it's a media beat up," he said. 
Entsch, one of the MPs leading the charge for a free vote, accused journalists of indulging in rampant speculation. 
"There is no evidence what we're going to do, you're just looking into a crystal ball," he said.
Days after admitting he was "tormented" over the issue, gay MP Tim Wilson said he wouldn't discuss it, leading Sky News host Peter van Onselen to shut down their interview after just 30 seconds.
There's no doubt that, for most Australians, same-sex marriage is a relatively minor issue (new research out today shows six per cent of voters rate it as a major concern). And it's true journalists are fascinated by it. This is a story packed with all the key ingredients: conflict, a cast of colourful characters and a cut-through clarity more technical policy issues lack. 
The problem for Turnbull is that many of his MPs are just as interested in it. That's why they have been outlining their case, making threats and digging up old quotes to embarrass their opponents. The Coalition is divided and a reckoning is coming. Whichever way it goes, a good chunk of his colleagues is going to be angry about the outcome. 
The Prime Minister may prefer us not to notice, but this is all really happening, much of it in public view. 
Just because a story is sexy doesn't make it fake and blaming the media won't save you if your ship is going under. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winston Churchill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Laundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Onselen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Churchill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandurah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mindarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Jason Falinski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
