<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417429444321637</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/03/canada-opens-stadium-asylum-seekers-us</url>
  <title>Canada opens stadium for asylum seekers from the US</title>
  <content>
Quebec has opened its Olympic stadium to house asylum seekers after a growing influx in refugee claimants coming from the US.

36 MINS AGO  UPDATED 9 MINS AGO

Canadian health authorities and aid workers are using an Olympic stadium to shelter  as a growing number of people walk into the country from the US.

The Quebec Red Cross and local health authorities opened Montreal's Olympic Stadium on Wednesday to  brought in by bus after having crossed the US border, Red Cross spokeswoman Stephanie Picard said.

MORE NEWS:

The city is seeing a growing influx in refugee claimants coming from the US and is scrambling to house them all. The Red Cross is assisting with beds and providing bedding and other personal-care items.

Montreal's health authority would not provide exact numbers on how many people are being housed in the stadium, built for the 1976 Olympics and which now serves as an event space.

More than 4300 people have walked across the US border into Canada this year seeking refugee status. The vast majority of them come to Quebec, according to figures from the federal government.

Many  who spoke to Reuters say they left the US fearing President Donald Trump's immigration crackdown.

People who cross the border illegally to file refugee claims are apprehended and held for questioning by both police and border officials before being allowed to file claims and live in Canada while their application is processed.

Montreal Mayor Denis Coderre welcomed the  on Twitter on Wednesday afternoon, saying 2500 people had come in July alone. He said on Twitter that providing for the new arrivals is a "humanitarian gesture".

Selon mes sources: 2500 nouveaux arrivants en juillet (refugies frontiere americaine) il y aurait presentement 500 a St-Bernard de Lacolle
- DenisCoderre (@DenisCoderre)

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 9 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DenisCoderre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Picard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lacolle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quebec</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montreal's Olympic Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quebec Red Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Bernard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montreal Mayor Denis Coderre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Cross</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montreal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
