<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418627740216200</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/breaking-news/abe-reshuffles-cabinet-as-support-dips/news-story/fc358be0857b0cbf38a461247c6a2e07</url>
  <title>Abe reshuffles cabinet as support dips</title>
  <content>
Japan's Prime Minister Shinzo Abe has reshuffled his cabinet, opting for seasoned party veterans to help restore his battered popularity.
Chief Cabinet Secretary Yoshihide Suga, who was among many ministers to be reappointed or taking up posts they have held before, announced the new line-up on Thursday.
Abe's approval ratings have suffered from a spate of scandals over alleged cronyism and other abuses and objections to the ruling Liberal Democratic Party's tendency to force unpopular legislation through parliament.
The shake-up reflects Abe's recognition that despite his party's overwhelming majority in parliament, his own once seemingly invincible position after more than four years in office might be imperilled.
The newly named ministers included many cabinet veterans, including Itsunori Onodera, a former defence minister who again was named to that post.
Last week, Abe's protege Tomomi Inada stepped down as defence minister after the disclosure the ministry hid information about risks faced by Japanese peacekeeping troops in South Sudan.
Abe also chose several popular MPs known to differ from him on key issues such as nuclear power and revision of Japan's pacifist constitution.
The new foreign minister, Taro Kono, 54, is known to be liberal-leaning and has opposed nuclear energy, though he toned down his stance while serving as reform minister in an earlier Abe cabinet.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Cabinet Secretary Yoshihide Suga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Democratic Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sudan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taro Kono, 54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Itsunori Onodera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomomi Inada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Prime Minister Shinzo Abe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abe</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
