<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418460236489004</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/sport/cricket/cricket-australia-and-players-sign-peace-deal-to-end-pay-war-20170803-gxokfe.html</url>
  <title>Cricket Australia and players sign peace deal to end pay war</title>
  <content>
Australian cricket's long and ugly pay dispute is finally over, with Cricket Australia and the players finally agreeing on a peace deal on Thursday afternoon.
After 10 months of butting heads, the sports' worst industrial crisis in 40 years had accelerated towards a resolution following a threat last week by CA chief executive James Sutherland to have the matter ruled upon by independent arbitration.

Up Next

Neymar leaving Barca, Spanish superclub confirms

00:42

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Why are Australia's cricketers in a pay dispute?

Australia's cricketers are in a pay dispute with Cricket Australia, but why?

The negotiating teams from CA and the Australian Cricketers' Association had worked long inTO the night throughout this week to settle their remaining differences in the drafting of a heads of agreement, as the troubled talks threatened to go off course again.
They were at last able to find middle ground on Thursday. An announcement in a media conference is expected in Melbourne at 4.30pm on Thursday.Photo: Daniel Pockett
The deal confirms an agreement for all male and female cricketers for the first time in Australia and the biggest pay rise in the history of women's sport in Australia.
The parties have agreed on a modified revenue-sharing model that gives players 30 per cent of agreed revenue, consisting of 27.5 per cent of forecast revenue streams.

All male and female players will then receive a 27.5 per cent share of revenue that goes beyond forecasts.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In addition, a forecast amount of $25 million will go directly to grassroots investment via the ACA-CA grassroots investment fund. That contribution will be matched by the estimated $25 million of CA savings on their current administration over the next five years. The fund is to be run by a committee involving CA and the ACA.
The players will also be back-paid to July.
The ACA will keep The Cricketers' Brand, which it established during the pay dispute, as its commercial entity.
The long-awaited deal on the game's next five-year memorandum of understanding between the governing body and players arrives just in the nick of time to save this month's two-Test series between Australia and Bangladesh. It also ensures that this summer's Ashes series in Australia will go ahead, as will an Australian limited-overs tour of India in October.
Steve Smith's squad is due to assemble in Darwin for a training camp next week before taking off to the subcontinent for a series that they were refusing to play in had a new MOU not been agreed to.
The members of the Test team are among 230 players who have been out of contract and not paid since the last agreement elapsed on June 30.
​MORE TO COME
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricketers Brand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA-CA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
