<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418636330151060</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/cops-taken-off-vic-shooting-investigation/news-story/12ef2f5762f2dc7efbfb123883151e78</url>
  <title>Cops taken off Vic shooting investigation</title>
  <content>
Two officers have been ordered off the case of a police shooting at a Melbourne fancy dress swingers party amid conflict-of-interest concerns.
Inflation nightclub owner Martha Tsamis has also called on police to release recordings of triple-0 calls made by people concerned about a toy gun that sparked the raid during which the shootings occurred.
Officers stormed the nightclub at 3am on July 8 and shot a man and a woman after claiming they received a call about the gun, which was part of the man's costume as The Joker.
"We would like Victoria Police to immediately release the so-called 'multiple' 000 call recordings so we can all hear the mystery callers who were concerned about the toy gun," Ms Tsamis posted on Facebook on Thursday.
She further confirmed her seven-year relationship with senior Victoria Police Detective Inspector Phil Harrison, adding that top brass have always known about the couple.
"News of the relationship has become more widespread since an individual police officer was taken off the investigation into the police shooting," she said.
"He is the second officer to have been prevented from working on the investigation because of a possible conflict of interest."
Victoria Police said it had received a complaint about a perceived conflict of interest and has ensured it will "not impact on the investigation".
The news comes after a perceived conflict of interest saw Assistant Commissioner Brett Guerin, head of Professional Standards Command, separated from the investigation.
Ms Tsamis launched legal action against police a week before the shooting over comments Mr Guerin made about the venue, where he called it a "honey pot" for drug dealers.
She slammed media reports about her relationship with Insp Harrison as anonymous leaks designed to smear her.
"This is a story that is designed to harm and distract from the actual story - why police shot two innocent people," she said.
Shooting victims Dale Ewins and Zita Sukys have also launched legal action against Victoria Police.
Mr Ewins, dressed as The Joker and carrying a fake gun, and Ms Sukys, as Suicide Squad character Harley Quinn, will seek damages for pain and suffering, medical expenses and loss of earnings.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insp Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police Detective Inspector Phil Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sukys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Ewins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zita Sukys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martha Tsamis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley Quinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Guerin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suicide Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professional Standards Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ewins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Tsamis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Commissioner Brett Guerin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
