<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417446624191441</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/oneplus-is-coming-to-australia/</url>
  <title>OnePlus Is Coming To Australia</title>
  <content>
Image: OnePlus
OnePlus, the phone brand that takes on the very best of Apple and Samsung at aggressively low prices, is launching its phones into Australia later this month.

In a statement to Gizmodo, OnePlus confirmed its imminent local launch: "Since the beginning of our company, we have seen a lot of interest in OnePlus in Australia. It has been a long-time goal of ours to bring OnePlus to our Australian fans. Therefore, we are excited to announce that we will be bringing the OnePlus 5 to Australia through a soft launch program later this month."

Talking to its traditionally enthusiastic fans on its forum, OnePlus founder Carl Pei said that it wanted users to help it refine its supply and shipping processes: "We're finally taking steps to enter Australia, and we'd like to enlist your help. Later this month, we're bringing the OnePlus 5 to Australia through a soft launch program. The goal will be to test our product and supply chain, and we'll be opening up a limited trial run for sales."

[]

The OnePlus employees seemed a little annoyed when I asked how they felt about people comparing its new device to an iPhone. Sure, both phones feature dual camera designs. Yes, the OnePlus 5 has curves that look a lot like an Apple product. Ugh, fine, it's a really good phone, too. What's the big deal?

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OnePlus Is Coming To Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OnePlus 5</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OnePlus</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gizmodo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carl Pei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
