<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418593380477297</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/teams/collingwood/collingwood-coach-nathan-buckley-keen-to-continue-playing-ben-reid-forward-alongside-darcy-moore/news-story/a01de4020bae1fab7fa8a1c3f342e352</url>
  <title>Reid settling into Magpies attack</title>
  <content>
BEN Reid could lose the "swingman" moniker next season with Collingwood coach Nathan Buckley excited about the All-Australian defender settling up forward.
Reid, 28, has booted eight goals in the past four games, including two in the draw with Adelaide last week alongside young gun Darcy Moore.
"There's probably an opportunity to see Reidy and Darcy (Moore) play some football together in front of the ball, so that hasn't been something consistent," Buckley said.
'COMPLETE RUBBISH':
FINALS QUARTERS:
"Darcy, Ben Reid, Jamie Elliott and Alex Fasolo have only played two or three games together for the whole season, to hopefully get a good three or four week block potentially gives us a bit of a look at what our forward line might look like (next year).
"We want that to settle and see how effective it might be with an eye to the future."
Reid only had six disposals last week but his impact was "profound", laying six tackles for the game including five inside 50.
Reid was sensationally dropped - in favour of boom mature-aged recruit Lynden Dunn - for a game last month after starting the year in defence.
"He's looked really good the last couple of weeks since coming back, it looks like he's got a bit more spring in the step," Buckley said.
"You'd love 20 touches and six goals every week but all we expect is for guys to play role and Reidy's influence was profound."
A reinvented Reid could ease the burden on the Magpies at the trade and draft table, with speed and key position talent the No.1 priority.
The club has been linked to uncontracted Adelaide young guns Jake Lever and Mitch McGovern, but Buckley is mindful of keeping player movement "behind the curtain".
"I do feel it's disrespectful to be talking about other clubs during the year, we probably learned a little bit from the Lin Jong situation last year," Buckley said.
"It's not good for the player themselves (and) the clubs that are involved to get caught in that so we'll let that happen behind the cloak."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lin Jong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Fasolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynden Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reidy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Reid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
