<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417992085046086</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/entertainment/irishaustralian-singer-damien-leith-brings-personal-stories-to-cairns-stage/news-story/b091d874f50a6259314683bef4d95ced</url>
  <title>Damien's moving stories</title>
  <content>
YOU'D be forgiven for thinking Damien Leith's tour The Parting Glass: An Irish Journey was a regular tour with original songs, a few covers and perhaps some clapping along.
But if you think that, you're wrong. The performance is actually a rewrite of a play combined with Leith's favourite Irish tunes to result in a pseudo-musical that pays homage to the emotional journey migrants make.
"I wrote a play about a father in a pub talking about his song," Leith explains.
"I thought I'd combine it with a live band, so in between his chats the band goes into rousing Irish songs."
He says it's a singular concert experience.
"It's like if the audience was transported to Ireland for two and a half hours," he says.
"I wanted to reflect my own experiences leaving home and travelling to Australia.
"I think the emotions of excitement and anxiety and confusion are things everyone can relate to.
"Australia has a long history with immigration and people leaving their homes to come to Australia.
"Those stories last through families."
He says the theory rings true, as this is the concert that people continuously write to him about.
"People are usually surprised when they walk in because they think it's going to be a normal concert," he says. "But when people leave it seems to stay with them."
As for his favourite show of the song, Leith says he can't go past the classic Danny Boy.
Damien Leith will bring The Parting Glass: An Irish Journey to Brothers Leagues Club Cairns on Sunday, November 26. Tickets are available online at www.brotherscairns.com.au.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Leith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brothers Leagues Club Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parting Glass</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish Journey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Boy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
