<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418627740216236</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/chinaindia-border-spat-casts-shadow-ahead-of-brics-summit-20170803-gxokp5.html</url>
  <title>China-India border spat casts shadow ahead of BRICS summit</title>
  <content>
Beijing: China is taking an increasingly tough line on a border row with India amid a crescendo of nationalism in official media, with President Xi Jinping looking set for an awkward encounter with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi next month.
Diplomats say Beijing would like to resolve the border issue before a summit of the BRICS nations - that also groups Brazil, Russia and South Africa - in the Chinese city of Xiamen in early September, and ensure nothing dampens what China wants to be a show of cooperation and friendship among developing countries.Photo: AP
But that could be tough. On Wednesday, China accused India of "concocting" excuses over the illegal entry of the South Asian nation's military into Chinese territory.
"China will take all necessary measures to safeguard its legitimate and lawful rights and interests," the Foreign Ministry said.Photo: AP
The two sides' troops are confronting each other close to a valley controlled by China that separates India from its close ally, Bhutan, and gives China access to the so-called Chicken's Neck, a thin strip of land connecting India and its remote north-eastern regions.

Responding, India reiterated an earlier line that work by a Chinese road crew in the sensitive frontier area would have changed the status quo and urging "utmost restraint" by all sides.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"India considers that peace and tranquillity in the India-China border areas is an important pre-requisite for smooth development of our bilateral relations with China," New Delhi's Foreign Ministry said in a statement.Photo: AP
Most previous stand-offs, such as one in 2014 just ahead of a rare trip to India for Xi, were resolved with both sides withdrawing their forces. There has been no shooting since a brief border war in 1962.
Talks are happening behind the scenes, but with little apparent progress. Meantime, Chinese and India media have been taking a strident approach, with a Chinese state-run newspaper last week saying China could use force.
An Indian magazine's front cover last month showing a map of China shorn of Tibet and self-ruled Taiwan also ignited public anger on Chinese social media with thousands of angry posts.
"The problem is the media on both sides are whipping things up. This makes it hard for China or India to back down," said a Beijing-based source who is familiar with the discussions between the two sides.
The Indian government has asked political parties to refrain from politicising the issue and allow diplomacy to work.
But last week, China's defence ministry also warned India not to harbour any illusions about the Chinese military's ability to defend its territory.
A source with ties to the military, who spoke recently to a senior Chinese officer involved in the stand-off, said China has no appetite for conflict with India but could not be seen to be weak.
"Nobody wants to fight about this, but if India keeps making trouble then we'll have to show them what we're made of," the source said, citing the conversation with the senior officer.
China has repeatedly called on India to withdraw its forces.
An Indian government source closely tracking the situation said there was no change in the ground situation in Doklam, with the two sides remaining in a stand-off.
Indian military expert Nitin Gokhale said India was prepared for a long haul.
"The decision is to stay resolute on the ground and reasonable in diplomacy," Gokhale said.
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doklam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gokhale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China-India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRICS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xiamen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nitin Gokhale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bhutan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Xi Jinping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tibet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India-China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicken's Neck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Ministry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Delhi's Foreign Ministry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beijing-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
