<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418026444784892</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/lifestyle/shopping/the-sale-whisperer-melbournes-best-shopping-august-310-20170731-gxm0is.html</url>
  <title>Where to score Bec Judd's leggings for a steal</title>
  <content>
This week's column has a bit of a celebrity vibe, with Bec Judd's activewear label having a sale, and author and general it-girl Zoe Foster Blake launching her first fashion collaboration.
It's hard to believe that a label as "Melbourne" as  has never had a warehouse sale in this city but hey, you learn something new each day.
Styles in 100 per cent organic cotton jersey, Japanese denim and pieces from mainline collections will all be heavily reduced.
. Friday 9am-7pm, Saturday 9am-5pm.

Bassike is bringing its warehouse sale to Melbourne for the first time.

Few things can break a winter rut like some new active wear, especially if the sun is shining (Friday is looking like the ).

, which is part owned by Bec and Chris Judd, is holding a warehouse sale with up to 70 per cent off past seasons' styles.
Friday 8am-6pm, Saturday 8am-5pm, Sunday 9am-4pm.

Best foot forward ... Jaggad has a sale on active wear this weekend.

If you prefer drinks with the girls over a sweat session, then head to party favourite  winter warehouse sale.
Before it premieres its new collection for Myer in two weeks, it's clearing past seasons' stock.
Designer Jacqui Demkiw promises it's the best sale yet with prices from $5 to $250, including leather, coats and knitwear. 
(behind old Coles car park). Friday 7am-7pm, Saturday 9am-3pm.

White Suede promises this will be its best warehouse sale yet.

Shopping in your PJs again this weekend?  has you covered with up to 70 per cent off brands including Camilla and Marc, SENSO, J Brand and Paige denim.
Get an extra 10 per cent off with the code EXTRA10, and get free shipping if you spend more than $150.
. Starts August 2, while stocks last.

Order of Style has massive reductions off leading labels.

Shoe lovers, pay attention. Local favourite  is having a warehouse sale with massive reductions on past seasons' styles. Get in early because there are often big crowds at this one.
Friday 4pm-8pm, Saturday 10am-5pm.

Love shoes? habbot has its annual sale this weekend.

Sticking with local heroes,  is holding a nothing over $100 sale at its Toorak store (not to be confused with its Malvern Road locations). Labels in the sale include Rails, Robins Jeans, Nicole Miller and Cable.
While stocks last.
Just launched

I was fortunate enough to go to university with Zoe Foster Blake and even then, I knew she was destined to become a star. 
Since parting ways in our media and communications class, she has written numerous books, one of which, The Wrong Girl, has even been made into a TV show.
Now, with a skincare label, Go To, under her belt, she's turning to fashion, launching a cute-as-a-cupcake collaboration with lifestyle brand .
The 16-piece collection includes some of Foster Blake's favourite things (and mine), including hot chips and lobsters.
On sale August 7 (pre-order available online now).

Zoe Foster Blake wearing the Trench Coat and Melbourne At Night Logo Tee from the collection. Photo: Supplied

#inthecart: tomato tops

Since Kendall Jenner raised eyebrows (and pulses) by wearing a Bec and Bridge blouse sans bra , I've been perusing the wide range of red tops on offer, given the blouse in question isn't out in stores until October.
It seems the crimson blouse is one of the pieces de rigeur this spring. So make like a pot of Heinz Big Red and get cooking.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J Brand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Foster Blake</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sundays (9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaggad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foster Blake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go To</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wrong Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paige</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malvern Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bassike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toorak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robins Jeans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PJs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bec Judd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday, 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday (9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendall Jenner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Judd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SENSO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Suede</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui Demkiw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EXTRA10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heinz Big Red</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne At Night Logo Tee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trench Coat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday, 9</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
