<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417940545437650</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/entertainment/joh-for-pm-head-to-cairns-with-comedy-retelling-of-qld-history/news-story/82ab7b0e25db32141b919dde3fdf12e4</url>
  <title>Twist to pollie's tale</title>
  <content>
WHEN the words 'Joh Bjelke-Petersen' are spoken certain thoughts come to mind.
It's easy to think of the injustices to Indigenous people, to gay people, the corruption and the famous Fitzgerald Inquiry.
What most people don't do is laugh.
But the team behind Joh For PM are making people do just that with their laugh-out-loud musical comedy about the controversial Queensland premier.
Director Kris Stewart tells Play that it's time to laugh at the corruption and scandals of the Bjelke-Petersen regime.
"We wanted, for quite a while, to develop a 1970s or 80s musical set in Queensland as the state started to grow," he says.
"The underbelly of the state really started to show."
He says the spirit of the show worked to reduce the impact still felt by Bjelke-Petersen's government.
"We saw that the Joh Bjelke-Petersen story covered everything we wanted to tell," he says.
"We wanted to use it to lessen the blows from the Fitzgerald Inquiry.
"Now that 30 years have passed we're in a good place to laugh about it."
The creative team behind the stage show has a history of turning shocking political stories into works of musical genius.
"Paul Hodge composed for us. He's from Queensland and we knew he was a creative with a political bent," he said.
Hodge previously wrote the book, music, and lyrics for the American production of Clinton: The Musical.
The stellar team also includes a number of Australian stage actors who have worked extensively in Northern Australia.
"At every point we tried to highlight Queensland talent," Stewart says.
"Shaun has had a great career across Northern Australia.
"It's been very important to us to collaborate between regional theatres and Brisbane theatre."
The show premiered in Brisbane last month (JULY) to sold-out audiences, and Stewart hopes it will do the same in Cairns.
"Audiences love musicals and they love having a night out to have a laugh - this combines the two," he says.
Joh for PM will have its Cairns premiere at JUTE Theatre on Friday, August 4 and run for a two week season.
Tickets start at $34 and are available at www.jute.com.au.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joh For PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bjelke-Petersen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JUTE Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzgerald Inquiry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joh Bjelke-Petersen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
