<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418077984393452</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/st-kilda-saints-want-finals-for-retiring-nick-riewoldt-20170803-gxogfd.html</url>
  <title>Saints haven't ruled out playing finals yet</title>
  <content>
St Kilda may have suffered heartbreak in the last-gasp loss to Port Adelaide last week, but they think their season is far from over.
The looming retirement of club great Nick Riewoldt will give the Saints extra motivation to make their first their finals appearance since 2011, according to skipper Jarryn Geary.

Up Next

Sam Mitchell retires

02:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

Sam McClure previews all the footy action ahead of round 20 in the AFL.

Riewoldt, who was replaced by Geary in the role this year, announced this week that this season would be his last and the Saints remain hopeful they can give him an elusive premiership as a send-off.
Geary said the champion forward had set the benchmark players aspired to, both on and off the field.
"I guess it's a bit more motivation, but the finals is probably all the motivation that we need at the moment," Geary said.
"The next four weeks for us and for a lot of teams is going to be pretty important. We've got enough to focus on there.

"But definitely the motivation of trying to get another final for 'Rooey' (Riewoldt) is definitely there."
The Saints were stung by their last-minute capitulation against Port Adelaide last round, with Robbie Gray booting a goal in the final 10 seconds to snatch a two-point victory.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Geary said their review of the match had been painful.
"It's probably one of the more gut-wrenching losses that we've had certainly for a long time," he said.
"It was a tough way to lose a game of football, but it's what you take from that and I'm sure myself and a lot of the boys will learn some lessons from that last two minutes."
St Kilda have sunk to 11th on the back of a three-game losing streak, but Geary was adamant their season was far from finished.
But they need a win against eighth-placed West Coast on Saturday at Etihad Stadium, which would come from an improved strike-rate in front of goal and more consistency.
"When we play our best footy we are capable of matching it with anyone," Geary said.
"We went through a really good month, we won four and we've lost the last three, so hopefully we can get back to playing some of the footy that we played a month ago.
"The weekend was pretty positive aside from that last couple of last minutes, so we feel like we're getting back to that kind of form.
"If we bring the same intensity and pressure around the contest, we give ourselves every chance this week."
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam McClure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rooey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geary</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryn Geary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
