<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417854646090368</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/city/elisa-black-every-place-has-meaning-all-of-its-own/news-story/506c5fa6ab9cb7b10ccc68ef59557736</url>
  <title>Every place has meaning all of its own</title>
  <content>
PLACE is a funny thing.
There's not a lot that's more brick and mortar than, well, bricks and mortar; the physical tends to be unassailable like that. But my experience of a particular place is likely to be very different to that of the person experiencing it right alongside me. It's tied up in experience and perception and emotions. Memory is soft and malleable, it bends on reflection.
I grew up in the Adelaide Hills and my memories of that place, Stirling to be specific, smell like the lawn at the height of summer, as the sun dipped behind the tall gums that lined our property.
Obviously, as anyone who has spent any time in Stirling knows, it's only sunny for about 45 minutes a year and spends most of the rest of it blanketed in fog and smelling like wet school jumpers.
But in my mind the kids up the road are yelling as they ride their bikes around their yard, dust kicked up in their wake. I can hear music playing through the open door of our house, can smell the sausages on dad's barbecue, feel the cool grass tickling the backs of my legs.
After time overseas - that sounds like rushing traffic on a wet night - I lived just off South Tce in the city. It was creaking floorboards and questionable leftovers and men who wrote poetry and played bad guitar serenades.
Brisbane, where I lived for five years, itches like a mozzie bite, is sweaty and slick like the leaves of a fig. Even the winter felt red-faced, brash.
And then there was Stepney, where I lived when I came back to Adelaide, yet again.
Stepney is beginnings.
It's the noise of renovation, the buzz and sawdust of Otto's Timber.
It's the crying of a newborn in the night - over and over again. It's the looming pepper tree raining nuts into our yard. Crunching brown leaves at Richards Park. It smells like zinc cream. Flowering crepe myrtles. Unbrushed dogs and kindy kids.
Home is important. Place is important. It gives context to our lives. Literally grounds us.
I want to know what your place means to you?
Maybe you're new to your place. Maybe the sounds are jarring, the smells unfamiliar.
Or maybe you have lived there for 50 years, and every corner is ripe with memories, pictures that flood your mind when you round that corner for the thousandth time, open your mailbox and relax at that predicted creak of the hinges, when that same tree begins to drop its leaves first every year, heralding the new season.
Our new publication is working hard to get the balance right for all of you, who feel connected to this place, in this time, and we want to reflect all the things your place is. Your home is.
And the best person to tell us that is you.
What does your place mean to you?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Tce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stepney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richards Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unbrushed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Otto's Timber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
