<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418335682435440</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/movies/lost-starving-close-to-death-yossi-ghinsberg-and-the-gift-that-keeps-on-giving-20170802-gxnzuy.html</url>
  <title>'I would've eaten human flesh': Yossi Ghinsberg on true tale behind Daniel Radcliffe's Jungle</title>
  <content>
There are some moments in Jungle, which opens the Melbourne International Film Festival on Thursday night, that might seem a little too good - or maybe too bad - to be true. But director Greg McLean insists he played an incredibly straight bat on this based-on-fact survival story.
That shot of Daniel Radcliffe bobbing down an angrily foaming river in South America? "There's no blue screen, it's all real," says McLean. "I can't believe we got him to do that."

Up Next

Trailer: The Trip to Spain

02:22

More Trailers Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Trailer: Jungle

A trickster guide leads a group of friends into the Bolivian jungle.

But Yossi Ghinsberg​, the Israeli-born Byron Bay-based author, eco-entrepreneur and motivational speaker whose story this is, begs to differ.
"I have to tell you," he says, "usually movies are bigger than life. This movie is smaller than life. Everything you see is on a smaller scale than what really happened."

To capture the full horror of a storm so heavy the Bolivian jungle around him "fell down", says Ghinsberg, you'd need a budget well north of $100 million (McLean had $10 million).
"The river, which was much wider than the one you see in the movie, was not a river because it had tens of thousands of trees shooting from bank to bank. The raft scene" - in which Radcliffe's Yossi and fellow traveller Kevin Gale (Alex Russell) cling for dear life after their make-shift vessel is dashed against a rock - "was much more dramatic in real life. Also, the injury and adversity I had, you cannot show. Two nights before I was attacked by fire ants, I was attacked by termites. But for the movie you have to pick one."

McLean is best known for his Wolf Creek franchise, and there are moments in Jungle when you wonder if our intrepid adventurers are about to fall foul of their guide or indigenous tribespeople​. But in truth, it is nature that poses the greatest threat: there are skin-burrowing, blood-sucking worms, hungry jaguars, scorpions, spiders and snakes to contend with. But in the three weeks he wandered through the jungle on his own, slowly wasting away, Ghinsberg says the greatest darkness he faced was within, not around him.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I knew it was my own stupidity [that got me in that situation], not that the jungle was my enemy. Even while this was going on, I could still appreciate the beauty of it, especially because I knew no one else could see it, only me."Photo: Justin McManus
It was 1981 when Ghinsberg set out on a trek in the Bolivian Amazon with two fellow travellers and a German guide who promised to lead them to a lost tribe and a river of gold. But with the guide (played by Thomas Kretschmann​) terrified of the river and Swiss friend Marcus (played by Joel Jackson) struggling to walk, they split up. Marcus initially wanted to travel by raft, but was persuaded to walk out with the guide, Karl Ruprechter​. The two men were never seen again.
They had entered the jungle with a little rice and dried beans and a rifle to shoot game, but all they landed was monkey. Eating it was a challenge, but by the end, he says, "I would have eaten human flesh. With hunger at that level, it's just energy. It's beyond disgust."Photo: Hector Alvareza
He wouldn't have killed a fellow human, he adds, but he understands survivors eating the dead in such situations. "Survival is very powerful," he says. "All your faculties want to cling to life. We're not tested usually, luckily, but when we are, we become superheroes." 
For all the trials and trauma he experienced, "this is not a story that is unpleasant to me," Ghinsberg says. If he could undo the fateful decision to enter that jungle, he says, he wouldn't.Photo: Hector Alvarez
What happened has defined his life, and had enormous positive impacts. He went back to the jungle and lived there. He built an ecotourism resort with the indigenous people in the area where he had been lost. He has made a living sharing his story with people. And now, after more than 20 years of false starts, the movie of the book he wrote about his experiences is finally about to have its world premiere.
"The story," he says simply, "has been a blessing in every way I can see".
Jungle screens on the opening night of MIFF and on August 11, 17 and 20. Details at  The Age is a festival media partner
Facebook:  
Twitter: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yossi Ghinsberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolf Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radcliffe's Yossi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hector Alvarez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ghinsberg</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Radcliffe's Jungle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Ruprechter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivian Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLean</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Gale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli-born Byron Bay-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne International Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trailers Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11, 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hector Alvareza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIFF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Radcliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Kretschmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
