<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418288437794356</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/how-much-do-you-need-in-retirement-20170803-gxon8u.html</url>
  <title>How much do you need in retirement?</title>
  <content>
When it comes to the popular question, 'How much do I need to have saved for retirement?' there is generally a key assumption made when arriving at an answer.
That is, by the time you retire, you will own your house and have paid off the mortgage. But with house prices continuing to increase and the dream of home ownership becoming less realistic for more Australians, it is an assumption that really needs to be questioned.Photo: Louie Douvis
According to the Retirement Standards recently released by the Association of Superannuation Funds of Australia, retirees in Sydney, as an example, will need an additional $500,000 to retire in comfort if they don't own their home debt-free. While an individual who is renting will need $1.05 million, a homeowner will only need $545,000 to maintain a similarly comfortable standard of living in retirement.
According to ASFA, one in 12 Australians aged more than 65 live in private rentals, which is an issue considering that this rate is increasingly likely to grow for the foreseeable future. While around 75 per cent of households where the head of the house is aged over 65 currently own their house outright, the increasing difficulty of purchasing a home is likely to see a steady decline in that percentage over time.
Casting further gloom on the retirement outlook for renters is that these estimates assume people are enjoying reasonable health, so any serious illness or disability makes the situation even more challenging, as does rental instability and associated costs.
What is the solution?

Whether Australians continue to pursue the goal of home ownership or not, here are three tips that can increase the chances of a more comfortable lifestyle later in life.

Plan for the long term
Life expectancies are increasing and most people are retired longer than they expect. While your genes and health may influence your life span, plan to live into your nineties or even older.  While most think they will spend less when they are older, consider the cost of aged care and health costs.  
Strategy and structure first
Ensuring your investment are in the correct person's name or held by a family trust or super fund is essential in making sure that your money lasts as long as possible and you are minimising your tax. Get this right first before choosing your investments.
Review your investment strategy
Investing for the long term is essential if you want your funds to last into your nineties.  Ensure you review your investment strategy and have a good mix of both defensive investments to smooth your returns and growth investments to keep up with inflation and grow over the long term.
 is the co-founder of  and is a respected and independent financial expert.  Olivia's advice is general in nature and readers should seek their own professional advice before making any financial decisions.
You can follow Olivia on  or .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Association of Superannuation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Funds of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retirement Standards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
