<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418610560346781</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:45</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/hms-queen-elizabeth-what-life-is-like-for-crew-british-warship-2017-8</url>
  <title>Here's what life is like onboard Britain's enormous new $5.84 billion aircraft carrier</title>
  <content>
The HMS Queen Elizabeth is the most powerful aircraft carrier in British history.

on June 26, conducting sea trials around the North Sea.

It is scheduled to conduct flight trials off the United States east coast in October 2018 and plans to be fully operational by 2020.

The warship is already home to 900 people - 700 Royal Navy members and 200 industry personnel.

And thanks to , we can get a glimpse into what life is like on board.

Take a look at the photos below for some behind-the-scenes action on Britain's mega-ship.

It is home to about 700 Royal Navy members and 200 industry personnel. Here are some of them, waving from the ship.

Jeff J Mitchell/Getty

All 900 crew members share the ship's facilities, such as the canteen, gym, and medical resources, a Ministry of Defence spokesman told Business Insider UK.

It visited Scapa Flow in the Orkney islands on Wednesday to commemorate Edwin Dunning, the first pilot ever to land an aircraft on a moving ship.

These days, safety precautions are much higher. Here, crew test firefighting foam sprays on deck.

When they're at sea, crew walk over six miles a day to get around the ship. They also climb the equivalent of 80 ladders.

Some even go on morning runs around the flight deck.

The ship also has its own gym for people who prefer to work out indoors.

There's also a boxing ring, where people can let off steam with their fists.

Boxing coaches are on hand for those with less experience. Here is one of them leading a women's boxing session.

The mega-ship also has a ping pong table  --  much like many trendy startup companies around the world.

On a clear day, you might even find crew playing bucketball on the flight deck on a Saturday afternoon.

The warship even has its own rugby team. Here they are, playing on the flight deck while the ship is anchored.

Phew! That's a lot of exercise. Here's some food to recover with.

This meal was served in April this year, while preparations were still being made for the ship's maiden journey.

Steak Night is a  at the Royal Navy, HMS Queen Elizabeth's official Twitter account noted.

HMS Queen Elizabeth's crew members are a creative bunch. Here's a marine engineer painting a 'Despicable Me' Minion on a tank in the underbelly of the ship.

...and here's the finished product.

HMS Queen Elizabeth also hosted GCSE and A-level exam sittings for its crew members earlier this summer.

Crew members also get to read about themselves in the paper, albeit four days late...

Articles about the ship's departure were brought on board by contractors.

And with occasional views like this, it's no surprise that the Royal Navy is so proud of its ship.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orkney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Navy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GCSEs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff J Mitchell/Getty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scapa Flow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwin Dunning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMS Queen Elizabeth</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Despicable Me' Minion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ministry of Defence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
