<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418292732761866</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/national/malcolm-turnbull-has-downgraded-the-aviation-terror-threat-from-probable-to-possible/news-story/d0efd03039a5733c3e42a52209356555</url>
  <title>Aviation terror threat downgraded: PM</title>
  <content>
PRIME Minister Malcolm Turnbull has downgraded Australia's aviation terror threat from probable to possible in the wake of the alleged conspiracy to bomb a passenger jet flying out of Sydney.
Mr Turnbull said in Perth today, he expected charges and pledged to enhance security measures at airports across the country.
"The Director-General of ASIO (Duncan Lewis) has advised the threat to aviation will be restored to the level it was a week ago," Mr Turnbull said.
"It was raised, as you know, last week, following the discovery of this plot. But it has now been restored to the level it was before.
"The threat level to aviation had been prior to last week (set) at possible. It was raised last week to probable. And it has now been restored to the previous level.
"But, look, can I say to you, there is no room for complacency in this area at all. No room for set-and-forget at all.
"Now, what will happen at the airports is that there will be continued enhanced security measures. Some of them will be obvious to travellers. Some will not.
"But they will be modified in a way that will cause less delays to the travelling public."
Travellers were now being advised to arrive two hours before an international flight and one hour before a domestic flight. He said travellers will receive advice from their airlines.
Mr Turnbull said he was happy with how the investigation into the alleged terror plot was proceeding.
Three suspects remain in custody.
"The Federal Police Commissioner, Andrew Colvin, has advised me that the investigation efforts are proceeding very successfully in terms of the gathering of evidence, and that I should expect, and Australians should expect, charges to be laid in due course," he said.
"But that is, of course, a matter for the police."
Mr Turnbull said the threat of a terrorist act in Australia remained "constant".
" As the leader of our nation, my first duty is to keep Australians safe," he said.
"That is the fundamental obligation. The fundamental responsibility of government. There are no guarantees in a dangerous world. We all understand that. But we are focused, always, on protecting Australians. We feel it keenly. It is a task that, as Michael said, on which we have a laser-like focus.
"We are relentless. We are proud of our successes. We are proud that 13 plots have been disrupted. We're proud of that. Our agencies are outstanding and we congratulate them and we thank them. For their service.
"But the threat is constant. It becomes more sophisticated, more challenging, all the time. And so that is why there is no place for set-and-forget.
"That is why we are always focused on ensuring we do the job better."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Police Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director-General of ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
