<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418589085509984</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/cricket/crickets-pay-stoush-each-side-will-think-itself-the-winner-in-truth-there-are-two-losers-20170803-gxoqrw.html</url>
  <title>Cricket's pay stoush: Each side will think itself the winner. In truth, there are two losers</title>
  <content>
Photo: Simon Schluter
The cricket pay saga dragged on longer than the waterside workers dispute of 1997. That was a landmark in industrial relations in this country, with consequences for thousands of jobs and blood that remains bad to this day.
This was about how a rich sport was going to divide its spoils between mostly well-paid athletes for the next five years, leaving a bit for park players and kids. And yet Cricket Australia and the Australian Cricketers Association somehow turned it almost into Patrick Stevedoring versus the Maritime Union of Australia all over again.
First, last and always, the issue was revenue sharing. All week, lawyers and accountants from both sides have been crawling over the paperwork, alert for catches, convolutions and time bombs. As late as Thursday morning, the ACA's forensic people were still at it, convincing themselves that it was indeed revenue sharing.
Would that every workforce in the land had the luxury of bickering over the device by which they will be paid more, substantially, in some cases lavishly. Of course, the cricketers do not see themselves merely as a workforce. But the board was tactless in being seen to treat them merely as hired hands.
Elitism acted as a tripwire for both sides. The cricketers moaned about being "unemployed", but instead of manning picket lines posted on Instagram updates from exotic Pacific islands and exclusive Californian retreats. Conversely, the board people scarcely budged from their ivory castle. When anyone did deign to explain, it was through such organs and in such a way as to make clear they were speaking firstly to the business community whose fears they needed to allay. Whether to be shared or doled out, there still had to be revenue.
Each side will think itself the winner. The ACA will because revenue sharing has not been scrapped, nor entirely bastardised. CA will think so because it has been modified, opening the door to further massaging in the future.

In truth, there are two losers. To the extent that it is possible to discern through the propaganda, these negotiations were conducted greater ill-will than any since the signing of the first MOU 20 years ago, and any between board and players for 20 years before that.
Both sides talked about respect, but at times displayed only contempt. They underestimated one another, as individuals and organisations. It is pretty clear that CA thought the players would cave in once they were not being paid. But it is also clear that the players expected CA to soften in its hard line once commercial realities began to pinch. Meantime, trust and respect went by the wayside, and so - unforgivably - did an "A" tour to South Africa. 
Possibly only CA chief executive James Sutherland emerges with a scrap of dignity. From his belated entry into discussions, the focus evidently sharpened and the pace quickened. It is a flimsy straw.
The fall-out will be measured by Geiger counter. Between players and board, the bruising will fade, because they have few usual dealings anyway. Board men do not much go to the changeroom, nor do players stalk mahogany row. But philosophically, they remain poles apart. Both preach the gospel of grassroots, but have radically different ideas how to fund them properly. CA still thinks too much of its money is committed to the elite, the players that it is because CA squanders it in the first instance.
Notionally, these become matters for next time. In truth, the work needs to begin now, with new protocols and better mutual understanding, because a prosperous sport usually so blessed with public favour should not again be so demeaned by its own hand.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geiger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOU 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Stevedoring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Schluter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Union of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
