<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418546135836200</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/gunman-fired-into-townsville-river-police/news-story/0f3e7ba4265060409b88bd937e9ac47b</url>
  <title>Gunman fires into Townsville river</title>
  <content>
WALKERS on a popular Townsville path were met with confronting scenes this morning, when they came upon a man firing a sawn off rifle into the Ross River.
Police received several frantic calls from witnesses about 7am, after the man is thought to have fired the rifle, with the words "such is life" written on it, three times into the river.
The man was quickly tracked down riding a push bike, but did not have the firearm on him.
Police will allege he ran from them, before being caught again and telling police where he had hidden the gun.
He was arrested and was expected to be charged with a number of offences including going armed as to cause fear.
District Duty Officer Senior Sergeant Scot Warrick said
"Police received several reports from witnesses in relation to a male person down at Aplin's Weir on a push bike and in possession of a firearm," Sen-Sgt Warrick said.
"The witness reports were that this person was riding a push bike and was in possession of that weapon and further reports came in that that weapon had been discharged into the Ross River.
"Police have responded to the location and have located a male matching the description given to police and they've had a short conversation with that male person and as a result police have located a shortened, cut down .22 rifle secreted in bushland near the location.
"As a result of the investigation a 26-year-old male from Townsville has been arrested and is in custody at the Townsville Watch House, he will be charged with numerous offences, including going armed as to cause fear, discharging a firearm in a public place, possessing a modified and shortened firearm and obstructing police."
If you have any information that can assist police, contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen-Sgt Warrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Watch House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aplin's Weir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Duty Officer Senior Sergeant Scot Warrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
