<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418112344132289</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/boxing/mike-tyson-says-he-would-have-been-a-ufc-flop-for-the-weirdest-reason/news-story/f76aa44baa566e321585871607696c4d</url>
  <title>Mike Tyson says he would have been a UFC flop for the weirdest reason</title>
  <content>
Mike Tyson during an appearance on Norm Macdonald Live

Share

MIKE Tyson has been asked a few times about how he thinks he'd fare as a UFC fighter.
A few years back he was quizzed on his chances of knocking out legendary jiu jitsu practitioner Royce Gracie, who famously submitted his way to victory against much larger fighters at UFC 1 in 1993.
"Well, in '93, I was in prison, so there wouldn't have been a fight, but there is no way I would have won," Tyson told UFC Tonight. "I had no idea what was going on with that type of fighting and would've been taken by surprise. I would have had to train in that particular art of fighting before that happened. That's a particular art.
"You're not going to go in there with just your hand and not have a great ground game. You also need a great wrestling game to be successful ... You have to have both games. You have to know how to wrestle and box. That's just the truth."
But it appears Tyson possesses a fatal flaw that would have been easily exposed in the Octagon. After initially thinking he had the physical tools to make it in MMA, the now 51-year-old realises he would have been a flop.
"I thought that too," said Tyson, when it was suggested he could have been a UFC star during an appearance on  this week.
"Then I saw Royce Gracie step on somebody's foot. If anybody stood on my foot - I've got the worst feet in the world.
"If somebody stepped on my feet, my toes would blow up. It's horrible. I'd have to tap out right away. If you spit on my feet, I'll die. If you'd seen them, you would know why."

Mike Tyson and Ronda Rousey.Source:Getty Images
Tyson has a lot of respect for Gracie - and raised his name again when the discussion turned to the mental strength required to be a great fighter.

The former heavyweight champ recalled watching Gracie refuse to tap in a fight against Matt Hughes at UFC 60.
"Matt Hughes grabbed his arm and pulled it all the way in the back and just ripped it (and) he didn't tap out," Tyson said. "(Hughes) had to beat him unconscious. That's just the mentality - you've got to kill 'em. It was the same with Ali."

Mike Tyson reveals he was molested as a child
0:27

In an interview with ESPN's E:60, Boxing legend Mike Tyson opens up about the time he was sexually abused as a child. CREDIT: ESPN E:60

July 25th 2017
9 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC Tonight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Hughes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN's E</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronda Rousey.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royce Gracie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Tyson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN E:60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gracie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norm Macdonald Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
