<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418035034719755</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/entertainment/juilliard-graduate-anthony-albrect-returns-to-far-north-for-solo-shows/news-story/ab1ef31c880776c19405d775191ca99f</url>
  <title>Good to be bach</title>
  <content>
CELLIST Anthony Albrecht is bringing more than just some tunes to his Bach to the Bush tour through Far North Queensland.
The Juilliard graduate is also reconnecting his family with its roots.
"I did really want to come up to Far North Queensland to enjoy it up here but also really hoping there's an audience here," he says.
"I know that in Cairns, in particular, there is an audience for classical music."
He says this isn't his first time enjoying Cairns and all of its neighbouring cities.
"I came to Far North Queensland with my partner Pippa in 2014," he says.
"We had a wonderful time in the area, we spent a week on Hinchinbrook Island and did a few nights of diving off Cairns, and as a result we're pretty sure it was here we ended up with our baby Lyra.
"It's a very inspiring location, and ever since we thought it would be nice to come back."
Now the solo cellist is travelling in a one-man-only show to spread the good word of Johannes Bach to the people of the Far North.
"Classical music has survived the highs and lows of the charts for several hundred years now," he says. "They say that the death of classical music is its longest lasting trend. Ever since this music has been written people have been saying that it's going to go out of fashion.
"Although you never get as big an audience to solo cello as you would to Adele I think classical music can connect with people on a very deep level."
He says his shows are all about letting people into the secrets behind the famous pieces of music.
"My concerts are about offering lots of learning opportunities to my audiences," he says.
"If people are given an opportunity to understand why it's relevant to them and to be guided into the music a little bit, the same way you would be guided to understand art in a gallery exhibition."
"Sometimes you look at art and have no idea what's going on but if it's explained to you, you can start to connect with it and enjoy looking at it.
"I think classical music is the same."
Albrecht's Bach to the Bush tour reaches Cairns on Sunday, August 6. Tickets available via anthonyalbrecht.yapsody.com.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albrecht's Bach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Albrecht</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pippa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juilliard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinchinbrook Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johannes Bach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bush</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
