<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417983495111281</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/national/cliver-palmer-in-court-as-application-to-freeze-millions-of-dollars-in-assets-is-heard/news-story/64c32374552ef2bc40a80a9f3f03bc86</url>
  <title>Mensink 'left Australia for good'</title>
  <content>
Mr Palmer today tried to delay the multimillion-dollar lawsuit against him and 20 other defendants, including Mr Mensink, because his globetrotting nephew hasn't been served with the paperwork yet.
Government-appointed liquidators have struggled to serve former Mr Mensink and four other overseas defendants since launching the lawsuit in late June.
Mr Palmer, who is representing himself, has argued in the Supreme Court that it would be unfair for the lawsuit to progress without Mr Mensink's knowledge.
The former politician said that he hadn't heard from his nephew since February.
"His attitude seems to be that he's left Australia for good," Mr Palmer said.
Justice John Bond has decided Mr Mensink can be served via his lawyers and Mr Palmer.
The federal government has appointed special purpose liquidators PPB Advisory to try to recoup almost $70 million in taxpayers' money used to pay out the former MP's axed Queensland Nickel workers.
The liquidators want an application to freeze Mr Palmer's assets to be heard next Friday.
Queensland Nickel collapse last January with more than $300 million in debts and about 800 job losses.
Mr Mensink has been on what was believed to be a marathon overseas holiday since June last year.
Outside court, Mr Palmer said he was "tempted" to return to politics.
"I've got so many people contacting me ... my wife keeps on restraining me to do that," he said.
"But we do need to revisit our laws here."
Mr Palmer said he wasn't worried about his assets being frozen.
"I'm not concerned at all, I mean you never want to put your life on material things," he said.
But the self-claimed billionaire said he didn't think the government application would be successful.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Palmer</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mensink</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Nickel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice John Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mensink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPB Advisory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
