<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418455941521628</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/theres-no-escaping-an-outbreak-of-gastro-in-the-family-home-discovers-rebecca-morse/news-story/f21c6b3d3ab9f0eacdc9f88a540147c4</url>
  <title>Rebecca Morse: Illness is too much to stomach</title>
  <content>
WARNING: If you are eating a meal, or considering doing so in the next little while, perhaps return when you are feeling strong of stomach.
For my family has recently emerged from the soul-destroying depths of gastro and lived to tell the tale. Therefore, I thought I should tell the tale. You're welcome.
It started with the youngest. It was school holidays and the poor cherub was a little light on in the play date department, so where she picked up the bug remains a mystery. Those midnight footsteps into your bedroom that strike fear into the heart of every parent just trying to punch out a solid seven hours of sleep.
"I've got a tummy ache."
"Here hop into bed with Mummy." Frankie quickly hops into bed with Mummy.
"Do you feel like you're going to be sick?"
"Yes." Mummy quickly hops out of bed with Frankie.
And so begins a sleepless night that will require some serious steam cleaning of carpet/couch/soft furnishings.
The next family member to succumb was the dog, Henley. Now I would have thought gastro was unable to jump species but send a team of scientists to our place because we seem to have created some sort of vile petri dish of human/canine germs.
So the dog is supposed to sleep outside, because he's a dog. But because it's winter and I'm a big softie, he's been sleeping inside. Until he developed explosive diarrhoea.
To his credit, the gifted, stinky mutt made it to the bathroom. But our grout may never recover. (If we ever sell our house, this never happened by the way.)
"At least no one else in the family seems to have contracted Frankie and Henley's world-first cross-species bug," I said to the universe. And the universe laughed. And laughed. And slapped its thigh. And laughed some more.
For the universe had not even got started with us.
Friday evening rolled around and as I took my seat behind the news desk, the churning in my stomach had begun. As I moved the bin within emergency lunging distance, I considered whether my viral YouTube moment would be viral in the true sense of the word.
I survived the news bulletin and made it home just in time. A home, where one-by-one the previously uninfected family members dropped like flies, and all allegiances were abandoned in a race to the nearest toilet.
By the weekend the collateral damage had spread to my poor mother who cared for my sick child when I assured her it was probably food poisoning, my nephew, and my sports colleague, Nick Butler, who felt compelled to text me with regular and overly-descriptive updates of his internal and external misery as punishment for my workplace germ dissemination.
The only good to come of the whole sorry week of bodily expulsions was that I told the teen it's what having a hangover feels like and she vowed never to drink. In hindsight, I should have asked her to sign a statutory declaration to that effect.
And then she was so weak she couldn't slam her bedroom door in my face so she let me watch one of her favourite teen angst shows with her and we had "Quality Gastro Time" together. With a bucket nearby, just in case.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Butler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quality Gastro Time</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Morse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
