<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418546135836204</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/melbourne-storm-star-felise-kaufusi-out-for-bragging-rights-before-family-reunion-20170803-gxofas.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Storm star Felise Kaufusi out for bragging rights before family reunion</title>
  <content>
Melbourne Storm has countless links to Queensland but when it comes to playing North Queensland Cowboys, no one enjoys the clash more than Felise Kaufusi.
The Storm second-rower is enjoying a career season and his side is rated by many as the premiership favourite as they sit on top of the ladder heading into this round.Photo: AAP
But it's not his seven tries or his team's premiership hopes that make the trip to Townsville special for Kaufusi, it's the mini family reunion which follows.
Three Kaufusi brothers have played in the NRL with Antonio now retired back in Bundaberg after a long career which included a stop with the Storm while younger brother Patrick was impressing for the Cowboys earlier this year before going down with a season-ending injury.
Still the Kaufusi family will travel from Bundaberg to Townsville for the game and it means the world to Felise.
"I've got my little brother here so we have a little reunion where the family try to come up to watch this one as we are both here at the same time," Kaufusi said.

"It's always a good game and always good to see the family.
"It's 12-hour drive from Bundaberg so they have to fly to Brisbane and then up to Townsville.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It's a fair trek - they make a big effort."
While there is plenty of love in the air, sibling rivalry also creeps into the discussion, even with Patrick sidelined.
"I always want to win against my brother and this is just another opportunity to do so," Felise said.
"I'll be making sure I'm ready for it, get the win and have the bragging rights."
The Storm will be missing star five-eighth Cameron Munster due to an ankle injury with coach Craig Bellamy to either go with Ryley Jacks or Jahrome Hughes in that role.
Billy Slater is expected to return to the fullback role after a concussion forced him out last game.
Kaufusi knows it will be a change after Munster's impressive season but Jacks played several games to start the season and Hughes starred last game as Slater's replacement.
"I don't think it changes things too much because they have both played there," Kaufusi said.
"That gives us some confidence and when they have filled in they have done their jobs.
"Everything will go as planned and as normal and then it's just up to them to prepare as best they can."
The Cowboys don't have superstar playmaker Johnathan Thurston due to a season-ending injury but fleet-footed Maroons star Michael Morgan is leading the Cowboys attack and remains a danger player.
"Morgan is tough and he has a good running game," Kaufusi said.
"He likes to show the ball a lot and he is very good at doing that, he is like another x-factor for their team and without Thurston he is stepping up into that role."
Storm play the Cowboys in Townsville on Friday at 7.50pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundaberg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felise</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaufusi</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryley Jacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felise Kaufusi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jahrome Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Cowboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
