<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417601243016549</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/03/give-liberals-fair-hearing-same-sex-marriage-says-entsch</url>
  <title>Give Liberals a fair hearing on same-sex marriage, says Entsch</title>
  <content>
A furious Liberal backbencher insists it's time the party made its own decision on marriage equality without input from its coalition partner, the Nationals.

5 HOURS AGO  UPDATED 1 MIN AGO

Warren Entsch lashed out at reports he was among a group of rebel Liberals preparing to cross the floor on the issue of gay marriage as the divisive debate flares up and threatens Malcolm Turnbull's leadership.

West Australian senator Dean Smith is working on a marriage equality bill, and Mr Entsch is among lower house colleagues including Trevor Evans and Tim Wilson who have flagged support for it.

But Mr Entsch denied there were any plans to vote against the government, insisting he is only seeking to discuss the matter at next week's partyroom meeting as a long-time critic of the government's policy to hold a plebiscite.

RELATED READING

The plebiscite was not the result of a Liberal partyroom vote, but a captain's pick by then prime minister Tony Abbott to delay marriage equality rather than resolve it, he said on Thursday.

"Instead of being ambushed and deceived, I trust this prime minister to do the right thing and give us an opportunity to have a fair hearing on this," Mr Entsch told Sky News ahead of Tuesday's meeting.

Mr Entsch wants the Liberal party to make its own decision on marriage equality free from the National party.

The Nationals would be free to disagree with the Liberal position and vote against it.

The matter had been debated to death and it was time for a free vote on the floor of parliament, Mr Entsch said.

He also lashed out at what he says are "veiled threats and intimidation" after Queensland's Liberal National Party president Gary Spence wrote to members expressing disappointment that some were defying party policy.

'Why do gay people need a different law to everyone else?': Shorten

He goaded Mr Spence to have him disendorsed, calling on him to "bring it on".

"I found it quite disgusting - I think there is a law out there somewhere about directing elected members as to how they vote."

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull is reportedly planning to use a secret ballot to canvass the opinions of his partyroom on the issue.

Mr Turnbull has refused to be drawn on what would be discussed at the meeting, saying voters were more concerned about education and infrastructure than gay marriage.

Former prime minister Tony Abbott on Wednesday issued a stern warning that Liberal MPs crossing the floor would be engaging in a "serious attack" on Mr Turnbull's authority.

With the bill to enable a plebiscite failing to pass parliament last year, some Liberals want the bill re-committed to parliament, while others say a voluntary postal ballot could achieve the same aim without the need for legislation.

MPs pushing for marriage equality argue they have discharged their duty to support a plebiscite and it's not their fault the Senate blocked the legislation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Liberal-National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 1 MIN AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
