<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417987790078681</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/health/radio-host-em-rusciano-slams-antivaxxers-after-secret-movie-screening/news-story/f7d0bfea1791e03fc1738a78144011f1</url>
  <title>Em Rusciano hits out at anti-vaxxers</title>
  <content>
BREAKFAST radio show hosts Em Rusciano and Harley Breen have never shied away from calling it as they see it.
And their show on Thursday morning was no different as they covered the controversial film, Vaxxed: From Cover-Up to Catastrophe, which was dropped from the Tribeca Film Festival line-up earlier this year.
The Melbourne-based duo openly shared their views on anti-vaxxers following a secret screening of the movie at Village Crown on Wednesday night, .
The pair made clear they were staunchly pro-vaccinations and while they themselves have questioned science in the past, they don't believe not vaccinating your children is the answer.
"If your ultimate goal is to prevent sickness and illness in your child, wouldn't you get them vaccinated?" Em asked.
"I just don't understand - considering how many deaths are prevented by vaccine, deciding not to get one doesn't make you safe from sickness. The logic is not sound with these anti-vaxxers.
"There's not been one study done that has linked vaccinations with autism ... not one speck," she added, which is a large-part of the film.
The movie reportedly has an insider blowing the whistle on a cover up by the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, claiming they covered up a casual link between autism and the three-shot vaccine.
During the segment Em produced a number of facts and figures in favour of vaccinating children, which stirred more passion in the conversation.
"Vaccine preventable diseases are now on the rise again because people aren't vaccinating their children," Em said, before Harley cut in.
"People who had the fortune of being vaccinated - these people who got vaccinated by their parents and stayed fit and healthy are now 'we don't need it, we're fine' - yeah, that's because you got vaccinated," he said.
"I get questioning science but you won't find one not telling you to get vaccinated ... from credible scientists," Em said.
Later in the chat, Harley appeared to empathise with anti-vaxxers for a brief moment.
"As a father-of-two, I don't want to put sharp things into my child... I don't want my child to be in any kind of trauma and I'd rather not put these laboratory-made vaccines into my kid and I would love nature to just be nature but unfortunately, that's not the world that we live in.
"Unfortunately, we have to wear seat belts when we drive - cause there are idiots out there - to keep me safe. And unfortunately to keep my boys safe I have to vaccinate them," he added.
"Don't put other kids at risk. Do your research. Vaccinate your kids, d**kheads!" Em ended the segment with, adding that she expects to be flooded with hate mail for her stance.
Harley has two sons with fiance Hannah - Leonard, six and Walter, born earlier this year.
Em has two daughters - Marchella, 15, and Odette, 10 - with her husband Scott Barrow.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMS</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley Breen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tribeca Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marchella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cover-up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Em Rusciano</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disease Control</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Village's Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Odette, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaxxed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Barrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
