<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417983495111348</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/reality/rspca-formally-investigating-the-bachelor-australias-pig-scene-after-backlash-20170803-gxoiv2.html</url>
  <title>RSPCA investigating controversial Bachelor scene</title>
  <content>
RSPCA NSW has denied they approved the use of piglets for a controversial scene in Wednesday night's episode of The Bachelor, and will be formally investigating the incident following criticism from viewers. 
The scene, set in a renaissance fair, showed a number of Bachelorettes chasing down and tackling the piglets in a small enclosure in order to win a seat at a dinner banquet with Bachelor Matty J.

Up Next

The worst Australian accents

01:03

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

The Bacherlor 2017:
The first kiss

A one-on-one date gets Laura and Matty close, leading to the season's first kiss. Video courtesy The Bachelor facebook

Following outrage from viewers who called the scene "cruel", Warner Bros, The Bachelor's production company, issued a statement defending the scene.
"Producers ensure any instance involving animals has RSPCA approval and a handler on set... All participants were briefed by a handler on the humane handling of the pigs for this activity.", the statement, published by The Daily Telegraph, read.

But a spokesperson for RSPCA NSW refuted those claims.
"RSPCA NSW did not approve the use of piglets in the filming of The Bachelor as claimed by Warner Bros," they said in a statement.

"A filming notification form is a legal requirement to film with animals, but it is not an 'approval'.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The notification form supplied by Warner Bros in relation to this incident does not align with the events that took place on set, which claimed 'Piglets will be in a fenced pen and they will herd them and place them in another pen.'"    Photo: Ten
The animal welfare group says calls to Warner Bros requesting the full unedited footage from the shoot have yet to be returned.
"RSPCA NSW takes any potential breaches of animal welfare very seriously and will be formally investigating this incident further."Photo: Ten
Ten did not immediately reply to a request for comment.
The scene had drawn a number of complaints from viewers who criticised the show for "terrifying" the piglets in the name of entertainment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner Bros</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piglet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bacherlor 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
