<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418292732761848</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/development-provides-boost-to-facilities-on-queens-domain/news-story/43ba35e58356d332787590934d88b059</url>
  <title>Facilities boost for Queens Domain</title>
  <content>
A COMMUNITY wood-fired pizza oven is among a number of new facilities being installed at the Queens Domain in Hobart.
The Hobart City Council has started work within the Soldiers Memorial Oval Precinct as part of a plan to enliven the community area and complement the existing recreational facilities.
Hobart Lord Mayor Sue Hickey said the development will also include a playground, amphitheatre, picnic facilities and public toilets.
"The nature-based playscape will be a wonderful centrepiece, catering for children of differing ages and abilities," Alderman Hickey said.
Funded by the City of Hobart and the ANZAC Centenary Fund, the $2.2 million project is due to be completed early next year and has created about 80 jobs.
HCC parks and recreation committee chairman Alderman Anna Reynolds said the community and local school children had been consulted during the design process of the Domain master plan.
"We can't wait for it to be built as it's going to be a great new community facility that works in beautifully with the surrounding landscapes," Ald Reynolds said.
The work is part of the third phase of a five-stage community hub project.
The project's acting director Rob Mather said the community hub would encourage locals to visit the Domain.
Mr Mather said work would continue on the 2.5km running track known as , as well as a trail to the Botanical Gardens that will connect to the new walkway linking the Cenotaph and the Domain.
The bridge will span 200m across the Tasman Highway linking the Cenotaph to the Soldiers Memorial Precinct - 100 years after commemorations at the site began.
Stages one and two of the project included the reinstatement of 36 trees along Soldiers Memorial Avenue, upgraded parking facilities and the construction of a multi-purpose sporting pavilion, named the William Keith Eltham Pavilion.
"It's going to be a beautiful family avenue," Ald Hickey said.
Sean Anthony is a UTAS journalism student.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Mather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ald Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart Lord Mayor Sue Hickey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soldiers Memorial Precinct - 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botanical Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queens Domain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Keith Eltham Pavilion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alderman Hickey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alderman Anna Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ald Hickey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soldiers Memorial Oval Precinct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZAC Centenary Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soldiers Memorial Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
