<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417433739289154</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/christian-beliefs-are-not-worthy-of-labors-shoolyard-crackdown/news-story/df3eed8dfae4ad5722e5d5129f8560df</url>
  <title>Attack on values</title>
  <content>
OPINION: Of all the harebrained ideas governments blindly try to impose on us, discouraging Christianity in schools is bordering on the most sinister.
Annastacia Palaszczuk's Labor State Government was caught out last week advising teachers to deal with students caught "evangelising".
According to Education Queensland, evangelising can be as simple as giving someone a Christmas card that mentions the birth of Christ or singing a Jesus-themed Christmas song.
No mention of Islamic kids discussing Ramadan or Jews talking about Hanukkah, just Christianity.
I copped a bit of stick recently when I suggested Marxism was being pushed on us by elected leaders intent on changing society.
Well, destroying the Christian faith is one of the key tenets of modern Marxism and Palaszczuk's blatant declaration of war on the faith in our schools is more solid evidence of Marxism's influence on our decision makers.
Take these quotes attributed to one of the fathers of modern Marxism, Antonio Gramsci: "Socialism is precisely the religion that must overwhelm Christianity."
And: "...Any country grounded in Judeo-Christian values can't be overthrown until those roots are cut..."
I interviewed Australian Conservatives leader Cory Bernardi recently and he said "Marxism" was not too strong a term to use to describe the attempts we see daily at changing society and challenging conservative views.
You don't need to be religious to be a good person, but to suggest Christianity - a faith that preaches turning the other cheek and loving everybody - has no place in our schools is an idea straight out of the Marxist-Left handbook.
Would the world be a better place with less Christianity or more?
Do children really need to be shielded from any mention of it?
At the very least, Jesus was just a hippie preaching love in a time of great upheaval and violence.
But this hippie has had more influence on the modern world than anything else.
It's not right, nor should it be permissible, to deny His or Christianity's place in the world.
We don't need to force schoolkids to be exposed to Christianity, but there's a strong argument for at least teaching them: "Hey kids, you know our calendar, many of our holidays, why you get Easter eggs and Christmas presents is because there was a man called Jesus? Some people believe in a being called God and Jesus was His son. There's a religion called Christianity based on Jesus' life and teachings. Christians believe Jesus was born on Christmas Day and that He died at Easter, which is why we have days off. If you want to know more, ask your parents. Now, open your maths books to page 56."
Learning about Christianity does not mean automatic baptism and learning about religion surely should be a part of any well-rounded education curriculum.
Instead, we have governments actively trying to denigrate Christianity and saying that talking about Jesus is forbidden.
How mean and sad.
Christianity isn't a bad model to base your life on and it certainly shouldn't be demonised.
One comment I saw online suggested that if state schools want to stamp out talk of Jesus Christ, they should not take holidays based on the Christian calendar.
That sounds fair enough. It seems a bit rich to hold Christianity in contempt but then turn around and take advantage of its benefits.
Suggestions there is a war on Christianity in this country have been ridiculed but there is enough evidence to show this is true.
Former Prime Minister Tony Abbott was routinely ridiculed for his Christian faith, as is Bernardi, and the ABC recently was taken to task for making the outrageous claim that churchgoing Christian men were the most likely to beat their wives.
Then we have Catholic Cardinal George Pell, who has been attacked mercilessly in the media even though he has not been found guilty of any offences against children.
Meanwhile, proven transgressions against children committed in the name of Islam barely rate a mention.
There is a war on Christianity and we cannot trust politicians or the media to defend it.
Senator Bernardi is the only politician who has publicly stated his opposition to attacks on traditional values and his movement is worth researching if you are dissatisfied with the two big parties.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Conservatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic Cardinal George Pell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marxism</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marxist-Left</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus-themed Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annastacia Palaszczuk's Labor State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramadan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christianity</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus Christ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Gramsci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanukkah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judeo-Christian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cory Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
