<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418069394458696</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4831412/newcastle-bus-drivers-underpaid-after-privatisation/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Newcastle bus drivers underpaid after privatisation</title>
  <content>
Newcastle bus drivers have suffered pay "discrepancies" since private firm Keolis Downer assumed control of the company in July. PICTURE: Marina Neil

NEWCASTLE'S bus drivers have been repeatedly underpaid since a private company assumed control of the city's public transport system in July.

The Newcastle Herald has seen communication to staff from Keolis Downer's chief executive in the Hunter, Campbell Mason, acknowledging "discrepancies in pay for some staff"

In the letter to staff Mr Mason acknowledged issues with pay and said that while "a number of issues identified in the initial payroll" had been fixed, it was "of course possible that there may be some discrepancies this time around".
"Correcting any such issues is a priority for us," Mr Mason states in the missive. 
The Herald has been told that about 70 workers have been affected, with some drivers are owed about $200 from the previous fortnight's pay, and others short by about $600 in the latest pay period.
"When people live pay to pay and have that much missing its not good," one driver said on the condition of anonymity.

Keolis Downer has been approached for comment, but the Herald understands the issue relates to the company's payroll system.

r.

Transport Minister Andrew Constance. PICTURE: Max Mason-Hubers
For the first time in Australia, one company was awarded a contract to operate a city's entire transport system.

At the time Transport Minister Andrew Constance said it was a "new era" for the city's transport that would "guarantee a better deal for locals".

On Thursday his office was not aware of the pay issue when contacted by the Herald.
Port Stephens MP Kate Washington accused the company of having "prioritised its new logo instead of looking after its workers".
"It's only taken a month for the government's empty promises that we would see improved services and workers' rights retained, to have fallen by the wayside in the first month of operation," she said.
"The NSW government and its obsession with privatisation is hurting the people who can afford it the least.

"Every bus driver has a family who depends on their pay packet. Failing to pay workers for the hours they've worked hurts families who live in our communities."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Andrew Constance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens MP Kate Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mason</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keolis Downer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Mason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
