<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418112344132297</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/national/former-national-security-agency-deputy-director-john-inglis-warns-on-data-collection/news-story/b6fb180032bb9915cbaab1fb2f28f505</url>
  <title>Ex-security chief warns on data collection</title>
  <content>
A FORMER leading US security chief, who oversaw the investigation into NSA leaker Edward Snowden, has delivered a shocking warning over the "unchecked" collection of personal information by the private sector.
In an address to the National Press club today, former Deputy Director of American's National Security Agency John Inglis said Australians should be more concerned about the collection of their data by private business than by the government.
"I think we should never take our eye off the government, make sure we constrain them to the purpose for which they defined. But the private sector is running unchecked in this regard," said Mr Inglis who was with the NSA from 2006 to 2014.
"That's by design, you sign user agreements, you willingly give up the data, but the aggregation of that has stunning consequences. There's very few secrets about your life, where you have been, what you have done.
"I'm not suggesting that is used maliciously but it's a tremendous capability that can be used for good or evil.
"You as a citizen may not care about the commercial efficiencies that drive from having all that information in the hands of someone who can put the right advertisement, the right product in front of you, you may care about your privacy you want greater control on that."
Mr Inglis said limits needed to be put on the actions of private enterprise.
"We need to have some discussion about what are the appropriate standards for what
information can being a graded and aggregated and what degree of accountability should be effected upon those who aggregate it?
"I'm sure they will occasion a great hue and cry about the suppression of free action, perhaps liberty on the part of corporations. We trying to align the rights of individuals against the rights of groups of individuals. It's not taken in a way that fully addresses the implications of where we're in the 21st century.
"Is privacy dead? I don't think so. I think you can to some agree, modulate your own behaviour. You don't have to have a Facebook account, you don't need various social media accounts.
"But it's harder and harder. This is where government can assist. It shouldn't do so in a wet blanket way, but establishing the venue and the dialogue by which we can consider the matter and come to rational conclusions."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Director of American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security Agency John Inglis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward Snowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Inglis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-security</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
