<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417854646090449</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/suncorps-new-operating-model-includes-a-unique-executive-pay-deal-20170803-gxobsn</url>
  <title>Suncorp implements new operating model</title>
  <content>
When insurance, banking and wealth management group Suncorp introduced a new operating model it was designed to break the usual rules about engaging with customers.
Chief executive Michael Cameron heralded the "One Suncorp" operating model as a way of giving customers a single digital customer experience. He has abandoned the usual business segment silos found at other institutions.
When the roll out of the new operating model is complete there will be no distinction between the general insurance outlets of GIO and the bank branches of Suncorp Bank.
There will be a network of shop fronts open six days a week offering the Suncorp marketplace service which includes a range of Suncorp manufactured products and products sourced from partnerships with third parties.

This approach to serving customers requires analysts and investors to think differently about the performance of the company.

Cameron says those worried about the usual cost to income ratio for measuring the efficiency of Suncorp Bank should think again. He says that measure is no longer relevant because costs of distribution will be shared.
Nevertheless, Suncorp will continue to publish this figure.
On shareholders learned that the new operating model comes with a unique approach to executive remuneration.
The annual report revealed that Cameron and the 11 senior executives who answer to Cameron were all paid exactly the same short term incentive (STI) award as a percentage of target STI.

Also, Cameron and all 11 executives who report to him received the same STI award as a percentage of their maximum STI. They all received 94 per cent of target and 62 per cent of maximum STI.
This comes at a time when governance experts and executive remuneration experts have claimed that STI has become, in effect, part of base pay.
Cameron assesses each senior executive's performance at the end of the financial year against business function scorecards, considering actual outcomes relative to the agreed targets.
He then makes a recommendation to the remuneration committee for board approval on the amount of STI to be awarded.

In the 2017 financial year, Cameron recommended that "STI outcomes for 2016-17 should be consistent for all senior executives".
"It was determined that this outcome most appropriately recognised the contribution of all senior executives within the One Suncorp operating model that delivered results to our shareholders in 2016-17," the annual report said.
This will raise eyebrows in some quarters because the segment reporting disclosures released by Suncorp on Thursday showed variable performances by different divisions.
For example, the New Zealand division saw profit fall from $183 million to $82 million in the year to June.

Also, banking and wealth reported lower profits compared to 2016 and the losses in the corporate head office rose from $114 million to $120 million.
Suncorp chairman Ziggy Switkowski said in the annual report that Suncorp had "delivered value to shareholders, customers and the communities in which we operate" in 2017.
The STI award target at Suncorp is 100 per cent with the maximum opportunity being 150 per cent of fixed remuneration.
In 2017 the STI achievement against target was 94 per cent and long term incentives issued in 2013 did not vest because the total shareholder return was below the median peer comparator group.

Suncorp revealed on Thursday that the new marketplace at the centre of the One Suncorp operating model would cost $100 million to implement and this would be booked in the profit in 2018 but it would not affect dividend payments.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ziggy Switkowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Suncorp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
