<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418155293805840</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830999/international-agency-praises-uows-robust-financial-health/?cs=12</url>
  <title>International ratings agency affirms University of Wollongong's AA credit rating</title>
  <content>
University of Wollongong chief finance officer Damien Israel.

The ''good robust financial health'' of the University of Wollongong has it well placed to deal with proposed federal government cuts to the higher education sector.
That's the view of UOW's chief finance officer Damien Israel, who also welcomed agency affirming the university's AA credit rating.
The international ratings agency praised UOW for its very strong financial profile, sound financial policies and strong financial performance in its latest Ratings Research Update.

While UOW's financial position was strong, the report warned that its financial performance will be challenged by proposed federal government funding cuts over 2018 and 2019.

''We would certainly prefer that they [cuts] weren't happening,'' Mr Israel said.

''But the university is in good robust financial health and that means when you are faced with these sorts of measures and challenges going forward you have got some capacity to deal with them in a measured and prudent way rather than having to react suddenly and do things that are disruptive to the institution and the community, staff and students who rely on the institution.''

- UOW chief finance officer Damien Israel
These measured and prudent ways could include growing UOW's revenues and markets in the Illawarra, expanding further into south-west Sydney or offshore in Dubai or Hong Kong.

''We also have an ongoing program looking into the efficiency of our operations and applying new technologies where we can and looking at how we can do things more effectively,'' Mr Israel said.

''What is the critical thing for us is we've got that base we can work from and we can do things that are constructive rather than disruptive.

''It is essential that the university remains financially sustainable given its importance to the communities it serves and the large number of staff and students who benefit from the institution's ongoing presence.''

The S&P Global Ratings report said UOW's ''very strong financial profile was a reflection of its sound financial policies and high level of available resources''.

But while UOW does have high levels of cash and investments, these are expected to decline over the next two years as the university rolls out a large capital expenditure program, having committed $300 million to new infrastructure over the period 2016-2020.
The report also highlighted UOW's good academic reputation, it's high student retention rate (86 per cent for undergraduates in 2016), and the fact undergraduate students had a mean tertiary entrance score of about 72 out of a possible 99.95 in 2016.

It also described the university's international reputation as "robust", as evidenced by its high standings global university rankings, including the QS Top 50 Under 50 (17th in 2018).

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QS Top 50 Under 50 (17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Israel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ratings Research Update</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P Global Ratings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Israel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
