<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417511048702137</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/12/03/baby-diagnosed-with-meningitis-was-turned-away-from-nsw-hospital-twice</url>
  <title>Baby diagnosed with meningitis was turned away from NSW hospital twice</title>
  <content>
A four-month-old boy was turned away from a NSW hospital emergency department twice before finally being diagnosed with meningitis after his mother rushed him to an emergency ward for a third time.

Tegan Gilbert first took her son Brock Morschel to the emergency department of Shoalhaven District Memorial Hospital in Nowra on July 10 when his cold took a turn for the worse and his temperature spiked to 39 degrees.

But, because Brock seemed alert, doctors sent him home and told Ms Gilbert to give him Panadol and keep his fluids up.

Three days later, Brock was drowsy and lethargic and couldn't hold his head up, Ms Gilbert told nine.com.au.

"He was just going downhill. He'd had a fever since Monday and he was starting to get really weak," she said.

Growing increasingly worried for her son, the mother-of-three took him to her local medical centre and saw a GP who told her to take Brock to hospital immediately.

"She looked at him and just said, 'he's not well, take him straight to casualty' and she bulk-billed us and told us not to worry about anything at reception, just to go straight to the hospital," Ms Gilbert said.

Related Articles

But when a paediatrician came down from the children's ward to assess Brock, the little baby smiled at him, and he was sent home again.

"Brock smiled at the doctor at that stage and was looking at him, and yeah he basically said because he was alert at that time just to take him home," Ms Gilbert said.

"He did diagnose him with an acute upper respiratory infection that day but said just to go home and watch him."

Ms Gilbert said she was worried about taking her son home but didn't question the doctor as she thought he knew best.

But Brock's condition didn't improve and the next morning Ms Gilbert took her son back to the medical centre again, this time seeing another GP, who also sent her straight back to the emergency department of the Shoalhaven hospital for a third time in four days.

Ms Gilbert said staff at the hospital were prepared to send little Brock home again, after he took a sip from a bottle.

"They'd said to me we'll just see if he can have a bottle and if he can have a bottle then you can go home," she said.

But Brock was then seen by a new doctor, a locum from Sydney, who asked the mum one further question.

"He said to me, "Does he look like your son - like how he usually does" and I said "no", and that's when he said "well, mum knows best".

The doctor decided to keep Brock in overnight for observation, a move that may well have saved the baby's life.

Again Brock took a turn for the worse.

"That night he started vomiting and was still feverish and was just getting worse. His eyes were just rolling back in his head at that point," Ms Gilbert said.

The doctor who had seen Brock earlier began to suspect meningitis and performed a lumbar puncture to test for the inflammatory brain disease. His suspicion would soon be confirmed.

Terrifyingly for Ms Gilbert, baby Brock had begun to have seizures, due to the swelling on his brain.

He also suffered a small stroke and was found to have a blood clot.

Brock's seizures grew worse and were soon coming one after the other so a decision was made to airlift him to the Sydney Children's Hospital in Randwick on July 16, where he is still being treated.

Ms Gilbert said Brock's condition was now stable but doctors did not know what long term effects the meningitis and his seizures would have on his brain.

"They are not real sure of the long term effects it might have on him. We are only going to know that when he starts to walk and talk and all of that," Ms Gilbert said.

Ms Gilbert said she was more "frustrated and disappointed" than angry about her son being turned away so many times from Shoalhaven District Memorial Hospital.

"To have to go to the casualty three times, I've got no words for it," she said.

"But the one doctor that actually diagnosed him I could not fault him. If it wasn't for him I don't even want to think about what would have happened."

Nine.com.au has contacted the Illawarra Shoalhaven District Health Service for comment.

Meanwhile, Ms Gilbert said family members were helping to look after her 10 and 12 year old daughters while she and her partner Jake Morschel stayed by their son's bedside.

Doctors have said Brock may be in hospital for another month and a  page has been set up to help the family with the costs of Mr Morschel having to take time off from his truck driving and construction job.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Morschel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nowra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven District Memorial Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panadol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tegan Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Morschel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morschel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gilbert</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Shoalhaven District Health Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROCK</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
