<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417639897722617</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/more-sports/nfl-scouting-report-how-all-nine-australians-are-shaping-up-ahead-of-201718-preseason/news-story/a1ee8c37f2ef9dd8bd74bbd5b9049573</url>
  <title>History beckons for Aussie NFL hopefuls</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIA is on track for one of its biggest ever NFL seasons, with eight players in the hunt for 2017/18 roster spots.
The build-up to the new season officially begins on Friday (AEST), with Dallas facing Arizona in the annual Hall of Fame Game in Canton, Ohio.
Punter Sam Irwin-Hill is likely to figure for the Cowboys and is one of nine Australians who could feature in pre-season over the next month.
Australia had its heaviest representation in the NFL last season, with five players on 53-man rosters. Even more could feature in 2017/18 but the next month is crucial to determining selection fates before final squads are confirmed on September 3 (AEST). Here's a look at how the Australians are shaping up.
SAM IRWIN-HILL (punter, Dallas Cowboys)
Irwin-Hill, 26, is bidding to become the latest addition to the growing line of Australian punters - and the third to punt for the Cowboys at NFL level after Colin Ridgway and Mat McBriar.
The 192cm, 94kg specimen was a day before the 2017 NFL Draft and faces a tough ask to oust established Cowboys punter Chris Jones.
However, he's considered an outside chance of doing so and should get a decent chance to shine in pre-season.
Interestingly, there's talk Irwin-Hill could also get some reps at kicker against the Cardinals on Friday, after attempting a field goal in practice this week.
CAMERON JOHNSTON (punter, Philadelphia Eagles)
Johnston went undrafted but was picked up by the Eagles as a free agent in May.
The 23-year-old, another product of the Prokick Australia development program, is rated a realistic hope of ousting established punter Donnie Jones.
"Johnston has a legitimate chance to unseat veteran incumbent Donnie Jones, who had a superb season in 2016 but is also 37 years-old," Nick Fierro, of , wrote.
"Johnston would bring an Australian Rules skill set - namely incredible directional and distance-controlled kicks - to the position after spending four years proving himself at Ohio State, where the weather can be just as nasty as it is here in the fall and winter."
JORDAN BERRY (punter, Pittsburgh Steelers)
Arguably the most established Australian player in the NFL, Berry looks in no danger of losing his job as the Steelers punter.
He improved considerably on his rookie year to average over 45 yards per punt last season and Pittsburgh haven't bothered to bring in another punter to challenge him in pre-season.
"Twenty-five of Berry's 68 punting attempts landed inside the 20 last season. After beating out Brad Wing two camps ago, Berry hasn't done anything to put his job in jeopardy,"
BRAD WING (punter, New York Giants)
Like Berry, Wing is well established as a No.1 punter and his job looks safe.
In fact, the 26-year-old is being talked up as a contender for Pro Bowl selection this season.
Wing averaged 46.2 yards per punt last season, with 28 of his 93 punts downed inside the 20-yard line.
Dan Duggan, , wrote: "Giants coach Ben McAdoo referred to punter Brad Wing as a "weapon" multiple times last season.
"The moniker fit, as Wing gave the Giants a tactical advantage in the field-position battle. The 26-year-old former undrafted free agent raised his profile last season. If Wing takes his game to the next level this season, he'll truly be a powerful weapon.
"The Giants aren't messing with a good thing. They didn't even bring in an undrafted free agent punter to challenge Wing this spring. Wing could have long-term job security if he builds on a strong 2016 season."
Wing's profile is clearly on the rise, as evidenced by his
LACHLAN EDWARDS (punter, New York Jets)
Edwards made the Jets punting job his own but is perhaps the punter under most selection pressure of the current Australian crop.
He averaged 43.1 yards per punt and had 24 insides 20s last season but has been working with Aussie punting great Darren Bennett to up his game.
He noted much improved leg power and greater mental strength in a recent interview with USA Today.
"I think it's just a confidence thing right now. I trained pretty hard in the off-season, but noticeably it's a confidence thing when I'm out there. I know what's expected and what to do, so I've been punting a lot better just with a different mindset." he said.
The early season will be make-or-break for Edwards, according to
"After a disappointing rookie year, Edwards needs to show significant improvement - or else the Jets will be looking for a new punter," he wrote.
ADAM GOTSIS (defensive tackle, Adam Gotsis)
Gotsis, whose rookie season in 2016-17 came on the back of a serious knee injury, suffered a recent minor setback when he underwent arthroscopic knee surgery in June.
However the defensive end's workload is now gradually being increased and he saw his first team-period reps of training camp this week.
How much he's used in pre-season remains to be seen but big things are expected of the 2016 second round draftee, who has caught the eye recently for a stunning,
"Last year when he came in, he was coming off that ACL and I don't feel like he had the opportunity to train physically in the off-season and get prepared for his rookie season," Broncos defensive co-ordinator Joe Woods said last month.
"When you look at him now, he looks like a new person. I watch him through drills. He has great athleticism for his size and he's built like a superhero. He's doing great things for us right now."

Gotsis looking active in 9-on-7 work, doing a nice job shedding blocks and working into the backfield against the run.
BLAKE MUIR (offensive guard, Indianapolis Colts)
The dizzying journey of aspiring offensive guard Muir continues with the Colts, his fourth team in little more than a year.
The Sydney product spent time with San Francisco and Green Bay before joining the practice squad of Super Bowl runners-up Atlanta late last season.
Muir is locked in a battle with as many as six other hopefuls to push for a spot in an offensive line unit tasked with offering much-improved protection for Andrew Luck this season.
DAVID YANKEY (offensive guard, Carolina Panthers)
After several season on the fringe of selection at Minnesota, Sydney-born Yankey broke through for his NFL debut last year, making six late-season appearances for the Panthers.
According to local reports, his chances of sticking to the roster for the upcoming season appear slim but he should get a decent chance to make an impact in pre-season.
He's also under an injury cloud at the moment, with an apparent upper body injury keeping him out of practice this week.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro Bowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steelers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arizona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Ridgway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Cowboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gotsis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Fierro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BLAKE MUIR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie NFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OHIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Duggan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolina Panthers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pittsburgh Steelers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Bowls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben McAdoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JORDAN BERRY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-born Yankey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indianapolis Colts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Luck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Gotsis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donnie Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rules</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Irwin-Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardinals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-five of Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA TODAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muir</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irwin-Hill, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ohio State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mat McBriar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAMERON JOHNSTON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Wing</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAVID YANKEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minnesota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LACHLAN EDWARDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlanta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prokick Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pittsburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irwin-Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
