<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418112344132229</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/boxing/paulie-malignaggi-lifts-lid-on-sparring-conor-mcgregor/news-story/57378ff84e7e43e08bfe1dba30cad29d</url>
  <title>Paulie Malignaggi lifts lid on sparring Conor McGregor</title>
  <content>
Conor McGregor spars with Paulie Malignaggi.

Share

SO much for Paulie Malignaggi's "sparring details stay in the gym" code.
The brash-talking retired boxer has lifted the lid on his most recent sparring session with Conor McGregor - a 12-round brawl that got seriously personal.
The New York-based two-time world champion flew to Las Vegas for the second time this week to help the UFC superstar prepare for his upcoming fight against Floyd Mayweather.
We'll let Malignaggi take it from here on what went down.
"We had 12 rounds of sparring last night. It was good work, hard work. I actually wasn't too thrilled that they wanted me to go twelve rounds 24 hours after getting off a cross country flight," said Malignaggi, on his podcast From Brooklyn To The World.
"Especially when I hadn't worked all last week, so I wasn't thrilled and I kinda came into the gym last night with a bit of a chip on my shoulder and the sparring got intense, it got heated.
"We went 12 hard rounds and I think I made my point last night, I'll say that. Basically, don't f*** with me. I'm here to help, I'm here to do the best I can for you guys, so don't try to take advantage of me. Don't try to make like you're running a two-time world champion out of your camp or whatnot.
"Honestly I questioned last night whether I could go 12 rounds and the first five rounds of back-and-forth action, I wasn't really sure I could go the full 12. Then as we got to round six, he started fading a little bit and that's when I really tried to dig in there and that's when I said you know what I'm going to stay in here, I got a point to make tonight.
"I managed to last until about 12, but in rounds 11 and 12 he came back and put it on me. I just totally gassed out in the eleventh and twelfth. So we returned the favours to each other last night."

An image from Conor McGregor's first sparring session with Paulie Malignaggi.Source:Instagram
Malignaggi's revelations are backed by reports from those in attendance at the sessions about the intense nature of the to-and-fro.
Irish boxer Tiernan Bradley - who along with former Manny Pacquiao sparring partner Dashon Johnson and MMA fighter Frans Mlambo have been sparring McGregor - said "The Notorious" was taking a different attitude towards his time with Malignaggi.
"I was in Paulie's corner and although he hasn't fought since March and is retired, he's getting sharper by the day," wrote Bradley, in a column for the .
"You can see he's still a class operator, and it was an interesting spar to watch - more a full on fight actually. Conor told us all when Paulie came into camp 'this is not a spar, I want to fight him. I'm ready for a war' ...
"Paulie was talking to him in between rounds, trying to give him advice, but then he was getting slapped in the face."
Veteran boxing referee Joe Cortez has been officiating the sparring and has had to play peacemaker at times.
"They were both roughing each other up and I had to stop the action, like it was a regular fight," said Cortez.
"They were holding too much, they were trying to punch each other. I mean, it got a little bit out of control where I had to call, 'Time, all right guys, you've got to stop this now. I want a good, clean round. Give me sportsmanlike conduct, understand?'"

Elba: McGregor to floor Floyd
0:54

UFC: Star actor Idris Elba is backing in Conor McGregor to beat Floyd Mayweather in their fight of the century in August.

August 2nd 2017
a day ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/More Sports/

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulie Malignaggi.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dashon Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malignaggi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brooklyn To</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulie Malignaggi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cortez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Idris Elba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Cortez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frans Mlambo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiernan Bradley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manny Pacquiao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
