<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418412991848029</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/trumps-talk-of-complimentary-phone-calls-not-true/8770710</url>
  <title>Donald Trump did not lie about Boys Scouts and Mexican President's praise, White House says</title>
  <content>
The White House says US President Donald Trump did not lie about compliments he received from the Mexican President and the Boy Scouts of America, but they were delivered in person and not by phone as he claimed.
Mr Trump last week said he received a phone call from "from the head of the Boy Scouts" telling him a  "was the ".
The organisation's boss has apologised "to those in our Scouting family who were offended by the political rhetoric that was inserted into the jamboree" and another senior figure .
Earlier this week Mr Trump, said his Mexican counterpart Enrique Pena Nieto had also called him and praised his immigration policies.
"They said their southern border, very few people are coming because they know they're not going to get through our border, which is the ultimate compliment," Mr Trump said.
Responding to questions about a statement from the Mexican Government denying what Mr Trump described and the Boy Scouts being unaware of a phone call having been made, White House spokeswoman Sarah Huckabee Sanders defended the President.
"I wouldn't say it was a lie. That's a pretty bold accusation," Ms Sanders said.
"The conversations took place, they just simply didn't take place over a phone call ... he had them in person."
Ms Sanders said Mr Trump was making reference to "multiple members of the Boy Scout leadership" who "congratulated him, praised him and offered quite powerful compliments following his speech".
But she acknowledged no member of the leadership called the President.
Similarly, Ms Sanders said Mr Trump referenced a conversation the presidents "had at the G20 summit where they specifically talked about the issues that he referenced".
Mexico's Foreign Relations Department said Mr Pena Nieto remarked to Mr Trump during a July 7 meeting at the  that deportations of Mexicans from the US had fallen 31 per cent between January and June, as compared with 2016.
Mr Pena Nieto said 47 per cent fewer Central American migrants had entered Mexico in that period.
Mr Trump's suggestion that he and Mr Pena Nieto had spoken by phone became an issue in Mexico, where opposition politicians jumped on Mr Trump's account and complained about what sounded like a "secret phone call" between the pair.
Mexico has officially opposed many of Mr Trump's initiatives, including his claim that Mexico would .
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enrique Pena Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JULY 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Scouts of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Scout</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pena Nieto</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican President</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sanders</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico's Foreign Relations Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
