<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417768746743453</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/gay-marriage/turnbulls-political-striptease-over-gay-marriage-debate/news-story/c32de15803f2a3208f5fe13a7d419ecc</url>
  <title>Turnbull's political striptease over gay marriage debate</title>
  <content>
The emperor is increasingly wearing less clothes. (AAP Image/Richard Wainwright)

Share

COMMENT
It's been an absorbing political striptease as Malcolm Turnbull sheds layers of commitments in the bump and grind of the same-sex marriage debate.
It has reached the point where Labor is accusing the Prime Minister of standing naked before voters without the decency of leadership and principle.
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten today was referring to Mr Turnbull when he said there were people "too timid to work to back in their beliefs".
He said: "Everybody knows what Mr Turnbull thinks. He supports marriage equality. What they hate is he's too weak to do anything about it."
One example of the political undressing has been on the tradition of crossing the floor to vote against party policy.
Mr Turnbull did it in 2010 when he supported Labor's emissions trading scheme.
And late last month he basted the conscience vote was a proud part of Liberal tradition.
"In our party, backbenchers have always had the right to cross the floor," he said. "In the Labor Party you get expelled for that."

But suddenly what had been considered a clear right became an act of treachery, and back benchers who might cross the floor on same-sex marriage were told by Liberal figures they might lose their party endorsement next election.
Mr Turnbull did not reject the threat.
The Prime Minister has declined to comment on Immigration Minister Peter Dutton's suggestion of a national postal vote on changes to the Marriage Act.
"I talk to my colleagues all the time and we often have discussions about policy issues and they are best done privately in the party room. I'm not going to get into a public debate about internal party issues and discussions here," was all he would say of the idea recently.
But in 1997, when Mr Turnbull led the push got a republic, he had firm views on postal ballots, calling them insecure.
"A postal ballot of necessity will only reach voters who are living at the address recorded on the electoral roll," Mr Turnbull wrote at the time.
"Out of 11.8 million voters, it is estimated by the Australian Electoral Commission that as many as one million will have changed addresses since the last electoral roll was finalised."
The cause of the commitment shedding, at least in public comment, is that Mr Turnbull knows his opponents on same-sex marriage and the plebiscite proposal are prepared to remove him from office, and even bring about the entire government's downfall. They are ruthless and savage.
Former Prime Minister Tony Abbott, who has been sniping at his successor since 2016, on Wednesday held him personally accountable should any Coalition MPs cross the floor.
"For them to cross the floor to try to ensure the Parliament does [debate marriage equality], that is a real breach of faith with the public," Mr Abbott said. "It's obviously a dramatic loss of discipline inside the government and it's a serious attack on the authority of the leadership."
That's the state of current Liberal dynamics on marriage policy, but there is a longer-term problem for the Prime Minister.
That is whether the voters will see him making concessions to keep the peace, or merely disrobing shamelessly.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Image/Richard Wainwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Electoral Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
