<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418584790542597</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/brave-song-addictive-nature-set-for-showdown-at-randwick/news-story/55963b50dba62c1532ce41025fa00fe8</url>
  <title>Top colts on song for showdown</title>
  <content>
CALCULATED and Siege Of Quebec went toe to toe in a two-horse war down the Rosehill straight three weeks ago and now another two classy colts are set for a mighty battle at Royal Randwick on Saturday.
Addictive Nature ($2.30) and impressive last-start winner Brave Song ($3.20) dominate the betting in the www.walking2help.com.au Sprint (1200m) and bookies have labelled it a race in two.
RACE WATCH:
FRIDAY PREVIEW:
Brave Song was a dominant winner at Canterbury, while Addictive Nature, a full-brother to dual Group winner Savvy Nature, won comfortably on debut at Warwick Farm and has been spruiked as the real deal for some time.
"It was a good effort on debut and his work since has been really good," trainer Bjorn Baker said. "He just got a little bit wound up on debut but he normally has a great attitude and is relaxed so expect to see him a little bit more laid-back on Saturday.
"He is a good-looking horse and he has done everything right, so I'm looking forward to the weekend. It's early days and he has only won a race and it's just one step at a time.
"The horse has to do the talking at the end of the day and we will see more on Saturday."
Addictive Nature has already attracted a $1000 bet at $26 for September's  and Baker admits he is a likeable horse.
"He was a $775,000 (yearling purchase) from New Zealand and he has a pedigree and is a good-looking horse," he said. "He is a very fast horse already, particularly for a Savabeel. My gut feel is he has a lot of speed and he will be effective over the short course but if he can stay he is going to be a super stayer.
"We are probably a little bit ahead of where we need to be in terms of going towards the Golden Rose, so we will just take it one step at a time. But hopefully everything goes well enough so we can consider that race."
Brave Song was edged out by Calculated on debut but his recent Canterbury win was dominant.
Co-trainer Paul Snowden said he hasn't taken a backwards step since. "I know there are raps on (Addictive Nature) as well and it just ups the ante a bit to see where they sit among it," he said. "His next step, if he can bounce off this, is definitely up to Listed grade."
Bookies might see it as a two-horse race but there is a bit of depth to the Benchmark 70 3YO Handicap.
Solar Patch bolted in first-up at Gosford at his only start as a gelding, Regimen could not have been more impressive on debut at the same track and Wild Heart caught the eye last start and isn't hopeless either.
The Mighty Fed has also won two from three starts albeit against weaker company, while Funoon clocked the best late splits of the day first-up when flashing home to run second at Wyong.Tango Rain back in the game
TANGO Rain will make his much anticipated return to the track at Royal Randwick on Saturday after suffering a virus in the autumn where he had a high temperature for five days.
Tango Rain hasn't raced since last September and trainer Gerald Ryan revealed just how sick the four-year-old was after contracting a virus last campaign
"He was coming back for the autumn and after his second trial he copped a virus and he was crook for quite a while," Ryan said. "He trialled on one of those days when it was 40 degrees and a couple of them got crook and he got really got crook.
"He had a temperature and viral thing and it took five days for (his temperature) to come down even on heavy treatment."
Ryan gave Tango Rain a decent break and he won a recent Rosehill trial in dominant fashion before his return in the Benchmark 80 Handicap (1000m). The four-year-old had form around Star Turn last spring and is extremely quick out of the barriers.
"He has definitely got the ability to be a stakes horse if he races OK and if he hasn't taken any ill effects from the virus," Ryan said. "He seems all right and his bloods are good and he is bright and well in himself and he is working good.
"He appears to have come up good and it will be interesting to see how he goes under race conditions after such a long time (without a race start)."
Meanwhile, Ryan will also saddle up Harper's Choice in the Missile Stakes (1200m). The four-year-old hasn't raced since running second in the Group 1 Australian Derby in the autumn.
"He has come back well and he is very forward," Ryan said. "It will be too short for him (Saturday) but he is kicking off and then he goes to 1400m in a couple of weeks' time and then we decide whether we push out to 2000m or keep him fresh for the Epsom."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tango Rain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epsom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sprint (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerald Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benchmark 70 3YO Handicap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosehill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FRIDAY PREVIEW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siege Of Quebec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Turn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savabeel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-trainer Paul Snowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1 Australian Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wild Heart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benchmark 80 Handicap (1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Funoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brave Song ($3.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bjorn Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong.Tango Rain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savvy Nature</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper's Choice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addictive Nature</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mighty Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nature ($2.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
