<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418374337141794</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/fremantle-coach-ross-lyon-wont-speculate-on-mitch-mcgoverns-future/news-story/6ea49692dabeba23eb3e32b781a4b338</url>
  <title>Lyon won't speculate on McGovern future</title>
  <content>
COACH Ross Lyon says it's not appropriate to speculate on whether Fremantle are pursuing Adelaide forward Mitch McGovern.
There has been growing speculation that the Dockers have put a lucrative offer to McGovern, whose father Andrew played 63 games for Fremantle in the 90s.
McGovern, who is the younger brother of West Coast star Jeremy, is coming out of contract at the end of the season and is yet to recommit to the Crows.
"It's really difficult, I don't really deal in hypotheticals," Lyon said. "I'd love Wayne Carey here playing. There's plenty of names about. Speculation and that, it's not appropriate.
"We're respectful of other clubs but there was speculation about (Nat) Fyfe so it goes on. It's really not my role and it's certainly not an appropriate time with respect, I'm not in a position to answer that anyway."
Lyon also wouldn't be drawn on whether the Dockers met with players from opposition clubs during the season, amid reports McGovern's teammate Jake Lever has met with Melbourne.
The real tribunal bad boys

"I can put a fine point on it, I'm here to talk about the game and the players," he said. "I respect your interest in player movement but it's not my strong suit. "There's list mangers, CEOs and subcommittees that deal with that and as a rule we don't conduct that business at press conferences leading into home and away games so I'll continue on with that train of thinking I think."
Lyon said they were working through who would replace rising star Connor Blakely, whose season is over due to shoulder surgery, against the Gold Coast at Domain Stadium on Saturday night, with Ryan Nyhuis a chance to return to the side.
He confirmed they were considering resting exciting first-year ruckman Sean Darcy against the Suns.
"We're making noise about it, we'll have a look at it today," Lyon said. "He's really keen to play but Jon Griffin is fit and available and it's how he hits his markers today. If he was short on ... we would manage him. At some point we've acknowledged that he needs to be managed, this might be the week, we're hopeful it's not, but it might be."
Lyon said his young players would benefit from taking on Gary Ablett, if he makes the trip.
"He is great, I love him," he said. "I don't think we'll tag him but we'll deal with it when it comes.
"Maybe at some point we can get a Lachie Weller to him, he'll know he's alive. Lachie's really capable himself. Back him in and he can get the ball and run and spread. He's a beautiful kick so they're the moments along the way that help."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Nyhuis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fyfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Ablett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Blakely</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Darcy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Weller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
