<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418550430803612</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/open-for-inspection-homes-aug-3-9/3208495/</url>
  <title>Open for inspection homes Aug 3 - 9</title>
  <content>
Centrally located within the Oceanside precinct in Birtinya, these well-appointed turn key contemporary terrace homes won't be available for long. All properties display a functional design that provides good separation of living areas to bedrooms. Ranging in size from 167sq m to 200sq m all of the homes boast four spacious bedrooms, two bathrooms and double lock up garage.
Some of the larger floor plans also include a study upstairs and separate powder room downstairs. The 2700 high ceilings and the open plan design to downstairs living areas provides you with a light and spacious indoor/outdoor entertainment area to enjoy with guests. You will be spoilt for choice to find a quiet spot for yourself with three tiled balconies upstairs to choose from.
This low maintenance living opportunity is situated within walking distance to the new Sunshine Coast University Hospital and within five minutes drive to world class Kawana beach providing you with an unmatched Sunshine Coast lifestyle.
New homes within Kawana region are a highly sought after commodity in the current market and this is a rare opportunity to secure a brand new home to settle into prior to Christmas or acquire a great new addition to any investment portfolio.
These properties are currently under construction by a well-recognized, reputable Sunshine Coast builder Thompson Sustainable Homes which are due to be completed in October 2017. Some of the many features highlighted in the property are Euromaid Stainless Steel appliances and stone benchtops to kitchen; split system air-conditioning and ceiling fans through; security screens to all windows and doors.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euromaid Stainless Steel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson Sustainable Homes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birtinya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 3 - 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oceanside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
