<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418292732761815</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/australian-cricket-has-finally-reached-a-pay-deal-with-the-players-2017-8</url>
  <title>Australian cricket has finally reached a pay deal with the players</title>
  <content>
The long-running pay dispute between Cricket Australian and the players association is over.

The warring groups are set to announce a heads of agreement at media conference scheduled for 4.30pm today.

The deal comes just before Australia's tour of Bangladesh, which only a few days ago Australian captain Steve Smith was in doubt if the pay dispute was not resolved. Players have effectively been unemployed since the old agreement expired on June 30.

It's rumoured that the key sticking point - a share of revenue - has been resolved, with the players getting a cut in what would be a major concession for the game's administrators.

Last week Cricket Australia CEO James Sutherland said that a "peace plan" has been put forward to the Australian Cricketers' Association so matches to go ahead on short term contracts, and it looked like the two sides would end up in arbitration before the lucrative Ashes test series got underway in Australia this summer.

We'll update this story when we have more details from the official announcement.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia CEO James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
