<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418460236488949</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/accounting/aicd-appoints-angus-armour-as-ceo-reveals-he-could-earn-up-to-735000-20170803-gxon4s</url>
  <title>AICD appoints Angus Armour as CEO, reveals he could earn up to $735,000</title>
  <content>
The Australian Institute of Company Directors has appointed Angus Armour as its new CEO and managing director and revealed he could earn up to $735,000 in the role.
Mr Armour is currently principal adviser at the Business Council of Australia and was Deputy Secretary of the NSW Department of Trade and Investment between 2013 and 2015. He also spent a decade at the Export Finance and Insurance Corporation.
He replaces a role that has been vacant since . 
Mr Amour's salary will be made up of $525,00 in base pay with a potential bonus of up to 40 per cent based on as yet undefined key performance indicators. These benchmarks will be determined before he takes up the role in October.

He said he looked "forward to continuing the AICD's crucial work further improving the knowledge and skills of current and potential company directors."

The disclosure of Mr Amour's salary comes after AICD chairman Elizabeth Proust  because their contracts had contained confidentiality clauses.
Ms Proust said that these clauses were not good governance practice at a body which has the core mission of corporate governance and governance education and that she would end the practice.
Transparency of CEO and executive pay has become a key test of governance at member bodies after the implosion at CPA Australia, which was fuelled in part by an initial lack of disclosure over  and the amount paid to senior management.
Ms Proust said the AICD is still deciding if the body would break out the pay of key management personnel as is done in the reports of listed companies.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Proust</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Amour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insurance Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Trade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Proust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Secretary of the NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Armour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AICD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angus Armour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Export Finance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
