<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418498891195253</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4825514/academy-equestrians-sights-on-olympics/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>IAS equestrian talent Emily Lord</title>
  <content>
- Emily Lord
Emily Lord

Big ambitions: Illawarra Academy of Sport scholarship holder Emily Lord hopes to represent Australia in dressage at a future Olympics.
Sports Program Lonestar - Equestrian    
Club/Association: Berkeley Pony Club    
Why did you apply for an IAS scholarship? I applied for an Academy Scholarship to help me become more rounded as an elite equestrian rider. I wish to compete at the Olympics in dressage and believe the IAS will be a great stepping stone in my journey and provide me with the skill set to achieve my success.                      
Who's your favourite professional athlete and why? My favourite athlete is Charlotte Dujardin who is also the current Olympic Dressage champion. She seems so well rounded as a person which is a quality that I like in her. In winning the Olympics, Charlotte broke the world record for the highest dressage score ever.                               
If you weren't playing this sport what would you be doing and why? I played many sports throughout my early years which I loved, however my favourite passion has always been riding horses. My mum always had horses and both my sister and I started riding when we were very young.
How would you describe yourself in one sentence? I am outgoing with a bold personality who loves having fun.                             
What are your plans beyond school? After school, I would like to go to University, while also pursuing my sporting dream to represent Australia at the Olympics. 
If you could live anywhere in the world it would be? I would love to live in Europe. Equestrian competitions are strong in Europe and for me to represent at the highest level this is where I hope to be one day riding with a great trainer.
What do you do in your free time? I don't have a lot of free time due to my horse commitments and school, however when I'm free I love spending time with my friends.      
What is your favourite subject at school? My favourite subject at school is maths.          
What is your greatest achievement in your sport so far? My greatest achievement so far is winning the Australasian Grand National Championships in 2016. This is one of the highest honours in my sport, where I defeated some of the best show horses across Australia and New Zealand, many ridden by professional riders.    
When did you start playing your sport and how did you get started? I have played netball since an early age so would try and make a representative level if I wasn't riding.

Unfortunately, time doesn't allow me to concentrate too much on netball, but I do really enjoy playing it.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlotte Dujardin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Dressage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlotte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasian Grand National Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Academy of Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy Scholarship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Lord</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club/Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Program Lonestar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berkeley Pony Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
