<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417472393995815</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/business/work/amazon-to-bring-hundreds-of-jobs-to-melbourne/news-story/77ad4103c794345194ec528321a8ed59</url>
  <title>Now's your chance to work for Amazon</title>
  <content>
AMAZON will bring "hundreds" of jobs to Melbourne with the opening of its first Australian fulfilment centre in Dandenong South.
The e-commerce giant officially announced the location on Thursday, following  the industrial area had been chosen after a number warehouse, logistics and supply jobs were advertised online.
The company said it would  for a range of roles including operations managers, pickers, packers, systems technicians and HR specialists.
"We are thrilled to be creating hundreds of new roles in Dandenong South," Robert Bruce, Amazon's director of operations for Australia said in a statement.
"This is just the start. Over time, we will bring thousands of new jobs to Australia and millions of dollars of investment as well as opening up the opportunity for thousands of Australian businesses to sell at home and abroad through Amazon Marketplace."
Jobs previously advertised included manual labour positions for "physical warehouse activities", which, "depending on the type of job", would require "lifting and moving material up to 16kg each" and "standing and walking for up to 10-12 hours a day" in a building more than 400 metres long,  .
An Amazon spokeswoman said an announcement on the opening date would be made in the future. "Please stay tuned," she said. "People who are interested in a role should visit www.amazon.jobs."
The 24,000 square metre fulfilment centre is located in the Pellicano's M2 Industry Park, close to the South Gippsland Highway, Monash Highway and EastLink. Amazon said the lease was arranged through commercial real estate firm CBRE.
"This new fulfilment centre will stock hundreds of thousands of products which will be available for delivery to customers across Australia when we launch our retail offering," Mr Bruce said. "We will be focusing on offering our Australian customers low prices on a great selection of products and can't wait to get started."
In a statement, Victorian Industry Minister Wade Noonan said Amazon was the "the latest global company to choose Victoria for its Australian operations". "The company's decision to locate its centre in Dandenong South will create hundreds of local jobs and open up retail opportunities for thousands of local businesses," he said.
Amazon Web Services launched locally in 2012 and Amazon launched a Kindle Store on Amazon.com.au in 2013. Amazon already has nearly 1000 employees in Australia.
Earlier this year, Morgan Stanley warned that the "Amazon Effect"  from the earnings of listed chains including JB Hi-Fi and Harvey Norman, but said the biggest hit would be to Wesfarmers.
The retail giant, which owns Target and Kmart, could lose more than $428 million in earnings by 2026. The report said department stores would be the sector worst hit, as Amazon generates up to $12 billion in sales by 2026.

The world's largest online retailer is coming to Australia, so how is Amazon's physical presence going to change our retail landscape?

How will Amazon change Australian retail?
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kindle Store</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pellicano's M2 Industry Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kmart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Hi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Effect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesfarmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBRE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Web Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Gippsland Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong South</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Industry Minister Wade Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
