<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417429444321609</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/norwegian-nationalist-facebook-group-mistakes-empty-bus-seats-for-women-in-burqas-2017-8</url>
  <title>Norwegian nationalist Facebook group mistakes empty bus seats for women in burqas</title>
  <content>
A Facebook group run by anti-immigrant Norwegians has been mocked for mistaking empty bus seats for women in Islamic dress.

Pictures of the bus were posted to  (Norwegian for "Fatherland first"), a closed Facebook group, with the caption: "What do people think about this?"

Responses to the posts (translated from Norwegian) included:

"It looks really scary, should be banned. You can never know who is under there. Could be terrorists with weapons."

And:

"Get them out of our country."

The post was up for at least a day before admins of the group realised and apparently removed it.

, an advertising executive from Oslo, took screenshots of the post and published them on his Facebook page.

In an interview with Business Insider, he said Fedrelandet viktigst "produces a lot of fake news, spreads xenophobia and attacks Islam in particular."

Beyer said he was a member for some time "undercover" but has since been kicked out.

Fedrelandet viktigst took the post down after they realised their mistake, according to Beyer.

Norway's parliament is currently considering a total ban on facial coverings in schools.

Most parties support the bill, which is expected to pass in 2018, the BBC reported. It would make Norway the first Nordic country to ban facial veils.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norwegian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fedrelandet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nordic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oslo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
