<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418374337141769</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/football/socceroos/socceroos-world-cup-news-mile-jedinak-injury-qualifiers-v-thailand-japan/news-story/1d35e0a6f96230ebe52444764259013f</url>
  <title>Socceroos' seismic World Cup blow looms</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN captain Mile Jedinak's hopes of appearing in a Socceroos shirt for World Cup qualifiers with Japan and Thailand appear dashed.
Jedinak is still troubled by the same groin issue that ruled him out of June's Confederations Cup.
The combative midfielder, who turned 33 on Thursday, will miss Aston Villa's Championship season-opener with Hull City this weekend.
Villa coach Steve Bruce confirmed on Thursday the ex-Crystal Palace skipper would be out for "a couple of weeks".

Football: Watch every goal from Wednesday's FFA Cup fixtures

FFA Cup night three goals
A club statement said Jedinak was "in light training but is still approximately two weeks away from being available".
Given Socceroos coach Ange Postecoglou must name his squad at least two weeks before the August 31 qualifier with Japan, Jedinak is in grave doubt of missing the cut.
Jedinak was last sighted in club colours in April in Villa's 1-0 win over arch rivals Birmingham City.
With their season petering out, Villa then allowed Jedinak to rest for a busy June of national team action.
Jedinak returned to help Australia defeat Saudi Arabia in their must-win qualifier but was subsequently ruled out of the Confederations Cup in Russia. He returned to England and underwent groin surgery in early July, missing Villa's pre-season.
His rehabilitation timeline leaves Postecoglou in a tricky place. The national team boss has been a firm adherent to his "form and fitness" mantra, which gives credence to players firing at club level ahead of reputation.
But Postecoglou could be light on players for the matches against Japan and Thailand.
He has already signalled he is unlikely to pick any A-League players for his squad given the long off-season break.
Tim Cahill and Mark Milligan, recently signed by Melbourne Victory, are likely exceptions to this rule.
When Jedinak does return to fitness he is expected to fill a crucial role at club level.
Villa are the favourites to be promoted to the English Premier League this season, having signed former England captain John Terry to bolster their title hopes.
Bruce suggested the cost to add Terry to their squad would mean losing "one or two" players, but it's unlikely Jedinak would be one of those.
"We've had to box a little bit clever," he told the club's website. "I'm on no doubt that there will be a few people that might still leave the football club." Australia currently sits third in their qualifying group.
The top two places progress to Russia while a third-place finish would send the Socceroos on a tricky repechage pathway.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Milligan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confederations Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Victory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Cahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June's Confederations Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Postecoglou</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday's FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birmingham City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ange Postecoglou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hull City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aston Villa's Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jedinak</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mile Jedinak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
