<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418632035183620</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/business/breaking-news/shares-hit-fresh-record-xero-at-new-high/news-story/0371bf2663dbce336e7f4baed0ac13f3</url>
  <title>Shares hit fresh record, Xero at new high</title>
  <content>
New Zealand shares hit a fresh record on Thursday, with retailers Kathmandu and Briscoe gaining on positive earnings, while Xero hit a new high.
The S&P/NZX50 Index rose 5.44 points, or 0.07 per cent, to 7753.75. Within the index, 30 stocks rose, 12 fell and eight were unchanged. Turnover was $225.4 million.
"We're up nearly 13 per cent for the year, a very good performance and we've set up some quite high expectations going into reporting season," said Mark Lister, head of private wealth research at Craigs Investment Partners.
"People are watching the global reporting season continue. It's gone very well and our reporting season has kicked off in a minor way but really gets going the week after next."
Freightways was the best performer, up 2.1 per cent to $8.15, while Vector gained 1.8 per cent to $3.40 and CBL Corp gained 1.6 per cent to $3.75.
Kathmandu rose 0.9 per cent to $2.28. Full-year profit rose as much as 13 per cent to $37.4 million after a successful winter sales season and increased revenue from Australia.
Kathmandu shares have climbed 29 per cent in the past 12 months, outpacing a 6.4 per cent gain for the NZX 50 Index.
Xero rose 0.5 per cent to $27.80, marking eight consecutive sessions of gains and another record price.
"It continues to run very well and has had a pretty strong week - up 7 per cent so far," Mr Lister said. "It's up 59 per cent this year, in the top three stocks for the NZX50 and having another good day today."
TradeMe Group was the worst performer, down 4.2 per cent to $5.23.
Outside the benchmark index, Briscoe Group gained 0.7 per cent to $4.09. The retailer saw slower sales growth than expected in the second quarter.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBL Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Briscoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/NZX 50 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Briscoe Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xero</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Lister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigs Investment Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZX 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TradeMe Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathmandu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freightways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZX 50 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
