<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417906185698729</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/shopping/the-sale-whisperer-sydneys-best-shopping-august-411-20170801-gxn77a.html</url>
  <title>The Sale Whisperer: Sydney's best shopping August 4-11</title>
  <content>
With brands preparing for the new season there are less sales about this week. But don't fret, there's plenty of excellent shopping to be had.
This includes the new Acne Studios second store in the CBD and Birkenhead Point's new luxury offering which featured in . And have you ever wanted to own a piece of Zoe Foster Blake's wardrobe? Well now you can, sort of! The super-human (is there anything she can't do?) launched her first fashion collaboration with Skin and Thread next week. Photo: SuppliedSales Guide

Australian premium fashion curator, Order of Style is holding another online sale with up to 70 per cent off selected styles, and an additional 10 percent (code: EXTRA10) off if you shop in the first week. The sale will feature the sites signature brands including Camilla and Marc, American Vintage, IRO, Mother, Paige and Mara Hoffman.

It's the last week of 's pop-up sale, with the Parisian inspired Australian brand, renowned for its signature flares and eyelet pieces, offering up to 80 per cent off resort 17 and spring 17 at Westfield Sydney.
Till August 10

Offering an ethereal world of femininity and fantasy, Tutu De Monde is currently having an online final sale with up to 60 per cent off their signature tutus, dresses and accessories. Stocking sizes 1 to 12, the label is designed with aspiring ballerinas in mind.

You will now receive updates from

Daily Life Newsletter

Daily Life Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Till Stocks last.

Dream Within a Dream: Tutu du Monde

Gardening enthusiasts, this sale is for you. housed within the Royal Botanic Gardens, is selling 18,000 pot plants this weekend from the winter floral display, All About Followers. The colourful collection, which includes hydrangeas and orchids, can be purchased from $1-$10, with the sale running from 8am to noon on Saturday, or until the plants sell out. It's advised to take cash, and all the proceeds from the sale will go towards the , which supports conservation, horticulture and education programs.
Saturday 5, 8am-12pm.

The current Calyx exhibition will finish this Saturday before the plants are sold off to make room for the September display. Photo: Edwina Pickles

Renowned for their eye-popping prints and novelty designs, Australian brand Gorman currently has 20-50 per cent off all of their winter styles including clothing, shoes and accessories from their Starry Eyed, Love Lust and Fable collections. 
For a limited time only. 
Online boutique Esther still has 80 per cent off on wardrobe essentials in their end of season sale. The sale includes winter clothing and accessories from Finders Keepers, Blessed Are the Meek, Jetset Diaries, Grace and Hart and more, as well as home decor and gifts.
 Till stocks run out.
Just Opened
For more than 20 years, Swedish label  has cultivated itself in the fashion industry as minimalistic and innovative, yet timeless; which are the exact design elements found in their second Sydney store, which opened last week.
Following the original space in Paddington, shoppers can expect to find the label's experimental textures, tones and silhouettes in the new 390 square metre CBD store.
Creating an "alternate universe" in the inspired L-shaped store, stainless steel walls and yellow hues dominate- a design ethos that unifies their design spaces worldwide. The stores' windows and ceilings have been lowered, and it features 700 lighting fixtures. Steel fixtures work harmoniously with organic benches and stools.
"We opened our first store in Sydney in 2009 and since then the Australian market has been very close to our hearts," said Acne Chairman Mikael Schiller.
 "Now it feels great to open a large second store in the central of Sydney, the space being a good representation of the present day Acne Studios universe."
, Monday to Wednesday, Friday 10am-7pm, Thursday, 10am-9pm, Saturday and Sunday 10am-7pm.

The Acne Studios is on the corner of King and Elizabeth St. Photo: Supplied

Just Launched

The ultimate Australian slashie has now added fashion designer to her colourful CV, alongside author, app guru and skin care brand creator. Making her debut in the fashion world, Zoe Foster Blake has added her signature flair to a collection in collaboration with Melbourne-based label.
The 'flothes' as Zoe dubbed them on Instagram (a cross between food and clothes) have a nostalgic 80s and 90s Australian undertone, and give us the opportunity to add a little bit of Zoe's effervescence to our wardrobe. The pieces feature her favourite foods, animals and lifestyle, think Iced Vovo jumpers, retro-inspired graphic tees, a graphic tee with 'Chips' written in red glitter and oversize wool knits featuring giant cockatoos (her "good luck omen") and lobsters.
"Skin and Threads offered me the chance to do anything  in our collaboration and I was sure my taste would be too fruity. But no! I was given total freedom to have my ideas sartorially realised," said Foster Blake.
"I selfishly made the collection something I would want to wear,here's hoping my love of bright colours, lobsters and hot chips translates."
While the 17-piece capsule collection does have an element of novelty, it also includes current trending silhouettes and wardrobe staples including a gingham trench coat, high-waisted cropped jeans and metallic pleated skirts perfect for weekend adventures or making a statement at your next event. You can shop the pre-sale now on the Skin and Threads website, with the full collection available in six  stores nationwide and the brand's Myer concessions from Monday August 7.

Zoe Foster Blake wearing the Trench Coat and Melbourne At Night Logo Tee from the collection. Photo: Supplied

#inthecart

​Friday, August 4 is , and it's practically compulsory to wear denim in support of genetic research. Pair your jeans with a button up shirt and blazer for a casual friday work look, otherwise opt for double denim or teaming with a faux fur jacket for evening events.  If you want to take your look one step further in the fashion conscious stakes, wear your favourite vintage or custom denim with an old tee to show your support for sustainable fashion. If we are honest, goodwill is the best trending style to follow, and we have some style inspiration for you in our cart this week,
Jeans for Genes ambassador Nadia Bartel hasto our Melbourne Sale Whisperer, Melissa Singer for how to style the latest denim trends. She said she's encouraging her friends to "get wilder than ever before when it comes to their denim looks".
"Frayed, distressed, embroidered and even double denim, the more fun, the better," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acne Studios</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parisian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Foster Blake</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetset Diaries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sale Whisperer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finders Keepers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foster Blake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Sale Whisperer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Vintage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth St. Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fridays; 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paige</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppliedSales Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwina Pickles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Singer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gorman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Botanic Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tutu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birkenhead Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tutu De Monde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acne Chairman Mikael Schiller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starry Eyed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nadia Bartel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L-shaped</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iced Vovo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mara Hoffman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne At Night Logo Tee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trench Coat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday 5, 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Order of Style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
