<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418198243479517</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830502/details-missed-in-maldon-dombarton-report-transport-for-nsw/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Details missed in Maldon-Dombarton report - Transport for NSW</title>
  <content>
A new report into the Maldon-Dombarton rail line hasn't drilled down into details involving costs and engineering difficulties, according to Transport for NSW. Picture: Wolter Peeters

A document calling for the Maldon-Dombarton line to be built overlooks issues of cost, speed and engineering, according to Transport for NSW.
Earlier this week, advocacy group Illawarra First released the report Upgrading rail connectivity between Illawarra and Sydney.
Carried out by the University of Wollongong's SMART Infrastructure Facility,  - dubbed the South West Illawarra Rail Link (SWIRL) - be built as a dual track freight and passenger line.
It also said work should be carried out incrementally to improve the condition of the South Coast line.
When asked if it would look to the federal government's $10 billion National Rail Program, a Transport for NSW spokesman said it was in the process of "developing our Future Transport Strategy".

"We are looking beyond the projects in the current pipeline in order to tackle the big challenges like congestion, our growing population and climate change," the spokesman said.

However Transport for NSW said the Maldon-Dombarton was one of several options to address future capacity constraints in freight rail access to Port Kembla and that those issues do not exist at present.
It cited a 2014 business case that said  "operational and demand modelling undertaken has shown that the line is not required for current operations".

Transport for NSW said the Illawarra First report had excluded significant costs like the train fleet, the need to alter infrastructure to allow for tracks travelling in both directions and the redesigning of the Sydney system to accommodate the extra capacity.

It also believed that, because the line has some of the steepest inclines in the NSW system, the speeds assumed by the report may not actually be possible.
Transport for NSW also said, were the line constructed major engineering issues would need to be overcome.

This included the clearing of diesel fumes from a 4km tunnel for passenger services.

There were also environmental considerations of running the line through sensitive water catchment areas. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maldon-Dombarton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kembla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMART Infrastructure Facility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra First</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future Transport Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South West Illawarra Rail Link</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolter Peeters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Rail Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
