<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418498891195241</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/health/good-old-mother-nature-insomnia-is-natures-way-of-keeping-you-safe-from-lions-20170712-gx9gzp</url>
  <title>Can't sleep? Relax. Insomnia is nature's way of keeping you safe from lions</title>
  <content>
by
Sarah Knapton

A good night's sleep becomes more elusive with age, but what older people label insomnia may actually be an evolutionary survival trait that helped keep their ancestors alive.
A found that when family members of different ages live together, the differences in their sleeping patterns ensures that at least one person is awake, or sleeping very lightly, at all times. The research suggests that mismatched sleep schedules and restless nights may be an evolutionary leftover from a time thousands of years ago when a lion might be on the prowl at 2am.
"A lot of older people go to doctors complaining that they wake up early and can't get back to sleep," said author Charlie Nunn,  at Duke University, North Carolina. "But maybe there's nothing wrong with them. Maybe some of the medical issues we have today could be explained not as disorders, but as a relic of an evolutionary past in which they were beneficial.
"Any time you have a mixed-age group population, some go to bed early, some later. If you're in a lighter stage of sleep you'd be more attuned to any kind of threat in the environment."

The researchers tested their theory - dubbed ''poorly sleeping grandparent hypothesis" - on the Hadza people of northern Tanzania. The Hadza live and sleep in groups of 20 to 30 people in the savannah near Tanzania's Lake Eyasi. They sleep outside next to their hearth, or together in grass huts.

"They live a lifestyle that is the most similar to our hunting and gathering past," said co-author Alyssa Crittenden, associate professor of anthropology at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas.
As part of the study, 33 healthy men and women aged 20 to 60 agreed to wear a small watch-like device for 20 days, to record their night-time movements.
The results showed that Hadza sleep patterns were rarely in synch with some members retiring as early as 8pm and waking at 6am while others snoozed until after 8am, not going to bed until 11pm.
In between, many roused from slumber several times during the night, getting up to smoke, tend to a crying baby, or relieve themselves before nodding off again.

Out of more than 220 total hours of observation there were only 18 minutes when all adults were sound asleep simultaneously. On average, more than a third of the group was alert, or dozing lightly, at any given time.
The researchers believe that for much of human history, living and sleeping in mixed-age groups of people with different sleep habits helped our ancestors keep a watchful eye and make it through the night. Because of the evolutionary trait, the Hadza people do not need to post sentinels to keep watch, the team found.
The Daily Telegraph
The research was published in Proceedings of the Royal Society

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanzania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hadza</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Knapton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyssa Crittenden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Nunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanzania's Lake Eyasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Nevada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Carolina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Proceedings of the Royal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
