<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417811696416926</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/mitchell-freeway-extension-to-hester-avenue-opened/news-story/4fa625a3739fefe28fcf5c75e26702c2</url>
  <title>Freeway extension opened</title>
  <content>
AN EXTENSION of the Mitchell Freeway to Hester Avenue has been officially opened by Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull and Premier Mark McGowan.
But traffic may be delayed from using the new road for a few days as wet weather prevents the painting if white lines at the Burns Beach intersection.
The $236 million extension from Burns Beach Road in Joondalup to Hester Avenue in Clarkson also sees a new interchange at Neerabup Road, near the Clarkson Train Station.
Both the Neerabup Road and Hester Avenue interchanges have used roundabouts instead of traffic lights to reduce maintenance and operating costs, while also improving traffic flow, safety and reducing vehicle emissions.
Mr Turnbull said the project was critical for the northern suburbs.
"Less time in traffic allows motorists to spend more time with their families or more time at work. It means quicker, safer and cheaper commuting for individuals and businesses," he said.
Mr McGowan said: "Living down in Rockingham and commuting to the city every day I know the pressure congestion can have on families. Less time commuting means more time spent at home - and this can only be a good thing."
The project also included an extension of Neerabup Road to Wanneroo Road and duplication of Hester Avenue from Hidden Valley Retreat to Wanneroo Road, and the installation of LED lighting, wildlife underpasses at strategic locations and the use of recycled glass in the road base.
Drivers have been advised pending improved weather conditions, the extension should open on Friday, but should check the Main Roads website for updates.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EXTENSION of the Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burns Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanneroo Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joondalup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burns Beach Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarkson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarkson Train Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freeway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neerabup Road</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hester Avenue</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hidden Valley Retreat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
