<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417511048702104</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829953/robert-dillon-seven-days-in-league/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Robert Dillon: Seven Days in League</title>
  <content>
THURSDAY

NORMALLY at this time of year the Maitland Maniac is hammering Seven Days with his trademark, hand-written letters, fearlessly predicting his beloved Bulldogs will win the comp.

Funnily enough, he hasn't mentioned that particular subject for weeks, and I'm tipping it won't be raised any time soon after a 16-8 loss to Penrith that confirms Canterbury can start planning Mad Monday nice and early in 2017.

They were once known as the Dogs of War. These days it's the Dogs of Bore after scoring only 260 points in their first 19 games.
It prompts one bookmaker to frame a market on whether the Doggies can post more points as a team than former Belmore crowd favourite Hazem El Masri scored on his own in various seasons (342, 296 and 294).

How embarrassing.
It fills my heart with joy to imagine the angst the Maniac must be experiencing as the Dogs slip from bad to worse.

LIP SERVICE: Central Newcastle's Justin Worley, left, and Wests' Peter Mannion clash head-on at Harker Oval last weekend. Picture: Jonathan Carroll
FRIDAY 

THE Broncos hold a press conference to announce they have re-signed James Roberts, during which coach Wayne Bennett reveals the turbo-charged centre is off the grog and has "given up drugs".

Benny doesn't actually specify what type of illicit substances Roberts has been dabbling in.

Somehow I doubt the bloke they call "Jimmy the Jet" would feel the need for speed.

The super coach later clarifies his comments, saying Roberts had been over-indulging in prescription medication.

All of which, presumably, strikes me as information Roberts would probably prefer had remained on a need-to-know basis. One of your best, Wayne.

Later, the Broncos suffer an upset loss to the Eels in a game punctuated by cheap shots.

First Eels forward Kenny Edwards performs a high-diving shoulder charge on Broncos winger Jonas Pearson, then Brisbane's arch-niggler Josh McGuire appears to stomp on Tim Mannah's ankle.

If there is any such thing as karma, McGuire should be very, very nervous.
SATURDAY

KNIGHTS fans are celebrating a long-overdue and hard-earned victory when Dragons coach Paul "Mary" McGregor arrives for the post-match press conference.
It's a case of Mary, Mary quite contrary as he proceeds to blow up deluxe about a couple of refereeing decisions he reckons cost his team the game.
"Embarrassing and incompetent,'' McGregor fumes. "Anyone who knows rugby league would agree."

Turn it up, Mary.
The Knights have copped more than their share of stinkers this year, and coach Nathan Brown hasn't whinged once.
It was only a few weeks ago, I seem to remember, that the Dragons profited from a heap of leg-up penalties in the second half of their great escape against the Knights at Kogarah.
Then there was the last-round game at the same venue last year, when a tough call allowed the Dragons to kick a match-winning penalty goal at the death.
Tell your story walking, is my suggestion.
The real reason the Dragons lost had nothing to do with the refs.
As Seven Days was preparing to head to the stadium, I said to myself: "Self, I've got a good feeling about the Knights today. Let's stop at the TAB and back them at $4."
Somehow, between leaving home and walking through the turnstile, I forgot to place that bet. The Knights were destined to win from that moment onwards.
SUNDAY

COME on you Titans!

Novocastrians suddenly adopt Gold Coast as their "second" team before their clash with Wests Tigers at CBus Stadium.
A win by the Coasties, of course, will mean the Knights are only two points behind second last, with five games to play. Game on!

Apparently oblivious to what is at stake, Gold Coast proceed to perform like busteds and the Tigers emerge with a 26-4 boilover, to maintain a two-win gap in the race to avoid the wooden spoon.

Thanks for your help, Titans. You're no better than the Giants, Seagulls, Chargers or any of your other rubbish former incarnations.
In Melbourne, Cameron Smith racks up his 350th NRL game in the Storm's 40-6 smash-up against Manly.

It's a quiet day for the Test skipper: just the four try assists, five goals from seven attempts and 31 tackles.
Nothing special - a bit like his overall career.
Meanwhile, I read with interest a snippet in one of those sports-gossip columns that claims Cronulla warhorse Paul Gallen "could have signed the richest contract of his career if he had followed up interest from the Knights".
In what must have been a tough decision, Gal's loyalty to the Sharkies obviously outweighed the prospect of being paid 99 per cent of Newcastle's salary cap.
MONDAY

PENRITH playmaker Nathan Cleary appears in danger of being ruled out of Sunday's clash with Wests Tigers. "He might be grounded this week. His bedroom's a disgrace," declares Nathan's dad, Ivan, who also happens to be the Tigers' coach.

TUESDAY

THE Dragons are $10,000 worse off after the NRL issues a fine for coach McGregor's post-match rant, which will hopefully be used to fund the refereeing fraternity's Christmas party.
WEDNESDAY

Gavin Badger - the little champion who denied the Dragons two tries against the Knights last weekend - will become just the fifth referee to reach the milestone of 300 NRL matches when he officiates in the Penrith-Wests Tigers match at Pepper Stadium on Sunday.

TRIPLE CENTURY: Referee Gavin Badger.
He joins Bill Harrigan, Col Pearce, Shayne Hayne and Steve Clark in the exclusive club.

Meanwhile, Herald photographer Jono Carroll alerts me to a picture that captures a tender moment during a rugged Real NRL game between Wests and Central last weekend (see above).  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonas Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jono Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad Mondays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dogs of Bore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Dillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referee Gavin Badger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests' Peter Mannion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dogs of War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne Hayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharkies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Days</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seagulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pepper Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Gallen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith-Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Badger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lip Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Harrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Newcastle's Justin Worley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harker Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberts</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novocastrians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBus Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRIPLE CENTURY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coasties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kogarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Cleary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Maniac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hazem El Masri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Col Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
