<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417515343669480</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/diet-lose-7kgs-week/3208328/</url>
  <title>The diet to lose 7kgs in a week</title>
  <content>
ANOTHER DAY, another diet and this time it is a diet that promises to help you lose up to 7kg in a week. Seriously. So what is the latest GM Diet craze? How do you do it? And does it work?

The funny thing about the GM diet or General Motors Diet is that it's not new and best of all it is free.

Developed back in the 1980s for the employees of General Motors who were keen to take control of their weight, the GM Diet is a seven-day plan that basically alternates different food groups, for example eating only fruit some days, and meat and vegetables on others.

Overall this leaves you with a relatively simple but also low calorie, and relatively low carb diet which explains why some individuals may get big drops on the scales initially.

HOW DO YOU DO IT?
The GM diet suggests dieters follow the same seven-day cycle (with a few days off in between) until they reach their goal weight.

On Day 1, the diet suggests you eat only fruit, with the exception of bananas which are considered to be more calorie dense than other water based fruits.

Specifically the diet suggests followers focus their fruit intake around melons, which are exceptionally high in water and low in calories. While you can eat as much fruit as you like on Day 1, overall your calorie intake is likely to be relatively low.

Sorry, bananas are out...

On Day 2, you swap to a day of eating only vegetables, with the exception of potato which you can only eat at breakfast time.

Another low calorie day, as vegetables have even fewer calories than fruit and while you can eat as much as you like, you calorie intake will remain very low which also explains the rapid weight loss. Although mostly fluid, this initial weight loss is what tends to keep dieters interested.

Once you reach Day 3 you are allowed a mix of both fruit and vegetables, with the exception of potatoes and bananas.

Potatoes and bananas are still exceptionally healthy foods - and not significantly higher in calories or carbohydrates than other fruits and vegetables - and as such have been treated a little harshly in the GM Diet.

David Nielsen

If you make it to Day 4, the diet shifts significantly to a day of eating only milk and bananas - a little strange, but the combo of protein rich dairy and energy rich bananas just may keep you full and energised to continue with the GM Diet.

On Day 5, there is a big shift to two 200g servings of lean beef, chicken or fish and up to six tomatoes. It is proposed that the protein rich foods offer key nutrients including iron while the tomatoes offer a good dose of fibre to keep the gut happy.

Day 6, another day of meat here with two 200g serves of meat allowed along with unlimited amounts of vegetables. If you do not eat meat, cottage cheese must become your friend.

While the serving sizes of protein are hearty, and unlikely to leave you hungry, it may be at this point you start to crave your fresh fruits, cereals and grains.

The final day of the GM Diet is a suggested mix of brown rice, fruit juice and unlimited amounts of fruits and vegetables. A vegetarian or vegans delight!

So will it work for me?

Any diet will work if people stick to it. The primary issue with the GM diet is that for the average person it is unlikely to be sustainable. Eating a limited number of types of foods each day will naturally restrict calories and in this example, carbohydrates which explains the relatively quick weight loss.

There is nothing overly special about it, it is just another novel diet approach.

There is nothing overly concerning or dangerous about it either. Alternating foods ensures you get a range of different nutrients across the course of a week and eating regularly preserves metabolism and avoids the feelings of restriction that can result from calorie counting.

The biggest issue is that most people do not want to eat just one or two things all day, even for a short period of time.

Long term diet success ultimately comes down to choosing the diet that is right for you, and is this approach works for you, go for it.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GM</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Nielsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Motors Diet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Motors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GM Diet</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
