<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417897595764057</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/flights/these-are-the-best-airlines-for-when-youre-flying-with-the-kids/news-story/a0facfd9dd8654e8a7d1017640e9f923</url>
  <title>These are the best airlines for when you're flying with the kids</title>
  <content>
Secrets to (Sanely) Flying With Children
3:39

Every parent will have to, at some point, fly with young children. Are there ways to make trips less stressful? MarketWatch's Catey Hill discusses with Tanya Rivero. Photo: Vsurkov

February 25th 2016
a year ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Travel - News.com.au/

It's not easy flying with the little ones in tow.

Flip Byrnes

Share

NEXT time you're seated at dinner with your mini progeny, imagine sitting there for, say, 17 hours. Or 24. Strapped in.
Consider all that happens in a day (nap times, meals, play, nappy changes, hyperactive sprint intervals, the occasional meltdown) and picture it happening within the confines of 58A. It ain't pretty, but it doesn't have to be traumatic.
No airline is created equal, so research counts especially when travelling with babies and toddlers where things can go wrong ... quickly.
Some services are generous (incredible baby packs on China Eastern Airlines) to virtually non existent (no family boarding priority on some budget carriers).
Need a bassinet? Some airlines confirm at booking, others assign them on the day.
Here are our favourite ways to fly.
ETIHAD - FOR SOLO FLYING PARENTS
In March this year, Etihad's 2000th Flying Nanny graduated from UK's prestigious Norland College, for the specific purpose of helping families on flights. Sign me up.

Etihad wins King of the Kids when it comes to flying with children, with it's level of accommodation for little ones.Source:Supplied
If you're expecting a Mary Poppins-esque galley creche, you'll be sorely disappointed; it's an assistance more than daycare role. However, if flying solo with two toddlers or babies (for example), they step in so you can go to the bathroom, or eat your meal while attempting to feed toddlers simultaneously (impossible unless you're an octopus).

But this is just the start of why Etihad is King of the Kids. Flying economy it's possible to access their Premium Lounge kid zone (for a charge - complete with qualified nannies in some airports), at Abu Dhabi a Meet & Greet can take you from gate to taxi curb side, it's even possible to book another suitcase.
If you've experienced having only two hands to chase toddlers running in different directions though an airport, negotiate a customs queue or faced starvation on a 14-hour flight, you'll be taking this passport to an easier experience. Visit .

Flying Nannies on board flights can help look after your kids while you eat or visit the bathroom.Source:Supplied
CHINA EASTERN AIRLINES - BEST VALUE
The first thing you need to know about China Eastern Airlines is that economy allows a whopping two bags of 23kg checked luggage. Each. That's a lot of shopping. Or ski equipment. Or toys. I've tried to use it all previously - and failed.
This is the dark horse of the skies (China who?), but this Skyteam member and China's second largest carrier is stellar. Airbus A330? Tick. Best baby packs in the world? (Big tick, they come compete with nappies, food, spoons, little paper plates, even disposable bibs on some legs). They treat children like small rock stars and while English is sometimes borderline, the message always gets across.
In a country which adores children, the love continues on the ground in Shanghai with young child families being fast tracked through customs via a dedicated lane. The recent free Chinese transit visa laws are the cherry on the cake, so you can visit exciting Shanghai for a couple of days en route to Europe.
Also, this carrier regularly comes in significantly cheaper than competitors. Budget price, five star everything else. Visit .

Happy kids makes happy parents - especially on long-haul flights. Picture: iStockSource:Supplied
SINGAPORE AIRLINES - SERVICE WITH A SMILE
Singapore Airlines confirms bassinets at booking with a first-call, first-serve policy and boasts the largest bassinets at 77cm long, holding 14kgs (others are limited to 10kgs).
As the world's most awarded airline, you'll find the service is thoughtful and doled out with good humour.
For those travelling with babies, the baby pack includes a travel pack of baby wipes (try finding that on other airlines) and they're flexible about delivering meals when it suits. Your toddler doesn't feel like diner at 3am local time? No problem, they'll boomerang it back.
Oh, and Changi Airport. It is tempting to take a holiday inside the airport.
Split European flights with a nap at the in-terminal Ambassador Transit Hotel (complete with outdoor pool), and did we mention epic playground, outdoor Sunflower Garden and over 1000 butterflies in the Butterfly Garden? It's a transit Wonderland. Visit .

Air New Zealand offers Skycouch for parents travelling with children.Source:Supplied
AIR NEW ZEALAND - PURE GENIUS
It's sky-high playtime on the ... Economy Skycouch! Whoever invented this is a genius.
Convertible from seat to bed at the push of a button, this economy triple-seat turns the seat row into a flat(ish) bed area (it's not actually a flat bed). Or play area - and a decent sized one - the dimensions are 1.55m long and when the cushion and leg rest are combined the depth is 74cm.
Because each seat converts independently, the Skycouch lets you sit upright while the kids snooze. Or, in a parallel universe, your toddler self parents while you score eight hours of shut-eye. Woohoo!
The airline also offers a Jet Cadets Kids Pack, in-flight meals designed to appeal to fussy eaters and pre-board bassinet booking.
We love our Tasman friends, and especially their airline. Visit .
This article originally appeared on .

Economy Skycouch seats pop up individually across the row-of-three to provide a sleep or play area for kids.Source:Supplied
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jet Cadets Kids Pack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PURE GENIUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iStockSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya Rivero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbus A330</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MarketWatch's Catey Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunflower Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad's 2000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wonderland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SERVICE WITH A SMILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SkyTeam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vsurkov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King of the Kids</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skycouch</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SOLO FLYING PARENTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Eastern Airlines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore Airlines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEST VALUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flying Nanny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Poppins-esque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premium Lounge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butterfly Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flying With Children</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Changi Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambassador Transit Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norland College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
