<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418889733226298</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/justice-delayed-is-justice-denied-magistrate-slams-vince-colosimos-lawyers-20170803-gxoear.html</url>
  <title>'Justice delayed is justice denied': Magistrate slams Vince Colosimo's lawyers</title>
  <content>
A frustrated Melbourne magistrate has hit out at Underbelly star Vince Colosimo's lawyers for requesting another delay in his case.
Mr Colosimo, 50, who starred as murdered gangster Alphonse Gangitano in the TV series, could fight charges of driving while suspended and recording a positive drug test.Photo: Eddie Jim
The actor is interstate and did not appear in Melbourne Magistrates Court on Thursday, as is his right as he is charged on summons.
But the slow progress in his case was not welcomed by magistrate Ross Maxted.
The actor's case was adjourned without him appearing in court a month ago, and on Thursday Mr Maxted questioned why the case should again be delayed when defence counsel Tara Hartnett asked for an adjournment.
"That's the problem with this court, there are too many adjournments," Mr Maxted said.

"Justice delayed is justice denied.
"This is a relatively straghtforward matter. I am wondering why it is so complex."

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Ms Hartnett said Mr Colosimo was interstate and wanted his case adjourned.
Mr Maxted said Mr Colosimo was set to plead not guilty to the charge of driving while suspended, but the magistrate did not refer to the charge of recording a positive drug test.
Ms Hartnett said she did not have instructions on how Mr Colosimo planned to plead.
The matter was adjourned to November 3.
Mr Colosimo could face jail time if found guilty of the charges, having been put on a 12-month good behaviour bond earlier this year after admitting he had a small quantity of ice in his car when pulled over in September last year.
The latest charges relate to him being pulled over in Melbourne and allegedly testing positive to drugs on March 5.
Mr Colosimo, who is also known for his roles in Lantana and the Leonardo DiCaprio films The Great Gatsby and Body of Lies, was in 2014 fined $1000 for driving while suspended.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alphonse Gangitano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonardo DiCaprio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Maxted</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Jim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hartnett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Colosimo, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Gatsby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Colosimo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Colosimo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lantana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Body of Lies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday Mr Maxted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Hartnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Maxted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
