<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417429444321606</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sailors-mammoth-trip-to-become-voluntary-shark-bai/3208317/</url>
  <title>Sailor's mammoth trip to become voluntary shark bait</title>
  <content>
BYRON Bay to Mooloolaba is a long way to sail to put yourself on the menu as potential shark bait.
But it's an important journey Migaloo 2 skipper Dean Jefferys hopes will help highlight the importance of exploring other shark deterrent technology instead of relying solely on nets and drumlines.
Mr Jefferys is a passionate oceangoer and a lover of whales.
He's also prepared to take the plunge, swimming under the shark nets off Mooloolaba to show the limited protection the nets offer.
"The nets don't actually make people safer," Mr Jefferys said.
"Sharks swim under and around the nets."
The State Government's shark control program website says shark attacks were regular prior to 1962, but following effective trials of nets and drumlines in south-east Queensland, the measures were rolled out at major beaches across the state.
The program's website says bycatch levels are "carefully monitored" and research focused on minimising the impacts of the program on non-target species, including whales, dolphins and turtles.
Mr Jefferys hoped the swim, for which he was joined by a number of local environmental groups, would raise the profile of alternatives like Shark Shield and drone technology, in a bid to reduce bycatch in nets and on baited drumlines.
"We're trying to show they're killing sentient beings out there when we do have an alternative, lots of alternatives actually," Mr Jefferys said.
He was a member of Byron Bay's Shark Watch group, and worked as a drone operator for the group.
He said the response had been strong to the group's formation, with plenty of drone operators joining up and taking to the skies to help surfers and swimmers avoid shark encounters.
"The view on a clear day is second to none," Mr Jefferys said.
"This technology (including other shark deterrents) is available now."
Sunshine Coast marine expert, educator and diver Tony Isaacson was one of those who joined Mr Jefferys on the morning event.
He recently jetted back from Copenhagen to present in Brisbane to the Senate Inquiry into shark mitigation and deterrent measures.
Mr Isaacson told the committee of the virtues of Clever Buoy sonar technology which can send real-time warnings as sharks were detected, and urged further trials of the technology in "high-risk" locations including Amity Point on North Stradbroke Island.
He also recommended cost-benefit analysis be undertaken of other strategies, including drone technologies, shark spotters, physical barriers, magnetic 'kelp forests' and other non-lethal strategies.
Personal Shark Shield devices were another measure he touched on, telling the committee Shark Shield and similar devices should be "affordable and as accessible as car hire, bike helmets and sunscreen" for Australian citizens.
He suggested surf lifesaving clubs, service clubs and volunteer groups could be involved on the beach for sales, rentals and recharging of electronic safety units.
Mr Isaacson said he'd been surprised by the level of interest shown by the senators.
"I walked away from the inquiry feeling just so, so pleased with the level of interest that all senators had in everything I had to say," he said.
"That was not what I expected."
He felt there was a real chance for change, and urged them to move quickly to secure what could become iconic Australian shark protection technology.
"If we don't act now... we are as I speak at risk of losing that technology and development to the United States," Mr Isaacson said.
He was looking forward to greater collaboration with the State Government and its Shark Control Program operator in future.
A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Jetstar drops massive cut-price Sunshine Coast holiday deal.
Coast set temperatures set to soar
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Stradbroke Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clever Buoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Isaacson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Migaloo 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Inquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay's Shark Watch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amity Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shark Control Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shark Shield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Isaacson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Jefferys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Copenhagen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jeffery</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
