<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418803833878757</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/03/shortest-political-interview-ever-federal-mp-cut-after-29-seconds?cid=trending</url>
  <title>Shortest political interview ever? Federal MP cut off after 29 seconds</title>
  <content>
A Liberal MP was invited to to speak about the hot topic of same-sex marriage on Sky News. It ended a few seconds later.

By

50 MINS AGO  UPDATED 43 MINS AGO

It's probably up there as one of the shortest political interviews ever.

Liberal MP Tim Wilson was invited on to Sky News on Thursday to discuss  and the ongoing developments in his party on the issue.

Amid growing support amongst some conservatives  to resolve the impasse over , the Liberal Party is expected to discuss the issue in a meeting on Monday.

Mr Wilson is among a group of Liberal MPs who've left open the possibility of crossing the floor in favour of legalising  should a bill come to a vote.

Sky News host Peter Van Onselen opened the interview with a simple question: "Do you like the idea of a secret ballot in the party?"

Mr Wilson deflected.

"I have said everything I have to say on this issue and I make no plans to make any other comment at this time," the MP said.

"I'd rather talk about something else that actually matters to the Australian population."

Mr Wilson then went on to list all the things he'd rather talk about; the economy, energy prices or Labor's tax policies.

"I've said what I've said on this issue," he ended.

Van Onselen, unperturbed, cut the interview short right there.

"Tim Wilson, thanks for your company."

The length of the brief chat? Twenty-nine seconds.

Van Onselen later told The Australian he had considered Mr Wilson would address the topic in some way.

"I just decided in the spur of the moment to end the interview if he wasn't willing to answer a fair question," he said.

RELATED READING:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Van Onselen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Van Onselen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 43 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
