<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418756589237587</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/opinion/a-useless-bunch-of-indulgent-politicians-who-deserve-to-be-turfed-20170803-gxonj5</url>
  <title>Was there ever a more useless bunch of indulgent politicians who deserved to be turfed out?</title>
  <content>
On one side of politics, mayhem and policy of all sorts held hostage to a battle of wills on one issue. On the other side of politics, multiple signs of a party getting on with the job of thinking through policies they wish to advocate to voters.
On one side of politics, a party doing absolutely everything to suggest it is only interested in its own internal battles, not the electorate. On the other side of politics, a party doing absolutely everything it can to fit its policies into a message that may cut through.
The  is, to outsiders, almost beyond belief.
Let's summarise briefly. The Coalition is arguing over a policy position on which there is now : to allow same-sex marriage.

But having said that, it is not even a third-rate issue in the electorate, just something they have already processed and decided about and which they just cannot believe is still an issue of controversy in politics.

They just want to see it resolved once and for all so we can talk about things more important to their lives.
The discussion within the Coalition reflects that lack of interest among voters in this sense: it is not being discussed in terms of its rights and wrongs.
The language and the issues at stake are all about who is in charge and how much damage can be inflicted on Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull by his various colleagues, whether they be conservative opponents or moderate supporters.
With eye-watering chutzpah, opponents of a change in policy are accusing advocates for same-sex marriage of undermining Turnbull . And let's face it, some of the key protagonists among those opponents are experts in the field.

On Thursday, veteran political commentator Niki Savva succinctly summed up the options likely to emerge next week as federal Parliament returns as a choice between "the untenable (stick with the plebiscite to the next election), unsaleable (a postal plebiscite) or unpalatable (free vote) options".
The government appears chicken

Turnbull is trying to corral the issue into a more manageable one by calling a  for Monday afternoon to thrash it out.
The advocates of change are being told they have nothing like the numbers to get a change of policy. The possibility of a secret ballot holds open the spectre they do.

Whatever happens, the government will appear too chicken to use the Parliament for the purposes it exists: to argue out and resolve our points of policy difference.
With a ludicrous postal plebiscite seeming the most likely option to emerge here, the result is that both sides of the debate will have contributed to making Turnbull look pathetic in the eyes of voters, and he will have contributed to that by failing to find a way of resolving these deep divisions.
And in this febrile atmosphere, the ludicrous, Pavlovian suggestion that he will be "gone by Christmas" will reflect the on-going damage that the idea of prime minister swapping represents to our political system.
If you really do have to change your prime minister, you do it because you have a better option who can improve your standing with voters. The Coalition doesn't have one.

The idea that someone other than Turnbull can improve the Coalition's vote is based on the idea - one presumes - that a more conservative prime minister may somehow attract back more voters.
In fact, all the evidence that voters are disillusioned with Turnbull is because he is either not of the political centre as people thought, or because he is seen as weak.
These are two perceptions that will only have been, again, reinforced by this episode. And in the process, the idea that all these problems are ultimately a reflection of the Prime Minister, rather than a collective failure of the Coalition party room, will have been reinforced.
Was there ever a more useless bunch of indulgent politicians who deserved to be turfed out of office? (Well, don't answer that because, yes, they turn up frequently in our lives. Unfortunately. This is just the latest incident).

Labor's new policy clothes

Labor, of course, has been more than keen to point out the weaknesses of the Prime Minister's position and of the idea of a postal plebiscite.
Which you would do, wouldn't you, if you were in opposition?
But, just when voters have every reason to be discouraged about politics, it has also been one of those weeks when there are reasons for some encouragement that the whole process isn't brain dead.
The Coalition has been keen to pour scorn on , or inequality as the case may be. And it is true it is such a broad issue it could easily end up looking fairly lame: a generalisation in search of a new way of defining the purpose of a labour party.
But the Labor frontbench are dressing it with some new policy clothes.
The policy released this week on discretionary trusts was another example of  had the courage or political skills to go, as it did before the last election on negative gearing and capital gains.
It isn't just about being politically brave though: this is a well thought through bit of policy.

Across the board, Labor frontbenchers have been going back and having a think about what it is they and their party should actually be trying to achieve in government: what values they are trying to promote.
This extends as far as foreign policy where Penny Wong has now given two landmark speeches on Australia's interests and values.
In doing this, she has been trying to shift the ground in the way  are perceived.
In recent times, much of the discussion about Labor and foreign policy has been a binary one about just how "real" its commitment to the US alliance can be.
Wong is the first foreign affairs spokesperson, on either side of politics, to be refashioning policy from first principles in the post-Trump era.
That makes what she eventually says about the US alliance both much more difficult, but also much more interesting in an age when - suddenly - whatever Washington says can't simply be taken as credible, preferable, in our national interest, or a reflection of our own values and how we seek to portray ourselves in the world.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pavlovian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIKI SAVVA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
