<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418713639563526</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/the-giant-female-silence-on-abortion-20170803-gxod7w.html</url>
  <title>The 'giant female silence' on abortion</title>
  <content>
There is a great female silence when it comes to the issue of abortion and women should be unafraid to discuss the issue, social commentator and writer Jane Caro told a Brisbane conference on Thursday.
Ms Caro shared her own story about informing others of her termination in her early 20s during the keynote address at the Unplanned Pregnancy and Abortion in Australia Conference.Photo: Fiona Morris
She said some people seemed to believe abortion was something that happened to this "weird group of completely promiscuous and disgusting women over here".
"None of whom you would ever actually know or meet ... I don't know whether they wear a giant red 'A' carved on their forehead, so you know," she said.
Years earlier, Ms Caro said, she was invited to speak on Richard Glover's Drive show on ABC radio, along with fellow guests former NSW Liberal leader John Brogden and Archbishop Peter Jensen, when the topic of abortion was raised.
"In answer to the question, I said there is a giant female silence around the issue of abortion," she said.

"There would not be a single woman who hasn't, when her period was a little bit late, wondered whether or not she was going to have to make the decision about an unwanted pregnancy.
"Not a single woman alive."
Ms Caro said the men in the studio looked at her with a look of astonishment.
"And then I thought, well Jane, you can't put out there a 'gigantic female silence on abortion' and then be part of that gigantic female silence," she said.
So she shared: "I think I've had a fairly typical reproductive life for a woman of my age. I've had two children, a miscarriage and an abortion."
Ms Caro said you could have heard a pin drop in the studio.
"Oh my God, it's a whore and she's admitting to it right here," Ms Caro said.
"Where's that 'A' that's meant to be carved on her forehead so I can recognise her in advance?."
The conversation moved on to other topics including the Iraq war and their favourite recipes from the '70s.
Ms Caro's was apricot chicken, "because that was delectable, even to whores".
Ms Caro said she was scared she would receive abuse and the shame and stigma that might be attached to speaking about her abortion on radio.
But all she received was supportive messages and at the P&C meeting that night, the only comment was about the apricot chicken.
"I had been seriously worried that I would be vilified," she said.
Ms Caro said women faced shame and stigma in a variety of areas, not just when they had an unplanned pregnancy.
"Sometimes I think that from the minute a girl starts to develop secondary sexual characteristics, to start to go through puberty, our entire society unites to make her feel ashamed," she said.
Ms Caro said there was also the shame attached to women and what clothes they wore, leading to comments on whether they had self-respect.
"What the hell do you think respect is? It's got nothing to do with the clothes you put on your body, you need to bring your son up to recognise boundaries and basically the boundary is, she can be nude and walking down the street," she said.
"It's not an invitation for you to have sexual contact with her unless she says yes - and asks you. It's really simple."
Ms Caro said she had accompanied other women having abortion, and noticed the women in the waiting rooms kept their heads bowed.
"You know there's this real atmosphere of apology and embarrassment and people don't want to talk about it and it's all kept silenced," she said.
"And I wanted to stand up and yell 'you haven't done anything wrong and you're not about to do anything wrong'.
"You're just women and you're living what it is to be a woman, and sometimes things go wrong.
"A stray sperm can getcha, real bloody easy."
Ms Caro said her unplanned pregnancy occurred after a torn condom in the days before the morning after pill. 
"So there was no real options except to wait with white knuckles to find out whether we had actually conceived or not and of course we had," she said.
"All I felt afterwards and ever since was relief."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Brogden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Caro</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Conference.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archbishop Peter Jensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unplanned Pregnancy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Caro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Glover's Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
