<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418752294270200</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/08/33/controversial-anti-vaccination-film-secretly-screened-in-melbourne-cinema</url>
  <title>Controversial anti-vaccination film secretly screened in Melbourne cinema</title>
  <content>
An anti-vaccination film slammed by Victorian Health Minister Jill Hennessy as "dangerous" was covertly screened at a major cinema last night.
Vaxxed: From Cover-Up to Catastrophe, warning of the supposed perils of vaccination, was shown at Village cinemas in Crown casino, with attendees only notified of the film's location an hour before it screened, .
As part of the screening, organisers the Australian Vaccination-sceptics Network (AVN) also ran a stall selling books and DVDs promoting the anti-vaccination agenda and encouraging children to actively contract measles.
Ms Hennessy said the documentary - which reportedly claims US national public health institute the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention actively suppressed a study showing links between vaccines and autism - should be avoided.
"This screening's message is dangerous. Victorians should get health information from their doctors," she told the Herald Sun.
AVN spokeswoman Tasha David told the newspaper the organisation has been entirely transparent in its activities.
"The AVN went through the normal (cinema) booking process, which included volunteering information, trailers, and a full screening link to the film for review," Ms David said.

Related Articles

Last night's screening is believed to be one of a total of three screenings planned for Melbourne, with more expected to be held across the rest of Australia.
The movie is banned at multiple theatres around the world.
Vaxxed was expected to premiere at the New York Tribeca film festival in April last year, when it was abruptly removed from the schedule.
Crown casino has since stated that they "in no way" endorse the anti-vaccination film.
"Crown was not aware of the film screening until contacted by the media," a Crown Resorts spokesperson said this afternoon.
"While Village make decisions about what movies screen at their cinemas, we will be clearly communicating to Village that such a film is not screened at the Crown venue in the future."
Village has been contacted for comment.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Tribeca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVDs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Health Minister Jill Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cover-up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disease Control</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasha David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AVN</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaxxed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Vaccination-skeptics Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
