<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418803833878737</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/robbie-grays-match-winning-goal-against-st-kilda-has-made-headlines-in-america/news-story/9a1c724f09fdc064cd8fdffc326c26bf</url>
  <title>Saints' horror finish ends up on ESPN</title>
  <content>
YOU know you've really blown a game when you make it onto ESPN's SportsCenter.
Welcome to the club St Kilda.
The Saints featured on Scott Van Pelt's "Bad Beats" segment following their horror last 70 seconds against Port Adelaide.
But no matter how much research the Americans do, they just can't get their heads around Aussie Rules.
WATCH THE FULL VIDEO IN THE PLAYER ABOVE
"It looks like they're playing with a giant squash," was the standout analysis during the hilarious segment.
Paddy Ryder was given the three votes, with Van Pelt in awe of his stunning ruckwork (or tip) to Robbie Gray.
"Good tip. Look at that tip," he said.
21ST CENTURY FOOTY:
21ST CENTURY FOOTY:
However, his co-host was more interested in the boundary umpire throwing the ball in, letting out an enthusiastic "weeeeeeeee".
The show even found some time to have a crack at the AFL over the lack of goal-line cameras.
Just like Sydney coach John Longmire, who has campaigned for better score review technology, Van Pelt couldn't believe the lack of camera angles.
"How do we know (Gray's kick was a goal)? This guy (the goal umpire) is right there I guess," he said.
"Can we get better angles? We are trying our best here to understand what is going on.
"What we need is like a goal-line camera. I need a down the line shot so I can tell people if that was (a goal) or not."
Despite his lack of knowledge, Van Pelt is clearly keeping a close eye on our game this year.
from Round 15.
"It sets up some dudes in some really short shorts singing songs," he said.
Here are some of our other favourite times AFL has made headlines in the USA.
"IT LOOKS MORE LIKE A BAR FIGHT"
That was CNN's take on Brian Lake and Drew Petrie going toe-to-toe in 2014.
Lake was handed a four match ban for his involvement in the scuffle with Petrie.
"Brian Lake, the guy who is doing the choking, it turns out he is like the AFL's equivalent to the NFL Super Bowl MVP," reporter Laura Rutledge went on to say.
Rutledge also gave her take on why the incident occurred.
"The Australian Football League markets itself as being super aggressive, very physical and that is how they attract the fans that they do attract."

Mason Cox is making headlines overseas just like some of the other big AFL stories in recent years

American media gives its take on the AFL
SBNATION WHACKS THE 'LESS-THAN-STELLAR' PIES
American website SBNATION gave its take on Mason Cox's journey to the AFL during the 2016 season.
While the article was very complimentary of Cox, it did find time to give the Magpies a clip for their form.
"You might vaguely remember Cox from Oklahoma State's 2013-14 team that made the second round of the NCAA tournament," the SBNATION article said.
"Since leaving the hardwood he's made a hell of a name for himself in the Australian Football League playing forward in Aussie Rules for the Collingwood Magpies.
"Midway through the season Cox has scored 15 goals, which ranks 50th in the league. That might not sound great, but consider that among rookies he ranks close to the top and he's playing on a less-than-stellar team. Suddenly he's a player to watch."
Less-than-stellar?! Clearly SBNATION doesn't know what happens when you take on the black and white army.
"IT IS A BLEND OF RUGBY AND MUGGING SOMEONE."
ESPN gave two and a half minutes to some of the top plays of the 2015 season with a Lindsay Thomas hanger against the Gold Coast leading the way.
"I don't know what a ripper is, but I like it," one of the anchors said.
Collingworth - yes "worth," was next up with then Magpie Travis Cloke's don't argue or "stiff-arm" drawing plenty of praise.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBNATION WHACKS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BLEND OF RUGBY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LESS-THAN-STELLAR' PIES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PLAYER ABOVE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Van Pelt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ST CENTURY FOOTY</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL Super Bowl MVP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FULL VIDEO IN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mason Cox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpie Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Van Pelt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Rutledge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsay Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOOKS MORE LIKE A BAR FIGHT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rutledge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN's SportsCenter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBNATION</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCAA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Lake</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Rules</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Football League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MUGGING SOMEONE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
