<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418928387932560</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/billy-slater-cleared-for-storms-blockbuster-clash-against-cowboys/news-story/5a7ca1bea0c2fe56657a59ee34692ce2</url>
  <title>Slater locked in, Storm braces for Taumalolo</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE Storm superstar Billy Slater is a confirmed starter for Friday night's blockbuster against North Queensland.
Slater, 34, trained strongly on Thursday afternoon in Townsville after passing all the concussion protocols with "flying colours" during the week.
The veteran fullback was rested last week as a precaution after he was knocked unconscious in a crude late hit a fortnight ago against Canberra.
Slater's return is timely with forecast rain and high humidity in Townsville, likely to make controlling the ball difficult for the visiting Storm.
Ryley Jacks has the edge on Jahrome Hughes as the replacement for injured five-eighth Cameron Munster (ankle), with exposed form in tricky conditions early in the season working in his favour.
Despite the selection quandary, Storm football director Frank Ponissi said the club was fortunate to be able to recall Slater with Munster on the sidelines.
"The frustrating part about it is, I just can't remember any game this year we've had our absolute best 17 in for the game," Ponissi said.
"Having said that too (the Cowboys) have got two of their best players in Johnathan Thurston and Matt Scott (out of the game) ... it's very much a luxury bringing in Slater for Munster."
With key playmakers missing from both sides, the battle for supremacy will start in the middle of 1300Smles Stadium.
The Cowboys pack a punch with powerhouse Jason Taumalolo, ranked No. 1 in the NRL for running metres, Scott Bolton, Ethan Lowe and Coen Hess, off the bench, a handful gaining valuable territory.
But Storm matches up well through the middle, with Jesse Bromwich, considered the world's best prop, Jordan McLean and Nelson Asofa-Solomona spared a heavy toll last week in the runaway win over Manly.
Workhorse Dale Finucane also enjoyed time on the bench which should hold him in good stead.
"Whoever wins the battle of the middle will win the game," Ponissi said.
"We've got enormous respect for their pack and I think with Johnathan Thurston being out - because he's such a wonderful and creative player - they've probably had to rely a little bit more on their forwards and they've been great.
"He's (Taumalolo) statistically the best forward in the game at the moment, just a powerhouse ... we know how to stop him, but doing it is a completely different thing."
Taumalolo torched an Origin-depleted Storm in Round 15, running for 300m in the golden point loss at AAMI Park.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slater, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Finucane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slater</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smles Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ethan Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Ponissi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taumalolo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ponissi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Asofa-Solomona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryley Jacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Bromwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jahrome Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coen Hess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin-depleted Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Taumalolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
