<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418717934531017</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/volunteer-dreams-of-making-a-difference/3208200/</url>
  <title>Volunteer dreams of making a difference</title>
  <content>
WHILE some 20-year-olds might be saving money for new electronics or a car, Laura Wood's money is going to a very different cause.
The young Nambour woman is currently preparing to head to Pemba, near Mozambique, on a volunteer trip to help with projects such as a medical centre, a village feeding centre and orphanages.
Ms Wood said she has been passionate about volunteer work for as long as she can remember.
"My mum has this letter I wrote when I was six-years-old saying 'when I grow up I want to help people'," she said.
"This will be the fourth time I have gone to a third world country to volunteer... the first time was with my mum when I was 16 for two months, and have also done a similar trip to Africa, and a small trip to Cambodia.
"This trip will cost $7,500 and I'm a bit off that; it's fully self-funded but it is definitely worth it.
"I think these people don't have the money or equipment they need to help themselves so I think it is awesome that we can go over and help them."
Ms Wood is completing the trip through Iris Missionaries, along with 500 other volunteers from all around the world.
While she is currently working as a nanny on the Sunshine Coast, Ms Wood said her end goal would be to set up a safe home in Africa for girls who have been sold into the sex industry.
"Some of these kids are taken in so young and they are so traumatised so I want to help them recover," Ms Wood said.
"(People are) stuck in these situations of homelessness, or prostitution, or lack of clean water and if we don't help them it goes from generation to generation.
"We're trying to put them in a better situation and then hundreds of people will have a better life," Ms Wood said.
To donate to Laura's volunteer work visit www.gofundme.com /my-volunteer-trip-to-mozambique
Jetstar drops massive cut-price Sunshine Coast holiday deal.
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Ocean lovers take the plunge in daring shark net swim
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iris Missionaries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mozambique</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wood</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
