<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418713639563509</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/iron-ore/rio-tinto-chief-jacques-says-wider-iron-ore-discount-driven-by-structural-change-20170802-gxo3d8</url>
  <title>Rival iron ore chiefs clash on the discount debate: structural or cyclical?</title>
  <content>
Rio Tinto chief executive JS Jacques says the yawning gap between prices for higher grade and lower grade iron ore appears to be caused by structural changes to China's steel industry and is likely to persist.
Mr Jacques said he believed the wide price differential between high and low grade iron ore was becoming increasingly permanent as the Chinese steel market changed.
"I believe it is becoming more and more structural," said Mr Jacques, who was an executive at Tata Steel before he joined Rio Tinto.
whether the shift has been caused by short-term cyclical factors or whether it could be a function of structural changes in the industry, while lower grade iron ore producers have assured the market they expect the gap to tighten.

But  the closure of smaller, dirtier plants had pushed steelmakers to focus on larger and newer blast furnaces with lower emissions. Higher quality iron ore has been required to boost productivity in these furnaces to meet demand.

"That is exactly what is happening here," Mr Jacques said on Wednesday.
As evidence the change is more structural than cyclical, he pointed out that when steel and iron ore prices dipped in the middle of the year, Chinese steel mills didn't shift back to lower grades to cut costs.
"When the price started to come under pressure, the delta didn't change. That to me says it's more structural."
Mr Jacques also said about two-thirds of the iron ore stockpiled at Chinese ports was lower grade "and it is not moving".

Rio Tinto's sales of higher grade iron ore have benefited from the shift but a raft of other Australian miners have not.
Fortescue Metals Group, , BC Iron, Mineral Resources and  all highlighted the impact of the discount on their performance in the three months to June.
Historically, Fortescue has received 85 per cent to 90 per cent of the benchmark 62 per cent iron ore index price but in the 2017 financial year it achieved just 77 per cent, with an average price of $US53.27 per tonne for the year  in the June quarter.
The benchmark iron ore price fell , after hitting as high as $US90 per tonne in February and as low as $US53 per tonne in June.

Fortescue chief Nev Power told The Australian Financial Review on Thursday he was confident Chinese steel mills' preference for higher grade iron ore would not persist.
"I don't think there is anything permanent about this, it is steel mills working to optimise their business so it comes back to supply demand dynamics in steel and the supply demand dynamics in iron ore," Mr Power said.
Mr Power, who spent more than a decade at Smorgon Steel Group before joining Fortescue, said the government intervention had driven up steel mill margins and encouraged the preference for higher grade iron ore but that would correct as margins reverted to more normal levels.
"I do think the market is still suffering from some distortion because of the supply side reforms but we have already seen corrections start to come through and an instantaneous dip in the iron ore price is not going to change that, it is going to take a little bit longer for that to play out," he said.

Fortescue has said it expects the discount to return to historical levels in the second half of the 2018 financial year, guiding for price realisation of 75 per cent to 80 per cent for the year.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BC Iron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jacques</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Metals Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JS Jacques</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US53.27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Power</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mineral Resource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smorgon Steel Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tata Steel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
