<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418713639563424</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4831837/new-look-nelson-bay-golf-club-open-photos-video/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>New-look Nelson Bay Golf Club open | photos, video</title>
  <content>
New-look Nelson Bay Golf Club open | photos, video

CHEERS: Nelson Bay Golf Club general manager Trevor Harrison and captain Peter Power celebrate the opening of the new clubhouse on Thursday, August 3.

The main entry and new carpark.

The main entry of the newly opened Nelson Bay golf clubhouse.

The side of the clubhouse is one of the first things you see when your drive into the carpark. The balcony is for the function room, which is where reception used to be in the old building.

A punter stands on the balcony of the new clubhouse on Thursday.

Minor work is still being carried out on the inside and outside of the clubhouse.

Golfers return to the clubhouse from the greens on Thursday.

The entry.

A mural of the golf course is painted in the main entry and reception area.

Booths and chairs located near the main entry.

When you walk into the club, booths and chairs are immediately left while the bar is to the right.

The main bar, looking towards the entry.

The TAB area. Work was underway on Thursday to get the clubhouse TVs and screens up and running.

Light fixtures in the TAB room.

Nelson Bay Golf Club members enjoying a beverage at the newly opened clubhouse on Thursday. Craig Burnett, front right, said the new facility was "brilliant" while Ken Wagner, behind him, said it was "worth the wait".

The main sitting area.

A view of the TAB area, right, and the main bar, left, from the main sitting area within the clubhouse.

Blue Water Grill

This hallway leads to toilets, the entry for Bluewater Grill staff into the kitchen and into the function room.

The function room is located where reception used to be in the old building.

The function room is located where reception used to be in the old building.

The function room is located where reception used to be in the old building.

The function room is located where reception used to be in the old building.

The function room is located where reception used to be in the old building.

These stairs, located near the main bar, lead downstairs to the pro shop.

The balcony off the function room, also accessible from the dining room.

New Bluewater Grill menus adorn the tables in the main dining room in the clubhouse.

New Bluewater Grill menus adorn the tables in the main dining room in the clubhouse.

A heater on the balcony located off the main sitting area.

A sign near the entry to go under the building, near the pro shop or down on to the greens.

Watering the new garden beds.

Underneath the clubhouse. The pro shop is left.

Entry to the pro shop.

A sign at the entry to the pro shop.

Entry to the pro shop. The door the right leads up stairs into the clubhouse.

The new-look pro shop.

The new-look pro shop.

The new-look pro shop.

The new-look pro shop.

exit

"Worth the wait" was the general consensus punters visiting Nelson Bay Golf Club had when asked what they thought of the new-look clubhouse on Thursday.
The doors to the building opened at noon on August 3.

Soon after, members and guests interested in seeing the new facilities began streaming in.

There were smiles on the faces of many members who felt the loss of the building when it burned down on Father's Day in 2015 and anticipation during the past 23 months while waiting for the new clubhouse to be built.

Craig Burnett, a member for 14 years, said the new clubhouse is "brilliant".
He enjoyed a drink in the TAB area of the club with friends on Thursday, while technicians worked on getting the televisions in the room connected.
"The caravan they set up [after the fire] served us well, but this is brilliant," he said.
Friend Ken Wagner said the building is "magnificent".
"We waited close to two years for this and I have to say, it is worth the wait," he said.

More to come.
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Water Grill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Wagner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Bay Golf Club</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Burnett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluewater Grill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Bays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New-look Nelson Bay Golf Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bluewater Grill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father's Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
