<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418760884204899</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/real-estate/queensland/townsville/at-home-with-blockheads-caro-and-kingi/news-story/6ef4a0bdd6f9f2619fc60fec4bb112e1</url>
  <title>At home with Blockheads Caro and Kingi - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Caro and Kingie Tahana with daughter Halia 4 at their Hyde Park Home

FRESH from their season of The Block, Caro and Kingi returned to their new Hyde Park home with no furniture and a single old airconditioner that was loud enough to wake Sleeping Beauty.
Luckily it wasn't long before the reality stars embarked on a massive renovation and now the family of three, with another on the way, are living in stylish comfort.

The couple said they had just bought the home when they were told they would be appearing on The Block so they put their belongings in storage and headed to Melbourne.
"When we came back (from The Block) we had just been living in a $2 million apartment with amazing views of South Yarra and we were sleeping on a mattress on the floor because we had no furniture," Kingi said.
"We had one old Kelvinator airconditioner in the master and it was absolutely freezing," Caro added.
"This house was horrible and it had no wardrobes ... but we could see the potential."

One of the couple's favourite styling pieces is a pendant light made out of duck feathers.

Kingi and Caro live in the five-bedroom home with their four-year-old daughter Halia, cat Big Puss and dogs Reno and Arly.
They describe their style as a blend of Scandinavian and industrial with a touch of modern minimalism.
The couple favour natural materials like timber which is used on their floors, in the kitchen and on the ceiling of their theatre room.
Kingi's signature rendering will be making a welcome appearance on the upcoming season of The Block and features heavily throughout the home.
Caro said their time on The Block had heavily influenced how they styled their own home.
"I think if we weren't on the show we definitely wouldn't have been as creative as what we have been," she said.
"Being on the show teaches you to take risks and we have really found our style on the show."
"Style runs through everything," Kingi added.
"I think Caroline is really good at dressing herself and fashion so you just carry that through everything."

Inside Caro and Kingie Tahana's home.

Caro said it was important their home cater for their growing family and after a suggestion from their builder decided to turn the walk-in wardrobe attached to their daughter's room into another bedroom.
Renovating also allowed the couple to design the home around the lifestyle including the laundry being able to fit two washing machines.
Caro, sick of her clothes coming out of the wash covered in dust and small rocks from her husband's rendering clothes, now has a washing machine dedicated to Kingi's work clothes.
"I was having render and rocks in all my beautiful clothes and I was like 'I'm going to kill this render'," she said.
"We have definitely tweaked things to make our life just a little bit easier."

Caro and Kingie Tahana with daughter Halia, 4, at their Hyde Park Home
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleeping Beauty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyde Park Home</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingie Tahana</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyde Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelvinator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scandinavian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halia 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingi</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Puss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caro</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blockheads Caro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
