<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418756589237581</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4832319/tony-butterfield-knights-sweet-win-is-just-the-start/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Tony Butterfield: Knights' sweet win is just the start</title>
  <content>
Performances of the week were shared again after the Knights found that missing ingredient, "mongrel", and gnawed off a precious victory. How sweet it was.

JOB WELL DONE: Newcastle players celebrated a long-awaited victory against the Dragons last weekend. Picture: Darren Pateman, AAP
And, again, the Melbourne Storm. The pacesetter in the context of the modern sports "franchise", they belted the high-flying Eagles by 40, celebrated Old Boys day in style, and collectively honoured the Cameron "the Keel" Smith for his astonishing 350-game service. All class.

All things going well, Smith will surpass the irrepressible Terry Lamb (350) tomorrow night in Townsville, and fellow Queenslander Darren Lockyer (355) in the Storm's first semi-final. In so doing becoming the longest, winningest, and all-round bestest dang player to have ever crossed the professional stripe in 109 years.
Expected to continue to thrive and set new standards moving toward 400, his exploits will render most sporting superlatives bereft.
Regarded as the most effective player of his era, it's been said he has more on-field influence than the great Wally Lewis and Mal Meninga combined. Off field, Queensland heritage to one side, he has inspired most anyone from skinny accountants to trade unionists to a generation of appreciative young hopefuls, such is his example.
Congrats and keep up the good work, comrade.
But back to the Knights. Before leaving for the game last week, I asked my young bloke to come along and if he could find a mate to join him. "Yeah, nah, Dad, none of the boys go anymore. They reckon the Knights suck."

In my 30 years in this town, I had never heard that before. Maybe I haven't been listening. Well, I can tell you he was dark when the Knights triumphed and he wasn't there to see it. Ha!
A special moment, as much for the faithful as it was for our men in the middle. You had to be there.
So what was the takeaway?
For mine, I don't think it was any more complex than playing tough, playing with patience, hanging onto the ball for longer, and enjoying some rare good fortune with contentious refereeing calls.

A point not lost on bewildered Dragons coach Paul McGregor, who became the first coach to invest 10 large to put referees on notice before the semis.
While he's at it, he might want to tip the guy who did up the draw this year and thank him for the Dragons' final five-game line-up. Four of which are outside the eight.

The Knights by contrast will play two, but have also drawn both of last year's grand finalists.

Want to swap, Mary?
Moving on with the two points tucked in our sock, there is a real chance to smash the "Once Were" Warriors on Saturday at the ISC. A team that can dazzle and damage and do it all on their day, they can also collapse like a dodgy souffle.
In this regard, I imagine the notion of "staying in the grind" whatever gets thrown, will have taken pride of place in preparation, keeping upfield progress simple and error-free.

That won them the game last week, and against this mob, with some love from the referees, should do it again.

But they shouldn't forget the glue that holds the unit together - desperation in defence, enthusiasm and communication - all necessary, again, if we're to nail two in a row. Something we haven't done for the longest time. 
THE voting continues in earnest to decide if the Wests board receive the member "mandate" (they've confirmed they don't really need) to go ahead with the acquisition of the NRL licence.  

All week, social media has been busy discussing the pros and cons of such an investment.

No doubt, similar discussions are being had between the thousands of Wests members with an opinion.

A contentious issue for what appears a minority.
Concern about precedents like the Tinkler balls-up has seen some locals cautioning the wisdom of rushing in before the Wests board address various questions like: "Why has the decision been rushed?"
To be fair, I think it only appears rushed because the initial announcement was so recent. It's no secret Wests have actually been in discussion for some time.
The other timing imperative involves changing jockeys mid-race and being set up and in position for the start of the Knights' new financial year on November 1.
On that basis, and presuming a change in entity only, they'll need early oversight to the financial accounts, a review of governance, review management, consider strategy, and develop budgets.

Running alongside will be resigning sponsors, re-appointing suppliers, and re-engaging with stakeholders and punters.
About the only thing that confused in this whole campaign was the charade that held, by voting a member might make a difference to a decision the board appear already to have made.
And so, as counting continues, the region's league fans are on the cusp of something new. Definitely  something better, and hopefully something the young people will admire, support and be proud of.
While it may also be something everybody is ecstatic about, it's a heck of a lot better than the alternative. Long live the Newcastle Knights!
JOKE of the week was all the hype and recriminations aimed at Josh McGuire for stepping on an opponent's ankle after effecting a tackle and making his way onside.

I saw it in play and chuckled, because while any leg or hand left on the ground was asking for a stomping in the bad ol' days, it's not something one sees too often among the Aquarian brotherhood of today.
But in this case, not long after, the gods of footy played their cards to perfection.
Serial "grub" (but outstanding player) Adam Blair took out Michael Jennings "off the ball".

Not only did his late hit cost the Broncos two points in a close game, but Blair cleaned up his own teammate and best player for the season.

You reckon the coach wasn't happy? Clumsily done or not, karma can be a bitch sometimes.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Knights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Pateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WELL DONE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Congrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Lamb (350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Boy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Butterfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aquarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mal Meninga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslander Darren Lockyer (355</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinkler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
