<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418717934531043</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/augusts-money-challenge-find-a-cheaper-phone-plan/</url>
  <title>August's Money Challenge: Find A Cheaper Phone Plan</title>
  <content>
We've thrown all kinds money challenges at you this year, and all year long, you've been acing them. This month, we want to help you save on a specific expense: Your mobile phone bill.

In August, we challenge you to find a cheaper mobile phone plan that still offers the same level of service. While many of the big carriers have started offering their own discount options, there are plenty of off-contract, pay-as-you-go plans. In fact, many of these discount carriers have forced the big players to offer better prices, so there are options out there.

Despite the fact that contract plans through the major carriers can offer some of the worst deals out there, many people still overpay for phone service.

If you've thought about getting a cheaper plan but haven't gotten around to it, this month's challenge is for you.

First, figure out your usage. How many minutes and texts do you use every month? How much data do you use? This will help you compare apples to apples. Then, use a site like  or  to compare your options.

Make sure you know your new plan's details and you're happy with the network and speeds, too. Are you in? If so, let us know how much you currently pay and how much you think you'll save each month by switching.

WATCH MORE: Tech & Finance News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August's Money Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Find A Cheaper Phone Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
