<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418709344596072</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/bernard-foley-not-expecting-special-treatment-ahead-of-rugby-championship-20170803-gxonmt.html</url>
  <title>'You've got to go out there and do your job': Foley not expecting special treatment</title>
  <content>
Bernard Foley does not expect to be wrapped in cotton wool over the next two weeks despite being the only specialist No.10 in the Wallabies squad following Quade Cooper's surprise non-selection. 
Cooper, who started at five-eighth in five Tests for the Wallabies last year, was a shock omission from coach Michael Cheika's extended squad. Photo: Stuart Walmsley
He has spent time relaxing in Bali on holidays and will try to get some minutes under his belt in the National Rugby Championship for Brisbane City in the coming weeks. 
Although Kurtley Beale and Reece Hodge are playmakers at Cheika's disposal, the Wallabies could find themselves in trouble if Foley, the side's regular No.10, picked up an injury before Australia's next Test against New Zealand on August 19. 
Foley's direction and experience will be vital for the Wallabies but he is not giving too much thought about a Plan B. 
"I've got a role within the side and it's not like you're getting protected or anything, you've got to go out there and do your job," Foley said. "There are people to feel my shoes or fill the role if required. I don't think I'm definitely a shoe-in or essential to the side.

"Quade's a quality player and he's done a lot for the Wallaby jersey, so definitely it was a bit of a surprise for me. The coaches have their reasonings and have a plan for a lot of that stuff so that's beyond my control. I'm just dong what I can now for the team." 
There are concerns Australia is not producing enough quality No.10s, given a number of the five-eighth spots in Super Rugby teams are occupied by overseas players. 
Foley described the lack of Australian No.10s as "disappointing" but has faith that plenty of capable playmakers will emerge in the coming years. 
"Seeing the No.10s in a number of the franchises not being Australian, it all goes in ebbs and flows," Foley said. "A couple of years ago we were very blessed in that position so it's come around and I hope we're developing younger guys. 
"There's a couple of guys coming through at the Waratahs who have impressed me; guys like Mack Mason, even [Hamish] Stewart for the Reds. He did really well in the under-20s. There's some talent there so hopefully they can get developed."
Meanwhile, halfback Nick Phipps joked to Foley recently he might be nipping on former housemate's heels following a brief cameo for Sydney University at No.10. 
"He keeps saying he could be the back-up 10," Foley said. "He just said at the time I might be out of a job after the weekend." 
A Foley-Beale combination at No.10 and No.12 for the Bledisloe Cup opener is likely given Karmichael Hunt has been ruled out for at least the next month. 
Foley has enjoyed having Beale back in the Wallabies setup following a stint in the UK and said he has brought plenty of energy into camp. 
"What's really impressed me since he's back is his passion and enthusiasm to play in the Wallaby jersey," Foley said. "When he went away I think it probably hit home how much he missed the Wallaby jersey. It's really exciting to have him back in a really positive frame of mind." 
The Wallabies will gather in Cessnock on Sunday to begin a week of more skill-oriented training before setting up camp in Penrith ahead of the upcoming All Blacks clash. 
There has been a sigh of relief amongst players now that the "relentless" fitness sessions are coming to an end in place of more rugby-specific training. 
"It's been tough and very challenging and I think everyone has questioned themselves a few times," Foley said. "I think from that there will be a lot of growth." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quade Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reece Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtley Beale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Walmsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernard Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karmichael Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foley-Beale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack Mason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foley</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plan B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Phipps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian No.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Rugby Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
