<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419186085975248</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/they-should-be-gone-police-government-plan-to-dismantle-martin-place-camp-20170803-gxow4l.html</url>
  <title>'They should be gone': Police, government plan to dismantle Martin Place camp</title>
  <content>
The state government is planning to dismantle a homeless camp at Martin Place for a second time, and police threaten to throw anyone who resists "in the back of a truck".
The long-standing camp of 44 tents, which house about 50 people in front of the Reserve Bank, was first dismantled by the City of Sydney council in June but many of its residents have returned.

Up Next

Charges to be laid over Sydney terrorist plane plot

01:17

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Tent city inappropriate: Berejiklian

NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian calls on Sydney mayor Clover Moore to use her powers to move on the large group of tents in Martin Place.

On Thursday afternoon, as some of the residents were zipped into their tents to escape the cold, others gathered around a marquee, where volunteers cooked hot food and offered tea and coffee as part of a 24-hour kitchen.
It was hours after Housing Minister Pru Goward said about the camp: "We will move these people on. I don't care what it takes."

NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller told 2GB the "problem" could be fixed "easily" if council workers were sent to confiscate equipment from the camp.
"If one person puts a step out of line, I'll throw them in the back of the truck," Commissioner Fuller said.

"This is a broader issue than Martin Place, it's about what do we do long-term with these people.
"They should be gone and they should not be allowed back in the city."Photo: James Brickwood
The government will meet with the City of Sydney and Commissioner Fuller on Friday to discuss the camp's future.
Some of the camp's residents have been on the streets for a few months, while for others it's been decades.Photo: Daniel Munoz
Rewi Waetford, 33, who has lived on the streets for 4 1/2 months, said before he became homeless he used to have a poor opinion of homeless people.
"I used to think 'get a job'," he said. Similar taunts are now shouted at the camp by people who walk past.Photo: Katherine Griffiths
One woman, who did not want her name used, told Fairfax Media she had been homeless for about 30 years.
"No one wants to talk to us about a solution to being homeless, they just want to talk to us about what it's like," she said. "If you really want to know, go and live on the streets for a week."
Many in the camp, including the woman, have a deep distrust of the Department of Housing, while others such as Nigel Blakemore, 45, rush to speak to department representatives when they visit the camp twice a week.
The camp's residents fear they will be put into temporary accommodation for a few weeks, then be cast back onto the street, where they will have to start from nothing.
Ms Goward, also on 2GB, said she was "angry" and "very frustrated" about the tents.
She said the community could "expect action" on Friday, including dismantling the kitchen, which she described as a "magnet" for homeless people.
"We cannot make the same mistake that we made in June, when they moved the people out of Martin Place but they didn't move the kitchen or the gas bottles," she said.
"This time we move all those structures so that kitchen doesn't remain."
Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore said it was "tragic" it had taken "tents pitched outside the offices of politicians and financiers for it to be now making news".
"It's tragic that this debate has dehumanised the people forced into this situation so much that talk is about moving them on rather than on long-term solutions," Cr Moore said.
"Instead of papering over the issue by moving people to Belmore Park, Woolloomooloo or Wentworth Park, we need the government to take practical action. You can't solve homelessness without housing."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Housing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rewi Waetford, 33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Blakemore, 45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Brickwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Fuller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolloomooloo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wentworth Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
