<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419271985322989</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/more-sports/usain-bolts-main-rival-for-100m-title-at-world-championships-andre-de-grasse-tears-hamstring/news-story/e9cde94c8e05be19f48e04ab32c849f5</url>
  <title>Bolt receives huge title boost</title>
  <content>
USAIN Bolt's main rival, Canadian sprinter Andre de Grasse, is out of the world championships after tearing his hamstring.
The 22-year-old was regarded as Bolt's main challenger for the 100m title in London.
De Grasse won the 200m silver medal and 100m bronze behind Bolt at last year's Rio Olympics while he also had the quickest time this season, a wind-assisted 9.69sec in Stockholm in June.
While Bolt has looked sluggish in the lead-up, his hopes of going out a winner in his final race have now improved dramatically.
"Injuries are a part of the sport, and the timing of this one is especially unfortunate," De Grasse said.
"The entire year this 100m race in London was my focus. I am really in the best shape of my life and was looking forward to competing against the best in the world.
"To not have this opportunity is unimaginable to me but it is the reality I am now faced with."
His manager Paul Doyle added: "We tried to do everything we could to have him ready but he's just not going to be ready.
"Further MRI results today showed it's probably going to be another four to six weeks before he's fully recovered.
"So unfortunately he's out of the 100m, 200m and the relay and done for the season."
There had been bad blood between Bolt and his young challenger after the De Grasse camp claimed they'd been shut out of the Monaco Diamond League event two weeks ago to protect the world record holder.
Bolt, an eight-time Olympic gold medallist, made it clear at his press conference on Tuesday that he'd lost respect for the young Canadian.
When asked to pick his successor, Bolt said: "I am not going down that road. The last guy who was going to be great disrespected me."
Bolt, who has won 11 world tiles, is retiring after these championships where he is running in the 100m and 4x100m relay.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grasse</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Grasse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockholm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
