<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418799538911389</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/this-riverfront-brisbane-home-is-perfectly-angled-to-capture-beautiful-views-and-northern-light/news-story/ed060568bf781b6d45e89a16d3043ef6</url>
  <title>This riverfront Brisbane home is perfectly angled to capture beautiful views and northern light - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
This angular riverfront home in Fairfield is of excellent quality and perfectly captures light and views.

Sitting on the banks of the river at is a beautiful home striking an unusual pose.
The wedgelike four-bedroom, four-bathroom, two-level home appeared to float above its site, and its creator, Push Architects principal, Paul Curran, said the location dictated the design.
"It was definitely to bend the plan to get the more desirable northern aspect and the views," Mr Curran said.
"It was just such a fantastic site with the river views, and to also get the northerly aspect over to the Eleanor Schonell Bridge which had just been constructed over to the university at the time."
Mr Curran said the home was a contemporary take with modernist elements, which included blurring the boundaries between the indoors and outdoors.

41 Brisbane Corso, Fairfield captures the views.

"You're often entertaining out on the deck and it's nice to have the kitchen quite close. It really makes a good liveable Brisbane home," Mr Curran said.

The home's stunning kitchen.

"The automated aluminium louvres protect the high and large walls of glass that do get a little bit of the northwest sun. You're able to close it down when you need to."
Not surprisingly, fittings and features were top end throughout and included high ceilings with a panelled finish, louvres, large timber-frame sliding glass doors plus built in cabinetry.

An open plan to the lounge area.

The house offered a total living area is 550sq m, all set on a 1046sq m of riverfront land.
Mr Curran said among all the design elements, his favourite was at the front.
"I always loved the way the entry sequence worked where you sort of walked across those decks that floated above the water features and the landscape and through the entry into that void," he said.

One of its architect's favourite elements.

"And also lifting the house up above the site but not too much so that it flows onto the garden really nicely and down onto the river."

The house sits above its site.

The site included established landscaping with water feature and garden that led to a private pontoon.
is to be auctioned on site August 26 at 12:00 midday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleanor Schonell Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Curran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Corso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Push Architects</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Curran</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
