<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418756589237560</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/st-george-illawarra-dragons-coach-paul-mcgregor-responds-to-10000-fine-over-referee-comments-20170803-gxorih.html</url>
  <title>Dragons coach McGregor responds to $10k fine</title>
  <content>
St George Illawarra coach Paul McGregor has provided a measured response to a $10,000 fine slapped on him by the NRL following his criticism of the bunker after his side's loss to Newcastle last week.
McGregor labelled two decisions that went against his side in the first half of the Dragons 21-14 defeat "incompetent and embarrassing".Photo: Adam McLean
Souths coach Michael Maguire and Raiders coach Ricky Stuart have both been openly critical of referees in the past fortnight, but McGregor is the first coach to be hit with a fine this season.
The Dragons have five days to respond to the preliminary breach notice issued by the NRL on Tuesday and McGregor said he would reserve comment until after the matter was fully resolved.

"I've been issued a breach notice that I have five days to respond to about my wording around the officials in the game last week," he said.
"I've still got a couple of days left to respond, which I will do, and I'll make further comment next week once I get [the NRL's] response back."

McGregor said, after the Knights game, he would seek clarification on both decisions from referees boss Tony Archer, who publicly backed both calls on Sunday.
McGregor said he had  been in contact with Archer but was unwilling to comment on the discussions.
"I emailed Arch after the game," McGregor said.
"I texted him on the phone and emailed him through a dozen clips of the game and I got a response back."
Last week's loss to Newcastle has put the Dragons' finals hopes on tenterhooks heading into Friday's SCG clash with the Rabbitohs, with McGregor admitting his side reached a critical stage of the season.
"It's time to put it all on the line, that's for sure," McGregor said.
"We still, as a group, wanted to be in the top four. Last week's loss has put a dent in that, so we're now at a stage where we need to keep winning to stay in the eight. 
"If you take it back to before a ball had been kicked, no one gave us a chance to be in the position we are in except the playing group and the close supporters who knew what we were about.
"At this stage of the year, only five games remaining, we're still in the eight. 
"It's been a tough six weeks going from that top four spot to now being in that bottom half of the eight, but we're still in it. We've come too far to get it taken away from us. 
"We've been in the eight since round one, so [we know] the importance of every game from now on. It's really up to us in what we do next."
They still face a battle to make the finals but McGregor said his team remained capable of a run at the premiership.
"When we're at our best we'll beat anyone and we've proven that," McGregor said.
"I've said it a few times this year, the difference between our best and our worst is just too far apart at the moment. 
"The difference between winning and losing in the NRL is so close, and you really need to take those opportunities once you create them.
"I think on any given day, when we play our best footy and we take our opportunities, we'll beat anyone. 
"When we're at our worst, and we don't take the chances we create, it showed last week that we can lose games as well."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday's SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Archer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
