<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418971337606308</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/17/58/govt-spends-1b-on-big-4-consulting-firms</url>
  <title>Govt spends $1b on big 4 consulting firms</title>
  <content>
The federal government is facing calls to explain why it has spent almost $1 billion on Australia's four biggest consulting companies in the past few years.
Ernst and Young, KPMG, PricewaterhouseCoopers and Deloitte were awarded more than $420 million worth of contracts in 2015/16.
That was more than double the $196 million they received in 2013/14.
Senator Nick Xenophon said the figures, released by the Finance Department in answer to a question on notice from Budget estimates, were "staggering".
He wants the auditor-general to investigate the process involved in awarding a total of 2,743 contracts valued at $998.3 million.
"The government needs to urgently explain why at a time of belt tightening for practically everyone else, they seem to have let rip for the big four consultancy firms," he said in a statement on Thursday.
The exponential increase in payments to those companies raised serious questions, he said.

Related Articles

"Surely there's enough expertise amongst 243,000 Commonwealth public servants to have provided a lot of these services that taxpayers have forked out nearly a billion dollars for in just three years."
KPMG has been the biggest beneficiary by far, winning more than 1200 contracts worth $395 million.
Senator Xenophon said there was anecdotal evidence smaller firms were missing out to the larger four.
"The government needs to give a breakdown of these contracts, what they are for, why it couldn't have been done in-house and whether there was a competitive tender process for them," he said.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PricewaterhouseCoopers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
