<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418713639563556</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/ice-cooked-into-towels-in-sydney-drug-lab/news-story/fff434a897a660bd676bb99c4e6ece3a</url>
  <title>Ice cooked into towels in Sydney drug lab</title>
  <content>
Four men have been arrested after armed police raided homes across Sydney's west and uncovered a clandestine laboratory, seven kilograms of crystal methamphetamine and stacks of cash.
A large quantity of the drug ice, enough to produce thousands of hits and worth hundreds of thousands of dollars, was reportedly cooked into towels to evade detection, AAP understands.
Detectives, riot squads and local police attached to Strikeforce Bratsell executed seven search warrants at homes at Strathfield, Cabramatta, Canley Vale, Canley Heights, Camperdown, Smithfield and Bankstown on Wednesday afternoon.
Police seized more than seven kilograms of ice, gamma-butyrolactone (GBL), drug paraphernalia, more than $50,000 in cash, post parcels, mobile phones, electronic storage devices and documentation.
Much of the ice was cooked into bath towels to avoid detection before it was shipped out from the lab, a police spokeswoman told AAP.
A crime scene was established at a Bankstown suspected of being a clandestine laboratory.
Specialist officers from the Chemical Operations Team spent Thursday afternoon examining the suspected lab.
Four men were arrested during the raids and taken to local police stations.
A 41-year-old Cabramatta man, 36-year-old Camperdown man, a 36-year-old Canley Vale man and a 53-year-old Bankstown man were all charged with offences including large commercial drug supply and indictable drug supply.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canley Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strikeforce Bratsell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bankstown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chemical Operations Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smithfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canley Vale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camperdown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabramatta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
