<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418924092965210</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/graham-quirk-says-bus-driver-pay-rise-would-cost-rate-payers-extra-1-per-cent-20170803-gxou3v.html</url>
  <title>Graham Quirk says bus driver pay rise would cost ratepayers extra $48 million</title>
  <content>
Brisbane Lord Mayor Graham Quirk has said a bus driver pay increase of 3.5 per cent would cost ratepayers an extra $48 million over three years.
"The variation is $132 million under the 2.5 per cent, it's $180 million once you talk 3.5 per cent so it's a lot of money to find and that will equate to at least a 1 per cent increase in rates for residents," the mayor said.Photo: Chris Hyde
Brisbane City Council and the Rail, Tram and Bus Union have been in a stand-off over a new enterprise bargaining agreement for bus drivers. The council has offered a 2.5 per cent pay increase but the RTBU wants a pay increase of 3.5 per cent.
Following strike action  and  the union said union-member bus drivers would not be taking fares on Friday - a move that would cost taxpayers $515,000, according to the council.

"There's actually no financial pain to council with tomorrow's action, the pain will be to Queensland taxpayers because every cent that's collected on Brisbane buses goes to the state government," Cr Quirk said.
He added that not all drivers would be part of Friday's action, so commuters should still expect to pay as normal.

On Wednesday, as hundreds of council workers rallied in King George Square, RTBU assistant secretary Tom Brown said he would not rule out more strike action if an agreement could not be reached with the council.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Eventually the pay has to be settled, there can be no EBA until the pay is settled," he said.Photo: Ruth McCosker
But the mayor said he most council workers were happy with the council's offer.
"Yesterday we were still able to operate 65 per cent of services during the stoppage," Cr Quirk said.
"Now that's a very clear indication that there are a lot of people that are not taking up their union leaderships calls for industrial action."

Hundreds of union workers outside City Hall to fight for a better EBA. One is yelling "Graham Quirk come out and talk to your workers"

While Mr Brown said the union had been making "slow progress" after the industrial action began, Cr Quirk said he was not going to "roll over lightly".
"It's got to be fair for our workers, who do a great job for Brisbane, but at the same time it has to be fair to the ratepayers and the city and I believe the offer we have on the table strikes that balance," he said.
"Why should I budge? Why should the ratepayers be asked to fork out more?"
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lord Mayor Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hyde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Quirk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth McCosker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
