<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419229035649200</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4830885/newcastle-basketball-signs-shannon-seebohm/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Newcastle Basketball signs Shannon Seebohm</title>
  <content>
Newcastle Basketball signs Shannon Seebohm

Shannon Seebohm

exit

Newcastle Basketball has ticked another box in its bid for a women's national league team with the appointment of former WNBL coach of the year Shannon Seebohm.
The 28-year-old, who coached the Australian Sapphires to women's under-17 world championship glory last year, has signed a two-year contract to work for Newcastle Basketball in the new role of coaching director, starting in October.
His contract includes guarantees that he will be head coach of Newcastle's WNBL team if Basketball Australia grants the city a licence.

Seebohm's appointment is a coup for Newcastle Basketball as it pursues a spot in the 2018-19 WNBL. 
The association is about to break ground on a $5 million stadium next to its existing centre at Broadmeadow after resolving an Aboriginal land claim on the site.    
"This is a very exciting time for Newcastle Basketball and everyone involved in it," general manager Neil Goffet said. 

"Getting Shannon here and building a new stadium gives Basketball Australia a clear indication that we are serious about entering a team in the WNBL."
Newcastle Basketball's biggest hurdle will be convincing Basketball Australia that it has the financial backing to sustain a team.

The governing body is understandably cautious about club finances after the South East Queensland Stars folded halfway through their inaugural NBL season last year.
"Shannon is another piece in the puzzle, but there are still a few pieces missing," Goffet said.

"We will now go to the Hunter community in a bid to generate the support we need to make this happen."
A near-fatal heart condition ended Seebohm's playing career when he was 19 and a member of the South Dragons NBL team under Shane Heal.

The second cousin of swim star Emily Seebohm collapsed on court and was placed in an induced coma before having surgery to implant a cardiac defribulator.
The former Australian junior representative switched to coaching and was WNBL coach of the year in 2014-15 at the age of just 26 after taking the Sydney Uni Flames to the play-offs in his rookie season.
The South Australian spent two seasons at the Flames before stepping down last year to work full-time in a high-performance role with Basketball NSW.
He will be head coach of the Hunters women's team in the Waratah League as well as performing his broader coaching duties with the Newcastle association. Darren Nichols will continue as Hunters men's coach.
Veteran former Opals centre Suzy Batkovic and current national representative Katie Ebzery would appear logical recruitment targets for Seebohm if Newcastle join the WNBL.
Two more Newcastle products, teenagers Lara McSpadden and Cassidy McLean, play with Ebzery at the Flames and were on the Sapphires team who beat the USA en route to their first world title in Spain last year.
The WNBL season has contracted from 5 1/2 months to a little over three months this year, tipping off in early October and wrapping up with finals in early January.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ebzery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Seebohm</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Goffet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basketball Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzy Batkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sapphires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle's WNBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWCASTLE Basketball</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratah League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South East Queensland Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassidy McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basketball NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Uni Flames</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goffet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Ebzery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seebohm</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Dragons NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Heal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Seebohm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Nichols</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara McSpadden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sapphire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
