<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419194675909941</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/fight-in-the-night-features-in-latest-qld-raceway-/3208406/</url>
  <title>'Fight in the Night' features in latest Qld Raceway action</title>
  <content>
FRESH from his Supercars main game debut last weekend, up and coming racer Todd Hazelwood is set to contest his second APC round this weekend.
Round four of the 2017 APC season will be held at Queensland Raceway - the venue of Hazelwood's Supercars debut during the Ipswich SuperSprint series.
The Super2 Series race winner impressed during his wildcard stint with Matt Stone Racing.
Now, the 21-year-old is preparing to take on two 300km races this weekend at 'The Paperclip' - including the infamous 'Fight in the Night' race under lights on Saturday evening.
Hazelwood will share driving duties in the #40 Mainpoint Advisory/Pulse Capital BMW130i with Scott Turner.
"I am really looking forward to this weekend, sharing the drive with my good mate Scott," Hazelwood said.
Hazelwood took out the Class C honours with Turner and Robert Rubis in the same entry at the 2017 Hi-Tec Oils Bathurst 6 Hour, which doubled as round one of the 2017 APC season.
"The little BMW is a great fun car to rip around in and hopefully we can replicate the success we had a Bathurst this weekend at Queensland Raceway."
When it comes to the prospect of racing under lights, the enthusiasm for the concept held by the South Australian is clear.
"I love night racing. It's a great spectacle for the fans but also a very cool aspect for the drivers," Hazelwood said.
"I haven't raced at night since I was in go karts so I'm looking forward to it."
With his Supercars debut last weekend being preceded by a test day at the venue the week before, it is unlikely any other driver in the field has done as many laps at QR in the last few weeks as Hazelwood.
"I think I could do the practice laps in my sleep this weekend,'' he said. "I have done so many laps around Queensland Raceway in the last two weeks, it's been crazy. I am definitely feeling well prepared for the weekend.
"I would like to think we can challenge for a Class victory. Scott has been testing recently, getting back into the groove, and with our combination hopefully we can have a great weekend of racing."
Hazelwood and Turner's entry will be part of a 25-plus field of cars taking part in round four of the 2017 APC from Friday until Sunday.
The event to feature two x 300km races, including the infamous 'Fight in the Night' under lights race on Saturday evening.
Spectator access on Friday is free, $20 for Saturday or $30 for Sunday admission.
A weekend pass is available for $40.
All of Sunday's action will be streamed online live and free via thenationals.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Stone Racing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Class C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hazelwood</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Hazelwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Rubis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hazelwood's Supercars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mainpoint Advisory/Pulse Capital BMW130</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Raceway</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hi-Tec Oils Bathurst 6 Hour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld Raceway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super2 Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich SuperSprint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
