<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419241920551273</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/a-league/teams/central-coast/central-coast-mariners-out-but-not-down-despite-ffa-cup-loss-says-paul-okon/news-story/19a465d2f2369157cd7e9e1ebcc6055c</url>
  <title>Mariners: We're out, but not down</title>
  <content>
DEFIANT Mariners coach Paul Okon insists the  won't derail his bid to rejuvenate the club for the A-League season.
Exit from the tournament means Central Coast have not won an FFA Cup game since reaching the semi-finals in 2014, and now will have no competitive games before the A-League season starts in October.
Two goals behind after 16 minutes against Blacktown, the Mariners hauled themselves level with the NPL team and seemed set to go on to win the Round of 32 tie played on the synthetic pitch at Blacktown's Lily Homes Stadium.
But a late winner from former Sydney FC striker Joey Gibbs left Okon ruing lapses in defence, though he insisted the overall performance was not that bad.
"I don't think too much went wrong - I thought we were excellent," he said. "They had a plan to sit back and take whatever chances came their way from us losing the ball, and trying to force things.
"It was made a little bit more difficult after going down a goal so early, and one we should never concede. But the positives for us are that there are a few gears we can step up, our movement was excellent, we created a number of chances and we certainly should have scored more goals.
"The disappointing thing is we gave away three cheap goals and we're out of the cup. But if we'd turned up and not played the way we did, maybe there would be some concern. We have (new) players to come in. I think we're going to be a really exciting team."
Okon admitted the goals his team conceded would require focus on the back four, after keeping clean sheets in the preceding four pre-season friendlies, though he said the artificial surface - and pre-season rustiness - had also played a part.

Football: Jos Mourinho has had his say on the record breaking Neymar transfer fee.

'He's strong commercially'
"It's down to a bit of everything, but we hadn't conceded before," he said. "That's the disappointing thing, the goals we gave away, because I think we did enough in the 90 minutes to win quite comfortably. That's an area we'll definitely be working on.
"But we're nowhere near our fitness levels and we'll step it up. As it was, Blacktown struggled to get near us and their three goals weren't scored because they outplayed us. They were goals we gave them. It was always going to be a leveller, the synthetic pitch, but that's the beauty of the competition that Blacktown get that advantage as the home team.
"Playing against a defensive block when you're behind, you maybe try to force things too much. Credit to Blacktown, they go through and we wish them luck."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey Gibbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jos Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown's Lily Homes Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Okon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
