<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419194675909956</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/nambour-crushers-to-reflect-on-grand-final-milesto/3208578/</url>
  <title>Nambour Crushers to reflect on grand final milestone</title>
  <content>
RUGBY LEAGUE: Nambour will turn back the clock to celebrate a milestone as its A-grade side hits the field for its final home game of the season.
As the Crushers battle against Caloundra in Sunshine Coast's division one, the club will celebrate the 30th anniversary of its first grand final win.
Former players and members will reminisce as they watch the current outfit play on Saturday (4.30pm) at Crusher Park.
"It'll be good if everyone can get out there and support the club and support the players that played 30 years ago in the first grand final," coach Ben Olsen said.
"It should be a great day and night all round."
It's been a tough season for the Crushers, which sits last on the six-team ladder through 17 of 19 rounds.
Olsen said his side has been plagued with injuries and relied on reserve grade and U18 stocks to back-up and hit the field in A-grade most weekends.
"If you turn up to Nambour you'll see people on crutches, in casts and a lot of major players have injured knees, ankles, hands, broken arms and all sorts of ligaments."
Despite the run of bad luck, Olsen hoped Nambour could claim a win at home.
"We're always hopeful and we're always out there 100 percent committed," he said.
Ladder leader Maroochydore - which only needs to turn up to play its last two games to win the minor premiership - hosts Caboolture and Noosa hosts Kawana.
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
TERRY Fewtrell's new book shares the history of Palmwoods.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Crushers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TERRY Fewtrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olsen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday (4.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Olsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crusher Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUGBY LEAGUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
