<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419100186627680</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/sydney-swans/sydney-swans-captain-josh-kennedy-to-miss-geelong-cats-clash-but-kurt-tippett-returns-20170803-gxoph9.html</url>
  <title>Sydney Swans captain Josh Kennedy to miss Geelong Cats clash</title>
  <content>
Captain Josh Kennedy has succumbed to a hamstring injury and won't play in Friday's crunch clash against the high-flying Geelong Cats in a massive blow for the precariously placed Sydney Swans.
And in a further hit for the Swans, ruckman Sam Naismith will also miss the Cats game after suffering an abdominal strain in last Friday's loss to Hawthorn.

Up Next

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

03:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

but couldn't prevent Sydney suffering just a second defeat in its past 12 games.
A scan during the week revealed his hamstring was inflamed, and the hard-ball winning skipper was reduced to jogging duties at training on Wednesday and unable to prove his fitness in time for Friday's blockbuster at Simonds Stadium.

The Swans will decide on a replacement skipper on Friday, with vice-captains Luke Parker, Dane Rampe and Dan Hannebery likely to shoulder the extra leadership load.  to fill the gaping breach left by Kennedy's injury.
"The risk was too great [to play Kennedy], we'll see how he goes next week," coach John Longmire said.

"He pulled up a lot better earlier in the week, we're hoping at this stage it's just the one week. He was able to run around [Wednesday] but not get to full pace."
who will play his first AFL match since round 10 in an injury and form interrupted 2017.Photo: AAP
Swing man Sam Reid also comes back in after overcoming a groin injury, while Gary Rohan (back) and Jake Lloyd (hip) also come back in after their late withdrawals from the Hawthorn match last round.
Callum Sinclair hurt his ankle against the Hawks, but has been cleared to play.
Dan Robinson and Jordan Foote have been omitted as the Swans look to consolidate their position in the top eight. They're sixth with a strong percentage on 40 points alongside four clubs including the ninth-placed Western Bulldogs.
Tippett has played only five AFL matches this season kicking just three goals, and has been running around in the reserves of late although didn't play last weekend with the Swans having a bye in the NEAFL.
The 202cm ruckman has kicked 12 goals in five reserves games this year.
"Kurt, obviously with Naismith going out of the team, he's another marking target for us in our forward half," Longmire said.
"He was really good the week before, and obviously didn't play on the weekend. He's feeling a lot better now, he's moving quite well.
"It's good to have Sam back in, he missed a couple of weeks, he has got that versatility in his game as well."
Longmire said the return of Lloyd down back was a huge boost.
"He's a very important player for us, he's had a fantastically consistent year this year, he's been really good from the first round," Longmire said.
"It's really important to get him back in."
The Swans won both games against Geelong last season, most recently in last year's preliminary final by 37 points at the Melbourne Cricket Ground where Tom Papley booted three goals.
They also prevailed by 38 points at Simonds Stadium in round 16.
Sydney's chances received a massive boost on Monday when the match-review panel handed reigning Brownlow medallist Patrick Dangerfield a one-match ban for rough conduct after his tackle on Matthew Kreuzer left the Blues' ruckman concussed.
"It's a real challenge going down there, they're one of the best teams in the competition clearly and they play that ground so well," Longmire said.
"We enjoy the trip down to Geelong and our players enjoy getting down there and taking on the second best team in the competition at the moment on the ladder."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Rampe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Naismith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong Cats</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Sinclair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Hannebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naismith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cricket Ground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tippett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Foote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Longmire</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
