<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419143136301532</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/paul-pisasale-faces-fresh-charges-after-ccc-probe-20170803-gxoxq2.html</url>
  <title>Paul Pisasale faces fresh charges after CCC probe</title>
  <content>
The Crime and Corruption Commission has charged former Ipswich mayor Paul Pisasale with two counts of attempting to pervert justice.
Fairfax Media understands the charges relate to calls Mr Pisasale made this week to his former driver, Steve Potts, in which he offered to help him find a job in exchange for Mr Potts recanting allegations the former mayor had misused his official car.Photo: Tammy Law
On Sunday, Fairfax Media revealed claims by Mr Potts that Mr Pisasale had used his mayoral car and driver for chauffeur-driven trips to brothels and frequent visits to massage parlours.
The CCC late on Thursday announced it had issued a 65-year-old Ipswich man with a notice to appear in court to face to counts of attempting to pervert justice contrary to section 140 of the Queensland Criminal Code.
Mr Pisasale is due to appear in the Brisbane Magistrates Court on August 8 to face the charges.
The CCC said it was unable to comment further as its investigation remained ongoing.
Mr Pisasale is already on police bail on a charge of extortion and two charges of assault.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Potts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tammy Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Potts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pisasale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Criminal Code</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corruption Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pisasale</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
