<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419014287280140</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/south-sydney-rabbitohs/coaches-under-pressure-after-des-hasler-its-michael-maguires-turn-to-feel-the-heat-20170803-gxop5v.html</url>
  <title>Coaches under pressure: After Des Hasler it's Michael Maguire's turn to feel the heat</title>
  <content>
Another day, another column about a coach under pressure. This job would be so much easier if every team just won.
On Friday night, Michael Maguire shoves Des Hasler out of the way and the interrogation lamp falls on him as South Sydney meet St George Illawarra at the SCG.

Up Next

Cherry-Evans: Defence the issue for Manly

00:43

More Rugby League Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Canberra keep slim finals hopes alive

The Raiders claimed a solid 32-18 victory over South Sydney.

Maguire's predicament doesn't seem as dire as Hasler's at the Bulldogs, but serious questions are starting to be asked about whether the man who guided the Rabbitohs to the 2014 premiership is still the man the Rabbitohs need.
Speculation is cranking up. More than a few have suggested to this column the call to sack Maguire and replace him with assistant Anthony Seibold has already been made. It's just a matter of when.

I've been assured this is nonsense and that no discussion with Seibold or fellow assistant David Furner about taking control has ever taken place.
Nevertheless, Maguire is feeling the heat. He should be.

In March last year,  after his side had smashed arch rivals the Roosters in the first round.
Souths' title defence had flopped the year before amid plenty of talk from his own players about being "worn down" by Maguire's relentless style of coaching.Photo: Renee McKay/Getty Images
I asked if he would change his coaching style.
"No."
Does he have to change his coaching style?
"Not at all. I am who I am. My players work really hard with me to achieve what I want to achieve this weekend."
Souths finished the season in 12th position. They are 14th with five rounds remaining and even though they've been up to their necks in a few close matches, that is a position a glamour club can only tolerate for so long.
Maguire is reportedly still as intense and focused as ever. He didn't change, as he said. Is it wearing the players down? You hear a few rumblings but nothing compared to the dissatisfaction of 2015.
When Souths re-signed Maguire last year, they did so because the place needed some stability. Players had come and gone and co-owner Russell Crowe had been in a pre-season stink with Luke Keary.
And, in reality, there was nobody else out there.
Much of the blame has been laid at the feet of a messy salary cap, with former officials accused of re-signing Burgess twins George and Thomas on too much money.
Fixing the roster takes time. Just ask Phil Gould at Penrith.
But if you told any coach they could take on a team that includes Sam Burgess, the Burgess twins, Adam Reynolds and Greg Inglis, they would jump at it. Next year, add Dane Gagai to the mix and it's some team.
The loss of Inglis to depression for most of the season also cannot be underestimated.
Those handful of games Souths have lost may have fallen their way with a game-breaker like "GI" on the field. But more than that, as captain, he's become the heart and soul of the team and he's been sorely missed.
The counter-argument to all this is to put the onus back on the players; that they aren't prepared to make the same sacrifices they made in 2014 to climb the premiership mountain again.
But Souths look like a side that needs a change. They need a different voice. You suspect this is what is also happening at Belmore with Hasler. It certainly seems to be what's happening at Redfern.
Next Thursday, Souths play the Bulldogs at their mutual home ground of ANZ Stadium.
You can already imagine the two coaches bumping into each other in the tunnel, rolling their eyes and saying, "I feel you, bro. I feel you".
EXPLOSIVE HEADLINE
The Bulldogs switchboard is still lighting up like a Christmas tree after The Daily Telegraph's front-page story about terror suspect Khaled Khayat.
The Tele splashed with an image of a jubilant Khayat wearing his Bulldogs jumper, arms raised in the air - it must have been a very old pic - along with the headline, "BULLDOG AND A BOMB".
Khayat is one of the men being held for questioning over an alleged plot to destroy an aircraft flying out of Sydney. He has not been charged.
When fans are furious with something that's appeared in the paper, they often call the club to vent instead of the publication.
It must be said that other media outlets - including the Herald - ran the same image but only The Tele made such a strong link to rugby league and the club.
The Bulldogs say they are seeking legal advice but their only course of action is to take the matter before the Press Council.
Earlier this year, Arsenal fans called for a boycott of British tabloid The Sun after the paper focused on the fact that one of the men shot dead by police in the London Bridge terrorist attacks was wearing the strip of the English Premier League giants.
The headline: "KILLER IN AN ARSENAL SHIRT".
ORIGIN DECIDER
NSW coach Laurie Daley finally put his head up this week, appearing on NRL 360 on Fox Sports to talk in detail about what went wrong in the Origin decider three weeks ago.
The decision to break his silence via one of his paid media gigs, instead of fronting a media conference and a handful of senior reporters, shows weak leadership from the NSWRL.
Next year, after they give him one more crack at the job after losing the last three series, the Blues will expect enthusiastic and positive prose about this being the year. Finally. Maybe. Whatever.
Daley's interview raised more questions than it answered.
Just exactly what was Andrew Fifita so angry about that prompted Daley to backflip on his decision to start David Klemmer?
And what about The Star?
It seems like the decision to stay at the venue of the major sponsor was a turning point if some of the speculation that continues to whir about game two is anyway near the mark.
HAIR IN WAITING
The announcement of Michael Hooper as the new Wallabies coach is exactly what rugby union requires - he just needs to let his hair grow longer.
A kid from Sydney's northern beaches, Hooper doesn't fit the rah-rah stereotype.
He rips in on the training paddock then on the field and then goes home and rides skateboards and rides Harley Davidson motorbikes.
I've had more than a few of the rugby establishment take aim at his beach-blond hair, saying he doesn't look like a captain. Seriously.
Talk to his teammates at various levels over the years and they say nobody hurts more after a loss.
Sounds like the right man for the job to me.The week

THE QUOTE
"Les Murray came to Australia as a refugee, and represents every refugee now so mistreated by a heartless government and nation. How many thousands of Les Murrays have we failed to give a chance?" - Craig Foster following the death this week of his SBS colleague and friend. THE quote of the week.
THUMBS UP
Eels centre Michael Jennings slammed Bronco Josh McGuire's stomp on Tim Mannah's ankle as a "low act" then implored teammate Kenny Edwards to never change despite his brutal attack on Jonus Pearson. Never change, Jenko. Nor you, rugby league.
THUMBS DOWN
Can I have whatever the person who is doing the NRL scheduling is on? Traditional rivals Dragons take on Souths at the SCG ... at 6pm on Friday. Why not a Sunday afternoon, so country members can attend, with the grand old ground bathed in sunshine? The NRL has cost itself about 10,000 fans with such a silly kick-off.
It's a big weekend for ... the Swannieeeeeees, who take on second-placed Geelong at the Cattery on Friday night. People on the streets of Vaucluse and Rose Bay are convinced Sydney will win the flag this year.
It's an even bigger weekend for ... Neymar jnr, who is about to nail down a deal to move from Barcelona to PSG worth about half a billion dollars. That's US dollars? Uh, OK.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonus Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsenal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Inglis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khayat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaucluse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Des Hasler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Gagai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cattery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronco Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Furner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgess</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Gould</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seibold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inglis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Seibold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KILLER IN AN ARSENAL SHIRT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSWRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ORIGIN DECIDER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Crowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Klemmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Keary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redfern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maguire</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Maguire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BULLDOG AND A BOMB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Press Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee McKay/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swannieeeeeees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tele</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
