<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419100186627657</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/racing-nsw-to-ban-sending-horses-knackery/8771386</url>
  <title>Racing NSW plan to stop thoroughbreds going to the knackers challenges secretive industry</title>
  <content>
The thoroughbred racing industry in New South Wales has announced a ban on sending horses to the knackery where they end up as food for the greyhound industry.
Racing NSW animal welfare officer Graham Hinton said while most retiring race horses went into breeding programs or the equestrian sector, the organisation wanted to ensure none ended up at the knackery.
"We've had a rule in place for the last two years that obliges owners and trainers to submit to us a final destination for their horse, and those statistics are quite positive," he said.
"[Only] 0.4 per cent of retiring thoroughbreds in Australia have ended up in an abattoir.
"We believe in NSW that we can make that number nil."
The ban, still to be ratified by the board, is part of a broader industry plan to invest 1 per cent of prize money into animal welfare.
That includes the purchase earlier this month of a 2,600 hectare property in NSW called Capertee, which will be used to retrain horses for the equestrian sector and recreational use.
Fate of horses in breeding and sporting sectors not tracked

While the number of horses going direct from racing to the knackery is very low - just 34 in 2015-16 - the industry does not track what happens when they move into the breeding or sporting sector.
About 8,500 race horses are retired each year and it is likely a fair number eventually end up in a knackery.
Statistics about the horse meat industry are hard to find, but it is estimated there are more than 30 knackeries around Australia processing sheep, cattle, goats, donkeys, camels and horses.
The Department of Agriculture said 9,000 horses were processed by two abattoirs licensed to export horse meat.
A United Nations Food and Agriculture Organisation estimate put the figure as high as 94,000 in 2011.
The NSW Food Authority inspects knackeries but will not give out information about their location, and said it did not keep track of how many horses were processed.
Two knackeries contacted in Sydney have so far declined to talk.

Decision welcomed by RSPCA

RSPCA NSW chief executive Steve Coleman welcomed the decision.
"Any industry that's prepared to take responsibility for the animals that they produce, particularly in the context of sport or for wagering, is a good thing, so we'd support that," he said.
But Mr Coleman does not want the processors shut down.
"There will always be a small percentage of owners that are unable to adequately deal with the disposal or the euthanasia of their animals," he said.
"Something we regularly deal with is complaints about old horses that are not being fed appropriately or are simply starving to death."
'Knackeries provide important service'

Horse traders buy stock for the knackeries and abattoirs.
There are about 15-20 in NSW alone who go to a number of sales in NSW, Victoria and Queensland.
One trader, who did not want to be identified for fear of being targeted by animal welfare activists, agreed the knackeries provided an important service.
"We buy horses privately out of the paddocks and the saleyards to send to the meatworks," he said.
"If people have a horse that's aged or a horse they can't afford to keep any more, it's certainly cheaper and better for them [if we] come and buy the horse off them and then take it away to be processed."

Mike Eathorne manages Meramist in Queensland, one of only two abattoirs licensed to process horse meat for human consumption.
He exports to Europe.
"We could process anywhere up to 7,000-8,000 horses a year, a mix of brumbies, thoroughbreds, to station horses," he said.
While there is not much demand for horse meat in Australia, it is legal to sell product coming from licensed abattoirs.
It is not clear if other horse groups will follow suit after the Racing NSW ban.
Equestrian Australia said it was up to owners to decide what they did with their horses, and it did not keep track of what happened to horses when they retired from competition.
But consumers should not be concerned about horse meat in cans or bags of pet food.
The Pet Food Association of Australia said meat from horses, whales and dolphins was not used by its members, which covered the vast majority of companies.
The knackeries only supply fresh meat that is coloured blue to ensure it does not get in to the human food chain.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meramist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capertee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Eathorne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Hinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pet Food Association of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agriculture Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Food</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equestrian Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knackeries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Food Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
