<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418971337606349</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/media-reforms-gather-momentum-with-greens-sarah-hansonyoung-keen-to-talk-20170802-gxo9am</url>
  <title>Media reforms gather momentum with Greens Sarah Hanson-Young keen to talk </title>
  <content>
The chances of a breakthrough on  have improved, with the Greens coming back to the negotiating table in a bid to stave off a Pauline Hanson inspired threat to the ABC.
Former Greens senator Scott Ludlam's resignation from the Senate has paved the way for the party's new communications spokesperson, Sarah Hanson-Young, to re-open talks with Communications Minister Mitch Fifield in a bid to strike a deal.
Any deal by the Greens would require the minor party to overcome its long-standing hostility towards News Corporation but Senator Hanson-Young recognised the need to help other media outlets.
"It's no surprise that News Corporation and Rupert Murdoch want to expand their empire," she told The Australian Financial Review.

"We are, of course, worried about media diversity but we are also very concerned about making sure we find ways to retain quality, independent journalism and not seeing smaller players hung out to dry."

The so-called two out of three rule - which bans a media company from owning a newspaper, TV station and radio station in the same metropolitan market - has been the major stumbling block to securing passage of the media reforms despite unanimous backing from Australian publishers and broadcasters.
While Labor is point blank refusing to budge on scrapping that ownership restriction, the Greens and One Nation have begun to soften their stances in return for concessions.
The government has listed media reform for debate when Parliament resumes next week.
Securing the seven votes currently held by the Greens for the media reforms would get the media reform package over the line when added to the votes of crossbenchers David Leyonhjelm, Cory Bernardi and Derryn Hinch. 

Senator Nick Xenophon and his two upper house colleagues are also likely to support the overhaul, with the South Australian saying on Wednesday progress had been made on his amendments to boost news coverage.
Despite One Nation backing away in May from a , the Greens remain fearful One Nation could convince the government to gut public broadcasting in return for supporting media reform.
"We're not going to stand by and let the ABC and SBS come under attack from One Nation," Senator Hanson-Young said.
Senator Hanson-Young stressed the Greens had not made a decision to support media reform and was tightlipped about the details of amendments the party would push in negotiations.  

"We're open to seeing whether we can do something to secure a better outcome for Australian journalists," she said.
The Greens would pursue protections for local content, amid a push by commercial TV networks to axe quotas for children's programming.
"We know that kids TV is part of Australia's cultural heritage and the fabric of our community," Senator Hanson-Young said.
"Children's content is also the bedrock of Australia's production houses. It's where many people start out, it underpins the sustainability of Australia's entire production industry and the commercial broadcasters waging a war against having quotas is a real risk."

If the government fails to reach agreement with the Greens, it will need both Senator Xenophon's and One Nation's blocs. One Nation wants  in an already concentrated market.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communications Minister Mitch Fifield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corporation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens' Sarah Hanson-Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Hanson Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupert Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson-Young</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Ludlam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Leyonhjelm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cory Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
