<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419319229964186</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/lake-fenton-produces-the-states-best-water-but-the-local-area-remains-on-a-boil-water-alert/news-story/62565eac243bab1f480bd61d20938756</url>
  <title>Locals miss out on state</title>
  <content>
THEIR area may have just won the crown as the source of Tasmania™s best drinking water, but the people who live closest to Lake Fenton still have to boil their tap water before it can be drunk.

Residents and businesses in National Park and Westaway, and the many tourists who pass through on their way to Mt Field, will have to wait until a new water treatment plant is built next year to be able to drink from the tap.

The water from Lake Fenton, which is piped into Hobart's northern suburbs, was this week deemed the State's best drinking water.

However, those living and working near its source remain on a boil water alert.

Water from Lake Fenton runs along natural streams to a weir above National Park. From there it is collected by TasWater in the Fenton pipeline. It is chlorinated and distributed to several Hobart suburbs and also stored in dams at Waterworks Reserve

At times of heavy rain, organic material and sediments picked up by run-off in the Lake Fenton catchment as it travels along the natural stream to the weir means the water can becoming discoloured.

When this happens, TasWater stops using the water from Lake Fenton in the Hobart area and substitutes it with water from other sources.

"However due to the configuration of the infrastructure in the local area of Fentonbury, Westerway and National Park it is not practical to prevent the turbid water entering the supply network of these communities," TasWater said.

"Previously temporary boil water alerts were imposed during periods of increased turbidity. In consultation with the Department of Health and Human Services it was decided as a precaution and to avoid confusion, to put a permanent health alert in place."

Rachel Power, the owner of Waterfalls Cafe and Gallery in National Park said every time it rained the water became undrinkable and a permanent boil water alert had been in place for her nearby town of Westerway since the middle of last year.

"We needed to know what I was serving my customers was fit to drink so the boiled water is a good thing until the situation is sorted," Mrs Power said.

"We are pleased there will be a new treatment plant built and the alert will finally be lifted but TasWater must ensure the plant is built in a place which will allow all customers in the area to be able to drink from the tap."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fentonbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Fenton</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterworks Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasWater</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fenton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westerway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterfalls Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals Park</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
