<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419542568268192</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/bieber-breaks-silence-over-cancelled-tour/news-story/b12f05c0e4f001f0b6b71479c47cfa37</url>
  <title>Bieber breaks silence over cancelled tour</title>
  <content>
Justin Bieber has poured his heart out in an open letter to his fans after cancelling the rest of his world tour.
The Canadian pop star last week announced he was pulling the final dates of his Purpose tour "due to unforeseen circumstances".
Bieber, 23, has addressed the cancelled tour for the first time, and said it was due in part to wishing to have a "sustainable" career and future.
He told his fans he was "grateful" for the journey with them, for his previous tours and for going through "this life" with them.
The Sorry hit-maker wrote: "I have let my insecurities get the best of me at times, I let my broken relationships dictate the way I acted toward people and the way I treated them!"
He added he let "bitterness, jealousy and fear" run his life.
Bieber said he was "VERY aware" he would never be "perfect" and said he would keep making mistakes.
"What I'm not gonna do is be ashamed of my mistakes," he said.
"I wanna be a man that learns from them and grows from them.!! I want you all to know this tour has been unbelievable and has taught me so much about myself..
"I've learned the more you appreciate your calling the more you want to protect your calling. Me taking this time right now is me saying I want to be SUSTAINABLE.
"I want my career to be sustainable, but I also want my mind heart and soul to be sustainable. So that I can be the man I want to be, the husband I eventually want to be and the father I want to be."
He said he wanted his message to act as an opportunity for people to "know where I am coming from".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Bieber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bieber, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bieber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
