<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418924092965217</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/turtle-researchers-turn-to-sex-toys-to-determine-male-and-female/8772054</url>
  <title>Turtle researchers turn to sex toys to determine male and female of species</title>
  <content>
A Queensland university student says a vibrator can determine the sex of a turtle with 100 per cent accuracy for some species.
James Cook University PhD student Donald McKnight said if successful, the method could be used in Australia as a less invasive way to distinguish between a male and female.
"Most of the published methods are pretty invasive - like opening a turtle up surgically, which is stressful for the turtle and time consuming for the researcher," he said.
"We were trying to find basically, a better and cheaper way to determine which turtles were male and female and it turns out you can do that just with a cheap vibrator."
The shell shape, size of claw and colour patterns of a turtle usually indicate the sex, but when those visual characteristics gave researchers inconclusive results for a particular species, they looked for alternatives.

A vibrator has been used in previous research to collect sperm from male turtles.
"So we figured if you could use it to collect sperm, you could also use it as a method of telling males and females apart," Mr McKnight said.
He said when the vibrator was placed against the turtle, the animal produced a visible reaction quite quickly.
"For some turtles, if it's in an area where they don't really like it, they'll tuck their body up tightly," he said.
"Whereas, if you're in an area that's really arousing them, they'll start to relax and extend their limbs out and what you're looking for is for the the male to reveal himself and flash you - basically."
Mr McKnight said up to 10 minutes was spent with each turtle, ascertaining sex.
"The soft shells really responded quickly and we had one where the male was revealing himself in about four seconds," he said.
"Some of the other species took longer and as soon as the male revealed himself, we stopped but if after 10 minutes we hadn't seen anything, we ended the trial."

The research was done in Oklahoma in the United States on a wild population of locally-threatened western chicken turtles.
The method has also been used on spiny soft shells, Mississippi mud turtles and common musk turtles with 100 per cent, 80 per cent and 55.6 per cent accuracy respectively.
Mr McKnight said the method could work on Australian turtles.
"No-one's tried it yet so there's only one way to really find out, but I suspect it would," he said.
"I really hope people start experimenting around with this method.
"It's very possible that there are different vibrators and different techniques that will work better for some species than others."
The research was completed in the United States and .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald McKnight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mississippi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cook University PhD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McKnight</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
