<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419314934996794</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/18/31/heart-attack-myth-emily-rice-chest-pain</url>
  <title>Heart attack myths could be putting your life at risk</title>
  <content>
Think heart attack and the most dramatic symptoms often spring to mind - chest-clutching, severe pain, gasps for air, followed by sudden collapse.
But health experts fear the Hollywood heart attack myth could be putting lives at risk.
Dr Janet Bray, from Monash University's School of Epidemiology and Preventive Health, says many men and women dangerously wait for the stereotypical symptoms to kick in before seeking help.
"People were expecting severe crushing chest pain and when they didn't experience that they went on to misdiagnose themselves," Dr Bray said.
And this delay in seeking medical treatment may be life-threatening.
"The longer you wait when you are experiencing heart attack the more heart muscle that dies."
Dr Bray led a study during which more than 100 heart attack patients were interviewed about what happened before they made it to hospital.

Related Articles

Most of these were men with an average age of 59 years.
The study found 63% did not realise their symptoms, including mild chest pain, were a precursor to a heart attack. 
"One-in-five thought their symptoms were related to a gastric type problem like indigestion ... or related to a muscular skeletal problem like a pulled muscle in their shoulder," said Dr Bray.
The reality is the physical signals of an impending heart attack vary from person to person.  Often they are subtle and gradual.
"Some people have pain in their jaw, pain in their shoulder, pain in their back. And it's usually a feeling of tightness or pressure."
Just four days ago 53 year old Matthew Day suffered a heart attack.
While the father felt unwell he certainly didn't have a dramatic Hollywood style episode.
"I just hopped out of the car and felt really uncomfortable in the chest, a little nausea came over, sweating, cold feeling. Something wasn't right. I couldn't tell you exactly what it was but I know something wasn't right, he said.
He rushed to Monash Medical Centre where doctors discovered he had suffered a heart attack.
After having two stents implants he is healthy enough to go home.
But this lucky patient urges others to act on any chest discomfort that does not subside.
"Catch an ambulance, come in, find out and worst case scenario you get sent home in an hour or two."
The warning signs can include
- Chest discomfort, tightness or heaviness...
- Arms, shoulder, neck or back pain
- Or breath shortness, nausea or dizziness.
For more information .
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Medical Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Bray</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preventive Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Janet Bray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University's School of Epidemiology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
