<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418821013748245</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:34</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/a-look-inside-chuck-palahniuks-next-novella-which-is-also-a-colouring-book/</url>
  <title>A Look Inside Chuck Palahniuk's Next Novella, Which Is Also A Colouring Book</title>
  <content>
If you thought the adult colouring book craze was just , think again. After surprising us all with last year's Bait, a short story anthology/colouring book hybrid, Chuck Palahniuk is returning to the well again with his first long-form prose in three years, and it also happens to include gorgeous art for you to colour in, too.

Image: Dark Horse. Art and Design by Duncan Fegredo and Nate Piekos.

Published by Dark Horse, Legacy: An Off-Color Novella for You to Color marks Palahniuk's first return to long-form fiction since 2014's Beautiful You. Although since then he's been involved in a number of weird and wonderful projects, such as the comic book sequel to Fight Club, the weirdest of all has got to be Bait, an anthology that interspersed new stories from the author with vivid, absurd scenarios for readers to colour in themselves. Not quite the same as colouring in pictures of Jamie from Outlander or an , but still a weird prospect.

Legacy intends to be much the same, except this time Steve Morris and Mike Norton's art appears alongside a new, singular tale from Palahniuk that blends grim social satire with the blatant absurdity of colouring in intimate and human scenes and scenarios as you go along. Check out a few pages from the book, making their debut here.

Legacy: An Off-Color Novella for You to Color is expected to be released this November.

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beautiful You</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palahniuk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nate Piekos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dark Horse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outlander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Look Inside Chuck Palahniuk's Next Novella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fight Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chuck Palahniuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Norton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Also A Colouring Book</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Color Novella</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan Fegredo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
