<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419529683365917</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/conflict-of-interest-for-kate-carnell-to-lead-oakden-inquiry/8771410</url>
  <title>Oakden aged care home inquiry boss Kate Carnell denies conflict of interest</title>
  <content>
The person leading a government inquiry into the accreditation of a nursing home - where a sexual assault and a murder occurred - was a director of the very agency which approved the home.

Key points:

Kate Carnell heading review into accreditation of Oakden aged care facility
Ms Carnell was a director of the agency which approved the home
She says there is no conflict of interest

Former ACT chief minister Kate Carnell is heading a review into how .
"We are very concerned," Lynda Saltarelli of Aged Care in Crisis said.
"It's a conflict of interest. It's a bit like reviewing your old workplace."
Ms Carnell told 7.30 said she did not believe it was a conflict of interest and that, on the contrary, her position was helpful because she "understands how accreditation works".
She said the Federal Government was "well aware of the time I spent on the Aged Care Standards and Accreditation Agency".
Oakden closed earlier this year following revelations of widespread abuse and neglect of residents. .
The accreditation agency judges nursing homes on 44 criteria, including staff ratios and clinical care. Almost 100 per cent of homes get a 100 per cent score, despite complaints from residents and their relatives.
High score despite complaints

Aged care home Opal Lakeview, at Lakes Entrance in Victoria, has passed inspections by the Government accreditation agency with flying colours for the past nine years.
when she was struck around the head by an Opal worker. Police charges were dropped when the staff member said she was swatting lice.
. She had diabetes and died days after staff ignored doctors advice to get her to hospital.
Another top scorer was Opal Leamington. That was what attracted Yvonne Selir when she was looking for a nursing home for her father-in-law, Danny.
from sepsis and necrotic pressure sores in hospital.
Mandatory reporting not necessary, Commissioner says

The federal review into accreditation will also look at the performance of the Aged Care Complaints commissioner Rae Lamb.
Ms Selir complained about Opal Leamington to Ms Lamb, who told her Opal had organised "mandatory wound-care training" for all nurses and closed the matter.
At the moment, a home could have one or 100 complaints against it but the public has no idea. Advocates like Ms Saltarelli want that information made publicly available.
"We can look up information about cars, computers, when you buy a mobile phone or any product, except for when you're looking to place your mum or dad in a nursing home," she said.
But the Commissioner disagrees. She said believed nursing homes should volunteer details of any complaints made when families ask, but she does not want mandatory reporting of complaints.
"I'm not sure you should always need regulation to achieve these things," she told 7.30.
"It's like an apology. Should you say to someone that through regulation you have to apologise? Or should you encourage it as best practice and try to sell the fact that you get better outcomes and things like that.
"I think it's a more meaningful apology if it's not forced."
Out of 532 cases, only six categorised as high risk

The Aged Care Complaints Commissioner has the power to refer complaints to the Aged Care Quality Agency.
In the past 18 months the Commissioner has referred 532 cases to the agency but only six of those were categorised as high risk and resulted in an unannounced visit to the home.
The results of unannounced visits are not available to the public.
"We've looked at the UK and the US, and they have far more transparent systems than Australia," Ms Saltarelli said.
"We believe that all of the agency reports, including the unannounced site visits, contact visits, all of the site reports, should be published and available for consumers."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opal Leamington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Saltarelli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rae Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Accreditation Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opal Lakeview</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Selir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakes Entrance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aged Care Complaints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynda Saltarelli of Aged</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aged Care Quality Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yvonne Selir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Carnell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aged Care Standards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Carnell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aged Care Complaints Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opals</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
