<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419538273300737</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/football/a-league/aleague-to-scrap-rule-that-allowed-melbourne-city-to-sign-tim-cahill-as-a-seasonlong-guest-player/news-story/e6031b0138e0ce71407f7d1c29185fc7</url>
  <title>A-League to ditch 'Cahill rule'</title>
  <content>
THE rule that allowed Melbourne City to snare Tim Cahill is set to be scrapped after one season.
The Herald Sun understands the Season 2016/17 Guest Player provision will be discontinued.
And Football Federation Australia has confirmed the A-League's $3 million marquee fund is also to be abolished, with the funds to be distributed evenly to the clubs for marketing purposes.
The guest marquee rule was informally dubbed the "Cahill Rule", as City was the only club to use it.
The clubs agreed to the rule change before last season.
They knew it would pave the way for Cahill to return, but also understood they - and the league as a whole - would reap benefits.
Players to be recruited under the rule had to meet strict marketability criteria set by FFA, which would then chip in for part of the player's contract.
Western Sydney (Eduardo da Silva) and Melbourne Victory (Alessandro Diamanti) were knocked back in attempts to sign guest marquees.
But FFA did approve of Victory's pursuit of former Chelsea star Michael Essien, only for the deal between player and club to fall through.
The little-used 14-game guest player rule, which allows teams to recruit a star player outside of the salary cap for a short stint as City did with David Villa in 2014, remains.
While Cahill was a guest marquee last season, this season's wages will fall under City's salary cap.
It means City can still sign one other marquee this season, with Bruno Fornaroli occupying the other spot.
While FFA maintains marquee players, where affordable, can "add tremendous value to the league", chief executive David Gallop said discussions with the clubs in the past six months had led to the change of direction with regards to the marquee fund.
"In the new broadcast deal an amount of $3 million was set aside for spending on marquees for the coming season given the ratings impact that marquee players have had on Fox Sport's ratings in previous seasons," Gallop said.

Football: Jos Mourinho has had his say on the record breaking Neymar transfer fee.

'He's strong commercially'
"However in discussion with A-League clubs that began six months ago about the best use of these funds, it was agreed that attempting to bring one or two marquee players to the league was not something that the clubs wanted to pursue in circumstances where the international player market was overheated, particularly in our region due to the deals being offered by Chinese clubs among others.
"Therefore, with the clubs' unanimous agreement, FFA asked Fox to unlock the funds to be shared equally by the clubs to spend on the marketing of two or three existing high profile players on their roster, including new and existing internationals and local heroes.
"There is a belief that the game needs to improve its marketing broadly across all clubs to connect fans and create household names.
"It is also recognised that this will help increase ratings and improve future media rights values."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cahill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Villa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League's $3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Gallop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cahill Rule</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Victory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Cahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jos Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 2016/17 Guest Player</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno Fornaroli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alessandro Diamanti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Essien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eduardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
