<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419443784018085</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/opposition-builds-to-tassal27s-move-into-port-arthur/8770176</url>
  <title>Fish farming returns to Port Arthur as Tassal prepares to restock lease after 11 years</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Salmon giant Tassal is ramping up work to restock its lease at Port Arthur, 11 years after it was last used.
The 15-hectare site in Long Bay is being prepared for at least seven salmon pens, expanding to 14 in the future.
The return of fish farming to the area has angered recreational fishers.
Tasmanian Association of Recreational Fishing chief executive Mark Nikolai said it would reduce access to popular fishing spots.
"Recreational boats won't be allowed to go in there and there is also a lot of recreational diving that happens along the shoreline," he said.
"It's an extremely popular recreational family fishing area."
Mr Nikolai said his organisation had put forward its concerns to Tassal and the State Government.
"Any lease that hasn't been used for the last five years, we've requested the Government and industry to rescind those leases because the rules around which they were approved over a decade ago have significantly changed since then," he said.
"With [Primary Industries Minister Jeremy Rockliff's] stated position of trying to get marine farming out to oceanic waters this particular lease falls outside that."
Tassal consulted 'extensively' with community

Greens leader Cassy O'Connor said Tassal and the State Government needed to be more upfront about the plans and cited the close proximity to the World-Heritage listed Port Arthur Historic site.
"This is a very significant tourist attraction to Tasmania," she said.
"They know at the moment there's a heightened level of community concern about industrial fish farming and rapid fish farm expansion.
"If they want to have anything resembling a social licence then they need to have a conversation with the Tasmanian people."
Tassal said it had consulted extensively with the community and politicians about its plans for Port Arthur.
"In the Tasman region there were two advertised public meetings and numerous one-on-one stakeholder meetings and farm tours," a spokesman said.
The company said its operations at Long Bay would be used as a feeder site for its proposed fish farm west of Wedge Island at Storm Bay, which still requires approval from the Marine Farming Review Panel.
'No further approvals were required'

A spokesman for the Department of Primary Industries said a licence for finfish farming had been in place at Long Bay for the past 25 years.
"A licence to farm finfish is in effect and no further approvals are required however there are management controls, lease and licence conditions that must be complied with," he said.
Premier Will Hodgman said Tasmanians could be confident about the regulatory measures in place.
"We've increased environmental protections, we've increased penalties for breaches, we've put in place independent assessment and I hope that can give Tasmanians confidence we are putting the industry on a sustainable pathway," he said.
Long Bay is the second site Tassal has planned to stock this month, after it .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Nikolai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storm Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nikolai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wedge Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassy O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Arthur Historic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Association of Recreational</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Farming Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Arthur</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Heritage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary Industries Minister Jeremy Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
