<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419576928007376</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/vera-blue-and-the-post-breakup-album/news-story/e87cb1fc0dbd582204d441eed5f819d7</url>
  <title>Vera Blue and the post break-up album</title>
  <content>
The break-up album has changed.
The anger of Alanis Morrissette's Jagged Little Pill and melancholy of Adele's 21 have made way for self-empowerment.
Lorde's second album Melodrama, released this year, was one of the most prominent in this new post break-up genre.
In lead single Green Light she wasn't mopping up tears with her pillow as much as revelling in hearing "brand new sounds".
Australian artist Vera Blue has confidently stepped into the fold with the release of her debut album Perennial. It shot straight into the top ARIA 10.
"The record was written from the ashes of a relationship that had come to an end, so throughout the whole album it kind of goes through this ... journey where I developed a sense of who I was," Vera Blue told AAP.
The singer-songwriter who has combined her folk background as Voice contestant Celia Pavey with a youthful EDM style, emerged as Vera Blue a few years ago and found success with her collaboration with Illy on the hit Papercuts.
Her album, she says, is vulnerable but doesn't wallow in heartache. Halfway through, she appears to be emerging not just from a relationship but her adolescence, singing about her sexuality and desires in the spiky track Private.
"My record is more of a repairing album so it starts coming out of a relationship and that first week that awful feeling after a break-up," she said.
"Then I guess it goes through this way of self-development and learning who you are and learning that you are strong and ... have the ability to be able to overcome something."
Last month, the crowds at Splendour in the Grass festival hung on her every word and a track that hits you with the insistency of Destiny's Child's Lady Powers emerged as a clear favourite.
"The song is about not having to change for someone, not having to use your sexuality to be respected as a woman ... it's just a sense of having that respect and knowing who you are," she said.
This album comes from a woman who, at 23, has experienced relationships that "leave a mark" but she's not broken by them.
"It's something a lot of female artists are connecting to these days," she said.
"The fact that we've come out of something and now that we're in our early adult years, where we're kind of experiencing heavy love for the first time, real love, real feelings."
*Perennial is out now and Vera Blue is touring until September 10
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alanis Morrissette's Jagged Little Pill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele's 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIA 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papercuts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vera Blue</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celia Pavey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EDM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Light</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Destiny's Child's Lady Powers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
