<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419229035649174</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/fire-breaks-out-on-the-outside-of-the-famous-tsukiji-fish-market-in-japan/news-story/2beee04ca5382482ba65c2e08e3c5c71</url>
  <title>Fire breaks out on the outside of the famous Tsukiji fish market in Japan</title>
  <content>
The fire on the outside of Japan's famous Tsukiji fish market, where lots of tourists come all year round. Picture: Supplied

Staff writersNews Corp Australia Network

Share

A MASSIVE fire has broken out outside Japan's famous Tsukiji fish market, which attracts thousands of tourists daily.
Store owners and tourists have been forced to evacuate as the incident continues.
The Tokyo Fire Department reported that the building was burning at "Tsukiji fish market" in Tokyo from 3pm Thursday local time, NHK reports.
According to the Tokyo Fire Department and other media outlets, the fire started in a three-storey building. But local reports suggest there are three buildings now on fire since the main blaze broke out, making it a total of four fires.

The fire near the famous Tsukiji fish market in Tokyo. Picture: SuppliedSource:Supplied
A total of 25 fire trucks are on the scene near the Tsukiji fish market where many tourists visit all year round.
No reports of injuries or fatalities have emerged yet as plumes of smoke continue to emerge from the area.
Pictures from the scene have emerged on social media.
30+ fire engines on the scene as fire breaks out in Tsukiji's outer market.
Fire in

上空には報道のヘリが5〜6機.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppliedSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NHK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>writersNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tsukiji</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo Fire Department</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
