<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418889733226341</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/pms-emergency-gay-marriage-meeting/3208546/</url>
  <title>PM's emergency gay marriage meeting</title>
  <content>
LIBERAL MPs have been summoned to a special party room meeting next Monday to bring the same-sex marriage debate to a head.

Government MPs were told this afternoon that the Liberals would meet in Canberra at 4pm, the day before Parliament returns after the winter break.

Significantly, it is set to be a Liberal-only meeting, after former prime minister Tony Abbott infuriated his colleagues in 2015 by bringing their National Party counterparts into the room when same-sex marriage was debated and the plebiscite policy was finalised.

Mr Turnbull said earlier today that any issue could be discussed by the Liberal party room.

"But, of course, ultimately Coalition policy is determined in the Coalition party room," he said.

Queensland MP Warren Entsch, a key marriage equality advocate in the government, argued Liberal MPs were "ambushed" when the Nationals were brought into the 2015 meeting.

"Instead of being ambushed and deceived, I trust this prime minister to do the right thing and give us an opportunity to have a fair hearing on this," Mr Entsch said earlier today.

Mr Entsch said the Nationals would be free to disagree with whatever the Liberals decided.

The decision to call a special party room meeting comes amid speculation that a secret ballot of MPs could be held to determine their preferred way forward on same-sex marriage.

The options would include keeping the plebiscite, moving to a postal plebiscite, and holding a free vote on the floor of Parliament.

Jetstar drops massive cut-price Sunshine Coast holiday deal.
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland MP Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal-only</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
