<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418842488585153</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/alps-brendan-oconnor-sparks-alarm-among-business-over-union-bargaining-power-20170803-gxodma</url>
  <title>ALP's Brendan O'Connor sparks alarm among business over union bargaining power</title>
  <content>
Business groups are disputing , warning a fresh wave of pro-union industrial relations reform threatens investment and job creation.
Business is on edge after a speech by opposition employment spokesman Brendan O'Connor promising to re-empower trade unions under a Shorten Labor government to recruit new members and demand wage rises.
Australian Industry Group chief executive Innes Willox said it was "quite frankly preposterous" that unions were pressuring Labor to because they griped it was unfair.
"This sort of message being sent rings alarm bells to individual businesses large and small about the threat of further regulation at a time when businesses are already gearing up to face a higher dollar and seeing significantly increased energy costs," he told The Australian Financial Review.

"If we go further down the track of opening the door to allowing a manifestly untrue union campaign to succeed, it will make it almost impossible to attract investment."

Mr Willox called on unions to recognise the IR system was a two-way street and fairness cut both ways for workers and employers.
"Some employers find it hard to make agreements. We've probably got the balance right," he said.
Council of Small Business Australia chief executive Peter Strong said he was "deeply concerned" that Labor would increase unions' clout, saying they already were often caught flouting the law.
Unions poorly trusted

Mr Strong said a recent OECD report showed Australians had little trust in unions, ranked fifth last out of a survey of 35 countries.
"[That's] just ahead of the US where the unions are seen as branches of the Mafia. So why would we give more power to a group that is so poorly trusted," he said.
"If unions are to be believed it seems that the worst thing that could happen to a person is that they get a job. Then their lives would be in ruins, their world would fall apart and unemployment is a much better outcome."
Australian Chamber of Commerce and Industry chief executive James Pearson said Australians lived in one of the most egalitarian nations in the world.

"We won't increase our productivity and prosperity by winding back the industrial relations clock to the last century," he said.
"We do need improvements to our workplace relations system - because we need one that recognises how workplaces operate in the modern world and makes it easier for employers and employees to agree on terms and conditions that work for both and will help businesses to grow."
Employment Minister Michaelia Cash said Labor agenda would mean fewer jobs, lower wages and more industrial disputes.
"Bill Shorten's only plan is to slug Australians with higher taxes and hand over Australian control of Australian workplaces to law-breaking unions," she said.

Mr O'Connor  on Wednesday night, telling the Sydney Institute declining rates of collective bargaining and union membership were contributing to low wage grow and job insecurity.
While he did not go into specific policy details, he promised unions would be reinvigorated under a future Labor government, arguing businesses had too much power in wage negotiations.
"That's why we need to reverse the disastrous tilt in bargaining power and rising inequality," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Strong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Michaelia Cash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council of Small</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Willox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALP's Brendan O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Strong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Industry Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innes Willox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
