<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419830331083580</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4830505/hunter-united-win-metro-league-minor-premiership/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Hunter United win Metro League minor premiership</title>
  <content>
Hunter United win Metro League minor premiership

Traci Baber addresses the Hunter United players on Thursday night during the game against Eastwood-Ryde.

Hunter United before Thursday's game against Eastwood-Ryde.

Hunter United before Thursday's game against Eastwood-Ryde.

exit

Hunter United could have cause for double celebration after wrapping up the Netball NSW Metro League division-one minor premiership in Sydney on Thursday night.

Hunter beat second-placed Eastwood-Ryde 55-40 to lock up the minor title with three rounds to play. 

Hunter (27) are seven points in front of Illawarra (20), who jumped Eastwood-Ryde (18) into second after beating last-placed Manly 48-46.

The Hunter players and coach Traci Baber were so focused on the task at hand that they did not know they had won the minor premiership until they were driving home.
"It's a great achievement," Baber said. "We didn't even look at anybody else.
"We had to come from behind tonight, which we haven't had to do in too many games.

"With five minutes to go until half-time we were five down, and in that five minutes we did a nine-goal turnaround. Won the third quarter by eight. They played outstanding."
It has been a meteoric rise for Hunter, who entered Metro League division two last year, finished second to Illawarra then beat them in the final. Both sides won promotion and look destined to finish first and second again.

But Hunter are eyeing the bigger prize of a place in the top-tier Premier League next season.

Netball NSW is understood to have arranged a meeting with Hunter representatives next week to discuss their promotion bid.  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter (27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netball NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro League</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastwood-Ryde (18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastwood-Ryde</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra (20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netball NSW Metro League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Traci Baber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter United</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
