<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419791676377009</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/transport/accc-secures-second-biggest-fine-ever-against-shipping-cartel-20170803-gxoujv</url>
  <title>ACCC secures second biggest fine ever against shipping cartel</title>
  <content>
The consumer watchdog has claimed one of the biggest scalps in its history, with the Federal Court ordering Japanese shipping company Nippon Yusen Kabushiki Kaisha to pay a $25 million fine after convicting it of criminal cartel conduct. 
The fine is the second highest imposed in the history of the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission, and also marks the first successful prosecution under the criminal cartel provisions introduced.
that operated from at least February 1997, when it and other shipping lines formed understandings over the shipping of cars made by the likes of Nissan, Suzuki, Honda, Toyota and Mazda.
The Japanese group got a 50 per cent discount on its fine for its "early plea of guilty and past and future assistance and cooperation," the court said. 

ACCC chairman Rod Sims said the conviction and fine sent a message to the business community. 

"The Australian community relies heavily on imported vehicles, so a longstanding cartel in relation to the transportation of those vehicles to Australia was of significant concern," he said. 
"The sentence imposed on NYK by the Federal Court today sends a strong warning to the industry and the business community at large. The CDPP and ACCC can and will criminally prosecute cartel conduct. 
"It also highlights that parties who engage early and cooperate with the authorities may be shown leniency."
NYK pleaded guilty in July 2016 and co-operated throughout the ACCC's investigation. 

The watchdog said its probe into other alleged cartel participants is continuing. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzuki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 1997</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nissan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Sims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CDPP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nippon Yusen Kabushiki Kaisha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
