<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419748726702796</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/joe-daniher-taking-game-to-new-level-inspired-by-helping-essendon-win-premiership/news-story/999bfc5ebd19e4ef7aeb8d11e751832e</url>
  <title>Daniher ready to write next chapter</title>
  <content>
HE is the Coleman Medal leader locked in an aerial battle with Jeremy Howe for Mark of the Year honours.
But Joe Daniher says despite a "licence" to fly for those spectacular trademark "speccies" they aren't what inspires him to improve.
Instead it is the quest for Essendon's elusive premiership, well aware the Dons have not even won a final since 2004.
ROUND 20:
PRESSURE:

END NEAR:
You know that movie Brendon Goddard spoke about - where Essendon throws off the shackles of its ASADA crisis to win a rags-to-riches flag?
Daniher, who has kicked a remarkable 40.15 of his 53.31 tally since Round 6, wants to be there when Essendon writes the final chapter.
"Absolutely, (a premiership) is the reason we play. Brendon wants to make this movie. He is still keen on it, he said he's going to played by George Clooney so we better wrap it up quick smart,'' he laughed.

"There are a few chapters still to go. It would be disappointing to finish the career without (a flag), I know lots of players do.
"But that is the reason you get up every morning, to try to achieve something special and to achieve it with people you work hard with.
"We have gone through a tough period and guys have worked really hard to come out the other end of it so it would be pretty sweet to finish up with what we have all been working towards."
Daniher's only taste of finals ended with four goals in the 2014 elimination finals loss, his Anzac Day Medal this year more evidence he is a big game performer.
As well as improving his accuracy after 43 goals from 92 shots last year, his high flying marks have lit up Etihad Stadium.
He says it is part of his determination to enjoy his career rather than stress the small stuff.
"The older you get the more confident about the things you try to implement. I am just enjoying having a licence to do it and I have got some help and protection around me,'' he says of those highlights reel grabs.
"It is the old rule, if you go for one and stuff it up you put it away for a week or two. I am enjoying having a crack at it."
Against Carlton this week he is likely to get in-form defender Liam Jones, aware the wet weather will again make it a down-and-dirty contest.
At 9-9 Essendon have to win out to guarantee finals, with Carlton outsmarting and outgrunting the Bombers in the wet earlier this year.
It is the kind of contest perfect for big-bodied Jobe Watson, who continues to wear criticism for his inconsistent form.
Daniher says he would love to play finals for players like Watson - banned last year - but says that criticism belies his strong impact.
"He is incredible. He has got an incredible footy brain and great knowledge and thinks outside the square with a lot of things," he said.
"For the young guys he's an incredible leader but also as a person and footy brain. His stats old up, you know when he's around the ball he's going to win more contests than he loses.
"But that's not really what he's in the side for - to get the ball - he is there to be a strong communicator around the ball and through the week.
"He makes sure guys like Zach Merrett and Darcy Parish do their job, he's been huge for us."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Day Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASADA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniher</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Parish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GEORGE CLOONEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Howe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Goddard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
