<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418717934530980</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/the-sterile-politics-of-anger-20170802-gxo7oy.html</url>
  <title>Waleed Aly: Why Trump's Republicans can't kill off Obamacare</title>
  <content>
This seems to be a moment where the most heated political battles are among those who are meant to be on the same side. Australian voters will be familiar with this, having observed the slow implosion of the Coalition over the past two years - only underlined by this week's parrying on same-sex marriage. And more on that in a moment. But arguably the most telling illustration has come from America where, amid the continuing Trump-led circus, Republicans in congress have once more failed to kill off Obamacare.
This really is extraordinary. Republicans control every elected branch of government. They hold the White House, the House and the Senate. Accordingly, the country is theirs to run without the slightest hint of input from the Democrats, who are presently entirely irrelevant. And yet here we are, watching as the Republicans cannot deliver on what has been their most central reason for being for the past seven years. Imagine if Tony Abbott had booted Labor from power in a landslide that gave him majorities in both houses of Parliament, and yet couldn't manage to repeal carbon tax. We're looking at something that dysfunctional.Photo: Bloomberg
And yet, we're looking at something entirely understandable. The Republicans' problem is that, well, their approaches to healthcare largely stink. That can be masked in opposition, but when forced to implement something in government, the stench becomes overwhelming. Every attempt to replace Obamacare has come with a hideous number attached that forecasts just how many people will wind up losing their health cover under Republican proposals. First 23 million, then 32 million, then 16 million. You could bring that figure down, but only by keeping more elements of the thing you're trying to replace, at which point hardline Republicans would decry the policy for not going far enough. And when the principal benefit of this exercise seems to be the repeal of certain taxes for the wealthy, that's an awful message to defend publicly. Some congressional Republicans inevitably got cold feet. To date there has proven to be no magical balance that can satisfy both moderate and Tea Party-infused Republicans.
It's a study in the limits of oppositional politics. The cliche runs that you campaign in poetry and govern in prose. But how do you govern when you've campaigned in bumper stickers? It turns out you become largely mute. The Republicans' story is not one of lofty, utopian ambitions sullied by the inevitable compromises of politics. It is a story of no great ambition at all; of a bloody-minded plan for destruction that runs aground whenever the moment calls for construction. That's why after six months of unfettered political dominance, the Republicans have nothing of consequence to show for it. The politics of insurrection ran its course as soon as it achieved victory. The Republicans have proven little other than the sterility of their anger.
And that, more or less, has also been the story of Australia's Coalition since 2013. It is true the Abbott government at least succeeded to deliver its key promise of repealing Julia Gillard's carbon tax. But that was an entirely destructive enterprise, and for that reason a much simpler one than the Republicans' task of enacting a new healthcare system to replace the one that would be vanquished. And so, with the carbon tax gone, the Abbott insurrection took less than a year to fall apart, disintegrating at precisely the moment construction is demanded: budget night. Abbott's prime ministership was doomed immediately at that point, buried beneath the debris of broken promises and unexpected, desperately unpopular policies that seemed to take more from the struggling than the wealthy. It is a course Malcolm Turnbull has tried to correct on several occasions, most notably in his recent attempts to find a way through on education funding and climate change. But such is the state of the Coalition that this correction is simply not permitted. Abbott's insurrection has been renewed and flashpoints frequently assert themselves. This week we're back to an old favourite: same-sex marriage.
Turnbull is trying to move on from all this, and has some justification in complaining that the media is uninterested in his other initiatives, particularly on job creation. But this overlooks a crucial aspect of the problem: namely that the media's focus mirrors an obsession within his party. Put simply, it's easy for media to focus on the same-sex marriage divisions precisely because so many Liberals refuse to shut up about it - even as they argue Australians don't care deeply about this issue. And that's because the Liberal right-wing that so bedevils Turnbull is still behaving as an opposition, drawing its existential energy from its campaigns on climate change and marriage equality. And note again what unites these fixations: the sterile politics of stopping things. That sterility is now Turnbull's problem because in its presence, no other government agenda can grow.
The lesson from these trans-Pacific experiences is surely that there is a chasm between government and governing. For years now we've witnessed the irresistible success of angry politics; the electoral power of negativity. But we're also seeing just how limited that success can be. It delivers government, but it cannot help you govern. In this way the momentum of opposition seems to dissipate so quickly in government, but only because it was a mirage in the first place. That's one reason we're seeing such rapid political cycles now, with governments staring down one-term lifespans in a way that was once unthinkable. All that might one day change. But only once political machines recognise that what matters even more than victory are the terms on which it is claimed.
Waleed Aly is a Fairfax Media columnist and a presenter on The Project.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Coalition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's Republican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waleed Aly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obamacare</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tea Party-infused Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
