<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419787381409681</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/energy/gas/apa-ceo-takes-aim-at-energy-policy-based-on-fiction-and-folklore-20170802-gxo85f</url>
  <title>APA CEO takes aim at energy policy based on 'fiction and folklore'</title>
  <content>
APA Group chief executive Mick McCormack and Santos boss Kevin Gallagher have pumped up the volume of complaint from industry about policymakers' responsibility for escalating energy prices but have sharply disagreed on whether pipeline tariffs are partly to blame.
Mr McCormack, the head of the country's biggest gas pipeline owner, used an address in Sydney to take a swipe at federal and state politicians. He accused them of developing energy regulation "on the basis of fiction and folklore",
Both he and Mr Gallagher, who was speaking at the same event, pointed the finger at state and territory governments' gas restrictions for driving up prices unnecessarily.
But they differed markedly on the degree to which pipeline tariffs are also part of the problem.

Mr Gallagher said private pipelines were preventing the efficient delivery of gas to the market and backed a recommendation by the competition watchdog to examine "market power" as a criterion for regulating pipelines.

contributing to sky-high east coast gas prices but Mr McCormack disagreed, saying the industry had just been an easy target for a government unable to tackle the root of the problem.
"The focus on pipelines has been at best, misguided, and at worst, deliberately diversionary," Mr McCormack said, insisting there has been no real increase in tariffs since 2002 even though gas prices have trebled.
APA disputed Mr Gallagher's statement that transportation costs make up almost a quarter of the wholesale cost of gas delivered from central Australia to Sydney.
The two join Glencore's most senior executive in Australia,  inplacing the liability for surging prices on the absence of a cohesive energy and climate policy that cuts across state boundaries.

Mr McCormack demanded an end to "knee-jerk policy responses, fuelled by political self-interest", saying politicians owed it to electors to base decisions instead on facts and evidence.
"What I do take issue with is poor policy development based on conjecture and misinformation, and hastily put together to ensure the appearance of government action," Mr McCormack said, reiterating  that have a view on energy policy that are assumed to be experts.
Mr Gallagher directed much of his criticism at Canberra's new policy on LNG export controls, which stand to hurt Santos' GLNG project in Queensland.
He described the policy, enshrined in the Australian Domestic Gas Security Mechanism, as "reactive politics" and reiterated his argument that the focus of any export restrictions should be placed on LNG sold into the low-priced Asian spot market.

That would affect Origin Energy's APLNG and Shell's QCLNG projects in Queensland rather than GLNG, which has restricted production to match long-term contracts.
But Mr Gallagher and Mr McCormack noted a loosening in the tight east coast gas market in recent weeks,
They are critical of on-the-run policymaking in Canberra, with Mr Gallagher arguing that ADGSM has been rushed into place and that its serious consequences have been overlooked. The heightened sovereign risk it has created has worried LNG customers in Asia, he said.
Mr McCormack meanwhile noted that new rules on gas pipeline tariff arbitration had come into effect a minute after midnight on Tuesday this week, while APA got to see them in their final form only in the evening, forcing it to halt commercial negotiations in case it was in breach.

, but Mr McCormack described them as "heavy handed and rigid".
The new arbitration framework has also been criticised by gas producers such as

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McCormack</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADGSM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin Energy's APLNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shell's QCLNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santos' GLNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APA CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GLNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick McCormack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Domestic Gas Security Mechanism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APA Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Gallagher</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
