<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419748726702865</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/eu-seeks-new-relationships-in-pacific-wto-boss-pascal-lamy-20170803-gxojae</url>
  <title>EU seeks new relationships in Pacific</title>
  <content>
Australia, New Zealand and the European Union have an interest in assisting Pacific nations standardise their export products as part of capacity building in the region, according to the former World Trade Organisation head, Pascal Lamy.
Mr Lamy has been travelling through the region on behalf of the European Union, gauging views on how the EU's relationships with the 14 Pacific nations should evolve in the future when the current Cotonou Agreement - which outlines its development and assistance commitments with the African Caribbean and Pacific - expires in 2020.
The EU has signalled it plans to split up its dealings with the three disparate regions into separate agreements as the next stage of development of relationships which started with European nations dealing with their former colonies, to moving to donor relationships.
Mr Lamy says these new separated partnerships will be focused on political, security, environmental and trade ties.

The reworking of these relationships come as Europe itself is making a transition from being primarily a trade and economic based union to one that is contemplating greater defence and security relationships.

Its strategic interest in the Pacific, Mr Lamy says is particularly focused on oceans and fisheries, based in the EU's interest in global issues surrounding the oceans and climate resilience.
He listed security as the number one issue in the Pacific from the EU's perspective but said there was an "obvious link between security and economics" given the specific weaknesses in the region of poor countries often constrained by weak governance and threatened by the physical and migration impacts of climate change.
These weaknesses "will have major security consequences if they are not addressed" he said with a number of powers, including China becoming much more assertive in the region.
Capacity building is a key focus for the EU he said, and particularly noted the importance of achieving standardisation in product markets, -whether that be in the sanitary standards of exported coconut milk to the way new medicines were marketed and air transport standards.

The lack of economies of scale on such questions faced by many of these small countries was an issue that had to be dealt with - and one in which the EU has a particularly expertise.
Mr Lamy said there was a commonality of interest with Australia and New Zealand in helping address these problems so that these small nations could export to Australia, New Zealand, the EU and the United States.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lamy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotonou Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pascal Lamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African Caribbean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Trade Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
