<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419658532387664</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/the-age-letters/naplan-tests-blame-the-use-of-ipads-in-the-lower-grades-20170802-gxo8j2.html</url>
  <title>NAPLAN tests: Blame the use of iPads in the lower grades</title>
  <content>
​Results of the year 3 and 5 NAPLAN tests show that Victorian students have done well in all but writing. I am not surprised. As a teacher with more than 40years' experience, both in secondary and primary schools (and now one-year retired), I saw the impact of iPads in prep to year 3. The process of learning was slowed down as children coped with the technique of the device instead of the task at hand.
Oh, yes, they love programs such as Mathletics, but their hands get tired while their teacher can sit back and let the computer do the corrections. The iPad in junior classes spelt the end of creativity: the writing was on the wall. When I received those first year 2 classes into my French class, I could not believe the difference in what those students were capable of - the standards just kept falling over the ensuing years. Blame the use of devices in the lower primary years for our year 3 and 5 children being below par in their writing tests.
Sally Holt, Balwyn
Why these tests are meaningless

Students' NAPLAN results may have gone backwards but it should be remembered that these tests are meaningless. First, they are set by people who did not teach the material which is being tested. Second, students in some schools might sit the tests before they have been taught the content in them (eg, fractions), while other students have already covered this topic earlier in the year. The data we should be paying attention to is that provided by classroom teachers, not external bodies such as the Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority.
Geoff Phillips, Wonga Park
So much to learn from the Scandinavians

NAPLAN is a seriously inaccurate reporting device. Education ministers and bureaucrats should be frog marched over to the Scandinavian countries to see how to run an education system.

Rod Oaten, North Carlton
A very limited feedback on learning

Oh, goody. It's NAPLAN time again, when politicians get to wrap themselves in their favourite blanket - meaningless statistics that they can spin into Rumpelstiltskin's gold. Please see through the smoke and mirrors. What they are measuring is very limited feedback on learning. It is not helpful for the majority of learners.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

To put it in true Melbourne terms, they are getting kids to drop kick a footy through a tiny hole in the schoolyard wall. Those who have practised a lot do well, those who are good at swimming and singing may not. Some teachers spend valuable school time doing nothing but practising that one kick for weeks. Either way, they are using the results of the drop kick to say how well everyone is at playing footy. Meanwhile, in the 21st century, no one uses the drop kick anyway. We need a variety of skills - and may choose not to play that game at all.
Peter Healy, Ivanhoe
We don't need another curriculum review

On Wednesday night's television news, it was suggested that a curriculum review was needed to improve students' educational outcomes. As a person who started teaching in the 1960s with "draft curriculum review", documents in hand, I think that other solutions may be needed.
Steve Smith, Lalor
Give our teachers the time to actually teach

Maybe our children's literacy and numeracy skills would improve if teachers were allowed to focus on the learning and teaching, rather than "the test".
Jan Saliba, Keilor
THE FORUM

Protecting the children

Bravo, Rachel Griffiths (The Age, 3/8). At last, an Australian celebrity who recognises the exploitation of vulnerable overseas children through orphanage tourism and who does not advocate inter-country adoption as the solution. She is "optimistic Australians' attitudes to overseas orphanages will change over time". I believe it would happen much faster if she referred directly to the shonky practices associated with many of the unregistered and unregulated orphanages in south-east Asia. "Selfie moment" sounds benign and innocuous, whereas "child laundering", "child trafficking" and "child adoption slavery" are more accurate and compelling from the children's perspective.
Penny Mackieson, Richmond
All assaults are wrong

Noel Ancell (Letters, 3/8), I do not agree that a comparison of the statistics of sexual harassment and assault in universities to that "for the same age group in the general population" is useful or necessary. Any sexual harassment or assault is unacceptable. Even if we ascertained that the number of incidents on campus was relatively low, it would not detract from the problem or absolve us from addressing it.
Avery Poole, Richmond
A very bleak future

The HILDA survey, as discussed by Peter Martin (Comment, 3/8), provided a sombre overview of how many of the middle-class are struggling to make ends meet. If things are getting worse, and this trend continues, what a bleak outlook lies ahead. One can only hope that ordinary incomes start to rise - or even better, that house prices level out to some kind of sane point to assist us keep our livelihoods in check.
Stephanie Ashworth, Pascoe Vale South
Joy of country living

Can I send a gentle message to our millennials who despair of owning a house? Try thinking outside the square. You could buy a house for $200,000 in my village and get a job, within a 30-minutes drive, in large, vibrant regional centres with lower than average unemployment. You could also enjoy a country/community lifestyle (not suffer road rage and kids can cycle to school) and still have your avocado on toast. You do not have to pay a million dollars and live in Melbourne or Sydney.
Mick Webster, Chiltern
Another trust 'bonus'

Further to revelations about trusts, it also needs to be pointed out that by reducing an individual's income this way, the main income earner may become eligible for the Health Care Card and associated benefits. The winner takes all - but not great for morale for the rest of us.
Peter Berenyi, Howes Creek
A lesson in giving

In reference to Australian Story (ABC TV, 31/7). Here is the difference between me and Sam Dastyari: I work in admin and earn a fifth of what he does. Last weekend I bought my workplace a $12 rubbish bin so that my colleagues and I can contribute to recycling. I did not think to ask my boss (or a wealthy Chinese businessman) for the money. It was an act of goodwill on my behalf.
Alison Ritlewski, Mount Waverley
Secret ballot for MPs

The debacle about same-sex marriage is contrary to the letter and spirit of the constitution and an abuse of the system by people with questionable motives. Federation specifically gave the central government control of defence, taxation, foreign affairs and postal and communication services, with which same sex-marriage has no connection. Those pushing the no vote are driven from religious or extra-moral beliefs, neither of which have any relevance to our sectarian government as defined by the constitution. The simplest way to resolve the matter is a secret ballot of the people's elected representatives. Invoke the true intention of the constitution and demand the vote.
Campbell Laughlin, Rowville
Right to a plebiscite

Why are supporters of same-sex marriage afraid of a plebiscite? I am intrigued by the claims of those who support same-sex marriage. My husband and I have never been asked, and nor has anyone I know. We live in the electorate of Goldstein and I can assure you that Tim Wilson does not represent our opinion. We support a plebiscite.
Margery Renwick, Brighton
Why voters are cynical

How about an optional, non-binding postal vote about whether to have a plebiscite on marriage equality? The breathtaking political cynicism of this refusal to take parliamentary responsibility for the issue of marriage equality will only confirm the widespread community contempt for the politicians we are struck with.
John Rickard, Windsor
A plea for action

"Did you know that Australia has a new prime minister called Michael Handball?" asked my daughter's 10-year-old friend in September 2015. "My mums are very pleased and hope he will move Australia forward". "Handball" seems an apt Dickensian surname, given the government's inaction - on marriage equality for that kid's mums, protecting our climate, resettling refugees, development aid and trains to move Melbourne's growing population.
Catherine McNaughton, Glen Huntly
Phasing out brown coal

The Great Barrier Reef is almost half dead (The Age, 3/8). The world needs to see it as an early indicator of changes to come. Think of the rivers, forests, farms and fisheries which are stressed by global warming and facing a similar fate. But global action might be more decisive if Australia showed more interest in preserving the reef.
With our federal government paralysed by the inconvenience of climate change, greater responsibility falls on the states. And Victoria burns brown coal - the dirtiest, most carbon-polluting fuel in the industrialised world - in furnaces that are killing the things we love. Soon we will be losing the things we need. Every day that our state government delays a rapid phase out of brown coal, Victoria sends a message that action on climate change can wait.
Tim Read, Brunswick East
Fines out of control

Transurban's system of imposing penalties way in excess of the damages incurred (loss of revenue due to an unpaid toll) is obscene profiteering (The Age, 3/8). A fine to cover these damages, and perhaps a modest loading to cover interest and administrative costs, is appropriate.
There is no justification for loading it with additional costs that double or even triple its value. I question the legality of this. Worse, this system is so harsh that it is forcing honest, hard-working people who committed a minor civil offence into financial hardship and treating them like criminals.It is also clogging the courts with what is, effectively, debt collection for private companies.
Emma Borghesi, Mount Eliza
Promises, promises

I travel regularly on the V/Line train between Albury/Wodonga and Melbourne. This line has been sadly neglected for the past decade. The original plan devised by the Whitlam government to develop thriving twin cities in Albury/Wodonga has been realised, in that the region is vibrant and growing.
What it desperately needed is a fast, reliable train service. Unfortunately, when elections are due, political visits are made, with predictable empathy and promises for improvements. Other regional towns have fast, regular Sprinter trains. Why not the north-east?
Mary Linnestad, Corryong
Walkers' right to safety

Road rage is definitely increasing across Melbourne (The Age, 3/8) but little acknowledgement is made of "footpath rage". Many cyclists illegally ride on footpaths and frequently abuse the foolish, selfish pedestrians who are in their way. Pity help the aged or infirm if the law is changed to allow all cyclists to ride on footpaths.
Ian Foote, Hawthorn
Endless nanny state

This smoking ban (The Age, 3/8) is ridiculous and takes the nanny state to another level. Does the Victorian government think that the electorate has no common sense whatsoever? The ban also makes dim "viewing" for visitors to the city on a night out. They may as well be given a rule book in cafes, rather than a menu.
Charlie Wood, Richmond
Beware the dark side

Chris Fotinopoulos writes about the increased incidence of teenage anxiety ("Clicks and likes contributing to a teen anxiety crisis", The Age, 1/8). Many young people, like me, understand what Fotinopoulos means by having a surge of dopamine upon receiving "likes" by friends on Facebook or Instagram. 
Social media is a platform for all to "socialise" and network, but its users are prone to being bullied or harassed by unknown or anonymous "keyboard warriors". In an age where physical, "human to human" interaction has been jeopardised by the smartphone, all we can do is be aware that with a great innovation such as social media, there is a darker side to it.
Abdullah Sheriffdeen, Newport
AND ANOTHER THING

Trump

America, I know how you feel. When Abbott was PM, I cringed every time he opened his mouth or did something silly.
Beng Lee, Blackburn
Forget Shakespeare's Comedy of Errors. Trump in the White House tops the lot.
Ros Levy, Elsternwick
Scaramucci's light fandango has left the White House a whiter shade of pale.
Lawrie Bradly, Surrey Hills
I predicted Trump's reign would be all bread and circuses. Well, we've got the circus ...
Harriet Farnaby, Geelong West
Scaramucci's farewell: "I told the (redacted) of a president that he can (redacted) his (redacted)".
Tony Lenten, Glen Waverley
Politics

Would it be fair to describe the Turnbull/Abbott NBN as a "fake" NBN?
Terry Tovey, Warrandyte
When things go wrong in the Coalition: Plan A, blame the media. Plan B, see Plan A.
Andrew McFarland, Templestowe
The Minister for Blame? Is it Barnaby Joyce? There must be one.
Leslie Hunter, Geelong
Turnbull wants his job more than he wants same-sex marriage.
Barbara Joy, South Yarra
All I want is a vote, says Warren Entsch, but he wants to deprive the rest of us of one.
Albert Riley, Mornington
Furthermore

Perhaps the Oakleigh smokers (3/8) could light up 'baklava cigars'.
John Bastiras, Elsternwick
Has the increase in childcare costs (2/8) gone to boost childcare workers' pitifully low pay?
Margaret Callinan, Balwyn
So the Queen has four alcoholic drinks a day. She'll have to cut down if she hopes to live to a ripe old age.
Tony O'Brien, South Melbourne
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Holt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull/Abbott NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beng Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balwyn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albury/Wodonga</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corryong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison Ritlewski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Rickard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Berenyi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howes Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANOTHER THING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Eliza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Barrier Reef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Ashworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Webster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Age, 1/8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathletics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Story</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McFarland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surrey Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margery Renwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Huntly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Letters, 3/8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Age, 3/8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdullah Sheriffdeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Handball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fotinopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scandinavian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Mackieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rumpelstiltskin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Borghesi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chiltern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keilor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Laughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elsternwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanhoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitlam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jan Saliba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Callinan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avery Poole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harriet Farnaby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reporting Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawrie Bradly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pascoe Vale South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastyari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wonga Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbara Joy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Fotinopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Healy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bravo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Bastiras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrandyte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Templestowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Linnestad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Tovey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Care Card</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ros Levy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Curriculum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Foote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickensian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Oaten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Waverley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V-line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lalor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plan A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Lenten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine McNaughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Ancell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Waverley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare's Comedy of Errors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
