<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419624172648609</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-03/no-standalone-vfl-team-for-sandringham-in-2018</url>
  <title>No standalone VFL team for Sandringham in 2018</title>
  <content>
Ben Long celebrates a goal for Sandy

ST KILDA'S VFL affiliate will not field a standalone team next year, with AFL Victoria standing firm on its decision to consider only Frankston's potential re-entry into the competition.

North Melbourne had already announced in April its decision to part ways with Werribee after this season, with both to have VFL sides in 2018.

There were rumblings at Sandringham - the Saints' partner - when AFL Victoria announced last month that the VFL's reserves competition would not continue beyond this season for financial and resource reasons.

The Zebras first aligned with the Saints for the 2009 season, after a previous partnership with Melbourne, and the club's chief executive John Mennie maintains the relationship is still strong.

The issue for non-AFL-listed footballers at aligned VFL clubs is that playing opportunities will be scarce, with a maximum of 23 spots each week. The leftover players will need to go back to grassroots level to make their case for promotion.

"The fact is there are no licenses available, and we accept that. We have no problem with St Kilda whatsoever," Mennie told AFL.com.au.

"It's just unfortunate the Development League was abolished, because it leaves clubs in an alignment in a precarious position with list size and managing that.

"We will meet with St Kilda soon to work out the best way to move forward in a positive way."

Mennie said any potential decision to be a standalone VFL club in 2019 would be made "down the track". But there is a player-driven push within Sandringham to find a way to achieve that.

"The meetings we had (last week) were to give everyone an opportunity to put their thoughts forward," Mennie said.

"In the end, we knew this is what it is. I don't know we were ever going to be standalone (next season), but some people - players and what have you - saw benefit in that for them and others.

"At the end of the day, the decision's been made and we will make this work."

AFL Victoria officials are meeting this month to discuss competition rules, including salary cap and appropriate list sizes.

Frankston will find out on August 7 if it will return to the VFL after a one-year absence.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Long</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ST KILDA'S VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Mennie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mennie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
