<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419744431735433</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/gene-repair-offers-hope-for-those-with-genetic-condition/8772748</url>
  <title>Gene repair offers new possibilities for Australian with genetic heart condition</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

When Barbara-Anne Tane was 16, she discovered she had the same genetic heart condition that caused her father's early and sudden death.
It follows that if she has children in the future, she could pass the gene on.
Ms Tane said living with the condition did not trouble her too much, and it was easily managed with medication, but it has coloured her thoughts on having kids.
"It's hard enough growing up, let alone having an inherited condition," she said.
could, in the future, put the fear of passing on a genetic condition to rest.
For Ms Tane, that's an exciting prospect, and one she did not expect to see in her lifetime.
"I was quite surprised. I thought it would be one or two generations before that type of research was developed," she said.
When she was seven years old, her father had just finished a rugby game when he collapsed, slipped unconscious and could not be revived.
At the time, his death was blamed on mitral valve prolapse, but his family now suspects that was a misdiagnosis.
Three years later, when Ms Tane's doctor noticed she had a heart murmur it raised alarm, given her father's recent death.

She was kept under close watch during her teenage years, and doctors eventually concluded the condition she has is Long QT Syndrome, a condition in which the heart does not return smoothly to its resting rate after exertion or stress.
The condition can lead to fainting or even sudden death.
"If I go for a run and I stop and rest - it's that recovery period when I'm resting that I can feel it or when the arrhythmia occurs," Ms Tane said.
She said she tried to live comfortably and not over exert herself.
Since her diagnosis, she has taken medication to make sure her heart rate and blood pressure do not become elevated during stressful moments, or if she exerts herself.
In her late 20s Ms Tane was fitted with an implantable cardioverter defibrillator, which will jolt her heart back into action should she get into trouble.
Despite the danger her condition presents, she said she would still take a considered approach to the type of gene editing technology announced today.
One thing that concerns her is the possibility that if you modify one part of the gene, another part of it could also be changed.
"I would need to look into the research in more depth to make sure it's sound and I was comfortable with the results," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbara-Anne Tane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long QT Syndrome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Tane</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
