<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419791676377021</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/health/wattle-health-triples-wealth-in-four-months-20170801-gxnhyt</url>
  <title>Billionaire families and small fry big winners from Wattle Health</title>
  <content>
Wattle Health is developing a reputation as a glamour stock after a capital raising was heavily oversubscribed in the wake of a purple patch where it has more than tripled the wealth of original investors in just four months.
Tony Gandel, the son of billionaire property magnate John Gandel, was among those who took up shares in the original ASX float of the infant formula and health supplements group at the outset in March, while other backers include Chinese entrepreneur Joel Chang, who runs an agricultural investment firm Genius Link Asset Management and a separate health products retail business.
Genius Link was one of the bidders for the S. Kidman & Co pastoral empire last year, which was eventually acquired by and another Chinese firm Shanghai CRED.
Wattle Health listed on the Australian Securities Exchange in mid-March  It has been off the boards over the past few days while an institutional placement has been taking place, with demand heavy for the stock at a price of 56¢ per share in the raising managed by JB Advisory and CCZ Corporate Finance. Wattle Health shares spiked by 29 per cent to as high as 75¢ by mid-afternoon on Thursday as it returned to trading after a previous close of 58¢ prior to the raising.

The company announced on Thursday that its raising had been expanded from an original $9.1 million. An extra $3.3 million will be taken in as part of a second tranche, making the total raise $12.4 million. The company said total bids received had been in excess of $20 million. It needs shareholder approval for the second tranche.

It is a much smaller company than rival Bellamy's Australia, which has been in the past few weeks after controversy over a capital raising and a rollercoaster ride where it has had difficulties with the China market. The Bellamy's share price was over $14 in early August, 2016 and is now just above $7.
Popular strategy

Wattle Health, which made a quiet start to life as an ASX company and aspired to the same level of success as Australian vitamins pioneers  has increasingly won favour as it pursues its strategy of building a vertically integrated nutritional dairy product company. Its main source of income initially was an exclusive sales agreement with JR Duty Free stores for the sale of infant formula and dried milk products.
Wattle's executive chairman Lazarus Karasavvidis has also outlined an expansion into the production of a baby food range that will start in September.

"This will further expand the product offering which will increase brand awareness and most importantly, sales in both the domestic and international market," he said on July 28 when Wattle released cash flow statements. They showed that in the three months ended June 30, receipts from customers was just $29,519. But the company pointed out sales from July 1 to July 25 had been "in excess" of $200,000.
Those extra sales came after Wattle signed a string of supply deals in the past few months including with Australian supermarket wholesaler Metcash, which supplies IGA stores, and southern China's largest mother and baby retailer, Aiyingdao Zhuhai Business Chain. Genius Link's Mr Chan and his partners own Aiyingdao Zhuhai Business Chain. Wattle also signed a supply deal with Tesco Lotus Supermarket Co, an arm of the global retailing giant Tesco.
The Hong Kong financial firm Mason, which is also part of the Genius Link stable, in early July bought the majority shareholding in Melbourne-based contract infant formula canning business Blend and Pack in a deal worth $100 million. Wattle Health is acquiring a 5 per cent stake in Blend and Pack, which has the certification of Chinese authorities to supply infant formula into China.
Mason has exercised an option to subscribe for $500,000 in Wattle shares as part of the raising.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesco Lotus Supermarket Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Chang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metcash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Link's Mr Chan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genius Link</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genius Link Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Gandel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lazarus Karasavvidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Gandel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy's Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mason</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCZ Corporate Finance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aiyingdao Zhuhai Business Chain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattle Health</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Advisory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JR Duty Free</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai CRED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S. Kidman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
