<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419830331083560</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/why-north-melbourne-should-give-ben-brown-a-pay-rise-20170803-gxoq1h.html</url>
  <title>Why North Melbourne should give Ben Brown a pay rise</title>
  <content>
Amid the departure of so many senior players at North Melbourne, Ben Brown has emerged as the type of forward the club's future can be built around.
There's no doubt he's enjoyed a breakout year in the absence of Drew Petrie, ensuring the Roos' decision to move on all of those veterans has been vindicated. Alongside skipper Jack Ziebell and defender Robbie Tarrant, he's comfortably one of the most important men at Arden Street.Photo: AAP
With 51 goals for the season, Brown is matching Buddy Franklin and is just two majors behind Joe Daniher in the Coleman Medal race.
While he mightn't be spoken about in the same category, finishing as the AFL's leading goalkicker would be some achievement in a side that is  sitting 17th on the ladder. You won't find any clubs admitting it, but for those out of the finals race chasing the Coleman Medal for one of your teammates can be something to strive for.Photo: AAP
Of course Brad Scott wouldn't want his players straying from the game-plan or putting the individual above the collective, but personal awards like that can provide a lift.
I remember back in 1990 under Wayne Schimmelbusch when John Longmire went into the final round needing just four goals to reach his century. He was only 19 at the time. Going into the match everyone was saying "make sure we kick it to Horse" and we certainly gave him plenty of opportunities. Unfortunately, John could only manage 2.8 and finished the season on 98 goals, although he still won the Coleman.

While it's a bit early for the Roos to start looking for Brown too often, they should have it in the back of their minds come round 23. The big forward from Tassie might be a bit unfashionable with his curly red hair, but he's come a long way since being drafted.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Brown was overlooked for three straight years before being taken with pick 47 in the 2013 national draft.
Initially it looked like he might struggle with the pace and movement of AFL football, but he's now a really dangerous player and is arguably one of the best marks in the game along with West Coast's Jeremy McGovern.
He has a great ability to meet the footy at its highest point, even when he's running full steam ahead towards the ball-carrier. That is not always easy to do, but when you can mark the footy out in front like he does it makes it almost impossible to defend.
Overall Ben's a really efficient player, because when the ball is in his area he generally marks it and kicks truly. His set shot routine is as unique and recognisable as Matthew Lloyd throwing the grass in the air. But while Brown has a run up like Michael Holding, he still manages to convert like Tony Lockett or Jason Dunstall.
Most importantly he runs in a straight line and kicks through the ball. So far this season he's booted 51.23 compared to Daniher's 53.31 and Buddy's 51.50.
What's also exciting for North Melbourne fans is the fact that he still has plenty of upside, particularly next to another emerging player in Mason Wood. He's clearly worked on his agility and forward craft, but could still push up the ground to find the footy more often.
Should the Roos climb up the ladder over the next few years as they continue to rebuild, expect his goalkicking tally to rise accordingly. However, Brown's form does mean the club will need to fork out a significant pay rise to sign him up long-term, as they reportedly want to do. The massive contracts the Roos are believed to be throwing at Dustin Martin and Josh Kelly wouldn't go unnoticed around Arden Street.
There's no point recruiting them if they've got no one to kick to, so his management would know his stocks are certainly very high at the moment.
Given what the Dogs paid a more unproven player like Tom Boyd, it's not out of the question to say Brown could command somewhere in the region of $800,000 given how crucial he is to the club's future.
The Roos would be smart to get that deal done soon, because should Brown keep trending in the direction he's been going, that figure might be even greater in 12 months time.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Holding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arden Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Tarrant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Schimmelbusch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Dunstall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Ziebell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniher's 53.31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast's Jeremy McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddy Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arden Street.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Lockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddy's 51.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
