<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418885438258928</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-union/brumbies/nick-jooste-channels-act-brumbies-injury-frustrations-into-john-i-dent-cup-premiership-bid-20170803-gxokpf.html</url>
  <title>Nick Jooste was given the nickname 'Bernie Junior', but his Brumbies time ended in injury heartbreak</title>
  <content>
Injuries stalled Nick Jooste's career before it even started, but the shattered 20-year-old is determined to turn his nightmare run into a positive before he leaves Canberra.
Jooste has been released by the ACT Brumbies after failing to play a Super Rugby game in his two-year stint in the capital.Photo: Rohan Thomson
The Australian under-20s playmaker was gutted when told he would not be re-signed, but he's on a mission to leave on a high when he plays his first John I Dent Cup finals series on Sunday.
Jooste says he's finally starting to trust his body again after being struck down by osteitis pubis and quad injuries, among others, after signing his first contract as a schoolboy star.

Jooste, nicknamed 'Bernie Junior' because of his similarities to coach Stephen Larkham, has played the past four games in a row for Wests in the longest consecutive streak of his past two years.
But rather than kicking stones because of his uncertain Super Rugby future, Jooste has set his sights on chasing Wests' first premiership since 2005.

"It's been a pretty frustrating two years, injuries have halted my progress at the Brumbies so it's been good to finally get some games together with Wests," Jooste said.
"It's been tough. I felt like I was going into this year in a really good position to play some Super Rugby with the Brumbies.
"It hasn't worked out like that with injuries and [Australian under-20s], and it's tough being here but not being able to do what you want.
"It was a tough conversation to have for both [Stephen Larkham] and I to have. I was pretty rocked for a while [when the Brumbies didn't re-sign me], but I'm looking to the positives now."
Jooste is set to join the Perth Spirit for the National Rugby Championship season as he prepares to relaunch his career.
Jooste will likely have to wait until the ARU reaches a decision on whether it will axe the Western Force or the Melbourne Rebels from the competition.
The Brumbies plucked Jooste out of school and made him the sixth youngest player in Australian rugby history to sign a full-time professional contract.
His kicking prowess and silky playmaker skills put him on the radar, but his transition to the Brumbies was derailed by an injury curse which delayed his development and hopes of making his Super Rugby debut.
"This is the most I've played since I've been in Canberra, I haven't been able to string minutes together but my body is feeling good and it's just good to be playing rugby again," Jooste said.
"Hopefully I can stay in one piece now for a while. I've got to see what's next and just keep playing footy.
"I'm trying not to worry about the future. I'll focus on Wests, then look towards NRC. But a good finals series would be a good way to finish my time here. That's the plan."
Wests will play the Queanbeyan Whites in a knockout semi-final at Viking Park on Sunday.
Jooste has found his feet after starting in the last four rounds before the play-offs, and Wests are keen to ignite their attack to keep their premiership hopes alive.
Queanbeyan has played in two of the past three grand finals, but hasn't won a premiership since 2010.
"We want to play with a bit more freedom this time, which will be good," Jooste said.
JOHN I DENT CUP FINALS
Major semi-final: Royals v Tuggeranong Vikings at Viking Park, 3.25pm on Saturday.
Minor semi-final: Wests v Queanbeyan Whites at Viking Park, 3.15pm on Sunday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Spirit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John I Dent Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jooste</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Larkham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Brumbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOHN I DENT CUP FINALS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Rebels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong Vikings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Viking Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Junior</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Jooste</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Whites</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Rugby Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
