<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419710071996313</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/richard-roxburgh-has-a-stare-that-scares-as-roger-rogerson-in-blue-murder-sequel-20170726-gxjc0j.html</url>
  <title>Look who's back: Richard Roxburgh revives Roger 'the Dodger' Rogerson in Blue Murder sequel</title>
  <content>
When it comes to playing Australia's most famous bent copper, the eyes have it.
"He apparently can send a kind of electric charge through you with his gaze," says Richard Roxburgh, who reprises his star turn as former NSW detective Roger Rogerson in Blue Murder: Killer Cop more than 20 years after he first played him in Blue Murder.

Up Next

$4 an hour internships

02:29

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Trailer:
Blue Murder: Killer Cop

Richard Roxburgh reprises his role as former NSW detective Roger Rogerson in the sequel to Blue Murder.

The Rogerson of this series is no longer the lean, mean verballing machine of the 1980s, when we last saw him; now he's a man in his 50s and beyond, struggling to make his way in a world where his reputation precedes him. But in Roxburgh's portrayal, the stare - unnerving, unflinching, intimidating - remains his defining characteristic, and greatest weapon.
Roxburgh won enormous praise (and a Logie) for his portrayal in the original two-parter, which screened on the ABC in 1995 (except for NSW, where legal appeals kept it off screen until 2001). But mastering that steely gaze didn't come easily.

"We'd been filming for a week on the first one," he recalls, "and I had this moment on the Friday afternoon when director Michael Jenkins came galloping in. 'You've f---ing got it,' he said. 'What you did then was f---ing excellent.' I said, 'What did I do?' and he said, 'You f---ing didn't do anything'."
He laughs at the memory. "It was about a great simple stillness, that shark-like focus, and that's an unusual thing that I did have to learn - and I didn't learn it quickly first time around."

This time, though, "It was an act of remembering". Did it come back immediately? "Yeah, it did."

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

He was 32 or so when he first played Rogerson; now he's 55. Then, it was a story of a crooked policeman in the King's Cross underworld. Now, he says, "it's about a self-funded retiree" - albeit one given to scrapping and brawling and bending the rules at will.Photo: Seven
The impetus for revisiting this most unsavoury character came from Jenkins. One of the biggest names in Australian television in the 1980s and 1990s, he was one of the creative forces behind Scales of Justice, Heartbreak High (the TV spin-off of his 1992 movie The Heartbreak Kid) and Wildside - and, of course, the original Blue Murder.
"I felt that was an important part of our television history, a turning point," says producer John Edwards of the original miniseries. "And when we had the opportunity to revisit it I just felt you couldn't not."
When Jenkins came knocking in late 2014, Rogerson was back in the news, thanks to the murder of university student and alleged drug dealer Jamie Gao. That made it timely, but also risky. No one wanted a repeat of the 1995 experience.
"We were a little nervous," says Edwards. "We were under way with scripting and financing well before [Rogerson and co-accused Glen McNamara] were convicted, and that trial was delayed and then aborted, so it was a bit of hold-your-breath for a while. But everyone was pretty confident of the outcome."
The series covers a span of about 20 years in Rogerson's post-police force life, with all the ageing that period demands. First time round, Roxburgh took care of his own physical transformations. "I ate like a pig the whole time we were shooting, and put on a lot of weight throughout."

Tony Martin and Richard Roxburgh in the original 'Blue Murder', which screened on the ABC in 1995.

This time, he had a team to help him. "It was three hours in the make up chair every morning," he says. "There was a neck piece we had to apply, and a bald head wig. There were days where I'd have to do a few changes of make-up, because there are three gradations of ageing and it was impossible to shoot chronologically. The script supervisor kept her eye on things like the decline of Roger's hip over time - that slow descent into decrepitude was something you had to work hard to plot out."
The two-part miniseries is punctuated with dates and times lifted straight from court transcripts; for obvious reasons, it was important to get the moments that legally mattered absolutely right. But plenty of other stuff in Blue Murder: Killer Cop is "an act of imagination", simply made up by writer Peter Schreck.
Rather than straight biopic, says Edwards, "It's much more 'inspired by', with a spine of fact. Some of the fabrications, some of the attitudinal things and emotional landscape, are very much Peter's conceptions. People will have different opinions on the validity of doing that, but it's what makes an interesting drama about the human condition."
It's a mark of how good Roxburgh is - and he's matched every step of the way by Toni Collette as wife Anne Rogerson - that in spite of everything he gets up to, you can't help but feel just a little for the bent copper looking for some semblance of normality in his life.

Toni Collette, right, lights up every scene in which she appears as Rogerson's wife Anne. Photo: Seven

"I think it's important that people understand the difficulty of that," says Roxburgh. "I don't mind that you empathise. It's important that we understand the people we fear the most, that we can reach into them and see what might make them tick. It would worry me though if you sympathise. There's a world of difference between those two states."
Blue Murder: Killer Cop is on Seven on August 6 and 7 at 8.30pm.

Facebook:  Twitter:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rogerson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scales of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxburgh</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Gao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heartbreak Kid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen McNamara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dodger' Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Killer Cop</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Schreck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni Collette</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
