<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419542568268169</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/basketball/australian-nba-star-andrew-bogut-training-in-us-as-four-teams-circle-for-his-signature/news-story/3f0d0012d7be09512f6706323f2f15bb</url>
  <title>Bogut edging closer to new deal</title>
  <content>
ANDREW Bogut has started working out in America to prepare for his looming deal with a new NBA franchise.
His Australian-based manager Bruce Kader told The Daily Telegraph the veteran centre was on holidays to recuperate following an intense rehabilitation after breaking his leg in March.
Four unnamed teams have expressed interest in signing the Boomers star, but a deal is yet to be confirmed with the NBA season to start in late October.
Bogut, who recently confirmed he was confident of inking a new deal in the near future, has sent the latest scans on his leg to interested teams as contract discussions intensify.
Bogut sent the internet into a frenzy on Sunday when he tweeted: "Newport, RI. Very nice place."
The 32-year-old was at a friend's wedding, but the fact he was in Newport - a 30-minute drive from Boston - sparked speculation he could join the Celtics.
New York City is also a within driving distance from Newport, which has started speculation the Knicks or Brooklyn Nets could also be in the mix for his services.
It comes as Australian Utah Jazz star Joe Ingles declared this week he was keen for his team Utah to give Bogut an offer.
Bogut, the No.1 selection in the 2005 NBA draft, is well known to Jazz fans after starring in college with the University of Utah.
"I would love for him to come over to Utah," Ingles told AAP. "He's got a connection there already and if they want to take him, I'll happily have him."
Bogut will most likely have to settle for a reduced one-year deal before being upgraded given it's late in the free agency period.
Former MVP Derrick Rose recently agreed to a one-year deal with Cleveland, worth a reported $US2.1 million after an indifferent season at the Knicks following a trade from Chicago.
That equates to a 90 per cent pay cut for Rose, who made a whopping $21.3 million last season.
Bogut may be forced into a similar situation as Rose to revive his injury-interrupted career, before picking up more money in later seasons.
The Melbourne-born product is coming off a three-year contract worth $44 million he signed during his time at Golden State before he was traded for a short-lived stint at Dallas.
He was then dealt to Philadelphia, who bought out his contract, and inked a $385,000 deal to finish last season with Cleveland but lasted less than a minute after breaking his leg.
If he doesn't pick up a new deal before the end of the NBA off-season, the Australian big man could wait until the mid-season to secure his future.
This could be beneficial for Bogut, as it would protect him from the draining impact of an 82-game NBA regular season.
He was waived by the Cavaliers after his tenure was cut short when he broke his leg in his debut game for Cleveland in March. Bogut hasn't played since, but is working overtime in the gym to be ready for his return to court.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newport</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celtic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brooklyn Nets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Bogut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Kader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bogut</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knicks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVP Derrick Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Utah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
