<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419014287280225</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/teams/sydney/sydney-swans-trio-rohan-melican-lewis-melican-and-dean-towers-know-how-to-win-in-geelong/news-story/75cd0bd44aab3a697a0ef36682e46808</url>
  <title>Swans trio have inside info on Cats fortress</title>
  <content>
WHEN it comes to home-ground advantages nothing compares to Geelong's fortress Simonds Stadium.
The Cats have easily the best record of any AFL club on their own turf, winning an incredible 66 of their last 73 matches at The Cattery, including their last seven straight and 15 of their last 16.
BUDDY TIGHTROPE:
WORLD NEWS:
That's why the Swans will be drawing on the local knowledge of county boys Gary Rohan, Lewis Melican and Dean Towers, who grew up playing at the venue, when they run out in Geelong on Friday night.
All three grew up in nearby towns and played plenty of matches at the famous venue as juniors.
Rohan came from nearby Cobden, Melican from Birregurra and Towers from Luke Hodge's home town of Colac. Rohan and Melican played a host of times when they were with the Geelong Falcons.
"It's great to have some country boys from back home to play with in Sydney," Rohan said.
"Footy is everything in that part of the world and naturally the Cats dominate everything."
Rohan started following Geelong when his cousin, Port Adelaide coach Ken Hinkley started playing there in the late 1980s.
"I've played a lot of footy on the ground and I love the long and narrow configuration," he said.
"There's plenty of space. The Swans and Cats have had plenty of great games there over the years and hopefully we will have another there."
Towers hasn't played at the venue as much as Rohan because he played mostly in the Colac and District League but still chalked up a few games with North Ballarat in VFL.
"I've got plenty of family and friends coming," Towers said.
"I didn't want to be too greedy asking for tickets but I've got a few. I'm expecting to hear from them during the game and they'll be easy to see wearing red and white."
The red and whites have won four of their last five matches against Chris Scott's men, including last year's preliminary final.
"The last time we played at Simonds Stadium was Kizza's (Kieren Jack) 200th and it was an awesome game," Towers said.
"We brought enormous energy to the contest and we have to get back to that. We know we can play good footy there as a team. It's a great ground. I really like playing there."
Sydney's cause has been helped by the match review panel and Geelong and Dangerfield's decision not to contest his one week ban for a dangerous tackle.
"The Cats and Danger have done the team thing," Towers said.
"He's taken the one match and he can get ready for the next."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDDY TIGHTROPE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Towers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong Falcons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cattery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melican</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Melican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieren Jack) 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cobden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Ballarat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birregurra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kizza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
