<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419753021670180</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/a-shameful-day-for-australia/news-story/2eb9b0e70195d0425acc0168de14d0a6</url>
  <title>A SHAMEFUL DAY FOR AUSTRALIA</title>
  <content>
Jews back to the ghettos:
A LOCAL council has banned the construction of a synagogue in Bondi because it could be a terrorist target, in a shock move that religious leaders say has caved in to Islamic extremism and created a dangerous precedent...
The Land and Environment Court backed the decision by Waverley Council to prohibit the construction of the synagogue in Wellington St, Bondi - just a few hundred metres from Australia's most famous beach - because it was too much of a security risk for users and local residents.
Jewish leaders are shocked the decision appears to suggest they cannot freely practice their religion because they are the target of hate by Islamist extremists - and that the council has used their own risk assessment of the threat posed by IS against it.
What next? Jewish shops also moved out to spare the residents?
Imagine what such a council in Germany would have decided when the Nazis started to target Jewish synagogues and shops. Protect the Jews - or evict them.
What a shameful day for this country.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waverley Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHAMEFUL DAY FOR AUSTRALIA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jewish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
