<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419619877681201</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/business/media/veteran-political-reporter-laurie-oakes-announces-his-retirement/news-story/6ac90a8c6e57feadd5c4ba43d05a4ef2</url>
  <title>Veteran political reporter Laurie Oakes announces his retirement</title>
  <content>
Laurie Oakes retires
5:17

Veteran reporter Laurie Oakes discusses the reasoning behind his retirement.

August 3rd 2017
5 hours ago

Laurie Oakes has announced his retirement. Picture Glenn Hampson

Holly ByrnesNews Corp Australia Network

Share

STEALING former Prime Minister Gough Whitlam's 1972 election slogan, Nine News veteran Laurie Oakes confirmed his retirement from journalism, telling colleagues and fans: "it's time."
The 73-year-old Canberra stalwart will farewell the Federal press gallery on August 18 - adding his latest personal scoop to a long list of political bombshells he's dropped over an unparalleled 50-year TV and media career.
Looming large - both in substance and style - since joining Nine in 1984, the News Corp columnist was praised by his peers and political rivals as arguably the most consistent TV newsbreaker in the medium's history.
His most recent exclusive - breaking protocol to report on Malcolm Turnbull's parody of US President Donald Trump at the Press Gallery's annual midwinter ball - making headlines around the world and sparking a debate about doing what Oakes does best: revealing what politicians don't want you to know.

Channel Nine Political Editor Laurie Oakes in the Canberra Studio at Parliament House. Picture: SuppliedSource:News Corp Australia
In a memo to staff, he network's news boss, Darren Wicks paid tribute to Oakes' crusading career as a reporter, newsbreaker and mentor.
"He's a father figure to the Canberra Bureau team and a ferocious defender whenever they've come under attack," Wick said, revealing: "many a politician and their minder have been sent from the Bureau with tails between legs after foolishly daring to challenge the veracity of a report."
Some of the biggest scoops in Australian political reporting carried Oakes byline - revealing the Kirribilli leadership pact between Paul Keating and Bob Hawke; exposing former Democrats Leader Cheryl Kernot's affair with Labor's Gareth Evans; and uncovering the truth about the Julia Gillard-Kevin Rudd showdown which triggered her claim for the Prime Ministership.
Dropping the 1980 Federal Budget in its entirety before the Government's then treasurer John Howard delivered it was a high watermark; with Howard nicknaming him "the budget burglar" over the legendary leak.

Laurie Oakes has announced his retirement. Picture: SuppliedSource:Supplied
Famed for steadfastly protecting his sources, Oakes did reveal a few details surrounding how he came to scoop that story which shocked Howard and put all Governments after on notice of his reach.
"I met a contact in a hotel carpark on the Sunday morning. He handed over the Budget speech and gave me 15 minutes to read it. So I gabbled the whole lot into a tape recorder while he went in and had a quick drink, and then I transcribed it back at the office. That evening [then treasurer] Mr [John] Howard was at home with toddler daughter Melanie on his lap watching cartoons on TV. Then the news started and I came up blowing every detail of his Budget speech."

Oakes is retiring after 50 years in the job. Picture: SuppSource:News Corp Australia
A multiple Walkley Award winner, including the Gold Walkley in 2010 and Logies Hall of Fame inductee a year later, Wicks declared Oakes "a living legend."
His Canberra colleague Lane Calcutt described a "Laurie ambush as like a bayonet thrust" and in Oakes editorial that followed on the state of today's power games no party or political leader came away unscathed, describing Australian politics as "a mess."
"People are sick of politicians and political parties talking about themselves, navel-gazing, not seeming to give priority to the things that concern their constituents."
"The pollies think it's all about them. Labor did it during the Rudd-Gillard wars. The Liberals are preoccupied and paralysed by the Abbott versus Turnbull revenge-athon and they wonder why minor parties are picking up support," Oakes raged.

Laurie Oakes is inducted into the Hall of Fame at the Melbourne Press Club Media Hall of Fame dinner. Picture: Mark StewartSource:News Corp Australia
"Bill Shorten's most important achievement as opposition leader has been to stop Labor from washing its dirty linen in public and the Liberals need to get their act together too - and quickly - otherwise they'll be handing Mr Shorten the next election."
Oakes was baffled by "the mess the Coalition has got itself into over same sex marriage, it's tearing itself apart."
They're threatening preselections, risking another leadership crisis and for what? It's pretty clear from opinion polls what the majority of Australians favour, so why die in a ditch over it?" warning, "I'm pretty sure about one thing ... Australians would not be impressed by another leadership change."
Signing off a live cross, Oakes said he would spend his retirement reading his favourite crime novels, quipping: "some cynics may say it's not that big a leap [from politics]".

A young Laurie Oakes. Picture: SuppliedSource:News Corp Australia
Tributes from friends and colleagues started pouring in soon after the announcement.
It's time.
Tip of the cap Mr Oakes. What a bloody honour.
Riewoldt, Usain Bolt & now Laurie. This is all getting too much.
9 Network Political Editor Laurie Oakes retires
A true great of Australian journalism ... announces "It's time" . Laurie is retiring & my goodness, we will miss the great man.
All the best  Bizarre memory of berating you on phone over an Iraq story while JWH wandered by my desk giving me thumbs up!
An absolute giant - nobody has ever come close in my view to his impact in political reporting.  Brilliant innings
kept the bastards honest for decades. What a role model for aspiring journalists. Hope he has a long healthy retirement.

Laurie Oakes Ties
0:27

Laurie Oakes wore six different ties to help punters who had made bets - Courtesy Channel Nine

July 3rd 2016
a year ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppliedSource</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Keating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Oakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine Political Editor Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Gough Whitlam's 1972</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Ministership</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats Leader Cheryl Kernot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark StewartSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JWH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logies Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtesy Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudd-Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Budget</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakes</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes Ties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's Gareth Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Press Club Media Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Gillard-Kevin Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lane Calcutt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly ByrnesNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirribilli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Studio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Wick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hampson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Press Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melanie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Political Editor Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walkley Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Walkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
