<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419658532387701</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/20/34/laurie-oakes-retiring-his-perspective-on-whats-next-for-government</url>
  <title>Laurie Oakes on the future of Australian politics</title>
  <content>
We're in a mess, and I hope our politicians come to their senses.
People are sick of politicians and political parties talking about themselves. Navel gazing, not seeming to give priority to the things that concern their constituents. 
The pollies seem to think it's all about them.
Labor did it during the Rudd versus Gillard wars.
The Liberals are preoccupied and paralysed by the Abbott versus Turnbull  revenge-a-thon - and they wonder why minor parties are picking up support.

Bill Shorten's most important achievement as opposition leader has been to stop Labor washing its dirty linen in public.
The Libs need to get their act together, too, and quickly. Otherwise they'll be handing Mr Shorten the next election.

Related Articles

I can't believe the mess the Coalition has got itself into over same sex marriage. It's tearing itself apart. Threatening preselections, risking another leadership crisis.
And for what? It's pretty clear from opinion polls what a majority of Australians favour. So why die in a ditch over it?
I'm pretty sure about one thing. Australians wouldn't be impressed by another leadership change.
When I first started reporting politics, Labor factions spent all their energies on internal fights.

They were more interested in that than making the party electable. That's how the Liberals strike me now.
In retirement I'll be able to watch it all from a distance and mutter about it the way normal people do.
And I'll spend my time doing something a lot less stressful: my favourite pastime, reading crime novels.
Some cynics might say it's not that big a leap. 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
