<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418713639563512</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/retail/amazon-picks-german-rocco-braeuniger-to-lead-its-australian-invasion-20170803-gxogxw.html</url>
  <title>The man leading Amazon's Australian invasion </title>
  <content>
Amazon has revealed it will parachute one of its German directors into Australia to lead its assault on the local retail sector. 
The Seattle-headquartered e-commerce giant said on Thursday it had appointed Rocco Braeuniger as country manager for Australia, as it . 

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Are companies like Amazon good for society?

NYU Stern Professor of Marketing Scott Galloway looks at whether other tech giants have to fear the Amazon juggernaut.

Currently director of consumables at Amazon Germany, Mr Braeuniger has worked at the online retailer for 11 years in positions including director of outdoor products and category lead in sports and leisure. 
Mr Braeuniger studied at the University of Bayreuth in his native Germany and has a Master of Business Administration from Babson College in the US, according to his LinkedIn profile. 

Also on Thursday, Amazon  that it would open its first Australian fulfilment centre in Dandenong South, in Melbourne's south-east.
The 24,000 square metre warehouse in Pellicano's M2 Industry Park will be manned by product "pickers" and packers who will prepare online orders for delivery. 

Amazon Australia's director of operations, Robert Bruce, said the facility would employ "hundreds" of people, with recruitment already under way. 

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"This is just the start," Mr Bruce said. "Over time, we will bring thousands of new jobs to Australia and millions of dollars of investment as well as opening up the opportunity for thousands of Australian businesses to sell at home and abroad through Amazon Marketplace."Photo: Amazon.de
Mr Bruce said the centre would stock "hundreds of thousands" of products, which will be made available for delivery to Australian customers when it launched its retail offering. 
Amazon has not put a date on when its full retail service will be online, but retail watchers expect it to be sometime during 2018, with some suggesting late 2017 was possible. Photo: AP
The business is expected to hit incumbent retailers' sales and force them to cut prices, particularly in electronics, apparel and sporting goods.
, hit by rising costs and international competition, which will only heighten with the entry of Amazon.
However, what form Amazon's offering takes in Australia, and whether it includes services offered in other markets such as its Prime subscription service or its Fresh grocery product, is yet to be seen. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Bayreuth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Galloway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pellicano's M2 Industry Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Braeuniger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bruce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle-headquartered</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Babson College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocco Braeuniger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYU Stern Professor of Marketing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master of Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LinkedIn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
