<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419229035649157</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/18/49/taxpayers-funding-debt-collection-for-toll-road-giants-as-bills-mount-up</url>
  <title>Taxpayers funding</title>
  <content>
Australia is in the middle of a toll crisis, with unpaid bills clogging the court system and diverting police resources as people face gigantic financial penalties.
With bills running to the hundreds of thousands of dollars, ordinary Australians are being arrested and brought to face court.
Victoria Legal Aid's Damien Stock said unpaid toll bills were the number one criminal matter of all the magistrates courts.
"It's incredibly stressful - most of our clients when they come to us have had a period of instability," he said.
"They're trying to get their lives back on track."
He said while most clients wanted to pay the original invoice, problems arose when the matter was transferred to police.
"The problem is not being able to deal with the disproportionate enforcement costs," he said.

Related Articles

He said there were concerns about using the apparatus of the state to enforce private debt collection.
"We certainly feel that taxpayers are being used as a debt collector for a multi-million dollar company," he said.
"If you don't pay your phone bill, the state doesn't step in and enforce compliance with that bill."
Mum Allison Crockett and her daughter Amy are both facing huge bills they claim are beyond their ability to pay.
Allison Crockett said she was arrested and put on bail over a $200,000 invoice, while Amy Crockett has a $280,000 tab to pay.
Ms Crockett said her daughter had tried to establish payment plans with Transurban, the company that manages most of Australia's toll roads, but claimed they had demanded to see her in court.
Melbourne grandmother and pensioner Maureen said she owed $130,000.
She said she blamed herself but amid dealing with health issues and hospital visits, the pile of mail became "overwhelming".
"I could build a house with just the paperwork they've sent me over the last few years," she said.
The problem has become so pervasive that special toll courts have been set up in some justice centres.
Transurban issued a statement outlining its process.
"We do everything we can to help people with their unpaid tolls, including sending at least two written notices and reaching out to people via phone, text messages and email to prevent the unpaid tolls reaching infringement," the statement read.
"We want people to know that help is available. If someone is struggling to pay an overdue invoice, we encourage them to contact us right away. We offer first-time forgiveness and hardship programs so we may be able to help people with their payment difficulties and alleviate the worry of an unpaid debt getting bigger.
"Once an unpaid toll reaches infringement, the Department of Justice has the overall responsibility for the infringement process and we are no longer involved, which is why we encourage people to get in touch with us as soon as possible."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Legal Aid's Damien Stock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Crockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allison Crockett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maureen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Crockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
