<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419533978333369</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/basketball/san-antonio-spurs-and-boomers-star-patty-mills-says-being-a-good-role-model-is-his-top-priority/news-story/5392eae95e9463c14674f5098c9fb98c</url>
  <title>Superstar Mills stays focused on the main goal</title>
  <content>
HE just signed a four-year $US50 million contract extension with the San Antonio Spurs in the NBA.
But Australian basketball star Patty Mills says being a good role model to younger generations is his top priority.
The triple Olympian and NBA championship winner was in Brisbane on Thursday as part of his national tour to promote the "Game Day" book series.
He received a rock star reception as hundreds of basketball fans queued for hours down the Queen Street Mall.
Mills said the books were based on his upbringing as a "little indigenous boy'' and were designed to teach life lessons about sacrifice, hard work and passion.
"I feel like that (being a good role model) is the most important thing (for) the next generation,'' Mills said.
"At the end of the day, I'm only a little indigenous boy that set out on this journey. If I can do it, everyone standing here can.
"I've used my stature to try and give advice and do all I can.
"It (the book series) has a lot of teachings and lessons about values and respect and how to go about different challenges.''
Mills said this week's announcement that three NBL teams - including the Bullets - will play NBA teams in the US in October was further evidence that basketball in this country has "come a long way''.
Mills said he would be pushing for a fourth Olympics in Tokyo.
"You want to go on to compete as much as you can. Basketball is only going to be around for a short amount of time for me to make the most of it when you put on the green and gold,'' he said.
"No matter what team I'm on, I always represent Australia, the indigenous communities throughout the country.
"It's what motivates me, it's what fuels the fire.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Antonio Spurs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Street Mall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patty Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
