<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419314934996838</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/crime-and-justice/paul-pisasale-charged-by-ccc-with-attempting-to-pervert-justice/news-story/44638a1ab09bd558bafe8f7bc8481e31</url>
  <title>CCC hits Pisasale with further charges</title>
  <content>
EMBATTLED former Ipswich mayor Paul Pisasale has been hit with two more charges by the state's corruption watchdog.
The Crime and Corruption Commission served papers on Pisasale this evening, charging him with two counts of attempting to pervert justice.
In a statement the Crime and Corruption Commission said a 65-year-old Ipswich man would face court on two charges of attempting to pervert justice.
"This evening the Crime and Corruption Commission (CCC) served a notice to appear in court on the legal representative of the 65-year-old man," the statement said.

In just over two weeks, former Ipswich mayor Paul Pisasale has resigned, been arrested and granted bail.

The recent times of Paul Pisasale
Pisasale is expected to appear in court on August 8 to face the charges.
He is also facing three earlier charges, including extortion.
The CCC would not comment further due to the ongoing investigation.
Pisasale resigned as mayor on June 6, citing ill health.
He has spent much of his time since then in a mental health facility in Brisbane.
Pisasale has said he will fight the earlier charges.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pisasale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pisasale</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corruption Commission</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
