<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419271985323024</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/fifa-officials-to-arrive-next-week-for-showdown-talks-with-ffa-clubs-and-players-over-future-of-football/news-story/cdaba3223e5feb3a2bf8d6d1856732df</url>
  <title>FIFA gears up for Aussie showdown</title>
  <content>
THE FIFA mission that will rule on the future of Australian football has been confirmed for next week, with a delegation to arrive on Tuesday to start taking submissions.
The A-League clubs, Football Federation Australia, the players' union and other interest groups including women's football are likely to interviewed by officials from FIFA's member associations department.
The visiting delegation will have to decide whether a compromise can be reached in the civil war that has erupted between the clubs and FFA, or install an appointed leadership to revamp the power structure of the game in Australia.
Melbourne City vice chairman Simon Pearce said the A-League clubs welcomed FIFA's intercession, after months of increasingly acrimonious exchanges.
"We're entering a period of extraordinary significance for Australian football," Pearce said.
"Next week Football Federation Australia will receive a mission from FIFA and the AFC, something which we - the 10 A-League clubs - welcome enthusiastically.

Football: Jos Mourinho has had his say on the record breaking Neymar transfer fee.

'He's strong commercially'
"I can comfortably speak on behalf of my club peers when I say that at this moment, there is a real commonality between all of us.
"We know that we have to work together to produce the best possible outcome for one another, but most importantly for the Australian football family.
"I was asked recently what the ultimate ambition of the A-League should be ... and it's a simple question to answer: we are all here to create the best possible football competition that we can."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jos Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
