<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418799538911364</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830474/students-welcome-moves-to-increase-university-atar-transparency/?cs=12</url>
  <title>University of Wollongong early student admissions for 2018 now open</title>
  <content>
SUPPORTING TRANSPARENCY: University of Wollongong first year International Bachelor of Science student Olivia Panozzo said students supported a more personalised approach to university admissions.

Students and the University of Wollongong have thrown their support behind a new national admissions transparency plan introduced by the Turnbull government.

UOW student Olivia Panozzo welcomed that students were now able to see minimum and maximum ATARs for all university course offers.

The International Bachelor of Science student said any changes that increase university ATAR transparency was a good thing.

''It opens up options for different study pathways to students. Particularly for Year 12 leavers, it could help ease the already mounting pressure they experience when sitting their HSC exams,'' Miss Panozzo said.
Universities are now required to report on the raw ATARs of students offered places in each course even if extra entry criteria such as bonus points are used, and outline the number of students admitted through various ATAR, non-ATAR, and combined pathways.

UOW is supporting the changes recommended by the Higher Education Standards Panel (HESP), and is presenting clear and simple information to prospective students about admissions pathways and processes, including ATARs.

But UOW Deputy Vice-Chancellor (Academic) Professor Joe Chicharo added the university had been putting the student at the centre of the admissions process for almost two decades.

He said the fact that about 40 per cent of UOW's annual domestic undergraduate enrolments first receive an offer on a non-ATAR basis, indicated that students valued a more personalised admissions process.

This was supported by Miss Panozza, who said the university's early admission program allowed her to defer a year and head overseas safe in the knowledge her spot was secure.

- UOW student Olivia Panozzo
''I think the reason I got in is because I had all this extracurricular stuff and showed the interviewer that I was really interested in the course and that I really wanted to do it,'' she said.

''The benefit of the interview is that you're able to show yourself as a whole person rather than just an academic number, or a result on a page.''
Mr Chicharo said the university's personalised admissions process continues to deliver outstanding achievements in student completion and graduate outcomes, particularly in graduate employability.

''We attribute this success to the approach we take in ensuring students are enrolled into the course best suited to them and UOW's track record of prominence in national and international rankings for the quality of its teaching, student experience and outcomes,'' he said.

- UOW Deputy Vice-Chancellor (Academic) Professor Joe Chicharo
''We welcome the recommendations for the way admissions pathways and process are presented and support any initiatives that will help students make more informed choices, leading to improved retention and completion rates.''

University applications for 2018 admissions through the Universities Admissions Centre (UAC) are now open.

Students currently in Year 12 and completing the HSC can take advantage of UOW's Early Admissions program and earn a place in a degree based on more than their ATAR.

Interested students can also attend UOW's annual Open Day on August 19. Visit  for details.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Panozza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HESP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Open Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chicharo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Panozzo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATAR</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW's Early Admissions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panozzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Bachelor of Science</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Joe Chicharo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Admissions Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW Deputy Vice-Chancellor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Higher Education Standards Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 12</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
