<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419448078985441</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/technology/gaming/house-party-banned-after-letting-players-get-women-drunk-and-have-sex-with-them/news-story/4f898a42c1db18e7d8b91d3e9fcca23f</url>
  <title>Graphic sex game banned from sale</title>
  <content>
A "GRATUITOUS" sex simulator game which let players enjoy graphic romps with a range of simulated beauties has been banned.
House Party, a "raunchy comedy adventure", has been removed from Steam, the largest games distribution platform in the world, reports .
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month and became wildly popular on YouTube, with hundreds of people uploading videos of the saucy action.
The game was set in a house party populated by a range of women and their grumpy boyfriends.
Players had to talk the ladies into getting their clothes off before being shown extremely graphic sex scenes.
One "mission" allegedly involved getting a woman drunk and having sex with her, after sneaking a bottle of booze past her extremely violent and anti-alcohol boyfriend.
The game reportedly allowed players to perform sex acts by pressing the letter "p" and bashing the number "1".
In a blog post, designers Eek! Games said Steam had received a number of complaints about the game.
"I understand where Steam is coming from," it wrote.
"They are responding to an alarming societal perception of sex and nudity as something evil, even more so than murder, genocide, torture, and gore which is widely accepted and prevalent in most other video games that are offered up on Steam and many other gaming platforms.
"I don't agree with Steam's decision, but I respect it."
The game has been removed from Steam and will be made available once again "after some modifications".
Eek! Studios added: "Of course this also brings up an issue of unfair censorship.
"Part of the reason I chose to write this game is that I didn't want to do another tired old game about killing, violence and gore, though I suspect if I had written a game about that, nobody would have a problem.
"It seems to me as if it's much more socially acceptable to engage in the fantasy of killing another person in every perversion imaginable than it is to fantasise about having sex with another person."

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
