<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419491028659324</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/lifestyle/experimanet-encourages-tasters-to-raise-a-beer-to-whisky-week/news-story/4913c05e2954f812851bf2fb9182dc4c</url>
  <title>Raising a beer to whisky week</title>
  <content>
A FATHER-SON distiller and brewer combination will deliver a cross-generational experiment in beer and whisky matchings during Tasmanian Whisky Week.
Peter Bignell will match his award-wining Belgrove Distillery Rye whisky, spirits and other concoctions to his son Tom's T-Bone beers at the North Hobart brewery from 6pm to 8pm next Tuesday.
The experiment forms one of the 27 events throughout the state for Whisky Week which runs from Friday until August 13. The Tasmanian Whisky Producers Association is hosting the nine-day event.
The Bignell pair also brewed a big stout a few weeks ago and aged it in a couple of Belgrove ex-rye whisky barrels.
"I am excited to see what comes of this. It's always a gamble - you never know what it's like until you crack the lid," Tom said.
"The whole event is a learning experience for us and the consumer. We are really interested to hear what people think of the matchings. It's a great opportunity to chat and exchange ideas.
"It will be a great night, but I suggest those who are interested book."

Peter Bignell said people thought of matching food and wine but beer and whisky could be amazing.
"I am doing something different with rye whisky, which is a fast-growing category in the USA, and also whisky with oats," Mr Bignell said.
During the week there will be distillery open days, tasting master classes, whisky and brewery boilermaker evenings, hands-on whisky making experiences, dinners and helicopter tours.
See the program of events at taswhiskyweek.com
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bignell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father-son</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bignell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Bignell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Whisky Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom's T-Bone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgrove Distillery Rye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Whisky Producers Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whisky Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
