<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419834626050931</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/dad-of-toddler-with-meningococcal-tells-of-his-agony/news-story/d9dee57158bb9b9a18552500038e5657</url>
  <title>Sick toddler's dad tells of his agony</title>
  <content>
A HEARTBROKEN dad has told his sick toddler "I'm here for you baby girl" as she fights the potentially deadly meningococcal disease.
Health authorities say the northern-suburbs two-year-old is in a stable condition, diagnosed with the meningococcal B-strain.
"I love you Mia ... I hope my little girl gets better soon," the tot's father posted on Facebook.
"Why has this happens (sic) to my child. I don't wish this (meningococcal) on anyone."
On Thursday, SA Health criticised the Goodstart Early Learning Centre, in Salisbury North, and St Augustine's Parish School, to parents.
SA Health issued an alert on Wednesday and reassured the public not to panic about the case because the disease does not spread easily.
Chief medical officer Professor Paddy Phillips said the school and childcare centre's advice caused unnecessary concern to GPS and to the hospital emergency department.
"We were disappointed the childcare centre and local school didn't contact us to ask what the risk to other children was," he said.
But the school maintains it acted only after it had spoken to SA Health.

* A two-year-old girl in hospital fighting meningococcal disease
* RAH specialists cop it from the coroner as he examines the death of two stroke patients
* Bitumen rains down on a Torrens Park street as a water main bursts
* Adelaide businesses warned about the dangers of cyberhacks
* The AFL gets behind organ donation
* The final word from the coaches on Showdown selection night

Adelaide's Afternoon Newsbyte 3/8/17
"The school contacted SA Health for information and decided to write to parents to inform them there had been a suspected case of the disease and to contact their GP or the SA Health hotline if they had any concerns," a St Augustine's Parish School spokeswoman told The Advertiser.
"The school said it was notifying families as a precautionary measure. The school has received positive feedback from parents thanking it for keeping them informed."
Goodstart's National Safe Work and Wellbeing Manager Kylie Warren-Wright said the centre was working closely with SA Health.
"We have provided health information to our families and educators including detail provided by SA Health. We are encouraging anyone with concerns to contact SA Health or to see their local GP," she said.
Parents praised the response by the childcare centre and school, with many saying they were "thankful for the call".
SA Health has directed nine people to receive antibiotics. There have been 21 cases of meningococcal in the state this year compared with 13 cases at the same time last year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Paddy Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salisbury North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-strain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Augustine's Parish School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's Afternoon Newsbyte 3/8/17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrens Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodstart Early Learning Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellbeing Manager Kylie Warren-Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Health</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodstart's National Safe Work</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
