<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418842488585133</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4831434/yates-waits-to-learn-if-he-is-in-knights-plans/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Yates waits to learn if he is in Knights' plans</title>
  <content>
LUKE Yates grew up just a decent punt kick from McDonald Jones Stadium and has never aspired to play for any team other than the Newcastle Knights.

LOCAL JUNIOR: Luke Yates grew up just down the road from McDonald Jones Stadium and is living his dream playing for the Knights. Picture: Jonathan Carroll
Yet as Knights officials sift through the player market looking for incoming personnel to reinforce their roster, 22-year-old Yates is waiting to learn if he will be required beyond this season.
The fearless back-rower, who debuted against the Warriors in round one and has now played in 16 NRL games, is off contract and hopes he has shown enough potential to warrant retention.
His manager, Steve Gillis, told the Newcastle Herald on Thursday he was "reasonably confident" preliminary talks with the Knights would produce a positive outcome, but added that the ball was in the club's court.
"Luke definitely wants to stay,'' Gillis said.
"He's worked his bum off to play first grade for the Knights and that's all he's ever wanted to do, since he was a little kid. But if we can't come to terms, he'll have to think outside the square and I'm sure there will be plenty of other clubs who know who he is now.
"But his preference is to stay in Newcastle, and hopefully that's what happens.''
Yates is one of a host of Newcastle's first-grade squad who are free agents, along with the likes of Peter Mata'utia, Lachlan Fitzgibbon, Brendan Elliot, Jaelen Feeney, Jack Stockwell, Anthony Tupou and Mickey Paea.
The Wests Rosellas junior said he would "love to stay" and become a long-term Knights player.
"I'm a Newcastle lad, a local junior,'' he said. "Hopefully something gets sorted, but I'm just leaving it to my management and trying to focus on football.''
Yates said his teammates enjoyed last week's win against St George Illawarra, which ended an eight-game losing run, but were realistic about Saturday's clash with the Warriors at McDonald Jones Stadium.
"The Dragons win, it probably wasn't one of our better performances,'' he said.
"We've probably played better and lost. We'll just focus on being better players and a better team.''
Yates was confident a shoulder injury he suffered six weeks ago, which initially required game-day painkilling injections, was recovering and would not require surgery. 
"It was only really affecting me when I was in the gym,'' he said.
"When I'm defending, it doesn't really give me too much grief. It's getting back towards full strength."

Newcastle will hold their final training session on Friday morning and winger Shaun Kenny-Dowall is expected to face a fitness test.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Knights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LUKE Yates</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Stockwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaelen Feeney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Fitzgibbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Gillis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Elliot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mickey Paea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yates</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Tupou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones Stadium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Rosellas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Mata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Kenny-Dowall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
