<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419233330616548</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/serious-injuries-from-faulty-phone-covers-lead-to-mass-recall/news-story/22eeb25f636d2dd27ddb3aa918c4c6ce</url>
  <title>Glitter phone cases causing severe chemical burns</title>
  <content>
POPULAR liquid glitter phone cases are being recalled after world-wide reports of chemical burns and skin irritation.
The manufacturer, MixBin, has issued a for a range of their iPhone 6, 6s and 7 cases which contain liquid and glitter floating in the plastic case.
The report states that there have been 24 reports world-wide, "of skin irritation or chemical burns."
One consumer has reported permanent scarring from the chemical burn while another has recounted, "chemical burns and swelling to her leg, face, neck, chest, upper body and hands."
People have been claiming they've received burns and irritations since at least 2016.
In a press release MixBin warned, "consumers should immediately stop using the recalled cases and contact MixBin Electronics for a full refund".
Australians could purchase the cases from websites Nordstromrack and Toryburch. Other websites that distributed the case include Mixbin, Amazon, Victoria Secret, Amazon and Henri Bendel.
Even though the product has been officially recalled they are still circulating on eBay.
Despite only 24 cases officially being reported there are an estimated 275,000 units sold.
Social media users affected have posted to Twitter and Instagram warning others to be cautious.
The cases were sold within the United States as well as online from October 2015 through June of 2017.
Consumers concerned can check the model number and UPC on the product's packaging to see if their case has been recalled, or can  of the cases through the press release.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MixBin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MixBin Electronics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nordstromrack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henri Bendel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Secret</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toryburch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
