<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418936977867245</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/comres-poll-british-people-believe-united-kingdom-split-after-brexit-scotland-northern-ireland-2017-8</url>
  <title>British people believe the United Kingdom will tear itself apart after Brexit</title>
  <content>
LONDON - A majority of British people believe the United Kingdom will tear itself apart after Brexit, a new poll has found.

62% of Scottish people and 53% of all UK voters, believe the country will fracture over the next ten years, according to a .

The independence movement in Scotland and growing uncertainty over the post-Brexit border between Northern Ireland and the Republic could combine to end centuries of political union between the nations of the UK.

Comres / BBC poll: The United Kingdom will no longer exist as either Scotland, Wales, or Northern Ireland will be independent:

Net Likely: 53%

Net unlikely: 45%

Britain's decision to leave the European Union has led to renewed calls for a second Scottish independence referendum.

Scottish first minister Nicola Sturgeon has pushed, so far unsuccessfully, for a new poll before Britain leaves the EU in 2019.

Theresa May's decision to leave the single market and customs union has also led to growing uncertainty in Northern Ireland.

In recent weeks the Irish government has  between mainland Britain and Northern Ireland after Brexit in order to prevent smuggling.

On Wednesday an Irish parliamentary committee also

The proposals, which were set out in preparation for Brexit, envision a cross-border referendum on a united Ireland taking place over the coming years.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Ireland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ComRes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicola Sturgeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theresa May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Likely: 53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
