<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418756589237553</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/retail/fmcg/lion-profit-squeezed-by-flat-beer-sales-orange-shortage-20170803-gxoeun</url>
  <title>An orange shortage hurt Lion's profits but soft mainstream beer sales a bigger worry. </title>
  <content>
Beer, yoghurt and juice company Lion has been temporarily squeezed by a national shortage of oranges but faces a much bigger problem as it wrestles with the
Lion, which is owned by Japanese giant Kirin and sells beer brands including XXXX Gold, Tooheys, West End and James Boag, suffered a 12.9 per cent drop in operating profit to $334.7 million for the six months ended March 31. Beer makes up close to 90 per cent of Lion's Australasian operations and it relinquished the rights to number-one selling imported beer brand Corona on September 30, 2016, and also offloaded the smaller premium wine business  owned by CHAMP Private Equity.
Lion also operates a substantial dairy and non-alcoholic drinks business selling Farmers Union, Dairy Farmers and Yoplait yoghurt, and juices under the brand names of Berri and The Daily Juice Company.
Lion didn't give any official response to speculation that  for a potential sale of the dairy and drinks business.

But Lion chief executive Stuart Irvine said the dairy and drinks business had generated "particularly strong sales in speciality cheese and yoghurt categories" as he described the overall performance of that unit as solid.

"Our turnaround program remains on track," Mr Irvine said. The company's Tasmanian Heritage brand was a strong performer in speciality cheeses as customers bought up in the brie and camembert segments. But a national shortage of oranges bumped up prices for the juice business, along with prices for orange juice concentrate. But this was a short-term issue.
Complex global mega-merger

Lion's beer portfolio shrank on September 30 last year when it gave up the distribution rights to Corona in Australia after a complex global mega-merger between Anheuser-Busch InBev, and SABMiller. SABMiller bought the Foster's beer business known as Carlton & United Breweries, Lion's big rival in Australia, for $12 billion in late 2011. The Corona shift pushed Lion down to the number-two player in the $15 billion Australian beer market, overtaken by CUB, which sells Victoria Bitter and Crown Lager.
Industry players say Lion's market share is now around 42 per cent, while CUB holds around 46 per cent.

Total sales revenue across Lion's entire operations in the six months ended March 31 slipped by 9.5 per cent to $2.176 billion.
Mr Irvine said the "tough conditions" in the mainstream beer market posed more challenges than usual this time around because the drop in volumes caused by the end of the distribution agreement with AB Inbev put more pressure on the cost of sales, requiring closer attention to costs.
Tripled volumes

Fresh investment behind the Kirin brand meant it had been able to triple volumes in Australia, while the XXXX Summer Bright Lager expanded its volumes by 10 per cent.

Lion's craft beer portfolio, which includes Little Creatures, James Squire and Furphy, made strong gains in the first half. Those shifting consumer patterns are being faced by all big brewers, as Australia's 400 small craft brewers eat away at the market share of traditional mainstream beers.
Those shifts are also driving a wave of buy-ups of . Japan's Asahi acquired Melbourne's Mountain Goat in 2015 as part of the trend.
Also on Thursday, Brewers Association chief executive Brett Heffernan said low and mid-strength beer now accounted for about one quarter of total beer sales, with beer the only alcoholic beverage that provided "credible options" for consumers to moderate their consumption.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Breweries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Heritage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Creatures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Irvine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's 400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHAMP Private Equity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toohey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Irvine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Boag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XXXX Summer Bright Lager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AB InBev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Asahi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SABMiller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion's Australasian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 31</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brewers Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Squire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Lager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Mountain Goat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XXXX Gold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 30</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Juice Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Heffernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anheuser-Busch InBev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yoplait</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Bitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmers Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
