<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419753021670229</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/ive-come-to-have-that-hatred-port-adelaide-midfielder-ollie-wines-draws-battlelines-before-showdown/news-story/0c480674d30382cd50061e70a0c35666</url>
  <title>'I've come to have that hatred': Battlelines drawn</title>
  <content>
GROWING up in country Victoria, Port Adelaide midfielder Ollie Wines didn't understand the rivalry between Port Adelaide and Adelaide.
But since crossing the border and living in a city where you identify as either Capulet or Montague, the 22-year-old suggested no one was immune to the rivalry.
"Initially I didn't understand that, but I've come to have that hatred," Wines said on Fox Footy's AFL 360.
"We see each other down the streets and are obviously pretty friendly.
"But once you cross that white line and probably in general when you see them play ... you want to do better than them."
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 20 PREVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
While Showdowns have historically defied form lines, Port Adelaide sits on the wrong side of recent history, having lost the past four matches against Adelaide.
In Round 3, Adelaide triumphed by 17 points.
"We want to win more games than them. And there's two opportunities a year to take them on and do as much damage as you can," Wines said.
"We're pretty hungry. We've lost four in a row and we don't like letting our supporters down. We really want to come out and spoil the party.
"Obviously there's a lot of animosity between the two clubs and it's hard to understand if you're not a stakeholder in one of the teams, either a supporter, player or staff."
Wines intimated the game was important not just for bragging rights, but in the context of the season.
"It's really important for both clubs," he said.
"Adelaide are trying to cement that number one spot on the ladder. We're trying to get in that top four and hold our spot down. This is going to be one of the bigger ones in a while."
Wines has enjoyed his best season to date at Port Adelaide, benefiting from the silver service of returning ruckman Paddy Ryder.
But it's another big bodied midfielder in Sam Powell-Pepper who has caught the eye of not just the competition, but Wines.
"He's been pretty special this year. He's right up there in our opinion for the Rising Star," Wines said of Powell-Pepper.
"His ability to hit the scoreboard and play through the middle of the ground and play a man's role at such a young age ... I think a lot of guys, myself particularly, dropped off at this stage.
"But he's just going on strongly. It's exciting to see him do so well."
Wines said it was strange to consider himself as a role model for someone who was only three years his junior, but that he had ample support in that department.
"I've had to battle with that a little bit. At times I've thought, 'how can I be that role model that I looked up to when I came into the system?'" Wines said.
"I guess having the guys around me like Paddy Ryder, Brad Ebert, Robbie Gray and Travis Boak ... I'm definitely not alone in leading this midfield."
Want to be the Wildcard Entry to FOX FOOTY's Longest Kick on Grand Final Day?
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capulet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Powell-Pepper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ollie Wines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rising Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX FOOTY's Longest Kick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildcard Entry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Ebert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battlelines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 20 PREVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Boak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Powell-Pepper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montague</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
