<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419920525398580</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/news/world/2017/08/03/donald-trump-real-news/</url>
  <title>Donald Trump launches 'real news' hosted by daughter-in-law</title>
  <content>
After months of discrediting the mainstream media as fake news, US President Donald Trump has launched his own news program hosted by his daughter-in-law.
Lara Trump - who is married to Mr Trump's son, Eric - welcomed viewers to the first edition of "real news" on Sunday, boasting about the President's achievements on his personal Facebook page.
"I bet you haven't heard about all the accomplishments the President had this week because there's so much fake news out there," she began.
"Watch here for REAL news!" the post read.
The two-and-a-half minute video lists stories Ms Trump states the mainstream media didn't cover, including the President's donation of his second-quarter salary to the Department of Education and that the stock market is at an "all-time high".
Watch the 'real news' below:

Want to know what President Trump did this week? Watch here for REAL news!
Posted by  on 2017年7月30日
She also declared that the US unemployment rate had dropped to its lowest point since 2001, and claimed almost 800,000 jobs had been created since Mr Trump took office in January.
"The President also met with some incredible veterans this week in Ohio, giving his thanks to them for their service to our country. Likewise, the Vice-President visited Walter Reed hospital, where he sat down and talked to so many wounded soldiers who have put their lives on the line for all of us," she added.
However, a simple Google search shows media outlets did cover the stories. The topics of , Mr Trump's ,  highs, and the announcement of a new  in Wisconsin, were well reported.
A report from  debunked some of the statements, noting that neither Mr Trump nor any other president could take full credit for the increasing employment rate.
It wrote unemployment has been in steady decline since the end of the recession in 2009.
Meanwhile, Ms Trump's news update failed to mention factual stories that have dominated the news this past week.
The Republicans' failure to repeal and replace , the President's decision to  from serving in the military, and the  which led to the departures of chief of staff Reince Priebus, press secretary Sean Spicer and communications director Anthony Scaramucci, were left out.
Ms Trump promises to provide "a glimpse" of the President's activities each week.
"Thanks for joining us, everybody. I'm Lara Trump, and that is the real news," she signed off.
The video is something of an official debut for Ms Trump, who joins family members Ivanka, her husband Jared Kushner, Donald Jr and Lara's husband Eric, in visible roles in the administration.
Ms Trump has previously done work for the Women for Trump coalition, as a producer for CBS show Inside Edition, and "helped" on Mr Trump's 2016 political bid,  reported.
In March this year she was officially hired as a new senior consultant to Mr Trump's 2020 campaign.
Mr Trump continued his claim on Tuesday he doesn't need the mainstream media given his reach on social media.
Only the Fake News Media and Trump enemies want me to stop using Social Media (110 million people). Only way for me to get the truth out!
- Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Media (110</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Reed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OHIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Trump's 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Trump's 2020</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wisconsin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inside Edition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald J. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>realDonaldTrump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
