<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419662827355020</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/2017/08/03/jane-bunns-run-mount-buller/</url>
  <title>Mount Buller staff say Jane Bunn's ski run is 'ridiculous'</title>
  <content>
Channel Seven presenter and meteorologist Jane Bunn's new ski run is a "ridiculous" attempt to attract media attention to Mount Buller, say bemused ski resort staff.
The weather presenter and avid skier officially opened 'Bunn Run' with Olympic aerial ski champion Jacqui Cooper on Friday last week after predicting about 10 centimetres of fresh snowfall.
"It's quite amazing to have a ski run named after me. I never thought anything like this would ever happen," Bunn said in a Mount Buller statement.
A Mount Buller staff member and long-term Mansfield resident told The New Daily staff at the ski resort and the wider skiing community shared in Bunn's surprise.
The staff member, who asked to remain anonymous, said the honour was an attempt to "suck up" to Bunn, who regularly does live-cross snow reports for Channel 7.
They said the skiing community was not impressed given the resort is supported by more "deserving and dedicated volunteers that work on the mountain for nothing".
"It seems very unfair she [Jane Bunn], gets recognition in that respect," they said, adding colleagues had called the Bunn Run name "ridiculous".
Bunn has a loyal fan base after making her start on country broadcaster WIN News.
Her Facebook fan group, the Jane Bunn Fan Club, has 20,000 followers.
Mount Buller spokesperson Rhylla Morgan said the ski resort and Channel 7 had a close working relationship, with the resort sending snow reports to the broadcaster and Bunn regularly presenting live broadcasts from its slopes.
She also did a radio snow report with Melbourne station 3AW during her recent visit to Mount Buller.
"Jane is a keen skier and this visit was perfect timing, allowing her to get out of the snow before rushing back to Melbourne later today to deliver her weather forecast from the studio," Morgan said.
The spokeswoman acknowledged most chairlift names at the ski resort were either descriptive or told the story of a local legend.
Morgan said this included the Grimus chairlift named after local Hans Grimus, who built many of Mount Buller's chair lifts.
The Lydia Lassila chairlift at the resort is named after the Australian Olympic freestyle skier gold medallist who competed in the 2002 Winter Olympic Games.
"You don't get a ski run named after you every day," Morgan said.
A Seven spokesperson told The New Daily Bunn's Run was not sponsored by Seven, but rather Mount Buller's attempt to "honour" Bunn for her "longstanding relationship with Buller and the alpine region".
"Her fascination with snow was actually what got her into weather," the spokesperson explained.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Buller</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mansfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hans Grimus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lydia Lassila</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhylla Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunn Run</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Bunn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grimus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winter Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Bunn Fan Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Daily Bunn's Run</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunn</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
