<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419916230431225</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4832517/blacktown-mp-john-robertson-to-retire-from-parliament/?cs=4219</url>
  <title>Blacktown MP John Robertson to retire from parliament</title>
  <content>
Blacktown MP John Robertson today announced he will retire from state parliament at the end of August. Picture: Isabella Lettini

Almost nine years after he entered the NSW Parliament, former Labor leader and union boss John Robertson will quit politics at the end of the month.
Mr Robertson has accepted a job as executive general manager at the not-for-profit organisation Foodbank, which acts as a conduit between the retail industry and charities to distribute food to the needy.
"I'm going to work in a bank, but unlike Mike Baird people like this bank," Mr Robertson quipped, in reference to the  after leaving politics in January.
Mr Robertson's decision to resign from parliament on August 25 will spark a second byelection in coming months after  at the end of the month.
Mr Robertson's seat of Blacktown is safe Labor, held on a margin of 13.2 per cent.
Mr Robertson, who has volunteered at Foodbank since 2011, said it was "an honour and a privilege" to have served the people of Blacktown.

"Hunger in Australia has reached crisis point, with one in six people experiencing food insecurity in the last 12 months," he said.
"I look forward to joining the great team of people at Foodbank NSW & ACT, an organisation that has values consistent with mine, and that is changing lives by providing food to those most in need."
Opposition Leader Luke Foley said Labor "owes John a huge debt of gratitude for assuming the leadership at perhaps the lowest point in our history, immediately after the 2011 election".
"John's courage, tenacity and hard work rebuilt NSW Labor from the ashes of our 2011 electoral defeat," he said.

John Robertson stepped into the ring on March 31 this year to raise money for Blacktown PCYC, an organisation he has vocally supported. Picture: Geoff Jones
"As I said on the night of the 2015 election, the winning of 14 seats back off the Liberals was due in a very large part to the work of John Robertson in his period of leadership."
A former electrician, Mr Robertson came to public prominence as secretary of Unions NSW.
In that role he campaigned against then prime minister John Howard's WorkChoices industrial relations legislation before the 2007 federal election and opposed the Iemma Labor government's push to privatise electricity assets.
He entered the NSW Upper House in October 2008 and served as a minister in the Rees and Keneally governments.
After Labor's 2011 NSW election defeat - at which he won the seat of Blacktown -  and set about rebuilding a devastated parliamentary party.

John Robertson in 2013. Picture: Steven Siewert
But  after it emerged he had years earlier signed a constituent's letter for Man Haron Monis whose December 2014 siege at the Lindt cafe in Martin Place left two hostages dead.
"I would never have dreamed as a 19-year-old apprentice electrician working on the extension to the NSW Parliament in 1981 that I would have these opportunities and achieve what I have," Mr Robertson said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabella Lettini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Siewert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Luke Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Robertson</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man Haron Monis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown MP John Robertson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Upper House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown PCYC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's 2011 NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Parliament</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard's WorkChoices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unions NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foodbank NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keneally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Robertson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iemma Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
