<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419276280290388</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/teams/geelong/tom-lonergan-applauds-patrick-dangerfield-for-brownlow-medal-sacrifice/news-story/85d038b982de1908fff3234e5e396af4</url>
  <title>Danger applauded for Brownlow sacrifice</title>
  <content>
TOM Lonergan says Patrick Dangerfield's decision to sacrifice his Brownlow aspirations for team success this week was an inspiration to the Geelong players.
And the premiership defender has urged .
, who was concussed after his arms were pinned as he crashed into the ground.
GAME 274:
FIRST CLASS:
AFL chief executive Gillon McLachlan told the Herald Sun the league was steadfast in keeping the current Brownlow eligibility.
The league has no plans to tinker with the discount formula used by the match review panel and allow more clubs to test contentious cases at the tribunal.
Lonergan, considered more likely to retire but happy to wait until the post-season to discuss his future, said Dangerfield's decision was typical of his selfless attitude.
"It shows a lot about his character. I sat down and had a coffee with him before the decision came out and he said 'I am not really worried about the Brownlow, I just want to do what's best for the team','' Lonergan said.
"Obviously, missing two weeks would have really hurt us; we have got a tough game against Richmond the week after.
"That is the type of person we want at our footy club. He is a fantastic leader and person around the footy club and the guys will look at that and say, there are sacrifices you sometimes have to make."
Lonergan said Dangerfield had no need to draw back from his long list of media -appearances.
"I reckon he's great for the game and the more people we can have like that the better," Lonergan said.
"He is incredible how much he can take on and still be able to get out on to the footy field and just get on with the game.
"He is a unique individual and an ultimate professional.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillon McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Lonergan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonergan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
