<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419186085975221</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4832163/celebrating-a-century/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Celebrating a century</title>
  <content>
FRANCES Jones has lived 100 years according to her motto, "there's nothing I can't do".

All smiles: Westfield Kotara staff surprised Frances Jones at her Thursday breakfast with friends with a cake in her favourite colour and flowers. Pictures: Jonathan Carroll
Mrs Jones, who becomes a centenarian on Friday, has never shied away from a challenge, from seeking work at 14 to help her family; to becoming secretary for department store founder David Jones' grandson; compering fashion parades; delivering speeches to university students and living independently from 80.

"I've always been on the move so I don't feel old," said Mrs Jones, a mother to three, grandmother to 11 and great grandmother to 12. "I'm not overexcited about it, but am thankful for all the things that have happened to date. I never think about age, it's only a number. I enjoy life and talking to all people - what extra do I need?"
Mrs Jones was born Frances McDermott on August 4, 1917, in Thorn Street Newcastle and was one of seven children. She was only 14 and a half when she answered an advertisement seeking 18 to 23 year olds to work at David Jones owned shoe shop, Sally Smart. "I couldn't sell, but I did all the bookwork for about five shillings a week, working from 7am to about 6.30pm."
The shop closed after about nine months and she received a letter and cheque, asking her to go to Sydney.
"They realised I had no father [he died when she was about 12 from tongue cancer] and a big family and so they interviewed me and asked if I was able to leave home. I had an aunt in Rose Bay and spoke to her."
Mrs Jones worked for the company from the ages of 15 to 29, including three years as chairman Charles Lloyd Jones' personal secretary.
"He came up three times to see if he was going to take over Scott's on Hunter Street [which he did in 1957]," she said. "I always got in trouble for being too lively. I had high heels, short skirts with a split up the side. You have to be jovial and look at the light side of life. Plus I eat healthily, with lots of homegrown vegetables." Mrs Jones married Robert 'Len' Jones and they relocated to the Hunter to start their family. She then worked as a buyer at Johns Silk Store for 10 years, which involved travelling interstate and doing a 12 month public speaking course to compere fashion parades.

Mrs Jones' friends held a breakfast at Westfield Kotara and a lunch at Crowne Plaza on Thursday in her honour. She will celebrate with her family on Saturday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield Kotara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frances McDermott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Lloyd Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FRANCES Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johns Silk Store</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thorn Street Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Jones</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crowne Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Len' Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Smart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
