<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418752294270172</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/laurie-oakes-said-one-word-and-i-tumbled-out-of-the-hammock-20170803-gxosub.html</url>
  <title>Laurie Oakes said one word and I tumbled out of the hammock</title>
  <content>
Early March, 2003. A sunny weekend afternoon. A hammock rocking you gently to sleep. As you drift off, forgetting the worries of the week, the phone rings. An unmistakeable gruff voice is on the other end.
"Oakes," is all he says by way of introduction.

Up Next

Charges to be laid over Sydney terrorist plane plot

01:17

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Laurie Oakes announces retirement

Bringing to an end a 50-year career, an "absolute giant" of journalism, Laurie Oakes, announces his retirement. Video courtesy Nine News.

You - editor in chief of The Bulletin magazine - tumble out of the hammock and snap straight to attention, like a soldier when the sergeant arrives in the mess hall for an unannounced inspection.
"I've got a cover story for you. It's not bad. But you might want to let the lawyers know."

The best political journalist the nation has ever seen has just snagged another one. Andrew Wilkie, a senior intelligence officer with the top secret Office of National Assessments, has decided to quit and go public with his concerns about the Howard government's pro-war policy on Iraq and his doubts that Saddam Hussein has orchestrated a program involving weapons of mass destruction.
It's a difficult story to tell. Secrecy is required lest the government tries to seek a last-minute injunction preventing publication. Over the next 48 hours the lawyers argue back and forth over what can and cannot be published. You brief Oakes about their concerns and you can hear his eyes rolling over the sound of a deep sigh.

But when he files his copy any concerns disappear. As always there is never a word out of place. Everything is in context. Not even the gaggle of nervous lawyers complain. No matter the medium - print, television or radio - Laurie Oakes delivers the story. Straight. Without embellishment. Without even a hint of a clue to the reader as to what he thinks.
And now he's decided to depart the stage after a career spanning half a century, tugging back the curtains and showing Australians how power really works - and why so often it doesn't. He became a fixture on our television screens, those head to head interviews compelling viewing as that unrelenting stare of his peeled back layers and layers of spin and lies, reducing even the land's most experienced and hardened political operatives to jelly.Photo: Andrew Meares
Such was his reputation that Oakes was as intimidating to editors as he was to seasoned frontbenchers. Small talk was never his forte. A few years after the Wilkie exclusive, I flew to Canberra as the new head of news and current affairs for the Nine Network. Laurie was bristling. The network was in a mess and he'd started wondering if it was time to go. Other networks, as usual, were circling. If he went, I figured I would forever be remembered as the man who lost Laurie Oakes.
He suffered fools with the same patience he reserved for politicians who dared mislead him. So I braced myself for a withering barrage of criticism over lunch. But as always he was polite. A good listener. After several wines, I became conscious that I'd done the majority of the talking and that Oakes was doing to me what he had done to so many others, subtly extracting information, putting the pieces together. He ended up staying on but I soon concluded that, had he not pursued journalism, he'd have made a good dentist. Your tooth would have been out before your mouth was open.Photo: Peter Morris
What made Laurie Oakes so good? He learned his craft in the 1960s on Melbourne's The Sun News-Pictorial, where story telling and an ear for what people wanted to read became ingrained in his approach. No one knew how he voted or what he thought. Other political reporters watched enviously as his phone rang from all sides of politics. He was trusted.
Back then it was all about breaking stories, a different and much simpler world to the modern day Babble-On where political pundits vie to get their heads on television, where political coverage has largely been reduced to a series of meaningless, petty squabbles. You wonder what he really thinks of it all and imagine the sound of eyes rolling over a large sigh.
Isaac Newton said that if he had managed to see further than most, it was because he was standing on the shoulders of giants. Well, one of the few giants of politics and journalism in this country has just left the room. Pass the binoculars because without Laurie Oakes our ability to see what really goes on is sadly diminished.
Garry Linnell is a Fairfax Media columnist and co-presenter of The Breakfast Show on Talking Lifestyle.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talking Lifestyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilkie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Babble-On</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Wilkie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac Newton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2003</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saddam Hussein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakes</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun News-Pictorial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breakfast Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Linnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
