<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419748726702821</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/chix-picks-former-deutsche-banker-as-ceo-20170803-gxoqc4</url>
  <title>Chi-X picks former Deutsche banker as CEO</title>
  <content>
Former Deutsche Bank executive Vic Jokovic has been name as the new chief executive of ASX rival Chi-X, four months after the sudden departure of John Fiddes.
Mr Jokovic,  in February, was co-head of Deutsche's powerful markets business when he left the bank, having previously run debt and equity sales and cash equities and derivatives for Australia, and served on various executive committees.
The veteran broker was appointed after a global search conducted by Korn Ferry.
Former Westpac chief executive David Morgan, who is now chairman of Chi-X Australia, describe Mr Jokovic as a "high- performing and inspirational capital markets executive, with more than 30 years of experience across equity, derivative and debt markets".

"He is a proven leader with the skills, depth of knowledge and personal attributes to lead Chi-X through the next phase of growth."

Mr Morgan is chairman at JC Flowers Europe and Asia Pacific, which acquired Chi-X Australia, Chi-X Japan and Chi-X Hong Kong in early 2016.
Mr Fiddes resigned from Chi-X Australia in April after four years at the helm of the business. Chi-X had experienced rapid growth during the period, building its share of the equities trading market to about 20 per cent, including on-market and off-market trades. The exchange now regularly handles more than $1 billon worth of trading activity.
Mr Jokovic said he was "delighted to be joining Chi-X as it plays an increasingly important role in the development and growth of Australian capital and investment markets".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korn Ferry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Fiddes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JC Flowers Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chi-X</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chi-X Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic Jokovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jokovic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fiddes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chi-X Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chi-X Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
