<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419186085975173</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/california-using-innovation-and-renewables-to-tackle-climate-change-20170802-gxnnif</url>
  <title>California's energy experiment</title>
  <content>
Californian-based Australian-born clean-tech start-up executive Danny Kennedy can only look in wonder at the energy debate happening in his home country.
While Australia is still stuck at an impasse over renewables versus fossil fuels in its escalating energy crisis, California - which made the decision decades ago to move away from coal and gas - is showing the world how it can be done.
The debate over whether renewables such as wind, solar or battery storage can help transform the electricity grid is over in California - the world's six largest economy - and a range of innovative companies are showing governments and utilities how to achieve ambitious clean energy targets to reduce carbon emissions.
"In California the political debate is along the lines of is 80 per cent renewables the answer or is it 100 per cent renewables - does it work or doesn't it," Mr Kennedy told The Australian Financial Review.

"There is no gnashing of the teeth in Parliament here. This works and we've got 300,000 jobs out of it. If you want an analogy, it's like Australia is still talking about the telegraph and California is building the internet."

Mr Kennedy, who is managing director of the California Clean Energy Fund, a nonprofit organisation which helps clean-tech start-ups get off the ground, said California's innovation culture-- which created Silicon Valley in the 1980s and spawned the tech giants of Apple, Facebook and Microsoft - was now being turned to clean energy.
Increase the target

"Rather than saying this is not going to work, here in California they see that as an opportunity for entrepreneurs to solve the problem," he said.
California has about 26 per cent renewables and is aiming to have 50 per cent by 2030. It is also considering legislating to increase the target to 100 per cent by 2045. If it does choose the higher target of 100 per cent, it will lock in a new target of 60 per cent renewables by 2030.

, California - which has long been a leader when it comes to environmental standards - has decided to go it alone.
If anything the decision by President Trump has emboldened Governor Jerry Brown to push ahead with their ambitious plans to help integrate renewables into the grid and assist with the roll-out of 1 million electric vehicles in California by 2020 to help cut transport emissions in the car-loving state.
Last week, Governor Brown signed into law an extension of the state's cap and trade program for curbing greenhouse gases, ensuring the program will keep running through 2030.
Like a lot of states in the US, gas is the dominant fuel source in California, making up 37 per cent of the state's electricity generation. Renewables are the second biggest fuel source on 26 per cent. This includes wind (9 per cent), solar (8 per cent), geothermal (2 per cent), biomass (2 per cent) and small-scale hydro (2 per cent).

Large-scale hydro (10 per cent) is not considered as part of the renewables mix in California - even though it is not a fossil fuel generation - which would take the state's renewable factor even higher. Nuclear makes up 9 per cent of the state's energy mix, while coal is only 4 per cent. Another 14 per cent is imported from other states.
Driving force

The Californian Energy Commission (CEC) is the driving force which helps the state government formulate policies to achieve its climate policy goals.
CEC commissioner Karen Douglas said the state was on target to reach its 50 per cent goal and was now looking at setting the next big target of 100 per cent renewables before the middle of the century.

She said the key to California's ability to meet the targets was a diversity of renewable options and technological innovation by companies helping to find new ways of taking pressure off the grid.
"What helps us is bringing a diversity of renewable energy resources into our system. It's not just wind and solar but we have the largest geothermal facility in the United States here," Ms Douglas said.
"One of the ways we deal with intermittency - for when the sun is not shining and the wind is not blowing - is technological diversity and geographic diversity. We are working actively with other western states and regional approaches to mitigate against intermittency to help us create a lot more robust system."
The natural gas disaster at the Aliso Canyon storage facility in 2015 - which resulted in the worst gas leak in US history - also fast-tracked the roll-out of battery storage to step into the breach.

California responded with a record roll-out of 100 megawatts of battery storage in six months, driven by companies such as General Electric,Tesla and AES Energy. This has fast-tracked the ability of utilities to work out how battery storage can be used to not only step in to help with peak demand on the grid on the hottest days of the year or cover if there's an outage somewhere else on the grid, but also provide frequency and inertia services for the energy grid which have been traditionally been provided by synchronous generation.
Quick response

One of those quick response projects was GE/Southern California Edison peaker plant in Norwalk, Los Angeles, which is the world's first natural gas/electricity hybrid peaker plant.
Traditionally, gas peaker plants are running on standby waiting to receive a call-up by the grid operators to kickstart into action. By attaching a GE 10-megawatt battery storage system, combined with the 50-megawatt gas turbine, it allows the peaker plant to respond to changing energy needs instantly. Traditionally peaker plants took 15 minutes to 30 minutes to ramp up and energy was wasted by having them running on standby.
"Peaker plants are responsible for the reliability of the grid. This allowed us to get the best of the gas turbine and battery storage. It's like a Prius or an electric vehicle when it takes off at a stop light. Why have that engine running when at the stop light?" said a GE Energy Storage product manager Joe Heinzmann.
Facilities such as the Los Angeles Cleantech Incubator - which has helped companies raise $US135 million ($170 million) in funding - are driving the innovation push. They take a 2 to 5 per cent equity stake in companies but help provide support with "executives in residence" to take ideas to commercial deployment.
Other innovators already in action include San Francisco-based Advanced Microgrid Solution (AMS) which has developed an energy analytics program which when combined with battery storage is allowing companies to shave a significant proportion off their electricity bill while also allowing energy utilities to take the edge off the afternoon peak demand on the grid.
"Renewable energy coming on to the grid has created havoc for utilities," said Advanced Microgrid Solutions president Kelly Warner. "This is a way for them to become part of the solution. Ultimately we don't see moving off the grid as realistic, but this is scalable and bankable."

Hybrid-electric buildings fitted with utility-scale battery storage can be linked and used as a virtual power grid, with a recent project by utility Southern California Edison helping fill a hole left in the grid by a decommissioned nuclear power plant.
The distributed energy system is seen as one of the key ways to move away from a centralised power grid. The battery is charged at night when prices are low and then distributed during the afternoon when the utility wants to take pressure off the grid. Host companies, such as Walmart, can save up to $500,000 on their annual power bills, while utilities don't have to build extra capacity into the network.
The company's first major project, a $200 million project funded by Macquarie Bank - using a 90 megawatt (360 megawatt hour capacity) battery - is to help Southern California Edison deal with grid-constrained pockets in west LA.
Mr Warner said not all energy utilities were getting on board with distributed energy systems and demand-side responses, but the smart ones were realising this was the future of the grid.
Electric vehicles

Another saviour for utilities is the rapid uptake of electric vehicles. There are already 300,000 in California from 20 different manufacturers - but .
California is aiming for 1 million vehicles by 2025 and 5 million by 2030. Utilities will benefit from households and businesses plugging into the grid to charge up their vehicles.
Southern California Edison senior vice-president of regulatory affairs Caroline Choi said the influx of renewable energy, especially from solar, was putting a lot more capacity into the system - or "fattening the duck" as its known in California, when looking at the daily energy usage curve - so electric vehicles would allow people to charge up during the day when there is excess power.

"We want to encourage people to charge their electric vehicles during the day so we can skinny the duck," she said.
Mr Kennedy said the most difficult part for California on its path to be a zero-emissions state is when they move closer to the 100 per cent renewable energy target and keeping up grid stability.
"The real challenge here for California is when they are on the final stretch with 70 per cent, 80 per cent up to 100 per cent. That's when you need new innovations," he said.
"It's like the glass half full rather than half empty. And certain people in Australia take the view that we just have to do what we did before because it's too hard."
The reporter travelled to California with the assistance of The Climate Council.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$135</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Climate Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kennedy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NORWALK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>20</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Jerry Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California Clean Energy Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco-based Advanced Microgrid Solution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GE/Southern California Edison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern California Edison</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian-based Australian-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GE Energy Storage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walmart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AES Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aliso Canyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Choi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Electric</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Cleantech Incubator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Heinzmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advanced Microgrid Solutions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian Energy Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
