<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418726524465826</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/jean-claude-perrottet-stopped-when-the-woman-asked-him-to-rape-trial-hears-20170803-gxof8f.html</url>
  <title>Jean Claude Perrottet stopped when the woman asked him to, rape trial hears</title>
  <content>
A couple stood kissing in the final bedraggled hour of the 2015 St Johns College ball before he uttered the words: "Let's go somewhere more private."
Many revellers had already peeled off to the "after-after" party at the Alfred Hotel, also known as The Gross.Photo: Facebook/@RedfieldOldBoysRugby
Jean Claude Perrottet, 20, had been twice kicked out of the party only to run in again from another entrance, and now he had come across this woman on the dance floor, a 19-year-old resident of the college to which he had been invited as a guest.
"I didn't really feel too comfortable standing in a very public place and I was under the impression that there would be further interaction," Mr Perrottet told the NSW District Court on Thursday of his suggestion to the woman.

There is no dispute that further interaction took place.
Mr Perrottet, the younger brother of the NSW Treasurer Dominic Perrottet, has pleaded not guilty to three counts of sexual assault.

But he says that two of the acts were consensual and one did not occur, and that he does not believe in sex before marriage.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

He later told police there was no way they had sexual intercourse. "It's against my religion," he said.
The pair made their way across the quadrangle, and he recalled her asking where they were going and himself making a humorous retort about it being her college and he did not know where he was, until they arrived at a tree canopy.
He "plonked" to the ground and she asked if he was OK, and then they began to kiss on the ground, gradually becoming more intimate.
At one point, while she continued to engage in the activity, he dozed off, he said. But he woke after a few moments, sat up and began where he left off.
He said at no point during this period did he force her to do anything and neither did she object to anything that was occurring, but then suddenly she sat up and said: "I can't do that."
He demurred that he did not want to have sex with her, they began to kiss again and he attempted to pull down her underwear, but she again objected, straightened her dress and stood up.
The court heard last week that the woman later told police the pair had had sex, while she asked him repeatedly to stop.
"He kept trying to have sex with me and I was like, 'That really hurts. Stop it'," she said.
But Mr Perrottet said when she raised objections he walked her back to her room.
They stopped briefly to kiss in a photo booth, but she then led him out of the booth and they continued to her room, he said.
When they arrived, she opened the door and stood to one side.
"I took that as an invitation to walk in," he said.
But it was clear to him by this time that she was distressed, and though he only wanted to chat and explain to her that he was not trying to have sex with her, all she would say was that she did not want to do that again and walked out of her room.
A friend asked him to leave, and he did.
Mr Perrottet said he spent that night on the floor of his friend's college room before leaving hung-over the next morning.
He exchanged text messages with his friend the next day in which she ribbed him for an unspecified piece of bad luck.
"LOL. Proves you dream about what you are thinking about," she messaged.
He replied: "Haha yeah. It's the same dream every time. Shows how sour I am that I have the same reacquiring [sic] dream."
Mr Perrottet said this exchange referred to him missing out on getting into Princeton University.
But under cross-examination he agreed he did not have a complete memory of the night; for example, he did not remember how he sustained a bump on the head.
The next day he sent a message to another friend confessing the only thing he could remember was "having an argument about politics with a leftie".
The trial continues.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Perrottet</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gross.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Treasurer Dominic Perrottet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean-Claude Perrottet, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princeton University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean Claude Perrottet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RedfieldOldBoysRugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
