<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419448078985471</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/brisbane-bus-drivers-to-refuse-fares-over-workplace-agreement-deadlock/news-story/fa024e54172d0ab117cd978a12d772dc</url>
  <title>More free travel as dispute rolls on</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE bus drivers will once again refuse to collect fares for an entire day as negotiations between union officials and the council over a new workplace agreement remain stalled.
Commuters will be able to travel for free on Friday, August 4, after the Rail Tram and Bus Union announced a "free fare day" on all Brisbane buses.
Union secretary Tom Brown said their fight would continue until members are "given a fair go" which can't happen until the Brisbane City Council Lord Mayor "starts listening to his workers".
"Only then can we sit down and negotiate an agreement that's fair to both parties and finally end this dispute," he said.
A spokesperson for TransLink confirmed industrial action would occur on "some" BCC bus services on Friday.

NSW's first trial of a driverless shuttle bus will begin later this month. An automated 'Smart Shuttle' will operate at Sydney Olympic Park

NSW's first trial of a driverless shuttle bus will begin soon
"All services will run as normal, however some drivers may not be collecting fares or wearing their normal uniforms.
"Only BCC bus services will be involved - this includes most routes between 29 and 599."
School services will not be affected.
TransLink has provided a full list of services involved here:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smart Shuttle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rail Tram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TransLink</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
