<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419357884670524</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/health/2017/08/03/18/50/healthcare-watchdog-warns-of-antibiotic-overuse-in-australia</url>
  <title>Healthcare watchdog warns of antibiotic overuse in Australia</title>
  <content>
Australia's healthcare safety watchdog has issued a warning about the overuse of antibiotics in the community.
A new report from the Australian Commission of Safety and Quality in Health Care found an antibiotic resistant superbug, Staphylococcus aureus, that causes bloodstream infections, is now more commonly caught in the community rather than hospitals.
This has raised concerns about its spread.
The latest figures show almost half of the Australian population were prescribed antibiotics once in a given year.
Only 23.5% of patients prescribed antibiotics had the reason recorded on their health record .
Of these people, around 60% were reported to have colds or upper respiratory tract infections, which antibiotics are not generally recommended.
The commission's Senior Medical Advisor Professor John Turnidge said antimicrobial resistance was "one of the most significant challenges for the delivery of safe, high-quality health services, and has a direct impact on patient care and patient outcomes." 

Related Articles

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Commission of Safety</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senior Medical Advisor Professor John Turnidge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health-care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staphylococcus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
