<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418967042638991</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/cricket-pay-deal-lauded-womens-pay/8772186</url>
  <title>Cricket pay deal huge for women as Australia's female cricketers get massive windfall</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

The pay dispute dividing Australian cricket is finally over, and this summer's Ashes series has been saved, but the new deal over cricketers' pay marks a historic boost to the women's game.
The pay deal reached between Cricket Australia (CA) and the Australian Cricketers' Association (ACA), following months of bitter negotiations, will apply to all male and female players for the first time in Australian cricket.
The deal is being lauded as the biggest pay rise in the history of women's sport in the country.
Female player payments will increase from $7.5 million to $55.2 million.
"[It's] a gender equity pay model, with the biggest pay rise in the history of women's sport in Australia," ACA chief executive Alistair Nicholson said.
In a modernised revenue-sharing formula, CA forecasts a player payments pool of $459 million, which covers all male and female players.
Furthermore, a performance pool will continue for male players while being extended to include the Australian women's team.

"The ACA is delighted for the men and women who play the game now and in the future," ACA president Greg Dyer said in a statement.
"And for the game of cricket which will continue to benefit from the partnership model which has served cricket so well.
"One MOU for men and women, the maintenance of the partnership model, and record investments for grassroots cricket is what we wanted and it's what has been achieved.
"The men and women have been rewarded for sticking together and for having the courage of their convictions. They have made history and created a legacy for generations of players to come."

The pay deal's key features:

Player Payments Pool (PPP)
(all male and female player payments and programs apart from Performance Pool)

A modernised revenue sharing formula achieved by developing a PPP to a dollar value based on external market benchmarks, internal equity and financial viability, and forecast cricket revenues
PPP of $459m (would be the equivalent of 27.5 per cent assuming Australian Cricket Revenue [ACR] of $1.67bn)
Includes player development program increased from $7 million to $14 million
Performance Pool (PP)

Continues for the Australian men's team on similar terms to the last MOU and extended to include the Australian women's team.
Female player payments

Female player payments will increase from $7.5 million to $55.2 million
Adjustment ledger

If ACR exceeds $1.67bn, players receive 19 per cent of the upside to $1.96 billion ACR and grassroots cricket receives 8.5 per cent. Above $1.96 billion, male and female players receive 27.5 per cent
Additional grassroots funding

Up to $30m that would otherwise have gone to the PPP under the old model.

Nicholson said the resolved dispute sees male and female players engaged as partners in the game.
"To have retained the revenue-sharing model and increased the level we have and ensure that men, women, domestic and international players receive a fair share is great news for the players and for the game," he said in a statement.
"It's right that all players, men and women will be partners in the game because that's a fair outcome. It ensures a game with all parties pulling in the same direction.

"I pay tribute to all of the players for their resolve. Enduring uncertainty and unemployment has been very difficult. They are terrific young men and women who have been rewarded for their determination.
"I especially congratulate Steve Smith, David Warner, Meg Lanning, Alex Blackwell and all ACA delegates for their outstanding leadership. They led the players in this process and prevailed."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Dyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Payments Pool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Performance Pool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Blackwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg Lanning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricket Revenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
