<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419233330616521</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/kew-clifton-hill-and-abbotsford-houses-set-for-auction/news-story/1a422d348aba95dbc8ba734bc6c6f9fc</url>
  <title>Kew, Clifton Hill and Abbotsford houses set for auction - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
36 Rutland St, Clifton Hill. For Herald Sun Realestate 05AUG17

LIVING in the inner city is a dream of many Melburnians.
If what you are looking for is trendy home in the inner northeast one of these properties could be the perfect proposition.
Take a look for yourself.

88 Little Charles St, Abbotsford.

WITH 4.2m ceilings and full-height windows, this inner northeast townhouse is light and airy.
It features an open-plan living area, with polished concrete floors and sliding doors that lead to a decked courtyard with garden beds.
The kitchen has a gas cooktop, overhead cupboards and a dishwasher.

88 Little Charles St, Abbotsford.

Both bedrooms have built-in wardrobes and ensuites, one with a bathtub and a separate entry.
Heating and cooling, a European laundry and a storage cage are also included.
It is close to the Yarra River and public transport.
The townhouse, which has a $700,000 to $770,000 price guide, is set to go under the hammer at 1pm, August 19.
The sale is being handled by Andrew Crotty, of Biggin & Scott, Richmond.

36 Rutland St, Clifton Hill.

ENJOY entertaining on the rooftop of this renovated Victorian terrace.
The kitchen has an integrated fridge, a dishwasher, walk-in pantry and wide freestanding combined oven and gas cooktop.
It flows through to the dining and living area and out to a grassed courtyard.
An external staircase leads up to the decked rooftop terrace, with built-in seating and privacy screens.

36 Rutland St, Clifton Hill.

Both bedrooms have wardrobes, and the main has access to a courtyard and the bathroom. Polished concrete floors and rear access are included.
Collins Simms, Inner City's Nicholas Corby has price hopes of $1.05-$1.55 million for the property.
It is heading under the hammer at 10.30am, August 19.

30 Stirling St, Kew.

SET on 372sq m, this single-fronted Edwardian features a decked outdoor entertainment area and landscaped gardens.
The galley-style kitchen connects the dining area with an open fireplace to the living area.
A gas cooktop, tiled splashback and plenty of storage are features of the kitchen.
All bedrooms have high ceilings, and there are open fireplaces and built-in wardrobes in the front two.

30 Stirling St, Kew.

Other features include Baltic pine floorboards, ducted heating, evaporative cooling and a double carport via rear of way access.
Campbell Ward, of Jellis Craig, Glen Iris, has listed the property for auction at 11am, August 19.
The property has price expectations in the $1.9-$2.05 million range.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun Realestate 05AUG17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rutland St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kew</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins Simms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Iris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwardian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifton Hill</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Charles St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Ward, of Jellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Crotty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbotsford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melburnians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inner City's Nicholas Corby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
