<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418971337606325</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4831640/academy-boosts-blakes-tokyo-dream/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Academy boosts Blake's Tokyo dream</title>
  <content>
EYES ON TOKYO: Long-jumper Blake Carr is training to represent Australia at the 2020 Paralympics, and says the Hunter Academy of Sport has improved his diet, training and chances of qualifying. Picture: Darren Pateman

TWO years ago, Blake Carr was a promising young athlete who trained half the week and had a soft spot for dairy snacks.

He also lives with autism spectrum disorder. Now, the sprinter, discus-thrower and long-jumper from Gateshead, 22, trains with the Hunter Academy of Sport six days a week and has an eye on the Tokyo Paralympics.

Mr Carr now eats fewer snacks, and represents his state and country.
"It used to be a lot of cheese, chocolate milk. Now it's salads and six days' training a week," he said.
"Tokyo 2020 is my dream. Long jump seems to be my best option in my classification."
Mr Carr and the athletes he competes against aren't physically impaired, pushing their results closer to those of Olympic athletes. But it was only through the academy, he said, that he registered as an athlete with a disability.
Nominations for the academy's Athletes with Disabilities program, for people with autism, hearing and vision impairments, intellectual and physical disabilities, close on Sunday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Pateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateshead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paralympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo Paralympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake's Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo 2020</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long-jumper Blake Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Academy of Sport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Carr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
