<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419701482061637</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/70-patients-to-be-moved-to-country-sa-for-old-rah-ramp-down/news-story/9fd141f8bf9ff7138838543a898d1b17</url>
  <title>Fears over mass patient transfer</title>
  <content>
AT least 70 patients will be moved to South Australian country hospitals over coming weeks to facilitate the Royal Adelaide Hospital ramp down - a transfer doctors regard as potentially dangerous.
The Advertiser understands the patients would be transferred by ambulance, where necessary, to sites in Murray Bridge, Mt Barker, Tanunda, Strathalbyn, Gumeracha and Victor Harbor.
South Australian Salaried Medical Officers Association spokesman Dr David Pope has expressed concern over the numbers, saying if a member of his own family was sick, he would not want them moved to a country hospital.
"I would make very sure they were in a major centre with the right specialty staff until it was safe and appropriate to go home," he said.
"You don't have the specialist staff and the specialist staff who have the recent experience in managing these conditions.
"To ask that of a doctor who hasn't worked in a (major) hospital for a long period of time ... that puts the doctor in a difficult situation."
An SA Health spokeswoman said participating peri urban hospitals within half an hour of Adelaide had the capacity to take up to 70 additional patients over the three-week ramp-down period.
She said the department was "contracting private hospital beds, if they are required".
Central Adelaide Local Health Network director of surgery Professor Guy Maddern said, at the time, that "the care (the patients) will receive will be exactly the same as what they received at the old Royal Adelaide".
"There is the capacity and there are ratios that have to be applied to the number of patients," he said.
Health Minister Jack Snelling said: "This (the new RAH move) is the biggest exercise that the state has ever undertaken ... we have to make sure patient safety remains paramount."

The new RAH is at technical completion stage - here's what it looks like inside

Go inside the new Royal Adelaide Hospital
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Jack Snelling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr David Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Adelaide Local Health Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumeracha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Guy Maddern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanunda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathalbyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Harbor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Salaried Medical Officers Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
