<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419873280757453</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832513/victorias-secret-glitter-iphone-cases-recalled-after-causing-chemical-burns/?cs=7</url>
  <title>Victoria's Secret glitter iPhone cases recalled after causing chemical burns</title>
  <content>
About 275,000 sparkly iPhone cases have been recalled after users sustained burns and blisters by fluid leaking from cracks in the coverings.

These Victoria's Secret phone cases have been recalled.

The affected cases are sold throughout Victoria's Secret stores in the United States, Canada and Mexico and online via Amazon and GetMixBin.com.
The United States Consumer Product Safety Commission issued the warning on Tuesday, by Thursday local Victoria's Secret stores had removed cases containing liquid and glitter from shelves.
Staff at the Parramatta store were aware of the international recall when contacted by Fairfax Media while the CBD site is now only selling Chinese-made plastic covers for older model Samsung phones for between $45-$49.
Victoria's Secret Emporium Melbourne do not sell phone accessories.
Authorities in the US said there have been "24 reports worldwide of skin irritation or chemical burns, including 19 in the US".
"One consumer reported permanent scarring from a chemical burn and another consumer reported chemical burns and swelling to her leg, face, neck, chest, upper body and hands," according to a statement.

The cases, which were sold for the iPhone 6, 6s and 7 from October 2015 to June 2017 and resemble a snow globe - thanks to the glitter floating inside the liquid.

A Forever New customer was burnt from a glittery phone case she bought in 2015. Photo: Facebook/ForeverNewOfficial

The Australian Competition and Consumer Commission are not aware of any incidents in Australia concerning these products which are manufactured in China and distributed globally by MixBin Electronics.
MixBin Electronics is owned by Ixin Global Trade, a Chinese company that ships tech accessories to Australia.
Forever New, an Australian fashion retailer, continues to sell similar products online and in store, despite an incident in 2015 when customer Erin Nelson suffered "second degree chemical burns"from a cracked iPhone case.
At the time Nelson claimed packaging on the $20 phone case didn't carry any warning labels.
Forever New removed the case from sale while an investigation was launched.
"Since 2015, Forever New has revised the type of plastic used from PC to TPU, which has a jelly-like property that prevents leaks from a break in plastic," a representative told Fairfax Media.
Accessories like the "Cara Caviar Shaky Phone Case" made from "hard plastic materials and consist of an internal case which contains liquid and metallic pink glitter which floats freely within the casing" are now available online for $16.99.

It carries no safety alerts, despite the representative claiming Forever New's "current glitter phone cases" carry warnings.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MixBin Electronics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Secret</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TPU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Secret Emporium Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GetMixBin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara Caviar Shaky Phone Case</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese-made</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ixin Global Trade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Consumer Product Safety Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forever New</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook/ForeverNewOfficial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
