<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418971337606341</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/social-media-tracks-down-stolen-ford-mustang/8771682</url>
  <title>Stolen Mustang tracked down hours after carjacking through Facebook posts in Canberra</title>
  <content>
A luxury car stolen in a carjacking in Canberra has been returned to its owner after posts on social media helped police track the distinctive Ford Mustang.
Three carjackers allegedly confronted Steve Thomas as he sat inside his red Mustang on a quiet Yarralumla street in Canberra this morning.

External Link:

Steve Facebook post about his stolen car
Mr Thomas said one man pointed a crowbar at his face while the other jumped into the passenger seat.
"I wasn't going to do anything with three guys and a crowbar," he said.
"But just before they took off, I said 'at least you could give me my phone' and they threw it out the window."
Mr Thomas immediately called police and then posted the theft of his luxury vehicle on Facebook.
Through comments and messages he was able to track the car's movements almost street by street, as people spotted the prominent car across Canberra.
"Everyone was watching what was happening all over the place," he said
Mr Thomas fed the information to the police, and when he received a photo of the carjackers refuelling at a petrol station in Fyshwick, police jumped.

Police arrested one man who was accused of being involved. Police said the two others were still inside the car and fled the scene - the mustang was later found in a Manuka car park three hours after the alleged carjacking.
"I don't think they'll be stealing a real estate agent's car, and a car that's noticeable, quite so quickly again," Mr Thomas said.
Mr Thomas thanked police and the community for their fast response.
Police are still searching for two of the men who got away.
The 33-year-old arrested in Fyshwick is expected to be charged.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Thomas</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fyshwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mustang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarralumla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Mustang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
