<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418752294270188</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/dog-that-killed-perth-woman-put-down/news-story/2fed4afdb4818fc4eee9ce83f06a61c1</url>
  <title>Dog that killed Perth woman put down</title>
  <content>
A dog that attacked and killed its owner has been put down.
The bull mastiff cross was seized by rangers after 58-year-old Perth woman Sue Lopicich was found dead at her Southern River home on Tuesday.
A family friend said the dog was known for being aggressive due to past abuse but Ms Lopicich, "loved it anyway".
"She was a very caring woman," 'Lee' told 6PR radio.
"She thinks every dog should have a chance and she just loved every dog that came through."
Ms Lopicich was walking several dogs on her property, which doubled as Barko's Boarding Kennels, when the attack occurred.
City of Gosnells rangers had to be used to capture the dog after police were unable to reach the woman's body.
The rangers were provided counselling, council spokesman Grant Bradbrook said.
"It wasn't a nice job to have to attend, so they're being supported," he said.
Another dog at the property, a Staffordshire bull terrier that was also seized has been returned to the family.
A veterinarian gave the dog a lethal injection on Thursday morning.
Police are preparing a report for the coroner.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barko's Boarding Kennel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staffordshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Bradbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Lopicich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lopicich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Gosnells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
