<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418936977867241</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/with-all-this-technology-they-still-get-it-wrong/3208554/</url>
  <title>With all this technology they still get it wrong</title>
  <content>
I DON'T know if you caught it but I watched the Redcliffe Dolphins win over the Papua New Guinea Hunters on Sunday, in the Intrust Super Cup match of the round.
It was a pretty good win but I have to say there were a couple of decisions coming out of the bunker that had me shaking my pumpkin head.
There was one in particular, where a Hunters try was disallowed, that was beyond belief as the replay showed it was clear the player had got the ball down.
Now, it probably didn't change the result as the Dolphins were clearly the better side but the game would have been closer and a better spectacle.
My point is though, as Canberra coach Ricky Stuart said the other week, what if it costs them the game, and it is clearly a mistake? It seems the referees boss says sorry and that's it?
I wouldn't be as concerned if there was no bunker, just referees and linesman as mistakes get made by all involved but with all this technology, they still get it wrong. Surely we can do better.
On the other hand how good was the Storm v Manly game on Sunday. (That's right I watched two games simultaneously, which really impressed my wife).
What a great result for 350 game man Cameron Smith and just as rewarding were tries to four of his team-mates who have all played for the Sunshine Coast Falcons, Kenny Bromwich, Jarome Hughes, Joe Stimson and Suli Vunivalu.
That shows what opportunity is available in the Intrust Super Cup with clubs like the Falcons.
-WHAT an effort by Alyssa Bull last week at the world under-23 and junior kayak world championships in Romania, where she won a gold medal in the K1 1000 and a silver in the K1 500.
Young Bully was the only Australian to come away with a gold which is really encouraging as she is still under 23 next year as well.
Maroochydore SLSC's Jordan Wood teamed up with Ryley Fitzsimons to take out bronze in the K2 1000 to be the only other Australians to get on the podium.
There is no doubt lifesaving and kayaking are joined at the hip when you have a quick look at the teams over there with Maroochydore's Tiarnee Massie, Mackenzie Duffy, Alexandra Headland's Lucinda Kelly and Mooloolaba's Billy Bain all donning the green and gold, along with team members from surf clubs all over Australia and paddling well against some pretty hot opposition.
Alyssa now heads to Italy for a training camp and then Budapest for the open world titles at the end of the month and of course she teams up with the other AB, Maroochydore's Alyce Burnett for their K2 journey on the world stage.
I must say both these young ladies handle themselves so well in and out of the water and I know the Sunshine Coast is very proud of them.
-AS mentioned last week, don't forget the Alex Surf Club has its Annual Golf Day on September 1 at Headland Golf Club and event organisers are very excited to have a new sponsor of the day in Best Western Plus at Kawana which is a fantastic venue for not only accommodation but dining and functions.
Hole sponsorship is going fast with some still available, plus some single and groups of four spots are still available.
It is an ambrose event and always a lot of fun. For enquiries ring the lifesaving club to book (54436677) or email me ashley@alexsurfclub.com.au.
Jetstar drops massive cut-price Sunshine Coast holiday deal.
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Bromwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore's Alyce Burnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackenzie Duffy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Stimson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K2 1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annual Golf Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Falcons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Surf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea Hunters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyssa Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K1 1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryley Fitzsimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redcliffe Dolphins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba's Billy Bain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Headland Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland's Lucinda Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore's Tiarnee Massie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suli Vunivalu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Western Plus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore SLSC's Jordan Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarome Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K1 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyssa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
