<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418885438258945</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/vacant-adelaide-office-space-slow-to-lease/8771718</url>
  <title>Vacant Adelaide office space very slow to lease, real estate agent warns</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Vacant Adelaide office space which might once have taken three months to lease can now take up to a year, an Adelaide real estate agent has said.
Ian Lambert of the Ray White agency said it was a frustrating process to find tenants.
"Coming from a 100 per cent occupancy rate for a number of years, it's unusual that we are having difficulty leasing these properties," he said.
He said most building owners now were willing to consider all reasonable offers.
Mr Lambert said owners sometimes offered rent-free periods as an inducement, or provided the office fit-out a tenant required.
A half-yearly Australian Property Council report found Adelaide's vacancy rate was the nation's second-highest, behind Perth.

The Office Market Report said Adelaide had 230,000 square metres of empty office space in the CBD.
That might worsen after a $500 million private commercial and retail development is completed in the Adelaide Festival plaza precinct, at the northern end of the CBD, warned City Councillor Sandy Wilkinson.
He said the council was keen to back city businesses with loans to help them achieve building upgrades and legal compliance with such things as disability access.
The councillor said $1.25 million had been allocated in the latest budget toward such efforts.
Empty space affects surrounding business

In the City of Adelaide zone, North Adelaide Traders Association representative Morag Horton said empty space in O'Connell and Melbourne street buildings was having an adverse impact for surrounding businesses.
"Business is very hard, [which] makes it difficult to pay rent prices - it doesn't make a vibrant environment for the consumer," she said.
Ms Horton said tough business conditions were prompting many tenants to seek short lease terms.
Property Council executive director Daniel Gannon said about 40 per cent of office space currently vacant was in older buildings, of lesser standard than many businesses wanted.

Another Adelaide real estate agent Andrew Bahr, who has worked in the field for more than two decades, said there were often compliance issues with older buildings, due to their energy use or shortfalls on disability access.
"Tenants are certainly wanting to occupy the best quality building with the best quality space," he said.
Mr Bahr said the lack of economic growth in South Australia meant many potential ventures did not get off the ground due to the high risk involved.
"Until we get more people in the state and there's more demand for goods and services, businesses are not going to expand," he said.
He said SA had growth potential with its defence projects, biomedical industry and its generally lower cost of living than some other states.
He said some vacant office space in suburbs such as Mawson Lakes, in the north, had been converted into housing, but there would need to be more CBD residential demand before older city buildings could see the same transformation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Connell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Adelaide Traders Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Property Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Horton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Lambert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Bahr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mawson Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bahr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Lambert of the Ray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morag Horton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Councillor Sandy Wilkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office Market Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
