<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419486733691928</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/nrl-salary-cap-clarity-the-key-as-penrith-panthers-eye-longterm-nathan-cleary-deal-20170803-gxoypy.html</url>
  <title>Cap clarity the key as Panthers eye long-term Cleary deal</title>
  <content>
The uncertainty about the NRL's salary cap beyond this season is all that stands between Penrith stepping up plans to sign Nathan Cleary to one of the game's longest contracts, with general manager Phil Gould declaring on Thursday the club had to protect its "asset".
The 19-year-old halfback, who will play the team coached by his father Ivan when Penrith meet Wests Tigers on Sunday, has a deal at the club until the end of 2019. However, Gould said the Panthers could not sit back and allow a "franchise player" to be courted by rivals.Photo: AAP
"He's foolproof, I think, as a player," Gould said in his Six Tackles with Gus podcast on Channel Nine's website. "He comes from a great family, a footballing family, he's been in the system a long time. There's no drink, there's no drugs, there is no partying. This kid is a true professional. He's got no potential problems down the track other than injury. So far as a franchise player I think Nathan ticks every box."
Like other clubs Penrith are eagerly awaiting the finalisation of the salary cap for 2018 and beyond when it comes to trying to lock down Cleary to a long-term contract. The code's longest ever player contracts are Jason Taumalolo's 10-year deal with North Queensland announced this year and Daly Cherry-Evans' eight-year agreement with Manly signed in 2015.
Just how long Penrith have in mind for Cleary is not yet clear but what is obvious is that Gould's forward thinking extends even beyond the reported five-year extension on the cards that would keep the halfback as a Panther until 2024.
"It's difficult because we still don't know what the salary cap is for next year. So what the salary cap might look like in five years or 10 years' time is problematical," he said. "I had lunch with Ivan Cleary and Nathan's manager earlier in the season, just throwing up the point that even if we extended Nathan's contract for five years he'd still only be 24 years of age when he came off his contract, still not in his prime.

"If another club was to come and, say, do a Ben Hunt [who has signed a six-year contract with St George Illawarra and will leave Brisbane after this season] on the Panthers and take away their halfback that they'd invested by that time 10 years of work into, it wouldn't be fair on the club.
"I think the club has got to protect itself with a player of this stature. You've got to be able to protect the asset and I think it's important from Panthers' point view that they never lose Nathan Cleary. I think he is a player that can make the club over the next decade."

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Gould said the potential problems associated with contracting players for five or more years were outweighed by the upside of the teenager and the central role he expects him to play at Penrith.
"It's very dangerous to try and contract players beyond the norm ... three or four years is usually a long-term contract ... But it comes down to a player like Nathan Cleary who plays in such an important position ... he's a goalkicking halfback and obviously a representative player of the future.
"He's a big a part of the future so I guess it's about protecting investment already made and making sure that the club has what I guess what [could] be called a franchise player or a marquee player for a long period of time."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gould</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Cleary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Six Tackles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleary</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Gould</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daly Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Cleary</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
