<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418760884204908</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832154/fashion-shows-helps-other-women/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Fashion fundraiser to help disadvantaged women</title>
  <content>
Shellharbour fashion business owner Michelle Taylor is bringing a popular fundraising event back to Wollongong Art Gallery on August 27.

Fashion Fundraiser:Michael Taylor, of Get Dressed Hire, Nicki Bowman, of Dress For Success, and Rebecca Armstrong, of Culinarius.

After a sell-out Spring Fashion Parade and Sparkling High Tea in 2016 the owner is teaming up with Monika and Rebecca Armstrong, of , to support a charity that helps disadvantaged women.

Mrs Taylor said the event will feature a spring racing fashion preview by  as well as the gourmet sparkling high tea Culinarius.

There will also be stalls by spring carnival fashion and beauty partners and a Dress For Success stand.

"We will have some local milliners who will be display or their new head wear for spring racing," Mrs Taylor said.
"That will be  and ," she said.
"A lot of other local businesses have supported us as well."
Women attending are encouraged to bring along a garment of clothing, shoes or a handbag they no longer use to donate to the Dress For Success.

It helps disadvantaged women to get back into the workforce. 

"We are also asking any attendees to bring unwanted good condition work.
The Spring Fashion Parade and Sparkling High Tea will run from 12pm to 4pm and include the fashion parade featuring five models in 15 outfits from 2.30pm.

The event will run on two levels and include a DJ. It will be followed by an after party for those women who want to go on an make a day of it. 

said there will be a Moet bar upstairs during the function at the gallery.
She said it was all about having a nice time, networking, supporting a great cause and seeing the latest fashion before the change of season.
"Last year we had 120 people," she said.

"The women of Wollongong enjoyed the opportunity to get dressed up and do this on a Sunday afternoon last year. So we are bringing it back by popular demand. We are showcasing the latest spring arrivals.  It will be a beautiful setting with lovely food."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicki Bowman, of Dress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Armstrong, of Culinarius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sparkling High Tea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dress For Success</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Fashion Parade</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Armstrong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dressed Hire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Art Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Taylor, of Get</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Taylor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Culinarius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
