<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418717934530996</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/markets/asx-drops-as-rio-tinto-cash-splash-falls-flat-20170803-gxoi1n.html</url>
  <title>ASX drops as Rio Tinto cash splash falls flat</title>
  <content>
Local investors ignored the latest set of records on Wall Street, focusing instead on a number of underwhelming earnings results to push the sharemarket lower.
The benchmark S&P/ASX 200 Index eased 0.2 per cent on Thursday to 5735, as early profits results threw up more losers than winners.Photo: DEAN LEWINS
Mining giant Rio Tinto shares dropped 2.5 per cent despite unveiling bumper half-year earnings on Wednesday evening, including a more than doubling of its dividend. 
While analysts enthused about the possibility for further cash returns over the coming 18 months, investors were apparently less impressed with an earnings figure that came in shy of consensus forecasts.
Suncorp was particularly hard hit on Thursday after the banking and insurance giant released a full-year result that was lower than brokers had been expecting. The company posted a 4 per cent increase in net profit to $1.07 billion. Investors were unimpressed and sent the stock tumbling 6.4 per cent.
Australian Pharmaceutical Industries suffered a heavy 13 per cent fall after it on Wednesday evening downgraded its full-year earnings guidance from 10 per cent profit growth this financial year to 5 per cent.

Elsewhere, investors were happy to bide their time as they await a flood of earnings over the next two weeks.
"There doesn't seem to be much conviction in the market at the moment," said James Gerrish, senior investment adviser at Shaw & Partners. "It's a lacklustre kind of day with investors just mostly moving between sectors."
Steadfast Group enjoyed an 8.5 per cent rise, most likely thanks to a broker note that expects a strong full-year result later this month. 
Mantra Group suffered a 7.1 per cent sell-off after Citi and Morgan Stanley downgraded the company to neutral ratings, pointing to the strong Australian dollar as the catalyst. 
Flight Centre lifted another 3.5 per cent on Thursday as investors continued to celebrate the company's decision to spend some of its cash pile and expand its presence in New Zealand and North America. 
Shares in wellness food company Wattle Health Australia leapt 37 per cent after its share placement was significantly oversubscribed. The company raised $9.1 billion but had enough interest to secure $20 million. As such, Wattle Health intends to seek shareholder approval to raise a further $3.3 million at 56 cents a share. 
Stock Watch: Select Harvests

Almond producer Select Harvests slumped 14 per cent to $4.25 on Thursday after the company warned that it now expects full year 2017 profit to come in between $7.5 million to $8.5 million, as a consequence of increased costs, currency movements, and high rents for its orchards. Select Harvest shares have now lost 36 per cent over 2017 as investors worry about falling almond prices after a record-breaking drought in the almond growing centres of California came to an abrupt end in 2016. Select Harvests has a market value around $300 million and will hand down its full-year results on August 25.
Market movers

Iron ore

Chinese rebar steel futures hovered near their strongest level in more than four years, supported by firm demand and tighter supply following Beijing's clampdown on low-grade steel production. The sustained strength in the steel market could keep profit margins at Chinese producers high through the end of the year, traders said, adding it should spur appetite for raw material iron ore. The most-active rebar on the Shanghai Futures Exchange was up 0.1 per cent to 3724 yuan ($698) a tonne. The construction steel product hit 3759 yuan on Tuesday, its loftiest since September 2013.
Trade surplus

Australia's trade surplus has come in at a narrower-than-expected $856 million in June, ABS figures showed on Thursday. That's down from the downwardly revised $2000 million seasonally-adjusted surplus recorded in May, and below the consensus forecast of $1800 million. The drop in the surplus looks heavily related to a month-on-month fall in the value of iron ore and coal exports. The sum of seasonally adjusted balances for the three months to June 2017 was a surplus of $2804 million, against a surplus of $7457 million for the three months to March 2017.
India cuts

The Reserve Bank of India used the room provided by slumping inflation to cut its main policy rate by 25 basis points to 6.00 per cent - the first easing by an Asian central bank this year. The rate cut is the RBI's first since one of the same size in October and a show of confidence in a country that has experienced a surge in foreign investments into debt and shares this year. The move had been widely anticipated as a slump in food prices sent June consumer inflation to a more than five-year low, but the RBI kept the market guessing about its future rates path.
US monetary policy

Two regional Federal Reserve presidents signalled that policy makers may announce the timing of the balance-sheet unwind when they meet next month, as the US economy shows itself strong enough to withstand a return to more normal monetary policy. The September Federal Open Market Committee meeting "would be an appropriate time to do this," San Francisco Fed chief John Williams told reporters of balance-sheet normalisation. He said that's consistent with what policy makers have been communicating throughout the year, not an acceleration.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Gerrish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Select Harvests</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Futures Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattle Health Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX 200 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattle Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September Federal Open Market Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Pharmaceutical Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Lewins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
