<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419237625583876</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/world-title-hopes-still-alive-for-julian-wilson/3208580/</url>
  <title>World title hopes still alive for Julian Wilson</title>
  <content>
SURFING: The cool and calm nature of professional surfer Julian Wilson belies a more intense determination and hunger for success in the surf.

The Sunshine Coaster has achieved several feats since breaking into the world tour in 2011 but the sport's coveted crown has eluded him.

He is eighth on this year's championship circuit midway through the season and the title is still well within reach, according to Wilson.

The Coolum product, who now lives at Peregian Beach, said he has had some "good results and a couple of poor results" this year.

But, fresh off a third place finish at the J-Bay Open in South Africa, he believed things were turning in his favour.

"The last few events are trending in the right direction and I've had some really good waves and I've been really enjoying myself," he said.

Heading to the seventh stop of the 11-stop tour next week, Wilson said there was still time to stake his claim.

"My goal is definitely to win a world title, and there's a lot of events left for the year and I just want to keep the momentum rolling."

"I know I'm sitting in eighth at the moment but there's a lot of ground that I can make up over the next few events so I'm just focusing on that."

In his seventh season on tour, Wilson believed he was only now starting to enter his prime.

If not achieved this year, Wilson said the prospect of being number one was very much "achievable" in the coming seasons.

"It's (world title) obviously something I haven't figured out yet and something that definitely motivates me," he said.

"I think the next five years is kind of the prime window of my career and I know I really want to make the most of it.

"So, I definitely feel like as the years have gone by I've definitely learnt more and more and I know it;s only a few heats away from happening.

"I'll just keep my foot to the floor and performing at the level that I know I can - I know its achievable."

Wilson is at home, during a brief break from the tour.

Along with catching up with friends and family, the 28-year-old also maintained sponsorship commitments and as OAKLEY ambassador completed a photo shoot for the brands Prizm lens technology on Peregian Beach.

"It's always nice to be home, there's no place like it," he said.

"Especially this time of year the weather is just outstanding and today (Thursday) we have some waves which is nice and I just really enjoy being home."

Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
TERRY Fewtrell's new book shares the history of Palmwoods.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prizm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TERRY Fewtrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J-Bay Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
