<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418889733226319</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/hanson-hears-from-concerned-elderly/3208547/</url>
  <title>Hanson hears from concerned elderly</title>
  <content>
CONTROVERSIAL Queensland Senator Pauline Hanson played a rare second fiddle during a trip to Buderim as she sat back and listened to stories - some of horror - of life in aged care.
More than 200 residents packed the Buderim War Memorial Community Hall today to meet with Senator Hanson and Buderim MP Steve Dickson, with changes to the Retirement Villages Act a hot topic of discussion.
Mr Dickson has been advocating for sweeping changes to the Act to protect the wellbeing of the region's elderly.
He reiterated that push, calling for standardised contracts and promised the establishment of an ombudsman to assist residents in disputes.
Joanne Wheeler was one resident who was eager to see changes to the legislation.
"The Act is so ambiguous, it's badly written and leads to so many disputes because of the ambiguity," Ms Wheeler said.
She said key inclusions they were seeking included a compulsory buy-back to protect those leaving a retirement village and better protection for residents against redevelopment of retirement communities.
Senator Hanson said she'd been "amazed" with the concerns raised during the meeting and felt it was a serious issue for the Coast.
Jetstar drops massive cut-price Sunshine Coast holiday deal.
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
TERRY Fewtrell's new book shares the history of Palmwoods.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retirement Villages Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TERRY Fewtrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Wheeler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Senator Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim MP Steve Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wheeler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim War Memorial Community Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
