<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420272712724433</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/with-swift-action-bystanders-can-reduce-damage-from-acid-attacks-20170802-gxo59w</url>
  <title>With swift action, bystanders can reduce damage from acid attacks </title>
  <content>
Should you be nearby when an acid attack takes place, you can make a real difference by acting fast.
Removing contaminated clothing and washing off the acid with copious amounts of water can minimise scarring and need for surgical reconstruction, according to an editorial in the British Medical Journal.
Written by experts from Barts Health NHS Trust and the Royal College of Emergency Medicine, the editorial says educating the public, providing clear guidance for health professionals and legislation could play a key role in tackling this latest menace on the streets.
It says the number of high-profile "acid" attacks has been increasing in recent years, especially in London.

Twitter / @Sarah_Cobbold

There were attacks as recently as last month and then just this week, a man was walking along outside Harrods when two men on a moped drew alongside and sprayed him. One report said they wanted his watch. The episode was captured on CCTV.

While acid is used to maim, disfigure and humiliate women and men in several countries, its use in Britain appears to be changing. It is still used in robberies but is increasingly being used against men in gang-related violent crimes.
As the carrying of knives is prohibited and as the carrying of corrosives is allowed, acid attacks appear to be replacing stabbings.
The chemical is often thrown into the face leaving victims likely to be blinded and severely disfigured.
Sisters in club attack

Facebook

In April this year, two Australian sisters were caught up in an acid attack at an east London club.
Isobella Fraser, 22, and her sister Prue, 20, both suffered burns when a man sprayed people inside Mangle E8 in Hackney.
Australia has no culture of this kind of violence but last year a man, 62, did put hydrochloric acid into a lube dispenser at a gay sex club in Sydney's west.
Following a number of similar incidents, dispensers had been alarmed to alert security officers if they were tampered with. An alarm sounded and the man was detained.

Mamunur Rashid / Alamy Stock Photo

Later he received a two-year good behaviour bond after his lawyer argued he was mentally ill and the magistrate rejected a police suggestion his actions were a hate crime.
In Australia a range of acids are available over the counter.
Limiting damage

In Britain, acid violence has involved a range of corrosive substances.  Acids appear to melt the skin. They cause so called "coagulation death" by denaturising the skin's proteins. The first step is to limit this damage.

London police have recently been issued with "acid response kits". Police cars get packs of eyewear, gloves and five-litre water bottles to help prevent skin damage.
The medical director of the London Ambulance Service has advised thorough irrigation after removing contaminated clothing. The victim should be removed from ongoing exposure as soon as possible.
When victims get to the resuscitation room of the emergency department it is just the start of their painful journey. They often experience physical and mental distress for the rest of their lives.
The editorial says once in the emergency department, the victim should have rapid airway assessment and intravenous rehydration, similar to treatment of thermal burns.

It is essential to continue washing off all the acid with water to prevent ongoing tissue destruction, starting at the area of contamination or the face and eyes.
Irrigation should continue until the pH of the exposed area has returned to neutral. If eyes were exposed or even potentially exposed, then local pH should be checked again after 15 to 30 minutes to ensure there is no re-exposure from acid that pooled in the recesses of the folds of the eyelids.
Several other medical steps follow.
Incidents on the rise

In London, the Metropolitan Police recorded 261 attacks in 2015. Last year this rose to 454 attacks and there has been a further increase already this year.
In Britain, carrying corrosive substances is legal with no restrictions on volume or strength, although a change in legislation is being considered.
In 2002, Bangladesh banned the open sale of acid and imposed stringent punishment of offenders, which saw the number of attacks fall by 15-20 per cent a year.
India and Cambodia have since implemented legislation to combat acid attacks but have yet to introduce laws restricting the ease and availability of acid.

Several non-governmental organisations have been formed to combat such attacks in countries where they are common.
The British charity, Acid Survivors Trust International, is the only international organisation with the sole purpose of ending acid violence. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>pH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Ambulance Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Medical Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mangle E8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah_Cobbold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barts Health NHS Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alamy Stock Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal College of Emergency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isobella Fraser, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mamunur Rashid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acid Survivors Trust International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prue, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
