<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418713639563417</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Tech Guide</source>
  <url>http://www.techguide.com.au/news/hp-unveils-backpack-pc-take-virtual-reality-another-level/</url>
  <title>HP unveils backpack PC to take virtual reality to another level - Tech Guide</title>
  <content>
Related Articles

HP is taking virtual reality in a new direction after unveiling the world's first professional wearable VR computer to improve immersive customer experiences and training simulations.

The HP Z VR Backpack has the potential to enable even more powerful virtual reality solutions for enterprises, businesses and entertainment.

The device is worn like a backpack to give the user freedom to move and maintain complete immersion.

The HP Z VR Backpack can also be docked and used as a powerful desktop computer as well.

It is powered by a high-end processor - the Intel Core i7 vPro - and includes the NVIDIA Quadro P5200 GPU with 16GB video memory.

Virtual Reality can be used in a variety of ways - and it's not just for playing games.

Here are the enterprise and business uses for VR:

- In medical training or heavy/large equipment operations, safe and effective simulated training that can help avoid costly mistakes in dangerous environments.

- In architectural building development, virtual walkthroughs at scale for client reviews can help quickly close the deal.

- In product development where product concepts are reviewed, and executive agreement and sign off for new product styling can be done in virtual product showrooms.

- In commercial entertainment: new location-based entertainment centres featuring exhilarating virtual reality experiences can now be realised with the HP Z VR Backpack.

"Virtual reality is changing the way people learn, communicate and create," said Xavier Garcia, vice president and general manager, Z Workstations, HP Inc.

"Making the most of this technology requires a collaborative relationship between customers and partners.

"As a leader in technology, HP is uniting powerful commercial VR solutions, including new products like the HP Z VR Backpack, with customer needs to empower VR experiences our customers can use today to reinvent the future.

Related Posts

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VR</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nvidia Quadro P5200 GPU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xavier Garcia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intel Core</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Z Workstations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VPRO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HP Z VR Backpack</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HP Inc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
