<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420259827822309</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/legal/law-firm-partner-salaries-stall-but-are-still-1m-a-year-20170802-gxo5yc</url>
  <title>Law partner salaries stall but are still $1m a year  </title>
  <content>
Income has flattened for the nation's law firm partners as they confront a subdued economy and intensely competitive market, but most major firm partners in the key financial districts in Sydney and Melbourne still crack the $1 million threshold.
The average national salary of partners increased by 3.5 per cent over the past year, down from 3.8 per cent the previous year, amid a market of turbulent movement by lawyers driven by more than just money.
"They start off saying 'I'm not getting enough pay or recognition', but when I really dig down, the cultural concerns will always hands-down beat remuneration concerns," said Mahlab managing director of Melbourne Katherine Simpson.
"When you drill down, they just don't like the way the firm is being run."

According to the latest report on the profession by , hiring activity was up across Sydney, Melbourne and Brisbane, where the most common salary for big firm partners was $1.25 million, $1.15 million and $970,000 respectively. Among demand areas were corporate, property and financial services.

Ms Simpson said the "conflicts issue" particularly prescient at global firms was "raising its ugly head more and more these days", motivating moves to firms where partners feel they can regain some autonomy and not be locked out of deals due to "something that's happening in the UAE" or some other jurisdiction.
But she said the "overriding reason" pushing partners to move was a "dissatisfaction or disillusionment with a firm they have helped to build that is now not delivering what they need".
And those needs are not all about income, Ms Simpson said, despite some new "deep pocket" US global entrants attracting partners with lucrative pay packets.
"If you've got a firm that is doing things well, and you can convince them it will be more flexible and innovative, they can run their own race, that's very persuasive," said Ms Simpson.

Nonetheless, she admitted partners were "usually loathe to take any drop in income even if everything else is better".
Heading in-house

as they barricade against raids: the attraction of going in-house.
Although corporate counsel saw a slightly lower average increase in salary for the financial year, of 2.7 per cent compared to 3.4 per cent the prior year, the prospect of working in an innovative team increasingly valued by corporates was increasingly attractive for lawyers at all levels, the Mahlab reports reveal.

"The corporates are more flexible, and they're looking at innovation and doing high-quality work," said Ms Simpson.
Partners often come to Ms Simpson to request an in-house move, to shift away from law firms, she said, but she said all firms were different and could offer a change for lawyers.
The report highlights one pocket of lawyers who are in a particularly strong bargaining position: those with three to six years of experience. Firms are finding it hard to recruit and retain talent at that level; a typical point at which paths might diverge.
Remuneration for lawyers in Sydney with five years' experience, for example, sits at between $114,00 and $165,000; in Melbourne, it can reach $140,000.

Meanwhile senior associates at the top of their game can have pay cheques that reach $243,000 in Sydney, $210,000 in Melbourne, $180,000 in Brisbane, $190,000 in Perth and $130,000 in Adelaide.
Ms Simpson said they face "longer queues" for partnership than they ever have, as well as facing challenges in finding a new home if they are unhappy because they are considered "less malleable" than their .
"They can be in a queue at their own firm which is moving not at all or very slowly. If they're going to a new firm, they're stuck in the same position in a firm with people who don't know them. If they go in-house, they're competing within a mature market.
"They're the most squeezed."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Katherine Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne, $180,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UAE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahlab</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Simpson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane, $190,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
