<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419486733691949</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832349/identity-crisis-costing-our-city-millions/?cs=304</url>
  <title>Editorial August 4 2017</title>
  <content>
When is comes to assigning slices of the funding pie it seems we are being dudded.
We are like the last kid at the birthday who watches on while all of the other kids get oversized slices, leaving nothing but a slither of cake, a wafer of icing and the last remaining chocolate bud.
That will come as no surprise to most as we have become rather used to it over the years.
Too used to it in fact.
However, it is high time the NSW Government stopped playing silly buggers with this region in terms of funding classification.
It seems our region is classified as either "regional" or "metropolitan" depending on the whim of the government without any basis or reason.
In fact you could argue the only reason or thread of consistency revolves around which classification is likely to make it the hardest or even impossible for us to win funding. 
It seems when it comes to the funding pie for this region the NSW Government wants to have its cake and eat it too. Our Urban Affairs reporter Kate McIlwain has shown the farce for what it is in black and white.
We're classed as "regional" for things like council mergers and NSW Resources for Regions, but when it really counts we are metropolitan.
For things like the Stronger Country Communities fund  for major infrastructure projects and the NSW Cultural fund we are classed as metropolitan completely leaving us out of the picture. Who can blame anyone for being confused really?
Premier Gladys Berejiklian and her NSW Government should come clean on this issue and allow us  to access the funding streams that can genuinely make a difference for our region. Much like the other "regions" in this state.
We are not South Sydney and nor - until the NSW Government does something to adequately connect our region with proper transport infrastructure -  should we be considered as South Sydney.
This confusion and inconsistency has undoubtedly cost this region millions in funding and and it is high time that is rectified.
The NSW Government needs to stop having it both ways and playing politics with how it divides the resources of this state.

It's simply not good enough Premier and we look to you to resolve this in a sensible fashion so we can move on and get the region access to the funding it deserves.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Affairs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Cultural</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate McIlwain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stronger Country Communities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Editorial August 4 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
