<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419271985323009</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/leaders/former-nsw-premier-barry-ofarrell-cleared-of-any-wrongdoing-in-icac-report/news-story/47241d2d611119338d6ce0d177371028</url>
  <title>Former NSW Premier Barry O'Farrell cleared of any wrongdoing in ICAC report</title>
  <content>
ICAC report recommends criminal charges
5:10

An ICAC report into Australian Water Holdings has recommended criminal charges are laid.

August 3rd 2017
7 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Barry O'Farrell appeared as a witness at the ICAC hearings in Sydney in 2014. Photos: Chris McKeen

Share

IT WAS the bottle of wine that brought down a Premier.
In 2014, Barry O'Farrell resigned as the Premier of NSW after admitting he misled a corruption tribunal about a $3000 bottle of Penfolds Grange red he was gifted.
and dragged in politicians from both Labor and the Liberals.
His red wine resignation was so swift, so bizarre, that many questioned his behaviour with his immediate predecessor Kristina Keneally labelling it "very strange". With Mr O'Farrell gone Mike Baird, and ultimately Gladys Berejiklian, took the top job.

Barry O'Farrell was NSW Premier form 2011 - 2014. He resigned the day after he gave evidence at the state's ICAC. Photos: Chris McKeenSource:News Corp Australia
But on Thursday, the ICAC cleared Mr O'Farrell of any wrongdoing.
In its findings, the ICAC said it was satisfied, "that there was no intention on Mr O'Farrell's part to mislead".
In fact, no adverse findings were handed down to any Liberal party members including AWH boss Nick Di Girolamo who gave the O'Farrell's the wine.
The same can't be said for three former Labor ministers whose wheeling and dealing was also scrutinised by the ICAC during operation Credo.
Labor MPs Eddie Obeid, Joe Tripodi and Tony Kelly could face criminal charges after they were found corrupt in relation to their actions concerning a lucrative public-private partnership proposal by AWH between 2007 and 2010.

The damning report also found former Labor staffer Laurie Brown, Mr Kelly's former chief of staff, engaged in "serious corrupt conduct".
", reported the Telegraph.

Mr O'Farrell came unstuck when he forgot about a gift of a $3000 bottle of Penfolds Grange Hermitage Picture: David GeraghtySource:News Corp Australia
The report recommended that the DPP consider laying charges against Obeid, Mr Kelly, Mr Brown and Mr Tripodi for misconduct in public office.
But given Mr O'Farrell has been cleared, did he jump too soon?
The former Premier came unstuck when he gave evidence to the ICAC in April 2014.
When asked during the ICAC hearing if had received the vintage bottle of red from Liberal fundraiser - and then AWH boss - Mr Di Girolamo in 2011, Mr O'Farrell said he had not.
But the very next day, Mr O'Farrell resigned after acknowledging a handwritten thank you note for the wine, signed by him, would be tendered at the ICAC.
He reiterated he did not remember receiving the wine and did not knowingly mislead the commission under oath.
"I still can't recall the receipt of the gift of a bottle of 1959 Penfolds Grange Hermitage, I still can't explain what happened to that bottle of wine.
"But I do accept that there is a thankyou note signed by me and as someone who believes in -accountability, in responsibility, I accept the consequences of my actions," Mr O'Farrell said.
"This has clearly been a significant memory fail on my part," he said. Within a week he was out.

Police mug shot of former NSW Labor politician Eddie Obeid.Source:Supplied
He wasn't the only Liberal to get burnt. Federal Senator Arthur Sinodinos, who was the deputy chairman of AWH between 2009 and 2010, stepped down from the front bench in March 2014 when he was drawn into the inquiry, but was reinstated 18 months later.
The ICAC made no corrupt findings against Senator Sinodinos who responded that the report "brings to an end a long and comprehensive process".
It had been suggested Mr O'Farrell's office knew about the wine well in advance of the hearing after journalists had been making inquiries.
In June 2014, one-time NSW Premier Keneally told the ABC that if Mr O'Farrell had acknowledged the gift to the ICAC at the earliest opportunity then it would have been embarrassing, for sure, but it also would have spared him drawing up a resignation note.

Barry O'Farrell appeared as a witness at the ICAC hearings in Sydney in 2014. Picture: AFP PHOTO/William WEST / AFP / WILLIAM WESTSource:AFP
The ICAC report on Thursday noted that when he gave evidence Mr O'Farrell said he had no recollection of receiving the wine.
"The Commission is satisfied that there was no intention on Mr O'Farrell's part to mislead the Commission on either occasion that he gave evidence.
"Mr O'Farrell gave further evidence, which other evidence bears out and the Commission accepts, that he never acceded to any request from Mr Di Girolamo or anyone else to give AWH special assistance."
Three months after he resigned from his position as leader of the state Liberal party, the former Premier told Seven News that, "crap happens but the point is to deal with it" in regards to the Grange incident.
"Personally I understand that things like this happen, even if unintentional, and there has to be a consequence."
A memory lapse, it seems, was enough to cost him his job.
Mr O'Farrell said at the time he had "nothing to fear" from the ICAC report. Indeed, he was right.
But he may still rue the day a $3000 bottle of wine robbed him of his job.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Barry O'Farrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Water Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP Photo/William West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Di Girolamo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Senator Arthur Sinodinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris McKeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tripodi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Obeid.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MPs Eddie Obeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WILLIAM WESTSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Farrell</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>7.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Di Girolamo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penfolds Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penfolds Grange Hermitage Picture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristina Keneally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penfolds Grange Hermitage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry O'Farrell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David GeraghtySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Farrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Keneally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris McKeenSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tripodi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWH</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Sinodinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
