<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420006424746096</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/feel-the-power-malcolm-turnbull-summons-electricity-retailers-to-canberra-for-summit-20170803-gxotv1.html</url>
  <title>Feel the power: Malcolm Turnbull summons electricity retailers to Canberra for summit</title>
  <content>
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has thrown the switch to brow-beating, calling in the nation's biggest electricity retailers for face-to-face talks next Wednesday in a bid to curb galloping household and business electricity bills, and improve their market sensitivity.
In comments that go some way to vindicating claims from one of his backbenchers that people would die this winter from not being able to afford heating, Mr Turnbull says the cost pressures from sky-rocketing energy prices are leading families to avoid turning on heating and lights, and that businesses are doing the same with plants.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Paying the lazy tax

The energy companies don't make it easy for anyone to shop around. Michael Pascoe comments.

Among the complaints he will level are the tendency of electricity retailers to switch consumers from off-peak rates to higher peak electricity costs without their knowledge, relying on the fact that consumers are reluctant to switch retailers. 
The Prime Minister cited research by St Vincent de Paul that found a typical family could save up to $830 a year by changing from "the worst standing offer, to the best market offer".Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
The meeting is also a demonstration of the government's intent to address more pressing matters than its excruciating internal pre-occupations with delaying same-sex marriage equality.
That issue seems set to account for most of the political oxygen in the first part of the week, when Federal Parliament returns after the winter break.

But Mr Turnbull is determined to move on to other matters as Coalition figures across the country expressed frustration at the endless questions and prominent headlines about marriage equality as they called for a return to the bread-and-butter concerns such as jobs, growth, and the rising cost of living.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Fed up with soaring prices, and unable to unlock the gas supplies needed to drive generation costs dramatically down, an exasperated Prime Minister has written to the electric eight, summoning them to the frozen capital for talks.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
In his letter to chief executives, Mr Turnbull acknowledges the difficulties of the industry and notes that the companies run "hardship" programs to help financially stressed consumers in some circumstances.
But he says more needs to be done, with energy prices threatening economic activity and creating investment uncertainty.
"Australia is blessed with abundant energy so it is simply not good enough that some families and businesses cannot always afford to turn on their lights, heating and equipment," he said.
The government has gone to lengths in past months to address the problem and recently went through a similar exercise with east coast gas producers, but with modest results.
Mr Turnbull used the letter to outline several other measures in train including steps to improve competition and increased supply in the gas sector, and "clamping down" on the time-honoured practice of companies using the courts to jack up network prices.
The ACCC is also investigating competition in the electricity system but is not due to finalise its report until midway through next year.
"However, since families are feeling price pressures now, it is important to ensure no family pays a cent more for electricity than it needs to," Mr Turnbull wrote.
"I am particularly concerned by reports that consumers are being pushed from discounted market rates to higher-priced standard contracts or non-discounted plans, often without realising it."
Also at the meeting will be the Treasurer Scott Morrison, and Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg.
Those called to the capital are: Catherine Tanna of Energy Australia, Frank Calabria of Origin Energy, Andy Vesey of AGL, Paul Broad of Snowy Hydro, Paul Geason of Momentum Energy, Jeff Dimey of Alinta Energy, Carly Wishart of Simply Energy, and Matthew Warren of the Australian Energy Council.
The meeting comes as the Turnbull government struggles to explain how retail energy costs could continue their sharp upward trajectory, even after the abolition of the carbon price which it protested at the time was virtually the sole cause of soaring bills.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Vesey of AGL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Calabria of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Vincent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Dimey of Alinta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Warren of the Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hydro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Geason of Momentum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Pascoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Broad of Snowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Tanna of Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carly Wishart of Simply</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
