<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420255532854991</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/cba-case-shows-all-thats-wrong-with-fighting-money-laundering-20170803-gxoxyi</url>
  <title>CBA case exposes weak regulator </title>
  <content>
Just about everything wrong with Australia's system for protecting against money laundering and terrorism financing is encapsulated in the
Normally you would have to trawl through the voluminous reports published by multiple government agencies to find such a comprehensive list of the systemic failings that have been around for years and continue to this day.
puts in the spotlight the ease with which criminal syndicates and terrorists can exploit blatant weaknesses in the banking system as it forges ahead with new machine-driven technologies.
It shows that even institutions that spend $1 billion a year on technology.

David Rowe

The case highlights the complete failure of the "know-your-client" regime that is meant to stop criminals and terrorists using offshore trusts, shells and various complex structures to hide the ultimate beneficiary of a transaction.

These opaque structures have also been used for years by wealthy business people and politicians to , which were leaked in 2015 and published in April last year.
Perhaps the worst aspect of the CBA case is what it says about the regulator.
It clearly has an overly generous and forgiving attitude towards reporting entities that allegedly breach the law. The concise  says the alleged breaches by CBA have been going on for about 2 1/2 years. The full statement of claim, which is 580 pages, was not available on Thursday.
Australia has a history of weak-kneed regulators being shaken out of their torpor by high-profile incidents. The Australian Prudential Regulation Authority was

The Australian Securities and Investments Commission has toughened up against financial advisers and their owners thanks to a series of scandals going back to .
AUSTRAC, which is about to get a new chief executive, has moved with snail-like speed to bring CBA to account. That is not surprising given the cutting criticism that was made of the organisation by the Paris-based Financial Action Task Force (FATF) in 2015.
FATF, which is an independent inter-governmental body that sets the standards for global anti-money laundering and anti-terrorism financing, concluded in a 200-page report that AUSTRAC had been ineffective in enforcing compliance by reporting entities.
It found that AUSTRAC's "graduated approach to supervision does not seem to be adequate to ensure compliance". At that time AUSTRAC had never issued a monetary penalty for non-compliance.

"Overall, the authorities were unable to demonstrate improving anti-money laundering/counter terrorist financing compliance by reporting entities or that they are successfully discouraging criminal abuse of the financial and designated non-financial businesses and professions," FATF said.
Since that report was published the federal Attorney-General's Department has reviewed the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006. The review came up with many strong recommendations, which are due to be implemented this year and next year.
But the release this week of an by Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer showed that multiple agencies need to be involved in fighting money laundering and terrorism financing.
Some solutions are quite simple and have already been implemented overseas, such as limiting the use of cash for large transactions.

It should be noted that AUSTRAC has toughened up its act in the past two years since the FATF report was published. Under former CEO Paul Jevtovic it took civil action against Tabcorp for 108 contraventions of the anti-money laundering and counter-terrorism law. Mr Jevtovic refused a request from Chanticleer to be interviewed on Thursday.
The .
Apply that to the CBA's alleged 53,506 contraventions and the bank is facing a fine of $22 billion. It is hard to see a court imposing that level of penalty as it would only serve to destroy the institution.
A fine of several hundred million would be manageable for a bank earning $9 billion a year.

The largest single fine for breaches of anti-money laundering and counter-terrorism law is believed to be the $US8.9 billion fine in the United States against BNP Paribas in 2014. The bank pleaded guilty to two criminal charges for violating sanctions against Sudan, Cuba and Iran.
In 2014 alone, banks in the US and Europe paid about $US65 billion in anti-money laundering related fines.
CBA said in a statement on Thursday: "We have been in discussions with AUSTRAC for an extended period and have co-operated fully with their requests. Over the same period we have worked to continuously improve our compliance and have kept AUSTRAC abreast of those efforts, which will continue."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BNP Paribas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Paul Jevtovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sudan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris-based Financial Action Task Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General's Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prudential Regulation Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanticleer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US8.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FATF</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US65</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jevtovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
