<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418842488585177</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/missile-stakes-trainer-kris-lees-hopes-to-start-new-season-with-a-bang-in-feature-sprint/news-story/1c565d88b1efc98be3608b450a08eef8</url>
  <title>High-flying Lees shoots for the stars</title>
  <content>
KRIS Lees is coming off his best season yet and if Saturday's fields at Royal Randwick are anything to go by then he might not have even reached his peak yet.
Lees is bucking the trend in building a powerhouse stable outside the Sydney metropolitan area.
The Newcastle trainer prepared 161 winners last season, 41 more than his previous best season (2014-15). His horses also earned more than $9 million in prizemoney between them in 2016-17.
RACE WATCH:
TOP TIPS:
So what's his secret?
The 46-year-old, who has about 90 horses in work, will tell you it's just a better class of horse and wonderful staff but the answer is in his response just there. Spend five minutes with Lees and you can tell why anyone would want to race a horse with him.
You would struggle to meet a more genuine bloke and his strike rate of 19 per cent from 844 runners last season clearly highlights he is not just a good fella either.
On Saturday, Lees will saddle-up two strong chances in the Group 2 Missile Stakes (1200m) in favourite Le Romain ($2.20) and improving mare Invincible Gem ($9).
In a fitting way, both horses have constantly improved just like their trainer has done ever since he took out his trainer's licence in 2003 following the death of his father, legendary trainer Max.
"It just shows where (good horses) can come from and Le Romain is a bit unfashionably bred and even Invincible Gem is by a top stallion in I Am Invincible but she is out of a very plain family," Lees said.
"She is probably the more surprising one. Her first prep was OK and she just got beat at (Beaumont) Newcastle by Awoke (at her second start). She come back and won a maiden first-up but even last preparation a couple of times she got beat in the prep.
"She had a really long prep but as she got deeper into it she excelled when we stretched her out a touch (in distance). She certainly took big steps last preparation from a maiden at Canterbury to just getting beaten in a Randwick Guineas."
Le Romain didn't set the world alight in his first preparation either but he now has three Group 1 wins next to his name.
"You don't think they will ever get to a three-time Group 1 winner when they get beat at their first start at Wyong," Lees said. "But he was always a smart horse."

Missile Stakes (1200m)

HorseTrainerJockeyBarrierWeight
1. LE ROMAINK LeesG Schofield858.5kg
2. JUNGLE EDGEM BellK Forrester458.5kg
3. THE MONSTARB CavanoughJ Adams558.5kg
4. BOSS LANER QuintonA Adkins (a)358.5kg
5. THAT'S A GOOD IDEAP & P SnowdenT Angland758.5kg
6. HARPER'S CHOICEG RyanJ Collett258.5kg
7. TYCOON TARAP & P SnowdenK McEvoy156.5kg
8. INVINCIBLE GEMK LeesC Brown656.5kg
9. MEMESJ CoyleMs R King (a)956.5kg
So who does Lees rate as his best Missile Stakes hope?
"I'm really happy with how Le Romain is coming up for the prep," Lees said.
"Invincible Gem is a little more forward as far as she has been in work a little longer and come to hand a touch quicker but Le Romain has the class on his side.
"I've been happy with his trials and he will improve with the run but I think he will run very well. I don't know if Invincible Gem can beat (Le Romain) at weight-for-age.
"He is quite well treated at weight-for-age against these types of horses but I'm always respectful of horses up and going with race fitness at this time of year."
The duo spearhead a strong list of runners for Lees at Randwick.
He will also saddle-up Wahng Wah in Race 2, Olympic Academy and Admiral Jello in Race 6 and favourite Launch Code in Race 8.
"Dropping back to 1000m and getting the right race shape was the key with Launch Code last start," Lees said. "He was able to get cover in the early stages and he raced fierce at the start prior to that. He has come up with a good gate (barrier two) which gives him that opportunity to get cover in the early stages (again).
"Wahng Wah doesn't have any tactical speed and she is not putting herself in her races, which is costing her, but she is still finishing her races off well so she deserves a chance at this journey (1800m).
"Olympic Academy will probably be better suited next start in a race like the Taree Cup that he won last year. Admiral Jello has returned in really good order and I think he is a real up-and-coming stayer. Whether he will produce second-up like he did first-up (I don't know) but he is in for a good preparation."
Lees looks set to be a big day at Randwick in what could turn out to be the perfect start to his 2017-18 campaign. Either way, he is keeping his feet firmly on the ground.
"I think it's pretty hard as a trainer to set too bigger goals and you rely on other factors with horses," he said. "If every horse can race up to their best and earn their maximum prizemoney, I would be happy with that."Tycoon out to increase value
TYCOON Tara's stud value rocketed with her first Group 1 victory last start, and now Team Snowden are upbeat the underrated mare can claim another feature race before her racing career winds down.
The last-start Tatt's Tiara winner is likely to head to stud in the coming months but not before she contests the Missile Stakes at Royal Randwick.
She is rated a $4.80 chance for the Group 2 feature and co-trainer Paul Snowden is hopeful race fitness will give her an edge over the resuming Le Romain ($2.20).
"She has got very good residual fitness going into this and the sting is definitely going to be out of the track and that's very good ground for her," Snowden said. "She will tick a few boxes on Saturday."
Snowden didn't confirm the Missile Stakes would be Tycoon Tara's last start but said she was coming towards the end of her career.
"This will determine it and there's no denying the fact she is into the latter stages of her career," Snowden said. "If she come out and blitzed them on Saturday you would rethink to maybe give her one more and see where you end up because you are getting closer and closer to missing the boat (breeding season).
"I'm pretty sure she will go to stud this year and we're looking at her welfare as well. I think if she happened to win she might still head that way."
Team Snowden will also saddle up That's A Good Idea ($26) in the Missile Stakes providing the Randwick track is not too wet. "He is going well, he is fit and the more recent racing he can get under his belt the better it is for him," Snowden said. "I still think he will run a solid race on Saturday providing it is not too wet."
Snowden also tipped Steyne to bounce back in Race 6 tomorrow. "Steyne is a momentum horse and he got offered none the other day," he said.
The Randwick track was rated a Soft 6 on Thursday.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>TARAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soft 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STAKES (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Romain</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Academy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tycoon Tara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P SnowdenK McEvoy156.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Gem ($9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LE ROMAINK LeesG Schofield858.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race: 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Romain ($2.20</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P SnowdenT Angland758.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MEMESJ CoyleMs R King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Snowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wahng Wah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S A GOOD IDEAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steyne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HARPER'S CHOICEG RyanJ Collett258.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EDGEM BellK Forrester458.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snowden</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Snowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Admiral Jello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 2 Missile Stakes (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GEMK LeesC Brown656.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Lees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONSTARB CavanoughJ Adams558.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Idea ($26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick Guineas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HorseTrainerJockeyBarrier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launch Code</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LANER QuintonA Adkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatt's Tiara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaumont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Gem</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
