<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418842488585169</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/same-sex-marriage:-malcolm-turnbull-calls-special-meeting/8771886</url>
  <title>Same-sex marriage: Malcolm Turnbull calls Liberal MPs to special meeting to debate party position</title>
  <content>
Federal Liberal MPs will debate their latest position on same-sex marriage at a special meeting called for Monday afternoon.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has told MPs to be back in Canberra a day early for the meeting.
The party is deeply divided over whether to change the law to allow same-sex couples to marry.
Mr Turnbull personally favours changing the law to allow same-sex marriage, but he is arguing the party needs to keep its promise to the electorate to hold a public vote, or plebiscite, first.
The meeting is an opportunity for MPs to express their views on the best option for dealing with the long-running issue.
, but others insist strongly the Coalition must stick to its pledge to have a plebiscite.
It is possible the Liberal meeting and a subsequent one which also includes Nationals MPs will decide to try again to have a plebiscite.
If the Senate again refused to pass the plebiscite, the fall-back position may be a postal ballot on the issue.
The same-sex marriage issue has exposed deep divisions within the Coalition and that tension is set to overshadow the early weeks of Parliament with some characterising it as a test of Mr Turnbull's leadership.
Liberal MP Warren Entsch -  - welcomed Monday's meeting.
"I am looking forward to it, I think it is great, we have been hoping for that for a while," Mr Entsch said this afternoon.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
