<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651418756589237543</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/tributes-have-been-paid-to-sue-lopicich/news-story/07de0eecb5c4a37e5261c074674ea70a</url>
  <title>'She made a difference to the lives of hundreds of dogs'</title>
  <content>
THE Perth mother who was fatally mauled by a dog she rescued has been remembered as a hero who made a difference in the lives of hundreds of dogs.
WA animal welfare group Dogs Behind Bars Rescue paid tribute to Sue Lopicich today in a moving Facebook post.
DBBR was founded last year by Natalie Plunkett who has years of experience with rescuing, rehabilitating and rehoming dogs.
Ms Plunkett and Claire Bingham-Hardacre lead a small team of volunteers on a mission to find new homes for unwanted or abandoned dogs.
"We are heartbroken to learn of Sue Lopicich's passing," the DBBR Facebook post said.
"Many of us at DBBR had the pleasure of knowing and working with Sue, and we wish to take some time to remember her and thank her for the hero she is.
"Sue stood for everything rescue is and should be. She believed in giving unwanted and forgotten dogs second chances and allowing them a safe space to decompress and gain confidence.
"She always carefully guided them through their difficulties, and each dog became her own for the time they were in her kennel.
"She made a difference in the lives of hundreds of dogs - most of whom are now in forever homes because of her."
The DBBR team said Ms Lopicich, 58, had a reputation for taking on particularly difficult dogs.
The bullmastiff-cross responsible for Tuesday's attack, named Stirling, was euthanised by a vet this morning.
There have been conflicting reports about the dog's behaviour.
Neighbour Greg Ball said he was saddened but not surprised to hear about the attack.
"Some dogs just can't be saved," Mr Ball said.
However DBBR said Stirling was a gentle dog who loved his "mum".
"(Sue's) years of experience and training allowed her to take the dogs no one else wanted and bring out the goodness in each of them," DBBR said.
"There has been much speculation about how these tragic events came about.
"What we do know is that Sue would be horrified by the attention being on background or breed of the dog involved in this sad situation.
"The dog in custody was a gentle sweet-natured boy who loved Sue. There was never a time that he had to be tied up when people came to the property, and he absolutely adored his mum Sue.
"The focus should remain on ensuring there is a fair and thorough investigation into the incident; finding care for Sue's remaining dogs at the property; and providing support to her loved ones, particularly her daughters."
DBBR ended their tribute by listing the names of the some of the dogs Ms Lopicich had helped on their journey to forever homes.
"We want to remember Sue for what she is: a hero and a caregiver with a heart of gold," DBBR said.
"She will always hold a special place in our hearts, and many dogs and people will know less good in the world because she is gone.
"Rest in peace Sue. Thank you for everything, and thank you from the dogs of DBBR who you helped on the way to their forever homes.
"Neera, Lil, Rigby, Missy, Bryce, Bella, Buddy, Kaiser, Hamish, Riley, Rosie, Shadow, Tigger, Anzac, Perry, Chopper, Boss, Buddha, Pirate, Zee, Cara, Justice, Buddy and Tommy."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Plunkett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Plunkett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Bingham-Hardacre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rigby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DBBR</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Lopicich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lopicich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dogs Behind Bars Rescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DBBR Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
