<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419443784018032</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/the-age-editorial/marriage-equality-impasse-poised-to-end-with-monday-liberal-meeting-20170803-gxouz1.html</url>
  <title>Marriage equality impasse poised to end with Monday Liberal meeting</title>
  <content>
The meeting of Liberal MPs that Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has scheduled for next Monday, the eve of the resumption of Parliament after the winter recess, creates a mechanism to finally end the impasse on marriage equality. A number of the politicians are expected to push for a free vote, which is the most sensible option.
An apotheosis is overdue; it has long been the overwhelming will of the people that this injustice ends. It is a cause of embarrassment - many would say shame - that Australia is the only industrialised English-speaking nation yet to stop blocking the right of certain people in love to get married. When this inevitable change occurs, perhaps very soon, the only thing that will happen is people in love will get married.
Research last year found majority support for marriage equality in all but one federal electorate. Polls have consistently shown as many as seven in 10 Australians want it. The annual Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia (HILDA) Survey released this week reported a "profound" increase in support for the rights of those in our community who are not heterosexual, estimated at more than 2 million people.
There are several scenarios of how events might unfold. A private bill introduced by a Liberal lawmaker might well be tested in the Senate. A similar thing is being considered for the lower house. Five Liberal parliamentarians have spoken in favour of engineering a vote.
It is clear the wasteful, expensive and potentially harmful plebiscite policy foisted upon the Liberal Party a few years ago by then prime minister Tony Abbott will not happen. Mr Turnbull honoured the deal he made with the party room at that time to take the policy to the 2016 election. He tried to deliver it but was blocked by the Senate. That is ample justification to abandon it in favour of what should have happened in the first place - a conscience vote in the Parliament. The idea of a postal "plebiscite", which would be open to legal challenge, is almost as disingenuous and just as unnecessary as Mr Abbott's original version.
The issue has been manipulated by Mr Abbott in his campaign to undermine Mr Turnbull's leadership. Mr Abbott is on shaky ground - he is unpopular in his party and in the wider community. Monday's meeting could offer Mr Turnbull a chance to demonstrate real leadership, and he and his party will further suffer if the issue is not resolved. The Prime Minister has shown strength by calling the meeting and by stating his colleagues have a right to cross the floor on moral issues. That opens the door. If they and the other MPs can manage to stride through it by bringing on a vote, it is likely to be carried. And that would be widely celebrated - by voters.

A note from the editor - Subscribers can get Age editor Alex Lavelle's exclusive weekly newsletter delivered to their inbox by signing up here:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Lavelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English-speaking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
