<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419486733691969</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/opinion/opinion-nbn-gay-marriage-the-battle-over-coal-are-all-victims-of-craven-and-stupid-policy/news-story/9af1cb502397974208f1b2dc948ddd77</url>
  <title>When stupidity stymies wisdom</title>
  <content>
AS you grow older, you imagine you will become wiser and that the mists of confusion and frustration that swirl through life will clear.
For those of more tender years anticipating this moment of revelation, this sudden emergence into the sharp, clear air of enlightenment, I have some bad news.
It doesn't happen.
If it did, I would be able to understand why the national broadband system which has cost something north of $60 billion, is a dud.
It was hailed as the internet superhighway along which we would all speed, our smiles of content reflected in the screens of our computers.
Instead, it provides significantly slower speeds than many users were enjoying under the old system.
So why not stick with the old system? Because it's been shut down to force you to use the new system so that the Government can claw back some of the billions is stands to lose on this hi-tech debacle.
Instead of the fastest download speeds in the world, we now some of the slowest. It's a disaster but no one in government seems to particularly care.
If I'd found wisdom I'd also understand why when this week Malaysian Airlines said they thought technological advances would allow the wreckage of MH370 to be found "eventually," no one questioned this indifference.
After all, Dr David Griffin from the CSIRO told a national marine conference in Darwin last month that he and his fellow scientists know "quite precisely where the plane is".
You would think that on hearing this, there would be a scramble by Malaysian Airlines and aircraft manufacturer Boeing to search the area identified.
Nope. One of the greatest aviation disasters in history yet there is a marked reluctance to pursue the cause.
Rogue pilot or catastrophic in-flight malfunction aboard the Boeing 777? The next time you take an international flight, chances are it will be on a Boeing 777.
It would be nice to know the answer, wouldn't it, but you could be forgiven for thinking that the airline and the aircraft manufacturer each has its own reason for not wanting to find out what that is.

The PM has been warned his leadership will be 'terminal' if party MPs cross the floor on marriage equality

PM urged to resolve same-sex marriage issue
Maybe I'd also be able to figure out why a nation so rich in resources is suffering an energy crisis.
In the absence of wisdom I'll offer the thought that stupidity on a grand scale and political cowardice are a few of the factors in play.
India's demand for fuel for its coal burning power stations will increase by 250 per cent over the next 20 years yet down here in little old Oz, there is hand wringing at the mere mention of building a single coal fired power plant.
Save the world and screw Australia!
One final thought. When the Republic of Ireland voted in favour of same sex marriage, only 60 per cent of the people entitled to vote did so.
What little wisdom I possess tells that the other 40 per cent was at home in bed, bored rigid by the endless, tiresome debate and incapable of movement. I know how they felt.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysian Airlines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr David Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSIRO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing 777</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republic of Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MH370</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
