<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419443784018057</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/19/31/prince-philip-marks-retirement-with-final-solo-engagement-in-london</url>
  <title>Prince Philip steps out of the spotlight with final parade in London</title>
  <content>
As the longest Royal Consort in history, Prince Philip has served his time.
On his last official day, he'd almost be forgiven for staying inside on this wet and windy London afternoon.
Yet that is not his way.
Especially when the occasion was a tribute to his beloved armed forces.
The last Date in the Dukes diary was for the Royal Marines. Since 1953, Prince Philip has been Captain-General of the Corp.

The Royal Marines is one of 785 organisations that Prince Philip has been patron of across his career.
Marines young and old paraded through the forecourt of Buckingham Palace today, before a rousing "three-cheers" for the Duke.

Related Articles

"I think we can safely say that his attitude towards the military and military charities is second to none," Brigadier Richard Spencer told 9NEWS.
Similar organisations to be supported by the Duke are no doubt just as grateful.
Hundreds of visitors watched the event from outside the Palace, protected by ponchos and brollies.
"I just think he's amazing, a great man," Sarah James from the (sunnier) Gold Coast said.
Yes, it hasn't been the most politically-correct career.

But when we remember the cringe-worthy quotes, keep in mind his record of public service:
More than 22,000 solo public engagements, close to 5500 speeches and the aforementioned contribution to various community groups.
At 96 years old, he's earned his retirement. 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain-General of the Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Marines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brigadier Richard Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Consort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
