<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419637057550733</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:44</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/bank-of-england-interest-rate-decision-inflation-report-august-2017-8</url>
  <title>Here comes the Bank of England...</title>
  <content>
LONDON - The Bank of England will deliver a snapshot of the bank's economic forecasts and thinking this Thursday lunchtime.

The central bank will release the decisions made during the August meeting of its Monetary Policy Committee on Thursday at 12.00 p.m. BST alongside its quarterly inflation report.

The MPC is not expected to make any changes to its two key policy tools, interest rates and quantitative easing. That will mean an unchanged base interest rate of 0.25% and a QE programme capped at a total of £435 billion pounds.

Given the slim chance of any change to policy, what will be most keenly watched by market participants is the potential for a shift in the bank's language in its official statements. Any change could be seen as a hint that an increase in interest rates could be on the horizon.

At the bank's last meeting in  While one of those who voted for a hike, Kristin Forbes, has now left the bank, the macroeconomic picture during the start of the summer suggested that a rates rise could be on the cards in August.

Chief Economist Andy Haldane made a hawkish shift in a speech a couple of weeks after June's decision, saying a "partial withdrawal of the additional policy insurance the MPC put in place last year would be prudent relatively soon." He effectively said that he is almost ready to increase rates.

However, in recent weeks other MPC members have confirmed their views that it is not yet the time to hike rates back to the 0.5% level they stood for seven years between the financial crisis and last August's post-Brexit vote interest rate cut.

that it must balance surging inflation brought on by the weakened pound since the referendum with the slowdown in the economy, dwindling consumer spending, and declining inward investment.

Inflation had surged as high as 2.9% in April and May, but moderated in June, dropping to 2.6%. This, many in the markets believe, has all but ended any chance of a hike this week.

Thursday also marks the release of the BoE's Inflation Report for the third quarter of the year, with Governor Mark Carney answering questions from the media at 12.30 p.m. BST.

This post will be updated once the bank's decisions are announced.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristin Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BoE's Inflation Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Economist Andy Haldane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Mark Carney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
