<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420216878148309</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/technology/science/incredible-pictures-of-feeding-sharks-dispels-myth-they-are-mindless-monsters/news-story/765481cc54982138d46c56d7f2b5f196</url>
  <title>Sharks snapped in feeding frenzy</title>
  <content>
FEW people would willingly jump into the water with a shark, let alone with one that is feeding.
But that's exactly what photographer and conservationist Tanya Houppermans has done to capture her "one in a million" shot of a sand tiger shark dissecting its way through a huge bait ball. Photographed from beneath, the image shows the top half of the shark's body diving into thousands of fish.
Ms Houppermans, 44, took the incredible series of photographs on July 10 and 11 in waters off the coast of Morehead City in North Carolina, where she has been shooting for the past eight years.
In all her time diving, the snapper said she had never seen a bait ball of the size she witnessed in July.
"I am always amazed by how incredibly graceful and beautiful sharks are," she said.
"Here is an animal that has been around in one form or another for a few hundred million years, and is so perfectly suited for its environment that you can't help but be awe-struck seeing one in the wild.

SHARKNADO! Unique pictures reveal stunning sand tiger sharks gliding through bait balls of tiny fish

This Jaws-dropping shot greeted a photographer as she got up close and personal with a group of sharks.Tanya Houppermans, 44, caught the moment as the sand tiger shark glided through a tunnel of tiny fish off the coast of North Carolina in the United States. PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

Sand tiger shark in bait balls. These stunning images get up close and personal with a group of sharks as they glide their way through gigantic bait balls. PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

Photographed from beneath a sand tiger shark, the image shows the animal as it penetrates a bait ball of thousands of fish, the top half of its body emerging out of the grouping. PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

Few people would willingly jump into the water with a shark, let alone with one that is feeding. But that's exactly what photographer and conservationist Tanya Houppermans has done to capture her "one in a million" shot of a sand tiger shark dissecting its way through a huge bait ball. PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

Ms Houppermans, 44, took the incredible series of photographs on July 10 and 11 in waters off the coast of Morehead City in North Carolina, where she has been shooting for the past eight years. PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

In all her time diving, the snapper said she had never seen a bait ball of the size she witnessed in July. "I am always amazed by how incredibly graceful and beautiful sharks are," she said. PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

Ms Houppermans hopes the images will dispel misconceptions about sharks, saying they are not creatures to be feared. Despite their ferocious appearance, there have been no reported human fatalities caused by a sand tiger shark. PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

Sand tiger sharks survive on a diet of bony fish, other sharks and crustaceans. With no reported human fatalities caused by a sand tiger shark, conservationist Tanya hopes her snaps will teach the public the truth about these awesome creatures.PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

The bait balls within which the sharks swim are constantly moving, and can sometimes measure as much as several storeys high, PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS

"Unfortunately, popular media has propagated the myth over the last several decades that sharks are mindless monsters." said photographer Tanya Houppermans. PICTURE: TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS
"They will look at you and watch you; sometimes their curiosity will motivate them to come in for a closer look, and other times they'll err on the side of caution and retreat."
Ms Houppermans hopes the images will dispel misconceptions about sharks, saying they are not creatures to be feared.
Despite their ferocious appearance, there have been no reported human fatalities caused by a sand tiger shark.
"One of the biggest misconceptions surrounding sharks is that they will seek out and attack people who happen to be in the water nearby. This is simply untrue," she said.
"Sharks are often quite cautious and timid around people. They will typically retreat if they feel threatened."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 10</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JAW-DROPPING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morehead City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Houppermans, 44</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TANYA HOUPPERMANS/CATERS</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Houppermans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya Houppermans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Carolina</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharknado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
