<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420285597626773</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/sydney-sweet-spot-in-australia-for-leasing-20170801-gxnhcg</url>
  <title>Sydney the sweet spot in Australia for leasing </title>
  <content>
Landlords in Sydney can enjoy further rental growth and improving conditions with office vacancy sitting at 5.9 per cent, the second lowest recording since January 2009.
With the vacancy rate now well below the city's historical average of 9.2 per cent, the country's largest unlisted office real estate funds are all well ahead on returns compared with retail and industrial sectors of the market.
Charter Hall's head of office Adrian Taylor, who helped the Charter Hall's Prime Office Fund to a 19.2 return in fiscal 2017, said the new infrastructure development in Sydney had been a major drawcard for tenants' leasing decisions in the CBD.
"Tenants are looking past the short-term inconvenience of infrastructure activity on Sydney's George Street to secure what will be prime office locations," Mr Taylor said. "One of the key drivers for tenants like NAB, HSBC, Clyde & Co and We Work taking up space at Charter Hall's redeveloped 333 George was the delivery of the new light rail, revitalisation of Martin Place and building amenity."
Upper grades

The reduction in Sydney's vacancy rate from 6.2 per cent was due to withdrawals of office space from the market, for the Metro and for residential conversions as well as a positive tenant demand (although the demand is lower than historical averages).
Property Council NSW executive director Jane Fitzgerald said strong demand was particularly noticeable in the upper grades of office space such as premium properties where the vacancy rate dropped from 12.5 per cent to 9.5 per cent.
Colliers International's national director for leasing Cameron Williams said sublease space in Sydney, now only a third of its historical average, may turn back up.
"We expect sublease space may make a return with tenants seeking to lock in future growth opportunities by space banking today in a period of reducing supply," Mr Williams said.

"This is occurring with some confidence that sublease space will be offloaded quickly (not typically experienced) meaning tenant costs for surplus space can be offset as they take control of their growth."
He said that as leasing conditions remained tight until the market enters its next supply cycle from 2019, the Sydney market would continue to see effective rental growth and declining vacancy across all building grades for the rest of the year.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clyde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charter Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charter Hall's Prime Office Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colliers International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's George Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
