<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419065826888617</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/ragata-shines-for-lighthouses-during-some-bleak-ti/3208373/</url>
  <title>Ragata shines for Lighthouses during some bleak times</title>
  <content>
RUGBY UNION: Caloundra's reeling on the back of a three-game losing streak but winger Maisiri Ragata has been a bright spot for the Lighthouses, according to pivot Mackenzie Burgess.
The Arthur Street side is guaranteed to finish the regular season in second place, amid four teams, after 13 of 15 rounds.
But it's endured a tough run of games.
"We're pretty devastated to be honest," Burgess said.
"We've had a lot of guys in and out of the side through work and being away but when it comes to crunch times in games we give away penalties to let the other teams roll down the field and it's really shooting us in the foot."
But Ragata has offered the side some spark.
"He's been really good in the last couple of weeks," Burgess said.
"He was on the fringes of A-grade for a while there but in the last few weeks he's sort of cemented his spot."
New to the club this year, the Fijian has emerged an important player in the lead-up to the three-team play-offs.
"He's usually a loose forward but this year we've got him playing wide because we've got some pretty good loose forwards and he's been really good out wide," Burgess said.
"He's really strong in defence and he always goes hunting for the ball and gets these sneaky pick and drives where he creates line breaks."
Caloundra will host a desperate University of the Sunshine Coast on Saturday (3.30pm), when unbeaten Noosa entertains Maroochydore.
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
TERRY Fewtrell's new book shares the history of Palmwoods.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maisiri Ragata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TERRY Fewtrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgess</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday (3.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ragata</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fijian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackenzie Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
