<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651419533978333376</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/breaking-news/trumps-talk-of-complimentary-calls-untrue/news-story/8d4d56ff6cb2fb862321d686a4605b1f</url>
  <title>Trump's talk of complimentary calls untrue</title>
  <content>
The White House says compliments President Donald Trump described receiving from the Mexican president and the Boy Scouts of America happened - just not on the phone as Trump had claimed.
"I wouldn't say it was a lie. That's a pretty bold accusation," White House spokeswoman Sarah Huckabee Sanders told reporters.
"The conversations took place, they just simply didn't take place over a phone call ... He had them in person."
It was the latest episode in Trump's rocky relationship with facts, raising questions about his credibility six tumultuous months into his presidency.
A Quinnipiac University National Poll conducted on July 27-August 1 found 34 per cent of Americans say Trump is "honest" - a record low for him.
Sanders was responding to questions about a statement from the Mexican government denying what Trump described as a recent phone call with President Enrique Pena Nieto.
Trump said on Monday that Pena Nieto had called him to praise his immigration policies.
"As you know, the border was a tremendous problem and they're close to 80 per cent stoppage. Even the president of Mexico called me. They said their southern border, very few people are coming because they know they're not going to get through our border, which is the ultimate compliment," Trump said.
Sanders said he had been "referencing a conversation that they had had at the G20 summit where they specifically talked about the issues that he referenced".
Meanwhile, the Boy Scouts denied on Wednesday the head of the youth organisation called Trump to shower praise on his politically aggressive speech to its national jamboree in West Virginia.
President Randall Stephenson and chief scout executive Mike Surbaugh later apologised to scouting community members who were offended by Trump's rhetoric.
Trump told The Wall Street Journal in an interview last week: "I got a call from the head of the Boy Scouts saying it was the greatest speech that was ever made to them, and they were very thankful."
Sanders said the president was making reference to "multiple members of the Boy Scout leadership" who "congratulated him, praised him and offered quite powerful compliments following his speech".
But she acknowledged no member of the leadership called the president.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanders</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Scouts of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinnipiac University National Poll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Virginia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pena Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Scout</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Surbaugh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27-August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Randall Stephenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Enrique Pena Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
