<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420530410768202</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/fire-star-garbin-happy-to-give-back-in-nt-trip/news-story/bd8afa8c77c1281d33d9e57c25a5c571</url>
  <title>Fire star gives back in NT trip</title>
  <content>
TOWNSVILLE Fire championship winner Darcee Garbin has returned to North Queensland after spending the past week mentoring Indigenous girls in Alice Springs.
Earlier this week the 23-year-old Fire and Townsville Flames star visited the Northern Territory with Charity Bounce, a not-for-profit organisation focused on creating positive change for disadvantaged individuals and communities.
Working alongside NBL legend Cal Bruton and Illawarra Hawks swingman Kevin White, Garbin participated in the organisation's Stand Tall program which provided basketball and leadership programs for young people, with a focus on Indigenous and culturally diverse groups including newly arrived refugees.
"It's an amazing program," Garbin said.
"I'm extremely grateful to Charity Bounce for giving me the opportunity to participate in such a good cause.
"While I enjoying travelling across the country playing in the WNBL, the opportunity to connect - and hopefully inspire - the young women and girls that I meet is something that I never expected."
Charity Bounce is a not-for-profit organisation that exists to inspire positive change to overcome disadvantage for individuals and communities.
With a focus on Aboriginal or Torres Strait Islanders and Culturally Diverse communities, including newly arrived refugees they aim to move people toward a more positive future through the development of sports, the arts, health, education and employment focused social programs.
Garbin and her Townsville QBL teammates face a gruelling triple header in southeast Queensland this weekend, starting against USC Rip City tonight.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charity Bounce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cal Bruton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stand Tall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOWNSVILLE Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville QBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Flames</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Culturally Diverse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garbin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Hawks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC Rip City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcee Garbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
