<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420483166126745</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/flashback-2000s-lot-has-changed-not-our-soul/3205659/</url>
  <title>FLASHBACK 2000s: A lot has changed, but not our soul</title>
  <content>
CHILDREN sprint through the sand, ploughing into the ocean before their parents have time to cap off the sunscreen.

Clusters of teenagers cruise by on pushbikes; loaded homemade surfboard racks strapped to their wheels.   

The salty air feels like opium to your lungs and the temperature is as warm as the smiles from passing strangers and familiar faces.  

It could be a scene from the 60s, 80s or today, which is what makes this region so special for Deputy Mayor and family man Tim Dwyer.  

He says a lot has changed on the Coast in the past 50 years, but its soul has never blurred.   

"I was born here in 63 and it's always been a changing area, that's nothing new, but it's still the same Sunshine Coast," he said.   

To celebrate the 50th anniversary of the naming of the region, we're going back through each decade from the 60s to today, telling the stories of the Coast through the eyes of our locals.   

This is the fifth part of the series - the 'now'.   

The Sunshine Coast today could be defined as a time of change, innovation and growth. But it's the region's ability to take on all this while remaining true to its character that Cr Dwyer says makes it so unique.   

"I think I would speak for a lot of the long-time residents when I say, yes at times we yearn for the old days when it wasn't congested and there weren't as many people, but we've grown up with so many changes and we accept that it's always going to be like that," he said.   

"I still think it's as beautiful as it was when I was a kid."   

While the Coast has long been known for its tourism and construction industries, in recent years Cr Dwyer said another industry had joined the podium.   

"Health and wellbeing has emerged and would have to be one of our biggest employers at the moment," he said.    "It goes hand-in-hand with the growth of our area, but also the aging demographic who retire here."  

Proof of that is the $1.8billion Sunshine Coast Hospital which opened its doors earlier this year.

"We've got the newest hospital in Australia, and the best kitted-out one, which has shined a brand new light on the health industry on the Coast," Cr Dwyer said.   

The health boom has seen the region continue to attract highly-educated professionals, as well as create them from the grassroots with the University of the Sunshine Coast which has continued to fertilise minds in the 2000s and show locals they don't need to move away to get a quality education.   

In the past 10 years, the Coast has seen a council amalgamation of Maroochy, Caloundra and Noosa shires in 2008 to form the Sunshine Coast Regional Council and a de-amalgamation of Noosa from the rest of the Coast in 2014. 

Cr Dwyer, who was initially with the Caloundra council, said the amalgamation was a tethering that needed to happen.   

"There was a lot of angst with the amalgamation, some people really didn't want it and some did," he said.   

"I didn't specifically call out for it, but I didn't disagree either. I thought as a region we needed to realise we're all one community despite boundaries on a map.  

"We weren't collaborating as well as we should have, there was some competitiveness between the councils and there was this parochialism that stopped us from being as good as we could be.  

"Now we are the fourth-largest local government in Australia and we've had opportunities we never would have seen if we had stayed separate."  

He encouraged those who feared change on the Coast to remember who we were as people and be confident we would stay true to that.   

"Sunshine Coast people are passionate about our community, they're not extreme greenies but they care about the environment and they're not afraid to give you a serve if you throw litter out the window," he said.

"They're laid-back and have a good sense of humour, will always say g'day and be up for a beer or a coffee.  

"They're the same type of people from 50 years ago. We're in good hands."  

Cr Dwyer lives in Caloundra with his two young children, James, 9, Daisy, 5, and wife Kelli, and said the future of the Coast held as much hope and opportunity as it always had.   

"We live here because we love it. And so does everyone else."

This Flashback series is brought to you by Yaroomba Beach - a world-class destination for all. 
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James, 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daisy, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Dwyer</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
