<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420517525865968</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/city-of-casey-councillors-told-to-stop-focusing-on-pet-national-projects-by-mayor/news-story/ae32fcb1201d4d7994be53f2ffb9ba67</url>
  <title>Stop raising federal issues, council told</title>
  <content>
CASEY mayor Sam Aziz has chided councillors for using meetings to push personal ideologies and pet projects outside the jurisdiction of local government.
The rebuke follows national controversy over a vote for compulsory military service earlier this month, and the latest "pet project" brought to chambers for debate by right wing Christian Rosalie Crestani - a push for the city to take a formal stand against marriage equality.
Cr Aziz said notices of motion that referred to state and federal issues distracted the media and the public from the "good work" council was doing.

Cr Aziz said while it was well known he did not support marriage equality, there was a difference between advocating for state and federal projects that would affect the way the council worked, and pushing personal ideologies.
"(The conscription motion) was taken and commented on Australia-wide and we copped a lot of criticism across our nation," he said.
"Whether it is right or wrong to raise this issue this is a federal issue, and it should not be coming to council.
"What's next, do we write to NASA calling for human settlement on Mars?
"I want us to focus on the things we were elected to do."
Cr Crestani wanted Casey to write to all federal members of the senate and lower house to present Casey's position on the Marriage Act that marriage be solely between a man and woman - something she said represented the views of most Australians.
Cr Crestani also presented a petition with 700 signatures from church groups in Casey opposing marriage equality, saying marriage was a "sacred covenant with God" and society would be damaged if marriage between same-sex partners was allowed.
"What price do we put on marriage; money doesn't matter if you do not have a healthy society," she said.
"(Allowing marriage equality) reminds me of the hedonistic end of the Roman Empire ... this could be the end of our nation if the Marriage Act is tampered with."
Only Cr Milla Gilic supported Cr Crestani with Crs Tim Jackson and Wayne Smith opposing it and Crs Aziz, Susan Serey, Damien Rosario, Rex Flannery, Gary Rowe and Geoff Ablett abstaining.
Cr Crestani asked if Casey could send the petition to the Federal Government on behalf of the residents but was told no.
According to the last census, 24.3 per cent of people in the City of Casey stated that they had no religion, compared to 31.7 per cent of the rest of Victoria.
This year's HILDA survey, run by the University of Melbourne, found 67 per cent of women and 59 per cent of men said gay couples should have the same marriage, parenting and employment rights as heterosexual couples.
AGENDA BENDERS:
n  July 18: Cr Rex Flannery puts forward notice of motion for federal government to consider bringing back mandatory military service;
n June 6: Casey Council uses a meeting to stand against the State Government's educational programs Building Respectful Relationships and Safe Schools. Led by councillors Rosalie Crestani and Amanda Stapledon, councillors vote to write to State and Federal Minister for Education, Opposition Education Minister and all State and Federal MPs expressing concerns about the programs' content, and calling for the immediate withdrawal of funding;
n August, 2016: Cr Amanda Stapledon uses meeting to call for Royal Commission into abuse in disability care;
n March 2015: Cr Stapledon puts forward motion to block use of the cyclone wire cages now allowed around MMA fighters in Victoria;
n 2014: Casey Council throws its support behind the Liberal party plan for East West link and calls on residents to do the same, despite project between the eastern freeway at Clifton Hill and the Western Ring Rd being more than 40km from the City of Casey.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crs Aziz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Stapledon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Milla Gilic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Empire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Flannery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Amanda Stapledon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Aziz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Rosalie Crestani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Stapledon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifton Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Respectful Relationships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia-wide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Rosario</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crs Tim Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Aziz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Rex Flannery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Ablett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Serey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Ministers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosalie Crestani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Crestani</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Ring Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safe Schools</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITY of Casey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
