<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420534705735569</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-east/jeff-kennett-says-filthy-bbq-area-at-glenferrie-oval-being-used-for-drugs-drinking-must-go/news-story/57039f787df03d4da0b28207c9910efe</url>
  <title>Horrified Kennett says grubby BBQ must go</title>
  <content>
FORMER Victorian Premier Jeff Kennett says Boroondara Council must remove a barbecue area in Hawthorn that residents say has become a haven for drinking and drug use.
The former Hawthorn Football Club president said he was horrified to read an article in last week's Progress Leader showing the amount of vandalism that has become a common place at Glenferrie Oval - the Hawks' former home ground - and has called on the council to do something about it.
"This is extremely disappointing," Mr Kennett said.
"This falls in the remit of Boroondara Council and unless they can ensure better use of the area, more appropriate use, and in particular somehow stop the abuse that leads to drug equipment and broken glass, then they've got no alternative than to remove the barbecue."

Mr Kennett said reading about threats to people's property had left him particularly disturbed.
"These are wonderful parklands which should be there for everyone's use," he said.
"It's not feasible to have someone there 24/7, you can understand that, but this barbecue does seem to be in an unusual site and that's why I think the best thing to do would be to remove it.
"It's a public space and I'm in favour of it being that, but it has to be a safe public place."
Hawthorn state Liberal MP John Pesutto said the time had come to clean up the area and he would raise it in State Parliament this week.
"Anti-social behaviour in the Glenferrie Oval precinct is worsening and drug trafficking and use appears to be on the rise," Mr Pesutto said.

"A safety review of the precinct is urgently required and must include not only the barbecue facility but the buildings and general area around the oval.
"It has reached such an acute level that I will be raising the matter in Parliament this week."
Boroondara Council's director of environment and infrastructure Bruce Dobson said there had been a barbecue in the area since 2005 and the most recent upgrade happened as part of the of Hawthorn Aquatic Centre development in 2014.
"The Glenferrie Oval surface is inspected for hazards by council officers every fortnight and the barbecue is cleaned twice a week in winter and three times a week in summer," Mr Dobson said.
"In light of the anti-social behaviour that is occurring, we are increasing our attention to the area and reviewing opportunities such as increased lighting.
"We are also in discussions with Police about potentially installing CCTV to assist in the apprehension of those who are breaking the law."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Dobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Premier Jeff Kennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP John Pesutto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kennett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pesutto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti Social</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn Aquatic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boroondara Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Progress Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenferrie Oval</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
