<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420560475540001</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/golden-age-adds-artist-bill-henson-to-the-mix-20170731-gxm39q</url>
  <title>Golden Age adds Henson to the mix</title>
  <content>
It worked nicely for the Medicis and Leonardo Da Vinci and then for Philip II of Spain and Titian.
Now dumpling king-turned-developer Jeff Xu and artist Bill Henson are putting a contemporary twist on one of the oldest arrangements in the arts, that of the patron and the artist.
Mr Xu's Golden Age has commissioned a series of works from  Henson, who has a celebrated reputation for his brooding, moody and,
The work will have a permanent home in the lobby of the  in the Melbourne CBD overlooking state parliament.

supplied

Henson accepts commissions only rarely, he told The Australian Financial Review.

"If I don't have an idea that I think is potentially really interesting then I tend to decline almost everything I'm asked to do."
It won't be his nudes - which have  - that grace the lobby of 85 Spring Street, but rather a series of moving pictures, time-based photography that incorporate a sense of changing seasons, weather,and fluctuating light, inspired partly by nearby parkland.
All that will be brought into "a conversation" with the built environment,  Henson said.
"My idea was to introduce a sense of the passage of time. What I was dreaming might be possible technically and physically did seem to appeal to them. That's a very fortunate accident."

Mr Xu's bid for high art on Spring Street, just around the corner from the Paris end of Collins Street, is a neat piece of product differentiation from another well known high-rise apartment tower now emerging at the other end of the city, being developed by Singapore's Fragrance Group.
The distinctively curving shape of the Bourke Street tower at the western end of the city, designed by architects Elenberg Fraser has a distinct pop culture inspiration,  of pop star Beyonce, in her 'Ghost' video.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elenberg Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Age</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Henson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip II of Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Xu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Xu's Golden Age</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonardo Da Vinci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore's Fragrance Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medici</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Xu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
