<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420573360442213</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/sophisticated-traveller/uluru-why-celebrities-struggle-to-describe-it-20170719-gxet2s</url>
  <title>Movie stars, royals, models or mums and dads, Uluru casts its spell on us all</title>
  <content>
by
Amelia Lester

This is a special feature in association with Ayers Rock Resort.
Celebrities aren't usually shy, but Uluru has a way of rendering them speechless. After Prince William and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge watched the sun set there in 2014, and were visibly moved by the spectacle, the headline in the British Telegraph was "".
Nicole Kidman, who made her first trip in 2015 for the cover of Vogue Australia, seemed similarly overwhelmed, telling that magazine: "It's just a very, very magical, special place." In an email, Chris Hemsworth, who took his kids last year with wife Elsa Pataky, grasped for superlatives: "awesome ... fascinating and inspiring". And Russell Crowe's view, as outlined on Twitter in May this year is simple: "Every school kid should visit Uluru."
Uluru's enduring star power is such that adequate words are difficult to find, while cliches are commonplace. How many times have you heard it described as a "looming monolith", for instance? In fact, Uluru isn't even a single rock. Rather, it's a massive rock formation which extends far below and around the visible tip. Millions of years ago, it was part of a mountain range that eroded, leaving what geologists refer to as an inselberg, or island mountain.

Supplied

There was once so much more here; perhaps that's why the visitor to Uluru always feels a little alone. There can be catharsis in that. Robyn Davidson, writing in The Monthly magazine about her Outback adventure memoir Tracks, described her journey through the Red Centre as an attempt to "shed burdens ... to pare away what was unnecessary".

And, perhaps, to challenge assumptions. When explorer William Gosse sighted Uluru in 1873, he wrote home of his astonishment at its "peculiar appearance". From a distance, and with his view obscured by sand dunes, he thought he was looking at a series of caves.
It continued to defy expectations as Europeans attempted to settle the area, unsuccessfully, for the next 60 years. It wasn't until the late 1940s that tourists - and miners - began to arrive. An enterprising local, Len Truit, began leading tours from Alice Springs and established a base camp. By 1958, 2296 visitors had travelled for up to 12 hours in the mud and dust to see it for themselves. As the Alice Springs road improved, and with an airstrip right next to the rock, that number climbed to more than 23,000 by 1968, and has since grown tenfold.
The area's first people were all but forgotten in the tourism boom. A climbing apparatus was erected on the rock face; international hotel chains muscled in. "A dingo ate my baby" became an international catchphrase. Even as the Uluru-Kata Tjuta National Park was dual World Heritage listed (for outstanding natural and cultural values), the hotels and camping ground fell into disrepair, awash in a tide of tacky "I Climbed Ayers Rock" T-shirts.
10,000-year history

Louie Douvis

The land around Uluru has been home to the Anangu people for 10,000 years, and Uluru marks the site of significant events from their ancestral period. Yet it wasn't until 1985 - two years after Princess Diana gingerly climbed the rusty red face in a white cotton dress - that the National Park was handed back to its traditional owners. Until 1993, it was officially known as Ayers Rock. It has only been since 2010, when the Indigenous Land Corporation , that the cultural significance of the site has taken centre stage for tourists. Today, at the base there is a sign, gently but firmly worded, which tells visitors that to climb the rock is to trample on a traditional route of great cultural and historical meaning. Even disregarding that, however, climbing is a perilous undertaking - yet the practice persists.
It's hard to understand that decision when there are so many other ways to experience Uluru's many facets. Bike riding, in particular, is popular. The easy one-and-a-half-hour cycle around the 9.4 kilometre circumference is an attractive option compared with the more arduous four-hour walk.
Exploring the base is the best way to appreciate that this is a series of rocks, not just one. Honeycombed crevices and caves give way to watering holes such as Mutitjulu, where tiny tjanpi birds - one of 178 species of birds in the park - dart between trees and sing in celebration of recent rain.
Tranquillity is abundant, yet stillness never lasts: a frog croaks, a desert oak sighs, something scaly scurries through the spinifex. In winter, when the flies are less assertive, you can enjoy a picnic lunch by one of the picturesque gullies.

Louie Douvis

As you make your way around, you will come across views of Uluru you've never seen before. That's because there are rules in place that forbid photography depicting significant ancestral sites, which means it is most often seen from one angle, or in silhouette. What seems an oblong in pictures reveals itself to be infinitely more complicated: a geometric as well as geologic wonder made up of sharp corners, jagged cliffs, deep recessions and sweeping fin-like curves.
The only constant is the delineation between red dust and blue sky. It's an outline so stark, it can look almost fake. When the sun is low, the contrast becomes sharper as Uluru glows like a lantern.
Even the most seasoned of travel writers, Jan Morris, was confounded by Ayers Rock, as it was called when she visited it. Indeed, it became something of a fixation. Her first impressions were not necessarily positive: "It is the most fearful of landscapes, more terrible by far than Sahara, painted a queer cruel red and corrugated by grotesque erosions."
But then the mood (Uluru's, or maybe Morris') changed: the wind whistled, a rock pool ruffled. Morris concluded that at Uluru we are "removed from the plane of the ordinary". And isn't that what all travellers search for?

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jan Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robyn Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Kidman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vogue Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayers Rock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelia Lester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru-Kata Tjuta National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayers Rock Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Len Truit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hemsworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Crowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sahara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elsa Pataky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Gosse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duchess of Cambridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Land Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Climbed Ayers Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mutitjulu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anangu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Heritage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
