<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420569065474812</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/cbd/forget-commonwealth-banks-98b-profit-next-week-ian-narev-will-be-explaining-cuckoo-smurfing-20170802-gxnwlz.html</url>
  <title>Forget Commonwealth Bank's $9.8b profit next week, Ian Narev will be explaining 'cuckoo smurfing'</title>
  <content>
The Commonwealth Bank reports its full-year results next Wednesday, but chief executive Ian Narev no longer has to worry about the forecast $9.8 billion profit dominating the headlines. Not after the bombshell from Austrac on Thursday that the bank had allegedly missed roughly 50,000 suspected money-laundering transactions of about $625 million. 
The CommBank boss has the weekend to bone up on new terms he might have to get his head around next week - like "cuckoo smurfing".Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
This is a form of money laundering that involves the transfer of money between associates within separate countries in a manner that avoids the need for these parties to transfer money internationally. Which basically means they square off their accounts without money crossing any borders. 
Explaining that in plain English shouldn't be a problem for a former McKinsey partner and Kiwi child actor like Ian. Photo: Louie Douvis
The concern for analysts and investors is the fact that the court documents filed by Austrac state that cash deposits through the bank's whiz-bang Intelligent Deposit Machines (IDMs), went from zero in 2012 to more than $1 billion a month as of May last year. 
Can you imagine the fees the banks must charge for a service that allows you to anonymously deposit up to $20,000, have it counted instantly, credited instantly, and available for transfer anywhere around the globe? What if this takes a hit? 

And this does not take into account another potential threat: bitcoin. 
"We are reviewing the nature of the proceedings and will have more to say on the specific claims in due course," said CommBank in reply to Austrac's legal proceedings. We assume this means that nobody at the bank has lost their job over this yet. 
A fine bromance 

There is so much happening in James Packer-land that it is hard to keep up. 
On Thursday he officially rejoined the Crown (casino) Resorts board, along with the ever-loyal Guy Jalland.
Along with John Alexander, Jalland has been a mainstay of Packer's inner circle. 
It was Guy who stood up at the AGM of rival casino operator Echo Entertainment (now Star Entertainment) in 2011 and  of the company's 10 per cent ownership cap. 
It precipitated Packer's attempt to snatch control of the rival group so he could build the monstrosity that is now known as Crown Sydney. But that's another story.  
The other news is that the new floozies in Packer's life, including former CPH boss and Crown chairman Rob Rankin, have definitely left the pack. 
Last week, Packer's CPH backed out of the investment vehicle he owned with Rankin, Pacific Point Partners (PPP). 
The news surfaced in substantial shareholder notices from Charlie Aitken's Contango Asset Management. PPP halved its stake to 10 per cent citing the end of its association with Packer.
On the same day, Packer's CPH sold the shares it directly owned in Contango. It may have been a modest profit by billionaire standards, but Packer made a cracking return on his money, having bought shares at 60¢, and sold out less than a year later for more than $1 each.  
All for one 

Michael Cameron's $1 billion-plus profit at Suncorp - which did not go down well with the market - got overshadowed by all the news at Commonwealth Bank.
But CBD thought it was worth reporting that his remuneration topped $5.5 million, which means he has taken home almost $11 million in his two years in charge of the group. 
The curious bit, as pointed out by our AFR colleague Chanticleer, was that Cameron decided that all of his executives got exactly the same short-term incentive - 94 per cent of their respective targets - under his new One Suncorp model. 
CBD will be impressed when he gives them all the same base pay as well. 
Recent departees did not miss out on the largesse, either. Suncorp's former chief transformation officer, Clayton Herbert, who transformed himself out of the job less than a year after he started, picked up a $775,000 termination payment. 
And the former head of Suncorp's banking and wealth management division, John Nesbitt, who "retired" last year, collected a $949,000 termination payment.  
Cameron is lucky enough to pick up money just by hanging around. This includes 240,000 shares that vest over three years, if he stays in the job, to compensate him for incentives forgone at former employer GPT. 
This stock was worth more than $3.2 million on Thursday, despite the shares tanking more than 6 per cent after the result to $13.60. 
Follow CBD on . Got a tip? 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer-land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Rankin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rankin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank's $9.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Aitken's Contango Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton Herbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Point Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Jalland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Suncorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Packer</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Packer's CPH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cameron's $1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanticleer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Nesbitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jalland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommBank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Echo Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
