<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420569065474713</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/loy-yang-b-discussions-turn-to-banks-and-their-assurances-20170803-gxomgm</url>
  <title>Loy Yang B discussions turn to banks and their assurances</title>
  <content>
It's less than four weeks until final bids for Engie's Loy Yang B power generator and those in the final round are in the throes of serious discussions with banks around locking down financing, sources told Street Talk. 
The conversations haven't been easy ones as most of the big four banks and even several US lenders have shied away from stumping up funds for coal fired generators.
Sources suggested that the bulk of the financing would come from Asia-based banks, but they too were seeking extra assurances from bidders. 
Those assurances include loans can be re-paid more quickly - through instalments - over a multi-year timeframe, which would drag on the new owner's cashflow.

The banks know there is some uncertainty about the generator's future revenues, as it lacks long-term contracts and is entangled in regulatory risks linked to electricity prices.

Blackstone is among final round acquirers that will look to maximise debt funding. A
Alinta Energy owner Chow Tai Fook Enterprises and Delta Energy (owned by interests held by Trevor St Baker) are also in the final round of the Rothschild-run sale process.
Elsewhere, Alinta Energy has emerged as the potential key rival to EnergyAustralia for the two gas-fired power plants in Victoria being sold by IFM Investors.
The near-1000 megawatts of capacity, split between the Newport plant near Melbourne's CBD and the Jeeralang generator 6km south of Morwell, is expected to match up well with Alinta's growing retail position in the eastern states.
This column understands EnergyAustralia is keen to keep control over the offtake from the plants even after its existing contract expires at the end of March 2019. It may not want to risk a rival industry player taking control of the two plants that would not want to extend the current contract.
 
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IFM Investors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loy Yang B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor St Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alinta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeeralang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chow Tai Fook Enterprises</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rothschild-run</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alinta Energy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Engie's Loy Yang B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnergyAustralia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
