<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420431626518181</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/old-band-back-together-for-peter-costellos-surprise-60th-birthday-party-20170802-gxo7vd</url>
  <title>Old band back together for Peter Costello's surprise 60th birthday party</title>
  <content>
The sticky pots and Peking duck pancakes were doing double-time Thursday night in establishment Melbourne eatery Bamboo House as former federal treasurer Peter Costello was the happy recipient of a surprise 60th birthday party thrown in his honour.
Partakers of the kung pao chicken at the Chinese power eatery included a who's who of former Costello staffers and Liberal party acolytes.
Cabinet ministers Mitch Fifield and Kelly O'Dwyer downed a dim sum or three with the birthday boy, speaker of the house Tony Smith, Victorian shadow treasurer Michael O'Brien, ScoMo COS Phil Gaetjens, chair of NSW competition regulator IPART, Peter Boxall, and the Lowy Institute's Mike Callaghan were also among the revellers in a crowd rounded out by Barton Deakin's David Alexander and PCost's colleagues at advisory firm ECG, Jonathan Epstein and David Gazard.
No word on whether Warwick Capper made another Bamboo House appearance, Stuart Wood - more's the pity.

We're told the nation's former chief number cruncher - and current chairman of Nine - had no idea the shin-dig had been planned. His surprise upon entering his favourite noodle house to discover a gathering of old comrades lying in wait was genuine.

We're furthermore told that as the libations kicked in and the night deepened, the heady combination of all that hoi sin and free-flowing Tsingtao plus the excitement of having the old band back together, talk inevitably turned to once again combining forces and mounting a full-scale Costello revival. The comeback we had to have?
Meanwhile, across the Coorong, it will be a celebration of a different kind in Adelaide as Qantas chairman Leigh Clifford's mum, Helen Clifford celebrates her 95th birthday on Saturday. Our nonagarian party spies report she's planning a long-lunch with nine of her 'gal pals' in a 'secret Adelaide party location'. We're not sure whether we're more impressed that she's turning 95 or that at that age she can muster nine gal-pals sufficiently mobile to party. Respect.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Clifford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ScoMo COS Phil Gaetjens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowy Institute's Mike Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Clifford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Capper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Gazard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Costello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coorong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bamboo House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tsingtao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Fifield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Boxall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barton Deakin's David Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPART</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Epstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
