<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420560475540008</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/the-economy/some-ethnic-groups-predisposed-to-deal-in-cash-says-black-economy-taskforce-paper-20170803-gxoe1y.html</url>
  <title>Some ethnic groups 'predisposed' to deal in cash: government taskforce</title>
  <content>
Refugees would be able to work while awaiting decisions on their refugee status under a proposal by a government taskforce, which says barring them from working increases the propensity for illegal cash economy activity.
And student visa holders could be allowed to work more than 40 hours a fortnight to avoid the same problem, in an option canvassed in a consultation paper released this week by the federal government's Black Economy Taskforce.Photo: Tanya Lake
The taskforce, headed by Board of Tax chairman Michael Andrew, also called on business, professional bodies and ethnic and religious community leaders to suggest ways the government could reshape cultural norms that have led to illegal cash economy activity becoming .
The paper said countering the cash economy was as much a cultural challenge as an economic one. The taskforce wants to help the federal government claw back an estimated $15 billion in lost federal tax revenue and illegitimate welfare payments due to the black economy.Photo: Louise Kennerley
There were "a variety of beliefs, assumptions and suppositions which people draw on to excuse, defend or justify operating in the shadows" and "particular ethnic, demographic and occupational groups may be reluctant to depart from established practices", it said.
Tighten visa rules?

Under current rules, student visa holders are barred from working more than 40 hours a fortnight while their courses are in session. The paper said this was a major contributor to the black economy.

"They [stakeholders] point out that foreign students who cannot afford to comply with this work restriction have no choice but to go underground," it said.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"As a result, a sizeable and rapidly growing pool of vulnerable employees is created. It is no surprise, in these circumstances, that cases of exploitation, bordering on slavery, have come to light."Photo: Erin Jonasson
It proposed a range of remedies including relaxing or eliminating the 40-hour restriction, not allowing foreign students to work at all, or better enforcement of existing rules.
The paper also highlighted the plight of those awaiting decisions on their refugee status.Photo: Louie Douvis
"Their visas do not allow them to work at all, forcing many into the black economy," it said.
But it also questioned whether tougher visa rules should be applied and student visas revoked from those engaging in criminal activities such as drug trading.  
We are conscious that some ethnic groups are predisposed to deal in cash and welcome suggestions on how best to influence this behaviour.
Black Economy Taskforce paper

Cultural challenge

Peer pressure might also play into the cultural challenge, the paper said.
"There is broad agreement that cultural change is required, but recognition that this is not something that governments, acting alone, can decree," it said.
It suggested ethnic and religious leaders join the fight.
"We are conscious that some ethnic groups are predisposed to deal in cash and welcome suggestions on how best to influence this behaviour," it said.
"Ethnic community leaders will probably have a strong role to play in this regard."
Social media was an underutilised tool in combating the black economy.
"Contact with potential whistle-blowers, for example, could be made through social media channels," it said.
The taskforce . One of the more controversial options in the consultation paper includes setting a floor under the tax paid by "high-risk" cash economy businesses such as cafes and restaurants.
Follow Nassim Khadem on  and .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Board of Tax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Economy Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Jonasson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Economy Taskforce.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nassim Khadem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Kennerley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
