<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420517525865986</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/salmon-farm-plan-for-long-bay-on-the-tasman-peninsula/news-story/42163bca37495c03628777cb82ac25b1</url>
  <title>Tassal to reopen Port Arthur fish farm</title>
  <content>
Tassal plans to farm salmon at Port Arthur's Long Bay for the first time in more than a decade.
The company is preparing to open seven pens at a 15ha site at Long Bay, which hasn't been farmed since 2006.
There are plans for seven more pens in the future.
Greens leader Cassy O'Connor said mooring work was under way at Long Bay.
Ms O'Connor said more community consultation was needed and called on Tassal and the State Government to be more upfront.
"It's a concern when you have an industry that's so poorly regulated ... that they think that they can go back into a bay in Port Arthur and start works without letting Tasmanians know," she said.
A Tassal spokesman said that was incorrect.
"We have been nothing but transparent in our communications with stakeholders about our plans for the Port Arthur lease," he said.
"Tassal has met with a range of stakeholders ... in the Tasman region there were two advertised public meetings and numerous one-on-one stakeholder meetings and farm tours. New baseline studies have been completed and the Department of Primary Industries, Parks, Water and the Environment has been consulted about restocking."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassy O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Arthur's Long Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Arthur</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
