<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420311367431065</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/barnaby-joyce-distances-himself-from-water-furore-as-sa-demands-his-head-20170802-gxo869</url>
  <title>Joyce distances himself from water furore as SA demands his head</title>
  <content>
Barnaby Joyce has distanced himself from former irrigation lobbyist Perin Davey after previously extolling her virtues when nominating her to fill a board position on the Murray Darling Basin Authority.
Ms Davey asked for her nomination to be withdrawn on Wednesday after The Australian Financial Review she had been part of a teleconference during which a NSW government official was offering irrigation lobbyists sensitive documents to.
The official, Gavin Hanlon, has referred himself to the NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption.
Ms Davey's withdrawal has done little to ease calls from federal Labor and within South Australia

The Nationals leader and Agriculture Minister dodged on Thursday when asked about Ms Davey, who is the daughter of National Party icon Paul Davey and herself, according to a party source, considered "party royalty".

Mr Joyce said he had "never had a conversation" with Ms Davey but "I have heard she has withdrawn her application".
"We've accepted that and l leave the rest for Perin Davey to answer".
Ms Davey was part of a teleconference, reported last week by the ABC's Four Corners, in which Mr Hanlon proposed handing over de-badged documents, those which are stripped of the departmental logo, to help irrigators exploit the Murray-Darling Basin Plan.
"Obviously we would have to de-badge it," Mr Hanlon says.

David Rowe

Ms Davey, responds: "Yeah, that would be fabulous".
In the South Australia Parliamen and moved a motion demanding the federal government comply with the legislative requirement to appoint independent experts to the Murray-Darling Basin Authority.
"The events of the past week or so in relation to water policy, or the commitment or lack of it to the Murray-Darling Basin Plan, should cause very significant alarm for not only our state, but also for the nation," he said.
"Remember on Four Corners we had that recording of this discussion between a NSW bureaucrat and the irrigators and they were seeking to collude in some way to assist the irrigator through this difficulty that had emerged.

"(Ms Davey) was on that phone call and she is also the person who said that the delivery of the Murray-Darling Basin agreement, the plan, was impossible.
"Why on Earth would you appoint to the expert independent body somebody who was a lobbyist for the irrigators and had declared themselves as being an opponent of the plan, unless of course you wanted to wreck the plan. These are decisions calculated to destroy the plan."
He called on Mr Joyce to be stripped of the Water Resources portfolio.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Joyce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Davey</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Plan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agriculture Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perin Davey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hanlon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia Parliamen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Davey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
