<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420521820833356</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/world/hiphop-legend-kidd-creole-has-charged-with-murdering-homeless-man/news-story/99a1820d45c65270a59316e2ddec302a</url>
  <title>Rap legend 'killed homeless man'</title>
  <content>
RAPPER Kidd Creole - one of the founding members of the legendary hip-hop group, Grandmaster Flash and the Furious 5 - has been charged with murder for the stabbing of a homeless man who he thought was hitting on him in Manhattan.
The 57-year-old New Yorker, whose real name is Nathaniel Glover, was arrested at his home in Mt. Hope on Wednesday after allegedly killing the individual on Tuesday night, according to police sources.
He had gotten into a shouting match with the man - identified as 55-year-old John Jolly, a registered sex offender - at the corner of E. 44th St. and Third Avenue before the stabbing occurred, the sources said.
After the incident, Glover apparently fled and left Jolly, who was drunk, bleeding on the sidewalk,
Police later found him and thought he was just too intoxicated to stand, but then noticed multiple stab wounds in his chest and rushed him to Bellevue Hospital - where he was pronounced dead.
A high-ranking police source told the paper that Jolly was an ex-con who did six years on rape charges.
He's been arrested at least three times for sexual assault, the source said.
After being found by officers, Jolly refused to co-operate with police - and even declined to ID his killer or go to the hospital.
"I guess he didn't think he was going to die," the source said.
According to officials, Glover works in the area of Midtown where the murder occurred as a maintenance man and security guard.
Police sources said he thought the man was coming on to him.
Grandmaster Flash & The Furious Five

The legendary lyricist rose to fame in the 1970s after forming Grandmaster Flash and the Furious Five with rappers Melle Mel, Keith Cowboy, Mr. Ness/Scorpio, Rahiem, and DJ Joseph Saddler, better known as Grandmaster Flash.
Their songs, The Message and White Lines (Don't Do It), helped catapult the group to stardom in the '80s and made them household names in the hip-hop world.
They would eventually break up, though, citing personal differences. The group briefly reunited in 1987 before eventually disbanding for good.
Flash and the Furious Five would go on to become the very first hip-hop group to be inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in 2007.
Over the years, Creole has tried to stay relevant by using social media to promote his shows. He tweets and posts pictures regularly - even popping a tribute to Keith Cowboy, who died in 1989, just before he was arrested on Wednesday.
"#RIP my legendary brother," Creole tweeted at 3:02pm. "#Salute."
This article was
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roll Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furious Five</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Ness/Scorpio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jollys</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midtown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glover</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grandmaster Flash</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Jolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E. 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathaniel Glover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furious 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Cowboy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Creole</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Third Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melle Mel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Lines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidd Creole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ Joseph Saddler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellevue Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rahiem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
