<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420517525866009</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/berwicks-pete-white-has-been-nominated-as-one-of-australias-gentlest-dads/news-story/bcb77ab2df9fea06de7f5c45e6ef2d8f</url>
  <title>Pete nominated as gentlest dad in Australia</title>
  <content>
PETE White says there is more to the job of being a dad than just helping to make the baby.
The Berwick resident loves story time and bath time with his two kids, two-and-a-half-year-old Jackson and four-month-old Indiana, when he gets home from his day job and says he believes wholeheartedly that men should do as much as their partners to raise their kids.
His wife Ally Faithful thought he deserved some kudos and nominated him for the Australia's Gentlest Dad online competition.
Mr White said it was "really cool" to be nominated.
"I love my family and my children very, very much," he said.
"I would like to think (men are stepping up to parenting), I think it's at least more prevalent and there are more dads doing it than they used to, which is great for kids and families.
"I am a big believer that if you are man enough to have a baby then you are man enough to be a parent as well.
"I have a son and I want to raise him to be a good man ... I have a daughter and I want to raise a good daughter and teach her what to look for in a man.
"You have different strengths and weaknesses as individuals so it is important to raise them together so you can get through the harder parts because your partner's strengths lie somewhere else."
For information about the competition and to vote, visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Gentlest Dad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ally Faithful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PETE White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
