<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420530410768165</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/doncaster-east-school-introduces-new-chess-club/news-story/a4c75f72f5761c9deb199e7724509399</url>
  <title>New club keeps students in check</title>
  <content>
STUDENTS will be aiming to checkmate their peers at St Peter and Paul's Primary School over the next few months.
The kids were keen to start up a chess club after a visit from the Australian Chess Federation's Leonid Sandler a few weeks ago.
Mr Sandler sparked interest in the game when he taught the kids the basics at the start of term three, and sold the game to them as an "equaliser where culture, age and race play no part".
His lesson finished with a "simultaneous chess tournament", where he played 31 students at once.
While he only took about an hour to win every game, the kids were rapt all the same and now want to play as much as they can.
Their plans have grown with Manningham Council offering to send along a bus load of seniors every week to put the young ones through their paces.
School principal Anita Kelliher said the activity would benefit the children's broader education, too.
"Chess teaches higher level thinking skills such as the ability to visualise, analyse and think critically," she said.
"It calms the brain and teaches the children patience, which is quite the opposite to the online environment that they're constantly exposed to these days."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sandler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manningham Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul's Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Chess Federation's Leonid Sandler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anita Kelliher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
