<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420272712724489</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/legal/noones-going-to-stick-up-for-the-lawyers-the-pilloried-target-of-tax-grabs-20170725-gxi61q</url>
  <title>Lawyers, the easy target for political point-scoring and tax grabs</title>
  <content>
Will nobody think of John, the top law firm partner?
Pilloried enough as it is for dominating the senior ranks of the profession as , John was held up by the federal Labor party this week as the enfant terrible of the wicked rich who are pocketing tax savings using trusts, as leader Bill Shorten revealed its policy .
Under the , John's $500,000 yearly take - $70,000 streamed to his spouse and two children, none of whom work - would attract an extra $15,900 tax under the proposal.
John was unavailable, so we asked Philip Diviny, tax expert and consulting principal at Keypoint Law, his thoughts (besides, he was previously a partner at top law firm K&L Gates; plus, there is a "John" at his new firm, albeit based in Britain).

Justin McManus

"The maths of that are all fine, but what you've got to remember about a lawyer is if they are operating in one of these large firms, they never get to sell any of their goodwill or firm interest," he says.

"When they leave that firm, they don't get a payout for their goodwill [with capital gains tax discount] in the same way a normal small business person would.
"It's all good political sport because no-one's going to stick up for the lawyers. It's just politically opportunistic."
Allocation of profits

The Australian Taxation Office introduced guidelines from 2014-15, setting benchmarks for the allocation of profits within professional firms it considers kosher, including an effective 30 per cent tax rate on the firm's gross income or at least half of the partner's income being assessable in their own hands.

They were the tax man's way of dealing with the issue, and lawyers have merrily gone along with it since.
Diviny adds that talk of trusts being the exclusive realm of those with access to boutique advisers is wrong: they're standard practice for any client starting a small business.
"People could go to Dennis Denuto and he could advise them to set up a discretionary trust, and print one off once he had fixed up his photocopier.
"Trusts are a legitimate tool. If they're serious about saving the budget some money, why don't they look at things like refundable franking credits? Why don't they look at the attribution managed investment trust system where foreign investors take stakes in property or infrastructure projects and pay only 10 to 15 per cent tax?"

Kicking appointment goals

Less taxing this week were some stellar appointments.
Supreme Court of Victoria chief justice Marilyn Warren will take up a vice-chancellor's professorial fellowship at Monash University after retiring on October 1 (although it is understand the chief will pack up shop three days earlier, in time for the Richmond Tigers fan to participate in the annual city shutdown in the lead up to the AFL Grand Final).
Lucinda Brogden was appointed National Mental Health Commissioner; her academic research is in mood disorder in lawyers - watch this space.

And King & Wood Mallesons appointed Wang Rongkang to lead its flourishing (oh, sorry, that's not very nice is it) Europe and Middle East development, based in London. He'll have quite the task ahead, after the firm's Eurozone implosion. Nobody dare say hospital pass.
In Australia, at least, KWM's lawyers were among the more than 1000 who have signed the pledge for marriage equality kicked off by Marque Lawyers this week. Top honours so far go to Gilbert + Tobin, who had 74 lawyers on the roll as of Thursday (others signed up to the pledge - a charge led by Marque's Michael Bradley, UNSW's George Williams, no introduction needed Gillian Triggs, and Michelle Painter, SC - hail from Addisons, HSF, Clifford Chance, Baker McKenzie, Clayton Utz, Allens, K&L Gates, Dentons, Maurice Blackburn...and more).
On Thursday evening, Marque's Sydney office celebrated in good wedding party fashion: breaking into 80 cases of rose sent by one client in lieu of fees.
Try distributing that to your next of kin.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton Utz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L Gates</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wang Rongkang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNSW's George Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marque's Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillian Triggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KWM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wood Mallesons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John's $500,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Diviny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maurice Blackburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marque Lawyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Taxation Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baker McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifford Chance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Grand Finals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucinda Brogden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marque's Michael Bradley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keypoint Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diviny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Mental Health Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Denuto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Painter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
