<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420564770507365</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/sophisticated-traveller/fit-for-james-bond-the-riva-56-rivale-makes-a-splash-in-sarnico-20170725-gxie3u</url>
  <title>Fit for James Bond: the Riva 56' Rivale luxury yacht makes a splash</title>
  <content>
Sunset in the tiny town of , 70 kilometres north-east of Milan, and Italians are out doing what they do best: showcasing their natural assets. The champagne is flowing, as are the bellinis, easing the 500 or so (strictly invitation-only) guests into , anticipated to end so far past the bewitching hour that no fini time has been set. Slices of blood-red prosciutto, shiny grapes and slabs of roughly cut parmesan float past on silver trays. And the bread - the fresh bread, dripping in olive oil.
A pop band flown in from the south of France is belting out covers atop a large stage erected on the lake, beyond which dancers in black leotards leap around on narrow floating mirrored squares. It's a choreographer's nightmare, and impressively energetic.
Apart from the surrounding mountains, the only thing that's still and quiet is the guest of honour - because it's a boat, with the engine switched off.
The shindig is to celebrate the launch of the , a 56-foot (17-metre), open-top, day cruiser with extended en-suite master cabin, priced from about €2 million ($3.9 million), plus add-ons. Excessive? The thought does occur.

Alberto Cocchi

Party time

Then again, you can forgive the Italians for wanting to honour their fine artisan traditions. Not only that, it's almost a decade since the global financial crisis decimated the discretionary spend across Europe. Time heals most wounds. If tonight is any guide, the worst of the pain is over.
"Are you enjoying the party?" Piero Ferrari, the 72-year-old patriarch of Ferrari, casually asks. He's here along with his daughter, Antonella Ferrari, who is married to Alberto Galassi, chief executive of Ferretti Group, which owns Riva.
Keeping it in the family, in April last year, Piero bought 13.2 per cent of shares in Ferretti, a move whispered by Europe's jet set to be living proof luxury is back. Or more accurately, proof that the Chinese market has discovered life's finer things. In more ways than one.
Not only are the Chinese among the leading consumers of global luxury brands, from cars to handbags, but in 2012, state-owned Chinese industrial conglomerate Weichai of Shanghai bought the then debt-laden Ferretti and its suite of brands, including Riva, Custom Line and CRN Yacht.

Supplied

After years of financial losses (including reported losses of €29 million in FY 2015), Ferretti turned in a profit of just over €14 million last year.
Riva remains best known for its old wooden speed boats, such as the Aquarama, beloved of movie stars and celebrities from Sophia Loren and Brigitte Bardot in the 1960s to George Clooney and Jude Law today. But these are long out of production, replaced by bigger boats built with modern materials.
Under new owners Weichai, Ferretti is also going harder after the Asia-Pacific market, including opening a service centre in Australia. Riva's dealer in Australia, Ray White Marine, reports record sales for super yachts on the local market.
"Since last financial year, Ray White Marine has had a record-breaking year with $60 million-plus in sales, new and used boats," says Sydney-based sales director, Brock Rodwell. "New super yachts are nearly non-existent in Australia, but we've secured several orders for the upcoming 2017-18 summer season. The first to arrive will be a brand new Ferretti 850 [worth about $8 million], bought by a Sydney-based developer."

Gina Pricope

From Sarnico to Sydney via Shanghai, you can hear the band still playing.
Rivaland

The Riva brothers founded their boat-building yard at Sarnico on  (between Milan and Venice) in 1842, and the company has come to lend the town a distinct flavour over the years. There's even a Riva Aquarama runabout resting in the centre of a busy roundabout. The distinctive white-and-blue workshop was built in the 1950s by Carlo Riva, who died at his home in Sarnico in April this year, aged 95.
Confirmed landlubbers can enjoy the spectacular walks, museums, vineyards, restaurants by the lake and the region's historical sites.

STAY
In the heart of the cobbled old town of Sarnico, you'll find , a smart B&B-style family operation amid the boutiques, bars and restaurants. It's an ideal base for long, languid days spent around Lake Iseo, or as a point from which to explore Brescia and Bergamo.
Built on the site of a 1670 farmhouse,  is about 1.7 kilometres from the lake and has 46 rooms as well as two Junior suites and twoLoft Tower suites with lake views. The spacious rooms have an old-world feel, with timber furniture and parquetry flooring. A terrace-style restaurant overlooks the peaceful garden.
PLAY

When in Sarnico, do as the locals - flaunt your booty around the shores of Lake Iseo and dive in for the occasional swim. Better yet, bask on the deck of a motorboat. See iseolake.info for local events and more.
Shop the local look on Riva's online store () where you can find everything from a cap for €27 or a €120 polo shirt to an Aquarama inside lounge chair, price on application.
DINE
Predictably, fish is the specialita locali, both from the lake and seafood. ST loved Ristorante Il Gabbiano, located at Via Arrio Muciano, 2, Predore. Phone + 39 035 938481, or see
RIVA LOUNGE, VENICE
Those heading to Venice can get a taste of Riva life at , a seasonal 36-seat lounge decked out in Riva design on the Gritti Palace's terrace.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riva 56' Rivale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>twoLoft Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferretti Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brigitte Bardot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weichai of Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venice</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ristorante Il Gabbiano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIVA LOUNGE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferretti</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riva Aquarama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferretti 850</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Marine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Custom Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aquarama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piero Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberto Galassi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weichai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRN Yacht</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Predore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gritti Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GEORGE CLOONEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlo Riva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gina Pricope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonella Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rivas</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarnico</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Iseo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Via Arrio Muciano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BERGAMO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rivaland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brescia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberto Cocchi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Rodwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophia Loren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jude Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
