<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420569065474773</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/lifestyle/field-of-light-adds-contemporary-magic-to-a-timeless-wonder-20170731-gxmq8n</url>
  <title>Join model Sam Harris as she celebrates her birthday in a Field of Light</title>
  <content>
This is a special feature in association with Ayers Rock Resort.
For centuries, Indigenous Australians have been reading the position and intensity of the stars, observing both subtle changes and meteoric events in order to better predict daily life, from when fish might be plentiful to the approaching change of season. The lights in the vast night sky provide a critical tool of interpretation.
So it's perhaps fitting that the first contemporary art work by an internationally renowned artist to be hosted near Uluru (situated 18 kilometres from the rock's northern flank) is a luminous light installation best viewed at dawn or after sunset. Field of Light comprises 50,000 solar-powered small frosted bulbs that continually change colour, secured atop flexible stems like a blanket of high-tech wild desert flowers that bend in the wind.
They cover an area greater than four football fields, situated on land owned by , part of Voyages Indigenous Tourism Australia.

Supplied

"I've been going to Uluru at least once a year over the last four years for the ," says Australian Indigenous model, , who is based in Sydney. "But my most recent trip [July 20] was the first time I've had time to see Field of Light. It's weird enough to go out into the middle of the desert and there's this ginormous rock. Field of Light is just another layer of amazing on top of that.

"I saw it at daybreak when the sky was pinky orange. It was actually my 27th birthday so it was a very special way to celebrate that."
Harris flew to Uluru with Australian Financial Review photographer Louie Douvis for a photo shoot.
"I grew up around the Gold Coast, so Uluru has always seemed very mysterious and special to me, as I think it is for most Australians," Harris says.
Tourism Australia managing director John O'Sullivan is another fan. "I've been lucky enough to experience Field of Light twice now," he tells ST.

Louie Douvis

Spectacular sight

"Like Uluru, at dawn and at dusk, it's a spectacular sight - almost spiritual, which I'd recommend to anyone. It's a great example of a new experience complementing an Australian icon."
The project has the blessing of the local Anangu people, who named it Tili Wiru Tjuta Nyakutjaku, in local Pitjantjatjara: "Looking at lots of beautiful lights".
Field of Light was created by acclaimed British light installation artist Bruce Munro, who makes the lights with a team of artisans at his studio in Kilmington, a small village in the south west of England. His distinctive installations have been shown at sites across the world and he often uses recycled stems and bulbs from previous displays.

But Uluru's Field of Light has special significance for the 68-year-old artist.
"I know it sounds cliched, but that rock changed my life," Munro told international media at a preview last year, adding he first travelled to Uluru in 1992, after he'd lived in Sydney for eight years. "Driving up to see the rock was one of the last things we did before returning to Britain. I made a few sketches in my notebook - and the image of that beautiful rock has always stayed with me."
The installation has proven so popular, it's been extended until March 31, 2018.
Field of Light is open every day. Prices start from $39 for a 45-minute walk or "immersion" experience. For more information:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 31, 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayers Rock Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Field of Light</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tili Wiru Tjuta Nyakutjaku</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kilmington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitjantjatjara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Munro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru's Field of Light</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anangu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voyages Indigenous Tourism Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
