<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420517525865976</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/technology/towing-speed-limits-are-not-what-they-seem/news-story/5e2e27504c14ad2482a827c305a13c16</url>
  <title>What's the speed limit for towing?</title>
  <content>
I am looking for a 4WD with some grunt and more than four cylinders to tow a van. I am delighted that Volkswagen has brought out the V6 Amarok with a healthy 165kW/550Nm. But, in looking at the fine print, I see that VW doesn't recommend towing at more than 80km/h or with a weight-distribution hitch in case the towbar tears loose. I used to have a horse and cart that could tow faster than 80km/h. Seriously, are they just covering themselves? I'd buy a LandCruiser but don't really want to sell a kidney to afford it.
Leigh, email
You're not the only one with this sort of complaint but Volkswagen spokesman Paul Pottinger has good news: "The owner's manual states, 'Never drive faster than 80km/h when towing a trailer (100km/h in exceptional cases)'. This statement is made to conform to towing laws in Europe. These do not apply in Australia."
SEDATE TOWING
We bought a Subaru Forester to use mainly around town with the odd excursion on some rougher stuff. We wonder how we would go pulling a small pop-top caravan, such as a Jayco StarCraft, which complies with the Subaru's towing capacity specifications. However, I also note the manual says not to tow at over
80km/h. Are they really saying "Don't use the Forester as a tug?" or just that I should be a road hog, since I rarely see any rig travelling at 80.
Allan Hunt, email
Subaru spokesman David Rowley has a similar reply to Pottinger: "The Subaru owner's manuals contain the following factory warning: 'Never exceed 80km/h or legal towing speed limit, whichever is lower. Exceeding the speed limit could cause loss of vehicle stability and/or could lead to an accident.' It is intended as an advisory and doesn't mean that vehicles can't be driven faster at legal speed limits based on driver experience and capability."
GREAT UNTIL IT FLOPS
I'm furious. I just got a new 2017 Mazda and it won't start. It seems the accessories were left on and apparently this has been happening to customers due to the iStop function. I walked away thinking the car would do its thing and lock automatically but it didn't, so the battery was drained. Another thing is I can't put my car keys in my work bag in the boot because the car doesn't sense the key. My friend has a Kia Sportage and she can have her keys anywhere in the car and no problem. But the guys at Werribee Mazda were very helpful and kept my car overnight to fully charge it and gave me an MX-5 as a replacement vehicle, which was nice.
Lucy Vassallo, email
New technology is great until it fails, so it's vital to learn everything about a new car. Stop-start can be tricky as you think the engine is switched off but it's just the fuel-saver kicking in.
PANNED
I have a 2015 Holden Trax, I am very happy with it, but the Pandora music option is no longer available. I have spoken to my dealer, who immediately threw their hands in the air and said to contact GM. I have done that and they say there is no current fix to the issue. There is no CD player in the car, as Pandora was the be-all and end-all, as advised by the sales team at purchase. Does the dealer have to supply a substitute? I am 55 and would love a CD player, just as I wanted when I bought the car, as I have no interest in using USBs.
Barry Turner, email
Holden spokesman Mark Flintoft has the unwelcome answer: "We, too, are disappointed that Pandora decided to cease operation in Australia (and New Zealand) - thumbs down to that. Mr Turner's Trax and all other Holden vehicles with the embedded Pandora app icon, will continue to offer Stitcher, SmartRadio and TuneIn apps as well as regular AM/FM radio and USB ports to plug their iPod into. Additionally, there's the option of using Bluetooth to stream music straight to the car. So, while the Pandora app is no more, customers still have a wealth of infotainment options in their Holden."
TURBO TRIBULATION
We have a 2013 Ford Territory that continues to drop into limp mode. It's been 16 times now and, according to Ford, it has been fixed four times. There have been three attempts to explain the problem so I really hope you can help with this one.
Ian Hardman, email
Ford has been on your case for over a month. Customer service chief Stephen Kruk says: "It appears the turbocharger had an internal failure but the concern could only be noted when driving under heavy load and having the driver accelerate as much as possible under this load. Due to these circumstances and the time the vehicle was off the road, Ford will cover the cost of the turbocharger on this occasion as a goodwill gesture."
IT'LL COME OUT IN THE WASHER
Re Jeep Grand Cherokee transmission fault codes. I own a 2012 Grand Cherokee Limited diesel which has done 170,000km and is a fantastic car which hasn't missed a beat. I had this car regularly serviced at the same dealer as your reader until its five-year extended warranty recently expired. On one occasion I reported that the driver's side windscreen wiper washer was not working and asked if it could it be looked at. I was told it was a pump issue and that the part was not in stock but it could be ordered at a cost. When I got home, I popped the bonnet and noticed that the tube connecting the washer fluid to the wiper was disconnected, so I stuck it back in and all is still good. Sometimes great cars like the Jeep Grand Cherokee are sadly let down by the dealers who service them. I won't be going back now my warranty has expired.
Rob, Geelong
So that's The Kick again for Jeep in Geelong.
STEER 'EM STRAIGHT
In 2015 I bought a 2012 Hyundai i30 auto diesel hatch. There were plenty of reviews that noted the steering in Hyundai and Kia vehicles was a little vague. I have found that the vague steering can require continual minor corrections at city speeds, sometimes gentle and at other times hard. Last September I did a 2400km road trip and about eight times I had to hold extra pressure on the steering wheel to keep it going straight. The car has had five wheel alignments and three diagnostic tests done, and no fault shows on the dash or in testing. But the Hyundai service manager says "it is a terrible car to drive". The car still intermittently pulls left and is not really a safe car to drive. In May, after a dozen-plus dealings, the service manager has said that the steering column is to be replaced as it is under warranty and does not show any fault.
Trevor Krake, email
Hyundai spokesman Guido Schenken confirms headquarters is now involved and the steering column is being replaced under warranty. There will be follow-up to ensure this solves the problem.
IT'S SO EASY TO SLIP
Before I picked up my Mercedes-Benz GLC 43, they made me sign a letter saying I was aware of the tyre slipping issue. Having now driven it for 2000km I find it very unnerving, as in the wet it will slide off line at up to 20km/h. I have contacted Mercedes and they say it is not a safety issue and they can't do anything to fix it. Are you aware of this and do you have any advice as to a fix?
Stephen Bates, email
Tyre slip is rare in road cars but can occur in an all-wheel drive car with tight tolerances in the differential for maximum grip. Benz Australia spokesman David McCarthy says: "Tyre slipping is a characteristic of some AWD vehicles, particularly with low-profile tyres. A different compound tyre is likely to reduce this characteristic. I suggest contacting your Mercedes-Benz dealer to see whether there is an alternative tyre available."
FLAT SPIN
I needed to replace a damaged run-flat tyre on my Mercedes-Benz GLC 250D. I took it to a tyre retailer on the NSW South Coast who told me that they are not allowed to repair a runflat and it would need to be replaced. This is where it gets interesting as, having checked availability of Bridgestone tyres, he told me they were unavailable or out of stock. He also checked Continental and Goodyear and - you guessed it - out of stock. I personally checked with every retailer from Nowra to Wollongong and was given the same story, not available or out of stock. I am very concerned because the car needs four new run-flats. One retailer told me to contact Mercedes, which might have stock for customers. I went back to the dealer, who ordered four new Bridgestones, due in three weeks. God help anyone needing to replace run-flats in the country. This is absurd. Mercedes blames the tyre makers.
Warren Cato, email
The situation is not remotely good and you're not the first person to strike trouble with replacing run-flats. Mercedes-Benz says it does what it can, as McCarthy reports: "We monitor stock levels of run-flats in our network and also with the original equipment manufacturers. It's not always possible to ensure the right stock is in the right place at the right time This is an issue all manufacturers face."
SPACE-SAVERS PAR FOR THE COURSE
I am deciding whether to buy a new Mazda CX-5, Subaru Forester or Kia Sportage. I like the higher seating of an SUV. I dislike the CX-5's temporary steel spare wheel. I had a look at a Jaguar XE sedan in Singapore the other day and the handout said all versions came with an "18-inch Alloy Space Saver Spare Wheel". So should the spare wheel be a game changer, or is it now par for the course?
Chris Jones, email
You're not the only one worried about space-savers and run-flats, particularly in the family-sized SUV class. If you spend your life in the city and suburbs, there is no reason to worry about a space-saver. All three of your choices get The Tick but I would go for the CX-5.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>S SO EASY TO SLIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayco StarCraft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy Vassallo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz GLC 43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SmartRadio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Hardman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TURBO TRIBULATION</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pottinger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landcruiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nowra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MX5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stitcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alloy Space Saver Spare Wheel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridgestone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeep Grand Cherokee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee Mazda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Continental</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pandora</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CX-5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turner's Trax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW/550Nm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Cherokee Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeep</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaguar XE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V6 Amarok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USBs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TuneIn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodyear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru Forester</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Flintoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW South Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benz Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz GLC 250D. I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Trax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Kruk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guido Schenken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluetooth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda CX-5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pottinger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Bates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EM STRAIGHT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Cato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAVERS PAR FOR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iStop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LL COME OUT IN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Krake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kia Sportage</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
