<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420573360442173</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/who-does-cba-ceo-ian-narev-go-to-for-informal-executive-coaching-20170803-gxofrf</url>
  <title>Who does CBA CEO Ian Narev go to for informal executive coaching? </title>
  <content>
Commonwealth Board director Andrew Mohl's work in an informal capacity as executive coach of the bank's chief executive Ian Narev has divided company directors and governance experts.
Mr Mohl, who has been a CBA director for nine years, confirmed he had worked with Mr Narev before and after he became chief executive but said the coaching was not regular or paid work.
"Because I'm an executive coach I've provided support to Ian as an executive coach from time to time before he became CEO and after he became CEO," Mr Mohl said. "That's never been in an official capacity."
Mr Mohl, a former AMP CEO, is listed as an  on Foresight's Global Coaching website, along with Australia Post chairman John Stanhope and AMP board director Trevor Matthews.

Two company directors contacted by The Australian Financial Review expressed surprise at the arrangement, stating it was unusual, and questioned if it would affect the flow of information between the CEO and the chair.

"You want the basic relationship between the director and CEO going thorough the chairman or involving chairman," said one long-time board director, who asked not to be named. "The relationship between the chairman and CEO is extremely important."
Another former board chairman, who also declined to be identified, said: "There's only one coach of the CEO and that's the chairman. Such a structure would break down the relationship between board chairman and CEO."
'Happens all the time'

Mr David Turner retired as CBA's chairman last year and was replaced in January by former Telstra chair and Cochlear CEO Catherine Livingstone.

Jessica Hromas

Ownership Matters co-founder Dean Paatsch said there could be benefits from such a relationship where a director provided informal mentoring or coaching. For example, he said, where a chair and CEO didn't get along.
He said it was normal for directors to offer CEOs advice or mentoring. "It happens all the time."
Governance Institute of Australia chief executive Steven Burrell said "if it's done pro bono and on an informal basis, it's pretty much what directors do. It's usually the chair and it's usually around more guidance and advice than coaching."
Mr Mohl said it was common for company directors to provide support to management in "various ways".

"Obviously as a director who's been there [at CBA] as long as I have, and who's worked with him [Ian] in various roles as I have - I have a strong relationship with him."
CBA declined to comment.
Many of Australia's top executives have throughout their career. Gordon Cairns, former CEO of Lion Nathan and now chair of Woolworths and Origin, has talked about seeking out an executive coach in his career as has former Graincorp chair Don Taylor.
Both Mr Burrell and Mr Paatsch said where a director, who acts as an informal coach, could find it tricky is if a CEO confides anything personal that the rest of the board should know, placing the director in a difficult "father-confessor" role.

Mr Burrell said examples of where it could become "complicated territory" for a director might be if a CEO confides details of a personal relationship or even views on their own performance.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Paatsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Institute of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Paatsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Burrell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear CEO Catherine Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA CEO Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Mohl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Hromas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Lion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr David Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graincorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mohl</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Stanhope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foresight's Global Coaching</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Burrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
