<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420607720181362</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/school-on-creep-alert-as-girl-approached/news-story/63ea26f975587b87f77939c73cff25f0</url>
  <title>School on creep alert as girl approached</title>
  <content>
A MOTHER has described the moment her daughter was approached by a strange man who tried to lure her into his rusty old car as she walked home from school.
Alexandra Potter's daughter, aged 12, said she was walking home along Lee Point Rd on Monday afternoon when an older man in a white late model Toyota pulled up alongside her and allegedly tried to lure her into the car.
The NT News understands it was one of four reports to police of similar incidents on Monday afternoon, one involving a female student from Dripstone Middle School.
Ms Potter said her daughter and a school friend were approached at the corner of Coleman St and Lee Point Rd in Muirhead.
"She had just gotten off the bus and was walking home when the car pulled up next to her and her friend. "They described it to be an older white Toyota which had rust marks on it. The car was being driven by an older male with tan skin with grey whitish hair and no facial hair."
Ms Potter said the incident has shaken their family.
"It's just rocked us completely. I rang the police straight away and emailed the school the following day.
"She had just started catching the bus because she was in middle school. It's every parents worst nightmare. I'm so thankful nothing happened but it is just so scary.
"As time has gone on she has realised how scary the situation was. At the time she was a little bit blase about it and I had to sit her down and say it's really serious."
Dripstone Middle School wrote a letter to parents outlining the approach to their students to parents.
Education Department Regional Director Aderyn Chatterton commended the school for how they handled situation. She said students and parents were reminded of potential dangers when walking home from school.
"Like everyone else in the community we want our students to be safe and feel safe in their local area," she said.
"For students that are walking home and ride their bikes home it's about parents asking the children who they walk home with. She said teachers tell students to follow the four R's, recognise the danger, refuse the offer, run away and report to a trusted adult.
An NT Police spokeswoman said investigators had spoken to a man believed to have approached the girls.
"Police have spoken with a person of interest in relation to the matter however no offences have been detected," she said.
"Northern Territory Police take all reports of this nature very seriously."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Department Regional Director Aderyn Chatterton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Potter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dripstone Middle School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muirhead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Point Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
