<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420474576192057</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/policy/tax/government-to-intervene-in-company-tax-muddle-20170802-gxnulj</url>
  <title>Government to intervene in company tax muddle</title>
  <content>
The government will seek to end tax time paralysis by introducing a legislation to .
Only active trading businesses will be eligible for the lower rate, not companies holding passive investments, such as those linked to family trusts.
The Australian Financial Review has been told a legislative amendment will "remove any uncertainty".
But the move will not allay  for companies moving on to the lower rate.

over the fact the Australian Taxation Office's interpretation of the law appeared to

But Revenue and Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer said the government only wanted "active" trading companies to get tax relief.
The "policy decision made by the government to cut the tax rate for small companies was not meant to apply to passive investment companies," she said in a statement in July.
"If any further direction is required on the government's policy intention by the ATO it will be provided by the government."
As far as the government was concerned, it was up to the ATO to issue further guidance.

But it now appears the government will act first.
BDO national tax director Lance Cunningham said on Thursday that "confusion still reigns" because of the stalemate between the ATO and government.
"The Tax Office has already made its interpretation clear on its website that most passive investment companies will be carrying on business," he said.
"Therefore, unless the ATO changes its interpretation to be in line with the government's intended policy outcome, the government needs to either change the law to clarify that passive investment companies are not taxed at the 27.5 per cent rate or change the law to allow small business companies to choose whether to apply the 27.5 per cent rate or the 30 per cent rate."

Chartered Accountants Australia and New Zealand had, a day earlier, urged the Turnbull government to end the uncertainty with a legislative fix.
But CPA Australia believed it was better to wait for ATO guidance.
Under the government's Enterprise Tax Plan, small businesses with turnover of up to $10 million became eligible for the 27.5 per cent tax rate for the year ended June 30, 2017. This year the lower rate applies to companies with turnover of up to $25 million.
What's irking some companies is that tax is payable on a company's current year turnover whereas franking is based on the past year's turnover. That means tax is paid at 30 per cent but credits can only be franked at 27.5 per cent.

As the Financial Review reported on Wednesday, the, with listed investment companies unhappy about being forced to revise their historic dividend statements to shareholders because of the mismatch.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BDO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chartered Accountants Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Taxation Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enterprise Tax Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
