<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420560475539956</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/jealous-bloke-asks-a-bar-to-spy-on-his-girlfriend-on-her-friends-hen-do-but-it-doesnt-go-to-plan/news-story/1b5cba6cb5f87206f4aa03e5603f953e</url>
  <title>Jealous bloke asks a bar to spy on his girlfriend</title>
  <content>
A JEALOUS bloke who asked a bar to spy on his girlfriend on a night out has been shamed on Facebook.
The anonymous lad messaged Filthy's, in Newcastle town centre, to ask them to keep a special eye on the hen do his lady was attending - and offering to pay for their services.
He wrote: "Hi, my girlfriend is headed with a hen party this weekend to Filthy's.
"I was wondering if I would be able to pay a staff member to keep an eye on her and make sure theres no men at their table etc. (sic)
"I don't want the staff member to let the group know they are watching though!"
But, hilariously, the controlling bloke has been called out by the bar, in a public post shared with their 8,500 followers.
They wrote: "For anybody else considering offering us cash to casually stalk their partners.. we are a bar, not private investigators / professional perverts.
"We can however add some finishing touches to the reserved area such as personalised name cards & bubbly on arrival!"
And hundreds of horrified people have commented on the post.
Jodie Stark wrote: "The girlfriend needs warned about what kind bloke she with woah".
And Katie Grant added: "Should have took money found out who she is and save her from him. Clearly he is a psycho".
While Donna Wilkinson commented: "Some great trust in that relationship mind - am surprised he ain't tried to tuck it and join them".
Natalie Get Carter said: "You should of took his money and bought them a round of drinks".
And Neal Campbell joked: "Controlling and bad grammar? Girl needs to leave that".
Meanwhile, many of the commenters were just hoping that the man's poor girlfriend wasn't the bride-to-be.
Jane Ruddick said: "Controlling, jealous, irrational behaviour.... She needs do ditch him at the altar."
This story originally appeared in  and is reproduced here with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Wilkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neal Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Get Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Ruddick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
