<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420517525866004</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/cronk-crash-course-a-big-boost/news-story/8868a58d65d844528bb3e47003f3100d</url>
  <title>Morgo's Mail: Cronk crash course a big boost</title>
  <content>
IT'S been well documented that Cooper Cronk was nice enough to give me a few pointers in representative camps after my move to halfback this year.
I've always been known as more of a runner of the ball but he gave me some tips on being a ball playing option instead for the times when JT is out.
He game me another way of looking at the game and it was a way of improving.
He helped me with being able to read on the run what the defensive line is doing and their numbers, and steering away from set structures if I see an opportunity.
Tonight we'll be rivals and we know we'll have to play at our best, or very close to it, if we are to beat the competition pacesetters.
It gives us a good chance to see where we're at as a team. We had a good run of results through the middle part of the season and unfortunately last weekend that winning run came to an end against the Roosters.
We had ourselves in a good position to win that game up 16-6 at halftime and we couldn't make the most of the opportunity we had.
This week again we get another chance to come up against the form team of the competition and for us as a whole group it's a real challenge across the park.
Cameron Munster's out for the Storm but whoever fills in at five-eighth will be very clear in what their job is and the guys around them will help them.
They've been fortunate to have three very experienced and smart football players in Cooper Cronk, Billy Slater and Cameron Smith who can help them settle in.
JT and Joey Johns anointed Smith the GOAT - the greatest of all time - after his 350th game last week and he's definitely up there.
I'm probably lucky in the sense I get to play beside JT every week. Sometimes you might get caught taking it for granted, but I try not to.
Looking at Cameron Smith from the outside looking in you can understand why people like JT and Joey call him that.
He's right up there in my opinion. The best, if not very close to.
The 'big three' are very smart players and have played a lot together, which means they can put focus on breaking down the other team because they know their game so well.
They'll pick up other team's game plans and do what they can do to shut that down as much as they can.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Cronk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JT</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgo's Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
