<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420307072463681</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/cash-flow-machine-rio-tinto-sets-a-standard-for-other-miners-20170803-gxoqhz</url>
  <title>Rio's road map sets a standard that other miners will ignore at their peril</title>
  <content>
Having reached its great ocean of free cash flow at least six months ahead of even the best of its competitors, Rio Tinto has done the whole mining industry a $US3 billion favour by offering full and early delivery on its new compact with shareholders.
Just more than three years after former boss Sam Walsh and still-incumbent chief financial officer Chris Lynch started plotting an expedition to balance sheet security and capital allocation freedom,  and the efficient executors of "the best strategy in the industry".
When he was unexpectedly delivered to Rio's top job, Walsh assessed his ambition as a rehabilitation of Rio's lost status as a preferred investment in the sector and the recovery of capital management options that would allow the board to express a rock-solid bias to returning wealth to shareholders.
Walsh and nearly all of his leadership have now gone. But their map has been followed with ever more refined precision and Rio has now reached its destination.

Forget about whether or not Rio missed the analysts' consensus through its first half. That misses the import of this result. Rio has presented a transparently sound, predictable and repeatable set of numbers that demonstrate its firm grip on operating costs, its capacity to pursue productivity enhancement, its related ability to translate higher commodities prices into cash and profits and the determination of its board and management to share that bounty with shareholders through dividend and share buybacks.

Rio generated $US6.3 billion in operating cash flow and $US4 billion in free cash flow through the first half. It reported an underlying net profit of $US3.9 billion.
What makes that so neat is that Rio's debt-light balance sheet and its clear capital spending disciplines announce that, given commodities prices continue as solid as new boss JS Jacques believes they will, t.
Rio plans to spend no more than $US5.5 billon annually on sustaining itself and growth projects for the foreseeable future. At the same time, it is working to extract $US5 billion in productivity gains by 2022, all of which should flow directly back to free cash flow.
Through recent year, debt reduction has consumed an overweight chunk of Rio's free cash and pretty much all of the $US8 billion that has been generated from the sale of unwanted assets.

The first half, for example, saw Rio through $US2 billion at debt management and reduction. But the pace of this deeply necessary debt trimming is about to slow considerably. Rio does not want to live debt free and has told the market it does not want to drift into a "net cash position".
by CEO Jacques and CFO Lynch were punctuated by sensible questions about the capital management plan from here. The most interesting of those questions raised the potential that Rio might find itself able to return 100 per cent of its free cash flow to shareholders. Neither executive was able to dismiss that proposition.
The Rio road map now stands more than a guide to everyone in mining business. Woe betide any of its competitors that ignore the Ango-Australian's lead.
The successful followers of Rio fashion will need to transparently justify how they intend to allocated growth capital; they will need to demonstrate the capacity to drive the things that have already built with ever more efficiency; they will need to get their balance sheets into deeply conservative shape, and when all that is done they will need to start returning every cent of excess cash to their owners, in whatever form makes the most sense.

The contentment that Rio has already started generating will work to easing more systemic concerns over the mining industry's capacity to allocate capital. Given Rio maintains its course, and given that others like BHP continue their pursuit of Rio's lead with transparent alacrity, then the miners will arrive at their next growth phase with owners who have recovered trust that their capital will be managed more productively than it might have been over the past decade or so.
Certainly Jacques is saying all the right things. On being pressed, paradoxically enough, on whether Rio was planning to spend enough on growing itself, Jacques was as certain as he was frank.
Rio will continue to build rather than buy, in contrast to, say, Glencore. But it will manage fewer growth projects better. Those assets will be built on time and, at worst, on budget. And Rio will continue to be a seller of its unwanted assets rather than a buyer. Jacques said the prices Rio has earned for assets like Coal & Allied announce only that mining is sellers' market. He said the Rio will add volumes where they lift returns and that productivity remains the most accretive path to growth.
"When we talk about growth, we talk about growth of free cash flow," he said. "And that links backs to the question about productivity. [Adding] $US5 billion of free cash flow [through productivity] in the next five years is the best return, the best investment we can do, all right. So for us, growth is about the productivity on one side and the additional volume growth coming from world-class asset."

It is instructive that some pretty obvious portfolio and operational issues were so completely overshadowed by Rio's ever brighter financial outlook. Once you please the owners, everything looks just that little bit brighter.
For the record though, Rio's copper business sits in oddly fragile and uncertain shape; its iron ore business endured a tough first half operationally and while the ill-starred aluminium business has taken impressive strides over recent years, it is still delivering nothing like an adequate rate of return with its Australian downstream portfolio sitting a very particular problem.
The Grasberg copper mine sits the most obvious canker in Rio's copper story and not just because of the current upset between the mine operator, Freeport, and the Indonesian Government.
"There is no doubt that Grasberg is a world-class resource when you look at the copper and the gold content," Jacques reiterated on Wednesday. "But there is a fundamental difference between a world-class resource and a world-class business for Rio Tinto."

My view, for what it is worth, is that Grasberg is a mine that hurts too many people, that is run by a management team that figures it is OK to sack 3000 people (as it recently did) and that operates with a waste management system that sits well outside standards that Rio ought to be living by (tailings a delivered to the sea through a river system). Rio should sell its 40 per cent share in Grasberg's future production and I firmly believe it will by Christmas.
The other really telling piece to the Rio narrative on Wednesday was the. The local talking point there is that for most of this year China's steel mills have consistently put a premium of about 40 per cent on 62 per cent grades of iron ore over lower grade materials.
Australia's biggest player in the lower grade reaches of the market is Fortescue. Its boss through the back end of 2018. The Jacques views says Power is being optimistic.
Three times Jacques was called on to reflect on the obvious state of price segregation in the iron ore market and three times Rio's boss assessed it to be the product of structural change rather than a cyclical trend that starts with the restructuring of China's steel industry and that has been exacerbated by new pollution controls.
"On the steel industry, they are restructuring, they are restructuring as we speak, no doubt about it," Jacques said.
"The demand for high-grade ore is significant. And interesting enough, even when the iron ore prices drop in a significant way, the premium, the spread, the discount, call it whatever you want, between high grade and low grade didn't change. And that gives me more and more confidence that it's a structural change.
"I'll caveat it by saying [it is] still early days, but the direction is moving, what I believe, is a very good directional travel for us," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFO Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freeport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grasberg</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US5.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JS Jacques</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>30</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Jacques</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walsh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ango-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacques</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US3.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
