<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420281302659333</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/suncorp-ceo-michael-cameron-talks-up-surprise-100m-strategy-spend-20170803-gxou4g</url>
  <title>Suncorp CEO talks up 'surprise' $100 million strategy spend</title>
  <content>
Suncorp Group chief executive Michael Cameron has conceded he needs time to prove to investors that his strategy of creating a marketplace of financial services products strategy can work, after announcing that the company will .
Mr Cameron said that the money will speed up the delivery of key parts of its digital marketplace, which will see Suncorp sell product such as insurance and annuities that are manufactured by other financial services businesses. Spending priorities include opening six more of its Apple-inspired concept stores and launching a new customer app.
Mr Cameron said said the $100 million investment should deliver results by the end of the year. But investors may still need some convincing, with shares plunging 6.41 per cent to $13.57.
Mr Cameron said investors are searching for "some evidence" that the marketplace strategy will deliver value.

"It may take a little bit of time to understand why we are bringing forward the one-off spend as investment in this year. They definitely get it, but they are cautiously optimistic about the future of the company ," he said.

"I know that investors understand the strategy, they buy into it and there is an element of saying 'Michael's decided to spend this money, we hope that it's going to deliver big benefits'."
The strategy of Mr Cameron, who was appointed CEO in 2015, is designed to make for Suncorp customers to connect with its brands which include GIO and AAMI. His "One Suncorp" operating model gives customers a single digital customer experience and removes distinctions between Suncorp's various businesses.
The banking and insurance group is also partnering with third-party providers so that customers can access different products and services. So far it has inked distribution deals with NIB and Challenger and it plans to form relationships with companies that are outside the traditional financial services remit.
Mr Cameron said there may be a time when Suncorp will no longer manufacture products at all.

"Were trying to forget that we are an insurance company and a bank and life insurance company, and were moving the organisation to be a platform or a marketplace," he said.
Rather than complete its marketplace plan over a three-year period, Suncorp now wants to speed this up. It plans to use part of the $100 million spend to launch its "single digital experience" app by the end of the 2018 financial year.
"The decision to bring that forward that expenditure really reflects our confidence in our ability to deliver value to our customers and also value to our shareholders in a much faster timetable rather than wait two or three years for those benefits to come through," said Mr Cameron.
But the jury is still out on this decision.

Morningstar analyst David Ellis said the "additional investment in the business improvement program surprised".
Morgan Stanley analyst Daniel Toohey had concerns over the return on the $100 million spend and the details around it.
"What has changed since Suncorp's strategy day in June? Surely, that was the time to talk about the business improvement initiative and the $100 million marketplace investment?" he said.
"Tangible upside demands a leap of faith, particularly as the market is not sitting idle. There is a risk that this proves to be maintenance capex and not an investment in growth. The return on equity at 8.4 per cent is not improving and the underlying margin outlook deteriorating."

But Mr Cameron said the addition of nearly 400,000 customers and a turnaround in retention help prove that the strategy is working.
"We were losing a significant amount of customers - we lose about 125,000 customers a month and we have to go and get a new 125,000 customers a month, that generates a lot of activity. We've dramatically reduced the cost of running the organisation," he said.
The added push to roll out the marketplace strategy came as Suncorp unveiled its results for the full-year to June 30 for 2017 on Thursday.
The lender and insurance giant's net profit rose 3.6 per cent to $1.1 billion in the 12 months to June 30, but it missed analyst forecasts of a 5 per cent and above lift.

"This was driven largely by a weak result in New Zealand (especially general insurance), and in the Australian wealth business, while the quality of the bank result was poor," Citi analysts said.
"This result misses consensus and seems relatively soft across the board although the 12 per cent underlying insurance trading ratio margin target was achieved in the second half of 2016-17 although there are headwinds for 2017-18. We are also not sure the market will like the extra $100m investment in Marketplace. We believe the stock is likely to weaken."
Suncorp shares are up 2.03 per cent per cent for the year to date. The benchmark S&P/ASX 200 index was up about 3.68 per cent during the same period.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morningstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Suncorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cameron</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Toohey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
