<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420955612540132</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/movies/meet-the-husband-and-wife-team-behind-judd-apatowproduced-comedy-the-big-sick-20170801-gxncj2.html</url>
  <title>Meet the husband and wife team behind Judd Apatow-produced comedy The Big Sick </title>
  <content>
There are few ventures more fraught with danger than going into business with a spouse. Stuff it up and you risk your losing both your loot and your lover.
Spare a thought, then, for Kumail Nanjiani​ and Emily Gordon, the husband-and-wife writing team behind The Big Sick, which comes with the Judd Apatow​ seal of approval but is in most senses far from your typical adult-oriented rom-com.

Up Next

$4 an hour internships

02:29

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Trailer:
The Big Sick

Kumail Nanjiani and Emily Gordon star in a 'sick' comedy that is far from being a typical adult-oriented rom-com.

The pair not only spent three years working up their script, they also based it on their own lives. To up the ante just a little further, Nanjiani plays himself in a tale that is largely about what a schmuck he was. Oh, happy days.
"He's a partial fabrication," says Nanjiani of his film self, also called Kumail Nanjiani and, like him, a stand-up comedian in America of Pakistani Muslim heritage.

"I think you had it a little bit more together," says Gordon, who is played in the film by Zoe Kazan. "You were a bit more of a grown-up than he is."
"But his problems were my problems," Nanjiani says. "We exaggerated them and simplified some of them but at core I wasn't making any decisions, I was leading everybody on, I didn't really have a plan for my life, I didn't really know who I was. I mean, I still kinda don't."

The Big Sick tells a true story about what happened when the pair met, around 10 years ago. They dated for a while, he sticking strictly to a rule of seeing her on no more than two consecutive days, she insisting she doesn't have time for a relationship because she's focused on finishing her master's in psychology and setting up a counselling practice.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Of course, they fall in love, only to break up when she discovers a cigar box in his bedroom full of photos of young Muslim women - potential brides in the arranged marriage his parents insist is his fate.The Big SickPhoto: Roadshow
And then she gets sick, and what started as a comedy of clashing cultures becomes something else - a testing ground for Kumail to work out how he feels about Emily, and what he plans to do about it.
The fact that the pair are sitting on a couch in front of me talking about their work and their life together kind of gives away the ending, but don't let that put you off. Besides, the film might be based on fact but it's not entirely as it happened.The Big SickPhoto: Roadshow
"I'd say it's about 60 per cent factual," says Gordon.
"I'd say 65 per cent," says Nanjiani. "As someone said, 'it's true but it's not accurate'."Photo: Roadshow
"That was Robert Altman," she says.
The broad brushstrokes are absolutely true, she adds. "It's the connective stuff we had to embellish a bit."The Big SickPhoto: Simon Schluter
"Living through someone being in the hospital is not terribly cinematic," Nanjiani explains. "It's mostly waiting, talking to doctors. You're sitting there and there's a tempest inside you, but for a movie you've got to do a little more work to get the audience to feel what the characters are feeling. So it was always like, 'This is what it felt like to live through this, so what are the changes we need to make to get the audience to live through this'."
For Gordon, living through it meant sleeping through it. She was in an induced coma. It was while she was under that Nanjiani met her parents, Beth and Terry, the film versions played by Holly Hunter and Ray Romano.Photo: Simon Schluter
The pair are hostile to Kumail at first, Beth because of the break-up, Terry because of, well, you know - 9/11.
The palpable discomfort of their first encounters owe much to the guiding hand of Apatow, who met Nanjiani at South by South West in 2012, declared they should work together, then turned down all his sci-fi pitches but fell in love with this weird story from his real life.
"Judd did this great thing," says Gordon. "He said, 'What you really want to think about is who is the worst kind of person for Kumail to be paired with?' Kumail is a guy who's really uncomfortable with the truth, and who's..."
Nanjiani: "...not in touch with his own feelings, is not direct. Unlike Holly Hunter's Beth, who's very direct and doesn't suffer fools..."
Gordon: "... and Ray Romano's Terry, who's just emotionally naked all the time. We built those characters on who we thought it would be most interesting for Kumail to be around. They're inventions."
For Gordon, letting go of what really happened was enormously liberating. "Because then it was like, 'Oh good, we're not going to be casting our lives, we're going to be casting this story that we created together'. Otherwise it would have felt way too uncomfortable to have Holly Hunter saying things my actual mother said. That would have been a strange thing. It really helped me to have it go fictional."
The pair have a habit of talking over the top of each other and completing each other's sentences like a couple of over-stimulated teenagers; maybe that's what happens when you spend all those years living and working together. Or maybe they're just excited to be speaking to someone from outside the unit. 
They've been working together for a while now. For about five years, they've done a weekly games podcast, The Indoor Kids; for a little longer than that, they also put on a weekly live stand-up show in Los Angeles, called The Meltdown, which she produced and in which he performed. It also spawned a TV series on Comedy Central, The Meltdown with Jonah and Kumail, which ran for three seasons.
It takes some negotiation, this business of working together. "We learnt to navigate some of the pitfalls early on," says Gordon. "Like, 'When are you my spouse and when are you my co-worker, and what do those dynamics mean?' My spouse is always supposed to be, 'Oh my God, you're the best' whereas my co-worker gets to be 'Oh, that idea's not so great'."
Do you ever fight?
"Yeah, absolutely. But they're always really functional arguments, that help make the script better. We don't get petty with each other, which is good."
"Even the disagreements, we were able to keep not personal," says Nanjiani. "We were able to keep it about the work."
"Though sometimes I'd say, 'Well CHARACTER Kumail is being such an asshole right now'," Gordon confesses.
They have strict rules at home. "You can't talk about work in bed. Ever," says Gordon. "You have to ask permission before you talk about work."
"Because it can be very easy to go from personal life to professional life when you're writing together," Nanjiani says.
But with The Big Sick, those rules fell apart a little because, he adds, "it was all we were doing".
"And it kind of fell apart there," says Gordon.
So, will you work together again?
"We'd love to," he says, "but right now we need a break".
"Go back to being just husband and wife," she says.
"We'd love to figure something out," Nanjiani says. "Probably not something so personal, not right away. Something a little different. Maybe a story about our cat."
Facebook:  
Twitter: 
​
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Hunter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Sick</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Kazan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Romano.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHARACTER Kumail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Altman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comedy Central</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Gordon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indoor Kids</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Schluter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanjiani</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kumail</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Hunter's Beth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judd Apatow-produced</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America of Pakistani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judd Apatow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kumail Nanjiani</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Romano's Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apatow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big SickPhoto</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JUDD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roadshow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
