<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420732274235685</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/3498626/dan-proudman-empathy-up-close-and-very-personal/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>DAN PROUDMAN: Empathy up close  and very personal</title>
  <content>
A FEW months ago I found myself blubbering at a funeral as I watched a woman gently brush a finger across a coffin holding her murdered son.
I had met the woman twice and had not known her for more than a week. And I had never met her son.
I was at the funeral to cover it as a crime reporter, something I had unfortunately done dozens, if not hundreds, of times before.
And although it is obvious they are almost always extremely sad, and the thought of being in the mourners' shoes still frightens me to my core, I am usually pretty good at holding it together.
But not this time. The tiny and very personal touch got me right between the eyes and in the middle of the heart.
Later, I reasoned it was because I saw a lot of me in that young man, and a lot of my mother in that grieving shell of a woman.
It was pure empathy. A deep connection which had me overcome with raw emotion. It still does as I write this. I didn't want to feel that way, and I almost hid my tears, embarrassed about being seen as overly sensitive or melodramatic. But I couldn't help it.
And that is what is irritating the hell out of me as we try to take in the atrocities in Paris.
Before the bodies were even pulled from the Bataclan theatre, the bandwagon brigade had piped up in yet another social media phenomenon borne out of another ugly I-am-better-than-you ideology, as my colleague Matt Carr pointed out in this space on Tuesday.
It revolves around what is now being termed selective grief, where the world and its media mourn attacks such as in Paris, where at least 130 were killed and 350 injured, while apparently ignoring attacks like in Beirut two days before, where at least 40 people were killed in suicide bombings.
There is no doubt each and every one of us should be better educated on what is happening across the globe.
In fact, by doing so, it may assist us in becoming a more tolerant society.
But since when has it become a macabre race to the moral high ground to find the least-known terror attack in a ghoulish attempt to appear more worldly and empathic than others?
As a colleague said much better than me, it is like these people are on a pedestal  trying to shout out how cool they are, that they knew all about Beirut and we didn't, like some teenager gloating they knew of a band before they had a No.1 hit.
It is a pity, another colleague said pinching a line from comedian Ricky Gervais, that these people fail to realise social media is  just like ''shouting into a bucket''.
And since when has empathy become a commodity we just shell out?
Can you turn it on and off when you wish to?
Is it real empathy if you need to make a conscious decision to feel it? 
During the near two decades of chasing crime stories, the one constant I have discovered about grief is that there is not a constant.
There are an infinite number of ways people deal with such a raw emotion. It is an extremely personal experience.
And empathy, to me anyway, is in the same basket. Just like the woman in the funeral made me weep, I have also found myself questioning whether I have started to get too hard for this game because of a failure to connect with others.
But I haven't got too hard.  It's just the way it is. Connection sparks the empathy.
So, forgive me if I snarl when someone tries lecturing me that I'm this nasty person because I chose to show support to the French by changing a profile pic to its national flag.
It's not that I don't feel for those in Lebanon too. I actually read the 380-odd words the Herald published about Beirut on Saturday before the Paris hell took over the headlines. I also spent some time looking at the feeds of those who were telling us we were horrible for only grieving for the Parisians.
To a person, I could not find any reference to any terrorist attack in the past three months anywhere in the world - until after Paris was attacked.
Unfortunately, my empathy may appear selective. But it was real.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parisian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebanon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAN PROUDMAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Gervais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIRUT</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bataclan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
