<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420904072931658</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/white-car-in-double-hitrun-outside-st-pauls-cathedral-20170802-gxoxcq.html</url>
  <title>Witnesses chase down white car after double hit-run outside St Paul's Cathedral</title>
  <content>
A man has spoken of the moment he chased down a hit-and-run driver who struck a cyclist and a pedestrian outside Melbourne's St Paul's Cathedral before the driver sped off in peak-hour traffic.
Police said late on Wednesday night that they had arrested a 32-year-old woman in Elizabeth Street who they believed was the driver of the car.Photo: Paul Harris
The witness, who did not want to be named, said he was cycling down Swanston Street when he saw a white car with no numberplates plough through a red light and hit an elderly man who was crossing Flinders Street near the cathedral about 6.30pm.
Moments later, the car then struck another a middle-aged man who was riding his bike at the intersection of Swanston and Flinders streets travelling towards St Kilda.
The witness said the cyclist was thrown from his bike and left lying on the side of the road.  
He said another woman, who witnessed the double hit-and-run, rushed to the aid of the elderly man who was lying unconscious in the middle of Flinders Street.

He said the woman appeared to revive the elderly man and treated him until paramedics arrived.
"I saw the driver stop briefly and people who witnessed the crash ran up to his window to speak to him, but then he just drove off, it was really the most ​peculiar thing," he said.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The man and another witness then chased the driver who stopped again at the next set of traffic lights.
He said the car windows were covered in fog and the driver seemed disoriented.
"We caught he driver at the next set of lights and we tried to get them to stop but they just looked at us and then drove off again," he said.
"It was almost like he wasn't aware of what had just happened."
The man said he had feared for the lives of the two men.
"They were struck really hard by the car and (they) appeared to be in a really bad way," he said. "Everybody who saw the incident was just completely stunned by it and even more so when the driver just drove off."
An Ambulance Victoria spokeswoman confirmed one man was taken to The Alfred hospital in a stable condition while a second man was assessed for minor injuries but was not taken to hospital.
A large number of police closed at least one lane and stopped trams near the busy intersection, but the road was soon reopened and the trams back running.

R70/75 operating between the suburbs & Flinders/Russell St with no trams between Docklands & Flinders St Station due to traffic incident.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders St Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders/Russell St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swanston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R70/75</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambulance Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Paul's Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swanston Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's St Paul's Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
