<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420861123257761</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/3021026/police-win-award-for-relentless-inquiry/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Police win award for relentless inquiry</title>
  <content>
The 2011 bowling club robbery, caught on camera.

 THEY had shown their intent when one of them walked back into a crowded club they had just robbed to shoot one of the patrons.
And although they may have intended to deflect the heat that was expected to come their way, serious criminals Ryker Jennar and Joel Barton must never have expected the doggedness of the members of Strike Force Kerwin.
The group of detectives and analysts set up to hunt down the shooters of patron Dick McGuigan used up a bigger bank of patience and perseverance than Jennar and Barton robbed during their violent crime spree of 2011.
And for the efforts, Strike Force Kerwin will be named the state's best police investigation across the 80 local area commands later this month.
''They [Barton and Jennar] are out of circulation for a while and that is simply because of the work of [Detective Sergeant] Matt Faber and his team,'' Mr McGuigan said.
''They were relentless, their effort was absolutely incredible.''
Strike Force Kerwin was set up in the hours following the shooting of Mr McGuigan at the Waterboard Bowling Club   at North Lambton in July 2011.
Jennar and Barton  stormed into the packed club and stole $44,000 before shooting Mr McGuigan and leaving him for dead.
Somehow, their victim survived  after several operations and many months of rehabilitation.

Water Board Bowling club patron Dick McGuigan, who was shot during the robbery.
Strike Force Kerwin quickly established links between the bowling club robbery and similar armed robberies of the Criterion Hotel at Carrington and Newcastle Permanent Building Society at New Lambton.
It took some time but they were able to identify Jennar, the son of an old Newcastle criminal, and Barton, a former rugby league prodigy, as the prime suspects.
It took three years, but both were convicted and handed significant jail terms.
In all, Strike Force Kerwin processed 223,000 phone intercepts, took 300 statements, collected 500 exhibits, conducted 42 search warrants and successfully achieved 23 convictions.
It is at least the fourth time a Hunter investigation has won the prize in the past 10 years.
''No police officer comes to work to get an award, but it is gratifying and humbling to have such diligent and dogged police work acknowledged,'' Northern Region commander Assistant Commissioner Jeff Loy said.
''These offenders were top-end armed robbers, they displayed a clear intent and capability of seriously injuring members of the public.
''The brilliant investigation techniques that were applied impacted directly on the safety of the public, and I am in no doubt that without such diligent police work these offenders would have continued their crime spree.
''We, as an executive, are truly proud of our officers and the investigation.''
The Strike Force Kerwin members will be handed their award later this month.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick McGuigan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Permanent Building Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryker Jennar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Force Kerwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Region</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Faber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Criterion Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGuigan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterboard Bowling Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennar</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Board Bowling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Commissioner Jeff Loy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Sergeant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strike Force Kerwin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
