<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420264122789697</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/boss/how-to-bust-the-venture-club-and-market-entrepreneurs-20170718-gxe1os</url>
  <title>How to market entrepreneurs: Follow[the]seed's Yifat Shirben</title>
  <content>
by
Yifat Shirben

The head of marketing for , has developed a unique methodology for marketing start-ups.
I started my marketing and entrepreneurial journey 10 years ago, working for [instant messaging client] ICQ and then on several different start-ups and projects.
Six years ago I started my own business in Australia called ILoveThisBox.com.au, which was a beauty subscription box [same model as the US Birchbox]. I learnt a lot from this, especially how different marketing for start-ups is from traditional marketing, and the importance of the customer experience and emotional response.
When I shut down the subscription side of the business, I decided to focus on what I did best: marketing. I decided to focus on entrepreneurial companies and developed my own methodology for consumer-driven market research. Since then I have been working with ingogo, OpenLearning, Sneaking Duck, Curve, Law of the Jungle and others.

When I meet start-ups for the first time I ask untraditional questions, such as: "What does using your product say about your users?" or "What is your customer's embarrassing truth?"

Then I do my own research to complete the picture; some of it is very traditional, but I also look at things like keyword searches, the books their customers read, the language they use in forums, their support questions, reviews etc.
I'm trying to understand what is the real problem these companies are solving for them; what is the emotional trigger and not the functional one?
Joining Follow[the]seed, with its RavingFans methodology and general vision, aligned perfectly. Working alongside Eliav and the other partners helped me perfect the methodology, which in turn helps the fund and its portfolio companies.
Working with start-ups there are the obvious challenges of an ever-changing business model, penetrating a market as a new player with low budgets, and the need to be very cautious and creative with the way you spend the money. But what I find more challenging, and interesting, is dealing with the actual product and the founders themselves, who in most cases have no marketing background but strong conviction and determination.

In most cases I have to convince them that while their vision holds, the path to achieving it is typically not what they imagined.
Yifat Shirben spoke to Joanne Gray.
Like Leadership with the Financial Review on . Follow us on . Join the  conversation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OpenLearning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law of the Jungle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RavingFans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ILoveThisBox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yifat Shirben</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Birchbox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sneaking Duck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eliav</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
