<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420289892594265</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/health/hospitals-and-gps/primary-health-care-to-axe-jobs-in-manila-considers-outsourcing-it-20170803-gxoa46</url>
  <title>Primary Health Care to axe jobs in Manila, considers outsourcing IT</title>
  <content>
Another tough day at the office looms for Primary Health Care, which has plans to close its data entry support office in Manila, where an estimated 100 staff will lose their jobs as the medical centre operator continues to look for cost savings.
Primary is believed to have signed a new outsourcing deal for data entry of pathology request forms and accounts processing with Indian conglomerate Tata Group. Primary already uses Tata for payroll and accounts payable. Primary declined to comment about any further redundancies.
The Manila office was opened two years ago under previous management. It is not clear the amount of savings Primary expects from the closure. It is understood that Primary acting chief executive Malcolm Ashcroft is also considering outsourcing IT development.
The company recently embarked on a cost-cutting program, . As reported by The Australian Financial Review, Primary said it has saved $6 million following its recent redundancies.

Several sources said Mr Ashcroft, who was previously chief financial officer under former CEO Peter Gregg, is trying to "clean house" before the new boss arrives in September. Malcolm Parmenter, who jumped ship from Sonic Healthcare, will take up the top job next month.

Dr Parmenter is taking on the helm of an underperforming medical centres and pathology operator. In late  stemming from medical centres goodwill and underperforming sites but said it would not impact on its banking covenants.The $1.77 billion company said that underlying net profit is now tipped to be $92 million compared with prior guidance of $92 million to $102 million, and below the $96.8 million reported for the 2016 fiscal year.
"Over past two years Peter (Gregg) and Mal (Ashcroft) blamed everything on the Batemans, you can't blame them forever, you have to take some blame, Primary is now going backwards," said one source.
One source said Primary was in a tough position given the weak business performance, and if management waited for Dr Parmenter to arrive and get his feet under the desk, half the year would be gone.
However, several sources questioned the level of involvement of Dr Parmenter in Primary, given his non-compete period.

"It seems unlikely that Malcolm Parmenter doesn't have some sort of input to all this," one source said.
While the company is looking at more ways to save on costs and get its medical centres business back on track, it is continuing to face major unrest at Dorevitch Pathology, where it operates more than 30 specialist laboratories across Victoria.
More than 500 workers are set to strike on Monday for 24 hours after a long and bitter pay dispute. According to the Health Workers Union, Dorevitch employees are paid the lowest wages in the pathology industry in Australia.
"Our members are overworked and underpaid. They are fed up with low wages. It's not fair and it's not right," said HWU secretary Diana Asmar.

Dorevitch Pathology provides services to about 20 public hospitals and performs work for Justice Victoria and Corrections Victoria.
Bank of America Merrill Lynch analyst William Dunlop said the strike, while not material to group results, suggests that new Dr Parmenter may need to increase wages in the pathology division, perhaps crimping FY18-19 margins.
Several sources said they are hearing of a possible industrial action also brewing in Primary's Western Diagnostic Pathology, which has about 140 collection centres and 12 laboratories.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ashcroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Parmenter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HWU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Parmenter</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health-care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tata Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Ashcroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Peter Gregg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorevitch Pathology</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Workers Unions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashcroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana Asmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary Health Care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MANILA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrections Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorevitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonic Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary's Western Diagnostic Pathology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Dunlop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrill Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
