<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420277007691853</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/legal/law-firm-atanaskovic-hartnell-sued-by-former-manager-elizabeth-kelly-20170802-gxnwkk</url>
  <title>'Pull up your socks', Atanaskovic told manager; one week later, Kelly resigned</title>
  <content>
When Elizabeth Kelly gave her resignation notice to John Atanaskovic and Tony Hartnell this time last year, she told them she would "continue to speak well" of Atanaskovic Hartnell, the Sydney law firm they co-founded and which she had managed for more than 12 years.
Now, Ms Kelly is embroiled in a , claiming she developed an anxiety disorder and depression due to her treatment and seeking more than $130,000 in unpaid salary and leave entitlements.
In turn, the high-profile firm is vigorously defending the action and its service company is counter-suing Ms Kelly for more than $226,000 in damages, alleging she failed to satisfactorily perform her role leading to a rejected renewal application for Mr Atanaskovic's UK working visa and a dispute with legal research company LexisNexis.
Court documents filed by Ms Kelly's lawyer Michael Harmer in the Federal Circuit Court in Sydney reveal the breakdown in relationship between Ms Kelly and Mr Atanaskovic in the years leading up to her leaving the firm in November, by which time she was paid a salary of $237,315.59 including super.

In emails sent in early July 2014, Mr Atanaskovic called Ms Kelly "work shy" and said her views were "half-baked", delivering a formal dismissal warning. Another referred to her "bureaucratic" approach and "harem scarem new non security proposals" over the repair of doors to the office.

In August 2015, after the firm overpaid value-added tax in the UK where it has a London office, Mr Atanaskovic said he was "not comfortable" paying her full salary and would reduce it by the alleged amount.
'Handsomely paid'

Almost one year later, on July 6, 2016, Mr Atanaskovic sent an email relating to the proposed lease renewal for the firm's Elizabeth Street office saying he would feel ashamed if he had produced the memo Ms Kelly had, and she should "do the job [she was] so handsomely paid for". Later that month, an email referring to alleged deficiencies in banking arrangements stated she must "pull her socks up", and her "current reward level" could not be justified.
On August 3, he suggested she was jinxing the process of hiring support staff and "someone younger, and significantly more approachable/sympathetic" should conduct first interviews.

Nick Moir

Two days later, Ms Kelly handed in her resignation letter.
From that time until she left on November 4, Mr Atanaskovic made further statements in a series of emails, including that she suffered from "ineptitude and slothfulness", was a "maliciously intermeddling fool" and was "conspiring" with another to "foul up" a new lease guarantee from the bank.
Ms Kelly alleges she made complaints to other partners at the firm "promptly and impartially" at various points, which were not investigated or addressed. As a result, she claims she "became fatigued, developed a generalised anxiety disorder and depression" and the target of "increased hostility", ultimately leading to a breach of a contractual promise to provide a safe system of work and her forced resignation. Threats to cut her salary came after Mr Atanaskovic found out about complaints, she alleges.
She wants compensation for her loss, along with $83,564 in unpaid annual leave, $45,200 in long service leave and $1662 for her final three days of work.

The service company which employed her, the firm itself and various partners during 2016 - Mr Atanaskovic, Tony Hartnell, Jeremy Kriewaldt, Michael Sophocles and Jon Skene - are named as respondents.
Mr Atanaskovic, a former Blake Dawson Waldron (now Ashurst) partner and Allen, Allen & Hemsley (now Allens) managing partner, started the boutique firm in 1993 with . They have acted for Rupert Murdoch, , and mining giant Glencore.
'Scurrilous' accusations

In a media statement, the firm said Ms Kelly makes "unfounded allegations, some of which are scurrilous" and "baselessly alleges" adverse action was taken against her.

"There is no proper basis for any of those allegations, and each and every one of them is straightforwardly denied."
In a 65-page document filed in the court on July 25, they set out a strenuous and detailed defence.
Despite admitting certain statements contained in email correspondence, they provide context and explanations for each incident - including that the term "half-baked" was "entirely apt to describe the view" of Ms Kelly, the "work shy" comment related to having to repeat a "clear and unambiguous request" to set up authority for Mr Atanaskovic to operate a particular bank account, and "constructive feedback" was given on improving future performance.
The treatment of unpaid invoices, leading to the overpayment of tax in the UK, "ought to have been obvious to any competent general manager"; while a late lease renewal option was "patently inadequate".

Attempts at mediation between the parties failed, and earlier  before the Fair Work Commission do not form part of the claim.
The respondents argue any entitlements outstanding to Ms Kelly - which they say are closer to $77,000 - should be offset against cross-claims by the service company relating to a failed visa renewal and LexisNexis settlement.
The parties are due to appear before the court for directions on August 15, with Judge Rolf Driver presiding.
Cross-claims filed

In addition to Mr Harmer, Eight Selborne barrister James Willis is acting for Ms Kelly. Mr Sophocles is representing the respondents.
In its statement to the media, the firm said if the claim proceeds "it will be met by clearly contradictory contemporaneous written evidence".
It notes Ms Kelly's salary was set when the firm was two to three times its current size, and despite her senior role "worked very much 9 to 5 on week days and not at all on weekends, and declined to make use of a mobile phone at all, or to use the internet at her homes".
The firm sent a letter to Ms Kelly on November 29, "pointing out [the firm and its service companies] had suffered significant damage as a result of Mrs Kelly's failure satisfactorily to perform her role, with details of one particular damages claim for losses incurred of in excess of $82,000".

The letter asked her to explain why she wasn't negligent and shouldn't be "held responsible for the damages", and "why the claim should not be offset against her outstanding claims for long service leave, holiday pay and a small amount of ordinary pay (aggregating about $77,000 after tax)".
"Despite numerous follow up letters and emails to Mrs Kelly and her solicitor, no response to those enquiries has ever been received."
In its first cross-claim, the firm's service company is seeking damages of $71,991.58, the amount paid to Deloitte to renew Mr Atanaskovic's "Tier 1 (Entrepreneur)" UK work visa, which it claims was "wholly and solely attributable to Ms Kelly". Ms Kelly attests she had asked for the engagement of a third-party payroll provider to carry out the London administration, at a cost of £2,000 a year.
In a second cross-claim it seeks $154,241 for her failure to find a "better deal" than the information service provided by LexisNexis, which devolved into a litigation claim ultimately settled by the firm. In her reply, Ms Kelly denies causing the loss and notes for the previous eight or so years the firm had hired a casual or part-time librarian to deal with legal subscriptions.
Mr Atanaskovic usually spends at least half of each year in the firm's London office; that, and time zone differences, means much of the correspondence is by way of email.
Ms Kelly could not be reached by the time of printing. In a typed resignation letter dated August 5, 2016, seen by The Australian Financial Review, she thanks the firm's co-founders for "the opportunities afforded" and writes she "will continue to speak well of AH".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atanaskovic Hartnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cross-claims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Dawson Waldron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sophocles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Atanaskovic's UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Rolf Driver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Kriewaldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Willis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Sophocles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupert Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Atanaskovic</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tier 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LexisNexis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Hartnell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 6, 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kelly</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Circuit Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Moir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Skene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atanaskovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Harmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Atanaskovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hemsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Harmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
