<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420002129778713</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/malcolm-turnbull-to-meet-with-power-retailers-to-demand-help-for-sa-families/news-story/3e2625df7909068f612f75fedd9d8f3a</url>
  <title>PM to demand power retailer help customers</title>
  <content>
PRIME Minister Malcolm Turnbull will demand that power companies help customers move to cheaper contracts, potentially saving South Australian families up to $1400 per year.
Mr Turnbull has summoned the leaders of Australia's eight largest electricity companies to a meeting in Canberra next week to discuss rising power prices.
In a letter sent to the chief executives on Thursday, Mr Turnbull said he was concerned about a spike in the number of families who were unable to pay their electricity bills.
Mr Turnbull said independent reports showed a lack of information was standing in the way of many power customers seeking better deals. Switching from the worst available power retail deal to the best could save SA families up to $1400.
"Since families are feeling power price pressures now, it is important to ensure no family pays a cent more for electricity than it needs to,'' the Prime Minister said.
"I am particularly concerned by reports that consumers are being pushed from discounted market rates to higher priced standard contracts or non-discounted plans often without realising it.''
Mr Turnbull wants the power companies to meet with him, Treasurer Scott Morrison and Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg at 9am on Wednesday.
"This situation must be addressed - urgently and directly,'' he said.
Last week, the State Government announced that it would ask energy retailers to deliver reduced prices and flexible payment options to the 180,000 South Australian households who receive state concession payments. Most households that receive concession payments are on standing contracts.
The power industry bosses asked to the meeting are Catherine Tanna of Energy Australia, Frank Calabria of Origin Energy, Andy Vesey of AGL, Paul Broad of Snowy Hydro, Paul Geason of Momentum Energy, Jeff Dimey of Alinta Energy and Carly Wishart of Simply Energy.
The Australian Energy Council's Matthew Warren has also been asked to attend.
A recent report by the Australian Energy Market Commission found that over the past five years only 53 per cent of residential customers in SA and 43 per cent of small business customers changed their electricity retailer or plan.
About 20 per cent of customers reported finding it difficult to compare the value of energy contracts.

Effective methods to allow you to save money on your energy bill.

Tips to save on your energy bill
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Vesey of AGL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.25</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Calabria of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Dimey of Alinta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Energy Market Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hydro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Geason of Momentum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Broad of Snowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Energy Council's Matthew Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Tanna of Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carly Wishart of Simply</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
