<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420818173583701</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/singapores-roxypacific-and-chip-eng-seng-buy-kiwi-offices-for-162-million-20170803-gxopxe</url>
  <title>Singapore's Roxy-Pacific and Chip Eng Seng buy Kiwi offices for $162 million</title>
  <content>
Singapore-listed property investor and developers Roxy-Pacific Holdings and Chip Eng Seng Corporation have jointly acquired a New Zealand A-grade office building at 205 Queen Street, Auckland for $NZ174 million ($162 million).
Roxy-Pacific and CES have an equal 50 per cent stake in the prime 25.361sq m twin commercial towers in the heart of the Auckland CBD. The 17-storey and 22-storey towers and a retail podium sit on a 3764sq m site close to public transport and the upcoming City Rail Link Aotea Station.
The property boasts large floor plates and is 96.37 per cent leased. It has a lease term until 2081 with options for another 98 years.
"Following the successful divestment of the 59 Goulburn Street property in Sydney at an attractive yield, we have wasted no time in recycling the capital into another yield-accretive investment to strengthen our recurring income streams," Roxy-Pacfic chief executive Teo Hong Lim said.

"This acquisition marks our maiden entry into the New Zealand commercial market, where we see an opportunity to capitalise on its upward trending market cycle. With favourable market indicators, we are optimistic to raise occupancy to 100% in the near future so as to maximise rental yield."

Like Sydney, and Melbourne, Auckland has enjoyed strong office market successes. A low supply of prime property and a solid economy has kept the Auckland office vacancy low.
"This property comes with decent yield and is located at a prime location. Amid global and local challenging market conditions, we hope to diversify our operating risk while improving our recurring income with this acquisition,"CES chief execuitve Raymond Chia said.
Roxy-Pacific has been active in the Australian market in both commercial and residential investments.
In Sydney, two months ago, the listing of its 59 Goulburn Street office building sale sparked a strong contest for the asset, with  eventually buying the property for $158 million, beating the likes of .

It also holds a 50 per cent interest in a 14-storey commercial building at 117 Clarence Street and is developing a $280 million apartment development, West End Residences in Sydney's inner west Glebe.
CES is also active recently snapping up the 84-key 4.5-star waterfront hotel Sebel Mandurah hotel south of Perth from Perth-based FJM Property for about $15 million.
I just listed a 10-level office building at 420 St Kilda Road, Melbourne for more than $65 million.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Rail Link Aotea Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulburn Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-based FJM Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore's Roxy-Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy-Pacfic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand A-grade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebel Mandurah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarence Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teo Hong Lim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy-Pacific</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raymond Chia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End Residences</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glebe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chip Eng Seng Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chip Eng Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy-Pacific Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CES</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ$174</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
