<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420268417757041</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/sport/cricket-pay-deal-struck-20170803-gxoptm</url>
  <title>Cricket pay deal struck</title>
  <content>
Australia's cricketers will continue to be the highest paid locally-based athletes after the  ended with a new deal that will pay them up to $500 million in the next five years
The average pay of Cricket Australia-contracted male players, including Big Bash League contracts, will rise from $1.16 million this year to $1.45 million by 2022 and top-ranked players will earn at least $2 million annually.
Female players will have their average pay increased by 166 per cent over five years from $79,000 previously to $179,000 this season to $210,000 by 2022.
Players will also be back-paid to June 30 and share in $58 million owed to them under the terms of the recently expired memorandum of understanding with Cricket Australia.

The deal , which included players going unpaid from July 1 and Cricket Australia unsuccessfully attempting to end 20 years of gross revenue sharing with the players.

Terms for a new five-year memorandum of understanding were signed after a final round of negotiations between Cricket Australia chief executive James Sutherland and Australian Cricketers' Association boss Alistair Nicholson in Melbourne on Thursday morning before a formal announcement in the afternoon.
Players will receive about 30 per cent of revenue from agreed sources, including forecast revenue streams in a modified revenue-sharing model.
Both Cricket Australia and the players will contribute $25 million each to a grassroots investment fund over five years, which will fund improvements to junior facilities and training programs. A joint committee will oversee the spending of the funds.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia-contracted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
