<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420216878148312</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/farefree-friday-for-bus-passengers-as-bus-driver-strike-continues-20170803-gxoyod.html</url>
  <title>Fare-free Friday for bus passengers as bus driver strike continues</title>
  <content>
As the pay stand-off between Brisbane City Council and the Rail, Tram and Bus Union continues, bus passengers can expect free rides on Friday.
Fare-free Friday is just the latest action taken by the union in the dispute over a new enterprise bargaining agreement for bus drivers.Photo: Michelle Smith
But Brisbane Lord Mayor Graham Quirk said only union drivers would be taking part in that action, so passengers should still be prepared to pay.
"Not all drivers are performing that, that non-payment of fares, so we would ask that passengers continue to expect to have to pay a fare when they get to the bus," he said.

The council has also previously said the fare-free move cost $515,000 - a cost that would be passed on to taxpayers and not the council, Cr Quirk said.
"There's actually no financial pain to council with tomorrow's action, the pain will be to Queensland taxpayers because every cent that's collected on Brisbane buses goes to the state government," he said.

On Wednesday, bus drivers walked off the job from 10am to 2pm and  outside City Hall.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

At the rally RTBU assistant secretary Tom Brown said he would not rule out more strike action if an agreement could not be reached with the council.Photo: Chris Hyde
"Eventually the pay has to be settled, there can be no EBA until the pay is settled," he said.
Brisbane City Council has offered bus drivers a 2.5 per cent pay increase over three years, but the RTBU wanted an increase of 3.5 per cent.Photo: Ruth McCosker
EBA talks continued on Thursday, but
"I think if you ask the average worker in Brisbane City Council, they want it over with, they want to accept the increase, which we believe is a fair and reasonable increase," he said.
"It's got to be fair for our workers, who do a great job for Brisbane, but at the same time it has to be fair to the ratepayers and the city and I believe the offer we have on the table strikes that balance."
He said the 1 per cent increase meant a difference of $48 million over three years, which would come out of the pockets of ratepayers.
"The variation is $132 million under the 2.5 per cent, it's $180 million once you talk 3.5 per cent so it's a lot of money to find and that will equate to at least a 1 per cent increase in rates for residents," the mayor said.
"Why should I budge? Why should the ratepayers be asked to fork out more?"
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lord Mayor Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hyde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth McCosker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
