<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421436648887376</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/03/33/nationals-meet-in-qld-ahead-of-joint-party</url>
  <title>Nationals meet in Qld ahead of joint party</title>
  <content>
The Nationals are expected to recommit to a plebiscite on gay marriage at a get-together in Queensland, despite key senators promising to block such a plan for the second time.
The party's MPs, many of whom are angry the marriage debate is detracting from other issues, will meet in Rockhampton on Friday.
It comes ahead of a separate, special Liberal party meeting in Canberra called for Monday afternoon to discuss the matter before Tuesday's joint party room meeting.
Veteran MP Warren Entsch wants the Liberal party to make its own decision on marriage equality even if it runs contrary to that of their coalition partners.
But Malcolm Turnbull has already poured cold water on the idea.
"Any issue can be discussed in the Liberal party room and the joint partyroom ... but of course coalition policy is ultimately determined in the coalition partyroom," he told reporters in Perth on Thursday.
Mr Entsch, one of the Liberal MPs pushing for a vote in parliament rather than a national vote, says the plebiscite was a "captain's pick" by Tony Abbott and has become impossible to sell because some MPs say they won't accept the result.

Related Articles

Key crossbench senator Derryn Hinch said a second attempt to launch a same-sex marriage plebiscite was doomed to fail.
"If they bring the plebiscite to the Senate again, (Nick) Xenophon and I will knock it down. If they bring a postal plebiscite to the Senate, we'll knock it down. Give them a free vote," Senator Hinch told Sky News.
Senator Xenophon this week told AAP his party, which has three senators and a lower house member whose votes would be critical to mounting a plebiscite, remains opposed.
West Australian senator Dean Smith is working on a marriage equality bill and Mr Entsch is among lower house colleagues including Trevor Evans and Tim Wilson who have flagged support for it.
Federal Labor leader Bill Shorten on Thursday said his party would support a move to suspend business in parliament to bring on a private members' bill on gay marriage.
He told ABC's 7.30 program the bill doesn't have to come from him or another senior Labor figure to get his support.
"Let's make it cross-party. Let's just get it done," Mr Shorten said.
He does expect, however, a "very small number" of Labor MPs will still vote against same-sex marriage if there is a conscience vote.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's 7.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
