<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420040784485491</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/leaders/anthony-the-mooch-scaramucci-is-preparing-for/news-story/4014ac58beb38acf68c22465bafa3b70</url>
  <title>Anthony 'the Mooch' Scaramucci is preparing for</title>
  <content>
Who is Anthony Scaramucci?
1:29

Anthony Scaramucci was sensationally fired from the White House after just 11 days as Communications Director. But who was Anthony Scaramucci before he made worldwide headlines?

August 1st 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

Sacked White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci. Picture: AP

Staff writers, APNews Corp Australia Network

Share

SACKED White House staffer Anthony Scaramucci is set to address the American people one more time online, after his secret plans for Donald Trump emerged.
Known as 'The Mooch', he is planning to do an online event on Friday during the day (US time), with some assistance from Fox News co-president Bill Shine, CNN reports.
It is unclear what format the event will take, but the former Communications Director to President Donald Trump will "address the American people directly".
His plan to enter the limelight again comes as his secret plans to change Trump's media plan emerged online by right-wing media personality and Trump supporter Mike Cernovich.
He obtained a copy of an internal memo that laid out Scaramucci's plan for the White House communications team and posted it on .

Fired White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci points as he answers questions from members of the media. Picture: APSource:AP
The memo lists five priorities for the communications staff, including "Improve the culture" and "Fill the content void".
Scaramucci writes that President Trump "can choose to fight with the media, but Comms cannot", and he even suggests "a constructive 'complaint box' for the media to make complaints".
Still, the memo points out, "Comms is a Customer Service Operation - POTUS is the Number One Customer". It says the office needs to "humanise" Trump and suggests "a national online lottery to play a round of golf with him ... or a charity auction".
Scaramucci also calls for "video content that constructively operates as 'The President Donald J. Trump' show".

Scaramucci envisions running the communications department "like a news channel with producers, scripts, and narration" that will be able to "dictate the news of the day on most days".

Anthony Scaramucci was dumped on the request of new chief of staff John Kelly. Picture: AFPSource:AFP
After his appointment was announced, Scaramucci was very vocal about leaks coming out of the White House - even telling a New Yorker reporter he wanted to "kill all the leakers".
His memo is a little more restrained. He writes: "No more threats about leaking and internal game playing - anyone who takes actions that do not serve the President will be dismissed - period. We will eliminate the bad eggs and send a powerful message to the remaining staff that well-intentioned mistakes are acceptable, but misconduct is not."
The memo is dated July 30, just a day before Scaramucci was ousted by new chief of staff John Kelly.
Scaramucci was named to the position on July 21 and lasted just 11 days in the role before being removed.

White House Explains Scaramucci's Abrupt Exit
1:28

White House Press Secretary Sarah Huckabee Sanders explained on Monday why Anthony Scaramucci was removed from his position as White House communications director just 10 days after his appointment to the post. Photo: Pablo Martinez Monsivais/AP

August 1st 2017
3 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

His online event comes after President Trump confirmed he would not be leaving Twitter anytime soon. On Twitter, Trump said: "Only the Fake News Media and Trump enemies want me to stop using Social Media (110 million people). Only way for me to get the truth out!"
The tweet came one day after retired Gen. John Kelly took over as Trump's new chief of staff. Tapped to bring order to the chaotic West Wing, Kelly quickly made his presence known on Monday - ousting newly appointed communications director Anthony Scaramucci and revising the command structure so that all senior staffers report to him.
Those moves were praised Monday by Trump allies and politicians, who expressed hope that Kelly would help stem internal conflicts and advance a policy agenda after six months of tumult. But less clear is how much control Kelly will have over Trump's predilection for sowing conflict and making off-the-cuff comments on social media.
White House spokeswoman Sarah Huckabee Sanders repeated on Tuesday that Kelly had full control over the staff.
Asked at a press briefing if senior advisers Ivanka Trump, Jared Kushner and others would be able to drop in to see the president, she said: "I don't think anyone just wanders into the Oval Office."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communications Director</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Media (110</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooch' Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald J. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen. John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>POTUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanka Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pablo Martinez Monsivais/AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Press Secretary Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Customer Service Operation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Cernovich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Explains Scaramucci's Abrupt Exit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Number One Customer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
