<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420285597626697</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/energy/madeleine-albright-pe-fund-makes-hay-from-australia-power-woes-20170802-gxo8lp</url>
  <title>A former US secretary of state is making hay from Australia's electricity woes</title>
  <content>
A private equity fund chaired by former US secretary of state Madeleine Albright is benefiting from Australia's electricity woes through its large stake in APR Energy, which has stopped short of giving an Elon Musk-style "free" guarantee if it doesn't plug a gap in time.
APR Energy, which on to supply the South Australian government with a new fast-start power plant made up of nine turbines to help avert potential shortages over summer, also filled the breach for Tasmania in 2016 when an under-sea power cable to the mainland failed.
APR Energy executive chairman John Campion told The Australian Financial Review on Thursday from the company's Florida headquarters that having Ms Albright involved was a big plus for the company in its global expansion and that the Tasmanian deal had been a winner for both the company and the Tasmanian authorities.
"All round it was a good situation," he said.

Mr Campion said APR Energy hadn't provided the same guarantee for the South Australian government that Mr Musk had promised of delivering within 100 days "or it's free", but there were serious financial penalties in the contract if APR wasn't able to deliver the 276 megawatt system on time before December 1.

But there was little chance of that occurring anyway.
"Our goal as a firm, as a partner in all this is to be up and running by the end of October, or early November," Mr Campion said.
in early July won a landmark tender to supply a 100-megawatt storage battery to help shore up South Australia's fragile electricity grid.
Mr Musk said he had insisted on including his  made in March, to have the system up and running "within 100 days" of agreeing on a grid connection "or it's free".

Mr Campion didn't divulge the finer details of the APR Energy contract with the SA government, but said there would be vast financial penalties if the fast-start back-up plant wasn't in place by December 1. "If we don't make it, it's a very very bad day financially," he said.
Albright Capital Management, chaired by Madeleine Albright, who was secretary of state in the US when Bill Clinton was president, has about US$650 million in funds under management.
It holds a 24 per cent stake in APR Energy, which Mr Campion said was headed for annual revenues of around $US350 million in 2017 from its projects in 30 countries where it supplies power plants at short notice to lift supply. Canada's Fairfax Financial holds a 68 per cent stake.
Mr Campion said electricity systems across the world were changing fast as renewable energy was stitched into traditional poles and wires infrastructure.

He said having Madeleine Albright involved was invaluable. "We as business people tend to think about the pounds, shillings, and and pence viewpoint," Mr Campion said.
"But that great world view that Secretary Albright brings, it certainly gives us an edge in the market," he said. One of APR Energy's major competitors is global giant Aggreko.
APR Energy, which had been a publicly-listed company in London, was bought out by private equity funds and Fairfax Financial in late 2015 after a rocky time which Mr Campion said had largely stemmed from political strife in Libya where the company had a large power contract which represented a substantial chunk of revenue.
"We had a lot of equipment tied up there," he said.

Mr Campion, who founded APR Energy, said in the early days of the company the business was almost exclusively focused on emerging markets but that had now transformed into increasing demand from "first world" countries like Portugal, Australia and Germany, as electricity grids changed fast.
"It's definitely changing toward more of a first-world focus and that's certainly driven by the shift to renewables."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Financial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada's Fairfax Financial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aggreko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Albright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$650</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary Albright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APR Energy</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Campion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeleine Albright</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Campion</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albright Capital Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Musk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
