<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420736569203049</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/chris-archers-astros-mascot-water-balloon-fight-2017-8</url>
  <title>Chris Archer's feud with the Astros' mascot escalated into a water-balloon fight</title>
  <content>
The ongoing feud between Rays pitcher Chris Archer and Astros mascot Orbit continues to escalate.

The rivalry between the two dates back to at least 2015, when Orbit , noting both their similar appearances and Twitter habits. Then, just a few days ago,
 in which he resolved to carry out "a campaign of PRANKS, GAGS AND HIGH JINKS (sic)" on the mascot.

Archer wasted no time in making good on his promise. On Wednesday night, Archer approached Orbit with what looked like a playful peace offering - , implying that he had learned everything he knew from the Rays' mascot.

But it was all a setup. As soon as Orbit stood for a series of photos with his diploma, he was ambushed by some of Archer's foot soldiers who were hiding in the dug out wielding water balloons. Orbit took a few good shots, but was prepared for the uprising, tearing off his jersey to reveal a second jersey protected by a poncho. He also scrambled to pick up a water gun which he used to douse some watery revenge on the Rays.

You can watch video of the exchange shared by the Astros below.

The Rays and Astros wrap up their season series Thursday night, and there's no doubt that both Archer and Orbit will want to get the best of each other in their last interaction of the season.

It's becoming an all-out war.
- Houston Astros (@astros)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GAGS AND HIGH JINKS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Archer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astros</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houston Astros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
