<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420294187561645</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/rio-tinto-can-keep-big-returns-flowing-to-investors-over-next-few-years-20170803-gxomda</url>
  <title>Rio Tinto can keep big returns flowing to investors over next few years</title>
  <content>
could return as much as $US10.5 billion ($13.2 billion) to shareholders over the next 18 months, with chief executive JS Jacques declaring the miner will focus ruthlessly on growing free cash flow and has no plans for mergers and acquisitions.
Rio . It also launched a $US1 billion buyback of its London shares, taking the total doled out to $US3 billion. The latest buyback was in addition to a $US500 billion buyback launched earlier this year.
Deutsche Bank economist Paul Young, who said Rio was "executing the best strategy in the sector" now expects Rio can unleash $US2 billion worth of annual buybacks from 2018.
"Shareholder returns should step up significantly in 2018, unless commodity markets deteriorate and/or M&A options become available," he said. "We now assume a $US2 billion annual buyback from 2018 onwards. On our estimates, even with this level of capital return, net debt would continue to fall."

M&A appears to be off the agenda. Mr Jacques told analysts on Wednesday evening that Rio had "a watching brief on M&A, but we will pursue M&A only if it creates value for our shareholders.

"Today, when we look at different options, I couldn't see a way forward to create value for our shareholders because the valuation was fantastic for the sellers, I'm not quite sure for the buyers."
. It will spend $US400 million on its Silvergrass iron ore development in the Pilbara, $US5.3 billion on its Oyu Tolgoi underground copper mine development in Mongolia and $US1.9 billion on its Amrun bauxite project in Queensland.
With the miner's gearing already low, Mr Jacques also ruled out to going to zero next debt on Wednesday.
This should mean shareholders will get the bulk of the .

UBS analyst Glyn Lawcock said he sees the possibility of Rio returning a total of $US10.5 billion to investors over the next 18 months - or 11 per cent of Rio's market value.
This would include a final dividend of $US1.50 a year (to be paid in February 2018 at the company's full year results, and taking the full year dividend for 2017 to $US2.60) and a dividend of $US2.44 in 2018, worth $US4.5 billion.
Further returns would come from buybacks. Macquarie expects the $US2.7 billion Rio will receive from the sale of its Coal & Allied business to Yancoal will be returned via a buyback, including an off-market buyback of the company's Australian stock.
Mr Jacques told The Australian Financial Review on Wednesday that Rio "will not be shy in giving health superior returns for our shareholders and today is a good example of that."

Mr Lawock also expects Rio could push ahead with further assets sales. A range of assets, including Rio's Iron Ore of Canada business, its interest in the Grasberg copper mine in Indonesia and its Australian refining and smelting operations.
Mr Jacques said while he was keen to remove non-core assets from the Rio portfolio, there was no hurry.
"For us, its all about value. If I need to wait another three months or six months or a year, I will wait."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jacques</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yancoal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grasberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US5.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US4.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10.5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JS Jacques</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glyn Lawcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio's Iron Ore of Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lawock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mongolia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amrun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silvergrass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oyu Tolgoi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
