<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420650669855353</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4831545/when-coal-mines-clash-it-isnt-pleasant/?cs=308</url>
  <title>When coal mines clash it isn't pleasant</title>
  <content>
MACH Energy put $220 million on the table in January, 2016 to buy the Mount Pleasant coal mine site from Rio Tinto.

There was an approval, from 1999, to mine 197 million tonnes of coal, and an expiry date of 2020.

It was reasonably apparent MACH Energy, part of the Indonesian Salim Group, would be taking some steps to extend operations, given the looming deadline.

The approach it has decided to take - seeking several modifications, including a current application to extend operations until 2026 - has met with opposition. Environmental and community groups have objected to the mine relying on the 1999 consent, with the relatively lesser environmental conditions than would apply today. They have argued the mine should make a new application and complete a new environmental impact statement.

The thoroughbred racing industry and local councils have also objected to the mine. They have argued the open cut Mount Pleasant, and the proposed open cut Dartbrook and West Muswellbrook mines, will take surface coal mining into a part of the Hunter region that has not been open cut before.

The most surprising objection - in terms of the issues raised - was from an unusual source. Bengalla coal mine has argued Mount Pleasant should make a fresh application, supported by an environmental impact statement prepared to 2017 standards.

It argues Mount Pleasant is trying to use a modification to get an approval and overcome the consent deadline. It argues the mine won't deliver the economic benefits it says it will. It argues Mount Pleasant is going to have "profound, unacceptable, material adverse impacts" on Bengalla.

In short, Bengalla is using all the arguments against Mount Pleasant that community and environment groups are accustomed to using against mining proposals.

Muswellbrook township already deals with the environmental impacts of three huge open cut mines within striking distance - Mount Arthur, Bengalla and Mangoola - but has benefited from the money that flows from coal mining.

MACH Energy must have weighed up the risks of paying $220 million for a mine with only four years to run before its consent expired. That risk should not play a part in a proper assessment of its proposal.

Issue: 38,562.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mangoola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian Salim Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muswellbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Pleasant</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dartbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bengalla</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MACH Energy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Muswellbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
