<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420302777496348</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/donald-trump-tweets-that-russia-relations-at-very-dangerous-low-after-approving-sanctions/news-story/d5c0dfeeac17aa434e15b363094e1615</url>
  <title>Russia relations at 'very dangerous low'</title>
  <content>
US President Donald Trump said that relations between Washington and Moscow had hit an all-time and "very dangerous" low after he approved sanctions against Russia passed by Congress.
"Our relationship with Russia is at an all-time & very dangerous low," Mr Trump wrote on Twitter.

Our relationship with Russia is at an all-time & very dangerous  low. You can thank Congress, the same people that can't even give us HCare!

"You can thank Congress, the same people that can't even give us HCare!", he added in reference to a recent defeat in the Senate on his health reform plans.
Yesterday, Russia's Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev posted inflammatory statements to social media in response to the passing of tough new sanctions aimed at punishing Moscow for interfering with the 2016 US election.
The President reluctantly signed the sanctions into law overnight after the US Congress passed the motion by a margin Trump could not overrule.
"It ends hopes for improving our relations with the new US administration," Mr Medvedev states, targeting Mr Trump's repeated assertions that he wishes to do exactly that.
"Second, it's a declaration of a full-fledged economic war on Russia," he adds.

The Trump administration has shown its total weakness by handing over executive power to Congress in the most humiliating way

The US establishment fully outwitted Trump. The President is not happy about the sanctions, yet he could not but sign the bill

But Mr Medvedev's sting was in an attack on the US democratic process - and Mr Trump's ego.
"The Trump administration has shown its total weakness by handing over executive power to Congress in the most humiliating way. This changes the power balance in US political circles."
"The US establishment fully outwitted Trump; The President is not happy about the new sanctions, yet he could not but sign the bill."
Mr Medvedev states the move was a "way to knock Trump down a peg".
"New steps are to come, and they will ultimately aim to remove him from power."BIPARTISAN MOVE TO SAVE MUELLER FROM BEING FIRED
Two members of the Senate Judiciary Committee are moving to protect Special Counsel Robert Mueller's job, putting forth new legislation that aims to ensure the integrity of current and future independent investigations.
Republican Senator Thom Tillis of North Carolina and Democratic Senator Chris Coons of Delaware plan to introduce the legislation today.
The bill would allow any special counsel for the Department of Justice to challenge his or her removal in court, with a review by a three-judge panel within 14 days of the challenge.
The bill would be retroactive to May 17, 2017 - the day Mr Mueller was appointed by Deputy Attorney-General Rod Rosenstein to investigate Russian meddling in the 2016 election and possible ties to Mr Trump's campaign.
"It is critical that special counsels have the independence and resources they need to lead investigations," Sen. Tillis said in a statement. "A back-end judicial review process to prevent unmerited removals of special counsels not only helps to ensure their investigatory independence, but also reaffirms our nation's system of check and balances."
Mr Mueller was appointed as special counsel following Mr Trump's abrupt firing of FBI Director James Comey.
Mr Mueller, who was Comey's predecessor as FBI director, has assembled a team of prosecutors and lawyers with experience in financial fraud, national security and organised crime to investigate contacts between Moscow and the Trump campaign.
Mr Trump has been critical of Mr Mueller since his appointment, and the president's legal team is looking into potential conflicts surrounding the team Mr Mueller has hired, including the backgrounds of members and political contributions by some members to Hillary Clinton.
He has also publicly warned Mr Mueller that he would be out of bounds if he dug into the Trump family's finances.
Mr Mueller has strong support on Capitol Hill. Senators in both parties have expressed concerns that Mr Trump may try to fire Mr Mueller and have warned him not to do so.
"Ensuring that the special counsel cannot be removed improperly is critical to the integrity of his investigation," Sen. Coons said.
Republican Sen. Lindsey Graham of South Carolina, another member of the Judiciary panel, said last week that he was working on a similar bill that would prevent the firing of a special counsel without judicial review.
Sen. Graham said then that firing Mr Mueller "would precipitate a firestorm that would be unprecedented in proportions."
The Tillis and Coons bill would allow review after the special counsel had been dismissed.
If the panel found there was no good cause for the counsel's removal, the person would be immediately reinstated.
n addition, only the Attorney-General or the most senior Justice Department official in charge of the matter could fire the special counsel.
In the case of the current investigation, Rosenstein is charged with Mr Mueller's fate because Attorney-General Jeff Sessions recused himself from all matters having to do with the Trump-Russia investigation.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Attorney General Rod Rosenstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tillis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Tillis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democratic Senator Chris Coons of Delaware</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Sen. Lindsey Graham of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOVE TO SAVE MUELLER FROM BEING FIRED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mueller</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Senator Thom Tillis of North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Medvedev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special Counsel Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosenstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Judiciary Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General Jeff Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Coons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capitol Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Director James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HCare</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolinas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
