<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421342159604845</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/japanese-sapporo-buying-us-craft-beer-anchor-steam-85-million-2017-8</url>
  <title>Japanese mega-brewery Sapporo is buying a popular US craft beer maker for $85 million</title>
  <content>
Japanese mega-brewery  is buying the maker of the popular craft beer Anchor Steam for $US85 million, the company .

The acquisition of Anchor Steam Brewing will help Sapporo - which makes the macrobrew of the same name - expand its footprint and distribution in the hop-loving US as beer drinking  in Japan.

The deal is expected to close at the end of the month.

Founded in San Francisco in 1896, Anchor is one of America's original craft breweries and the 22nd-largest in the country, according to the . It sold 1.75 million cases last year and generated $US33 million in revenue.

The deal is just the latest  of smaller craft producers, as American palates and preferences have tilted from traditional domestic offerings to the unique and myriad flavours conjured up by smaller beer outfits.

Craft beer continues to grow, albeit slower than in years past, according to Brewers Association chief economist Bart Watson. Two breweries are started every day in the US.

But regional craft breweries like Anchor - facing stiff competition from both the macrobrewers that have entered the craft market via acquisition and the local microbreweries and brewpubs - have struggled of late.

That may be why Sapporo got the brewery on the cheap, compared with other deals. Bloomberg reported that Constellation Brands paid 8.7 times revenue for Ballast Point in 2015, while Sapporo only paid 2.6 times revenue for Anchor.

"Some of the older brands are struggling a little more in the market," Watson told Business Insider. "Obviously Anchor have a venerable brand, as the original brewer that started this revolution ... but they fit the pattern of breweries that are struggling a little bit more in this slowdown."

Anchor's home base of San Francisco is an especially competitive and high-cost market, Watson said.

Earlier this summer, the Brewers Association  for earning the designation "independent craft," capping barrel sales at 6 million and conglomerate ownership at 25%.

As a result, 14 breweries - including  acquirees Goose Island, Kona, Blue Point, and Breckenridge - can no longer bill themselves with the associations "independent craft" seal.

Add Anchor Brewing Company to that list.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anchor Brewing Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballast Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goose Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breckenridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anchor Steam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brewers Association</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anchor Steam Brewing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bart Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sapporo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US $85</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constellation Brands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
