<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420869713192517</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/what-you-need-to-know-in-advertising-today-8-3-2017-2017-8</url>
  <title>What you need to know in advertising today</title>
  <content>
A year since Instagram launched its Snapchat clone, Instagram Stories, marketers seem to have settled on a clear favourite.

Instagram's pure scale, evident in its reach, targeting and retargeting capabilities, has made it an attractive bet for brands, who have been  to run ads on it.

To read more about why marketers are betting on Instagram over Snapchat, click here.

In other news:

Business Insider caught up with Trade Desk CEO Jeff Green for an ad tech reality check.

The brand's ascent can be attributed to a well-orchestrated marketing strategy that includes a focus on social media, particularly Instagram.

The HBO hackers have stolen "thousands" of internal documents. They reportedly have seven times as much data as was stolen in the Sony attack.

Facebook is changing its news feed to favour websites that load faster. It says the move is in response to frustrations over slow-loading websites.

Apple added a revealing word to its official business strategy, which reveals the direction the company sees itself heading. The company highlighted how important its services business is to it in an SEC filing on Wednesday.

Disney is working with The Void to open a special 'Star Wars' hyper-reality experience near its parks. The new experience will open near Downtown Disney in Anaheim, California, and near Disney Springs in Orlando, Florida.

Business Insider caught up with Scott Svenson, the CEO of MOD Pizza.

But advertising revenue within its Turner division declined 6% on the previous year, due to its networks airing fewer basketball games than last year.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram Stories</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anaheim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orlando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Wars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insiders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of MOD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapchat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trade Desk CEO Jeff Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Svenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downtown Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
