<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420564770507337</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/kkr-considers-equity-carrot-to-lure-pepper-top-dogs-20170803-gxod2m</url>
  <title>KKR considers equity carrot to lure Pepper top dogs </title>
  <content>
KKR & Co's credit team are assessing the merits of offering equity in a privatised Pepper Group to executives, shareholders and directors as they work to formalise a $650 million offer.  
​Street Talk understands that among options being considered by , is executing the takeover through a new entity controlled by the firm. That would allow management and key executives a scrip option in a transaction if it is ultimately signed off by the non-bank lender and loan servicing company's shareholders. 
The structure would act as a retention tool for key executives and also allow them to share in any upside once Pepper is taken away from the glare of public markets.  
The company has two significant shareholders including  and Perpetual with a 12.5 per cent.

Chief executive Mike Culhane holds 4.5 per cent of the company. 

Interestingly, other private equity-style bids have taken a similar approach in the past two years, being structured so management or founders can continue their involvement in the business as an equity holder.  
Pacific Equity Partners used a shell company named Australasian Foods to acquire Patties Foods. When the buyout firm bought the pie-maker Patties Foods last year, Patties shareholders were offered cash or shares in the new PEP controlled private company. The "class B" shares up for grabs were restricted to 45 per cent of the created HoldCo, which would operate under PEP's control. 
Quadrant Private Equity's investment in tap business Zip Industries also saw founder Michael Crouch with a residual ownership stake in the company, and Ken Lowe the founder of Canberra Data Centres rolled into the PE firm's takeover of the company. 
The Pepper scenario is likely to come to a head in the next few weeks as KKR decides whether to move forward with a binding offer. 

Shareholders may receive a fully franked dividend of 3¢ a share on top of the $3.60 a share bid.
With KKR's credit team running the deal it means the transaction would likely be funded using mezzanine debt and other products from KKR's arsenal.
This column flagged KKR's interest in Pepper in May. 
Elsewhere,  Ausgrid has made a successful debut in United States debt markets, closing the books on the biggest ever deal by an Australian issuer into the US privately issued debt market. 
Sources said Ausgrid raised the $2 billion it was after, including more than $US1.6 billion in the US Private Placement market, to refinance a bridge loan in full. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zip Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Private Placement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KKR</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HoldCo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pep</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Culhane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quadrant Private Equity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Data Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pepper Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ausgrid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Equity Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasian Foods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patties Foods</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
