<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420517525865944</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/travel-is-a-good-reminder-that-we-are-a-nation-of-migrants-20170803-gxoq2z.html</url>
  <title>Travel is a good reminder that we are a nation of migrants</title>
  <content>
 I've been away from Australia for three weeks, something I have never done before in more than 40 years of running a business that had three rules - service, service, service. And that meant never being away from the shop for too long.
So, 21 days on the other side of the world was quite an experience and nearly as mind-boggling as returning home to commentators ranting about immigration, refugees and marriage equality.Photo: AP
With the perspective of three weeks of distance, a few things have become clear.
First. We don't know how lucky we are. I can tell you Australia is a great place. I travelled from St Petersburg to London plus parts of southern Europe and the Mediterranean and, as they say, there's no place like home.
The second thing is, it's worth remembering that everybody is good at something. I ran our business that way. I used to tell my son, the CEO, that it's incumbent upon us to ensure new employees succeed. After all, half the responsibility of the hire was ours. So, under the banner of everybody is "good at something", we worked hard to slot people into places where it worked for them and us. Donald Trump doesn't get it.
We all have our strengths and specialities and the same thing seems to be true for cities and countries. In St Petersburg, it's the unique cultural assets such as The Hermitage and the Kirov that distinguish a bejewelled city where President Putin is a favourite son. Americans need to realise that the more they put the boot in, the more they elevate Putin's hero status. They might also be realising that whatever their problems with Putin, he is at least competent in running his own office.

I then moved to London where the British are so good at, well, being British. I think they're on a continuing demise, but they do some things brilliantly, like queuing.
Then to Barcelona where the Spanish have absorbed six million refugees while rebuilding a seriously damaged economy. They have just achieved GDP growth of 3 per cent, quite a bit higher than here. Our so called "illegal immigration" problems are nothing compared to what Europe is dealing with.
But it was on the final leg in Italy where one could see the strength of national identity and confidence in its undoubted strengths.
I'm not a Catholic, or even religious, but when you see the kilometre-long line of tourists trying to get into the Vatican, you realise the value of really owning your traditions as a country.
Not that they are all looked after with loving care. Louise, who is travelling with me, kept having urges to buy a packet of steelo soap pads and give a few of the ancient treasures a good scrub. I'm told the Roman buildings were last spruced up around 2000.
And of course, the Italians are really good at something else - pasta al dente. Pasta just tastes different in Italy. Louise kept peeking into the kitchens to see if they were using the "slow release from the ceiling" test. But the answer probably lies in government legislation that states all pasta must be made of 100 per cent Italian-grown Durum wheat flour. If protectionism creates this sort of perfection, I'm rethinking my position.
So, with the best pasta of my life still lingering in the memory, I touched down to find a new big bureaucracy that puts the life blood of the nation, immigration, into a department of police, paramilitary and spies.
We seem intent on emphasising threats, including ones that are minor by international standards, rather than opportunities.
Perhaps the Europeans simply understand these things better than us. After all, the monumental tragedies of two world wars that largely occurred on their continent are still within most families' living memory. They really feel for the displaced because they know what it's like.
I have often quoted George Megalogenis on these issues. He reminds us that Australia has been built on immigration and we must maintain our openness if we want to continue to build a great nation.
We're reminded we are the most multicultural nation in the world. Immigration works.
Our response in creating a mega department of homeland security that includes immigration sends exactly the wrong message.
Immigration is first and foremost a nation-building exercise and not a security issue.
America was also built on immigration but it is also fuelling xenophobia. And its power and influence is on the skids.
Ours will be as well unless we get a whole lot more confident in ourselves. Otherwise we are just throwing spaghetti at the ceiling.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian-grown Durum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vatican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hermitage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Petersburg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Megalogenis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
