<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420294187561601</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/transport/aviation/patience-pays-off-for-webjet-boss-in-jactravel-deal-20170802-gxnsti</url>
  <title>Patience pays off for Webjet boss John Guscic in JacTravel deal</title>
  <content>
Webjet chief executive John Guscic expects the online travel giant's business-to-business operations to more than double in the next two years following the.
Mr Guscic revealed he had been eyeing off JacTravel for more than four years as part of his  but did not have the market capitalisation to fund a deal that size until this year.
"I've known some of the management at Jac for more than ten years and I regularly go to trade shows in Europe and the Middle East and meet them and check on how their business is travelling," Mr Guscic told The Australian Financial Review.
"When we were starting our entry into the B2B market place they were always in our consideration but your market cap dictates your strategy. We couldn't have done this deal two years ago."

Webjet's share price has doubled over the last year, helping Mr Guscic secure the deal which the company is funding with cash, debt and a $164 million capital raising. The institutional take-up off the entitlement offer closed oversubscribed on Thursday.

Thebehind Hotelbeds Group by increasing its hotels portfolio from  10,000 to 17,000. Mr Guscic said he expected to grow Webjet's B2B total transaction value (TTV) to around $2 billion in the next couple of years. In the 2016 financial year, Webjet's B2B TTV was $346 million, about 20 per cent of its overall business. Webjet's consumer business traditionally made up the bulk of its earnings.
"We think on the B2B side that in light of the assets we already have, the growth rates we have, the Thomas Cook contract we are committed to, we have the opportunity of being north of $2 billion at a TTV level over the next couple of years," Mr Guscic said.
He said Webjet looked at other acquisition opportunities and would not say if anymore deals were on the horizon. The JacTravel deal will allow Webjet to bulk up the division which sells hotel products to travel agents as part of a strategy to head off fierce competition in the consumer travel market.
Webjet already owns European online B2B hotel provider SunHotels and owns the Lots of Hotels brand, which operates in the Middle East and Africa.

Mr Guscic said bookings in July were up 24 per cent and Webjet would continue to outperform the market.
"There are always competitive threats and there are always people who take a negative view ... we have a resilience around our business that is second to none," he said.
Webjet shares fell 12 per cent last week over a disagreement with its auditor over  the way it accounts for transactions linked to its supply deal with Thomas Cook.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JacTravel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunHotels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webjet</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thebehind Hotelbeds Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Guscic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webjet's B2B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webjet's B2B TTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Cook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lots of Hotels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Guscic</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B2B</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
