<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420650669855356</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/opinion/high-stakes-for-betting-industry/news-story/dde4eb1f7ab433fb85fec3efccae2d3a</url>
  <title>High stakes for betting industry</title>
  <content>
THE Northern Territory's status as the premier online licensing jurisdiction, and the 350 jobs that go with it, are under threat.
So too are events such as the Crown Bet Million Dollar Fish, the Crownbet Darwin V8s, and the Darwin Cup Carnival which features the Ladbrokes Derby Day and the bet 365 Sprint Day - all sponsored by the Territory's online betting operators.
The reason is the Territory has carved out a valuable niche by offering online betting operators an attractive tax regimen and the greedy money-hungry states have accused the NT of depriving them of "their" gambling tax due.
Online gambling is the fastest growing gambling segment, accounting for more than $1.4 billion each year. Most of the nation's online betting operators are based in Darwin at Fannie Bay and a newly introduced 15 per cent point-of-consumption tax by South Australia has made it a lot more costly for these operators to stay in Darwin. If a similar 15 per cent tax is introduced in every other State it could wipe out the Darwin and Territory online betting industry.
Why stay if it is cheaper to operate elsewhere? And with that will go $40 million from our economy plus millions of dollars in sponsorship towards some of our most significant tourism events.
Deputy Chief Minister and Treasurer Nicole Manison has made it clear that protecting the Industry in the Territory and the hundreds of jobs is the Territory Government's top priority.
Sitting down and working with the Federal Treasurer Scott Morrison on a federal point of consumption tax is the best course of action to save the industry and the jobs in the NT.
A federal level point-of-consumption tax would address some of the territorial inequities under current Australian gambling laws by providing a nationally consistent approach.
It would be the best possible outcome for the Territory.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Chief Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crownbet Darwin V8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Nicole Manison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Cup Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Bet Million Dollar Fish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fannie Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sprint Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territory Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladbrokes Derby Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
