<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420259827822289</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/rendezview/drugtesting-new-welfare-recipients-is-a-good-idea/news-story/6ad567c144493873efc305f89ca5bbd5</url>
  <title>Drug-testing welfare recipients is a good idea</title>
  <content>
WITH ice addiction declared a public health crisis, the Government's proposed drug-testing trial of welfare recipients couldn't come at a better time.
Methamphetamine-related deaths have doubled in Australia in just six years,  by the National Drug and Alcohol Research Centre.
Back in May, Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull defended the controversial trial by saying: "If you love somebody who is addicted to drugs, don't you want to get them off drugs?"
Naturally, but the fact is that addicts won't seek treatment or be motivated to change unless they see a reason to do so.
Labor and the Greens have already signalled they will oppose the trial when it goes before Parliament in coming weeks, citing invasion of privacy and the demonising of battlers.
This week Dr Alex Wodak, president of the Australian Drug Law Reform Foundation, launched an online petition against the testing because he thinks it will put lives at risk.
Dr Wodak says you can't punish people into recovery, but is this what the Government is trying to do?
Could it, as Treasurer Scott Morrison said in his budget lockup press conference in May, be trying to bring responsibility into accepting welfare payments?
Many Australians are fed up with their tax dollars going to support people who are unwilling to help themselves.
There is also wide acknowledgment that drugs are an increasing problem among our youth, particularly in regional Australia.
Under the two-year trial, 5000 new Youth Allowance and Newstart recipients will be randomly selected in three locations for testing for cannabis, ecstasy or methamphetamines, including ice.
Tests will be done, either through saliva or urine, at Department of Human Services meetings, and those who test positive will be called back for a second test to determine if their drug use is an ongoing problem, and the cost of that test will be deducted from their welfare payment.
Fines will be imposed for people who refuse the test, and those who test positive will take out less of their welfare payments in cash, with a cashless welfare card giving them access to selected goods.
Civil libertarians may bleat about a nanny state, but this is not about cutting people off from the assistance they need.
People who test positive multiple times will be referred to medical professionals for assessment and appropriate treatment, and this will form part of a plan to get them into the workforce.
Of the 5000 recipients, it is expected that less than 10 per cent - or 425 - will test positive.
Rather than demonising a minority, couldn't the fact that these are new and mostly young Centrelink clients indicate opportunities for earlier intervention and potential recovery?
Dr Wodak cites trials in New Zealand that he says have not worked and may have even caused harm to addicts.
Andrew Laming, Federal Member for Bowman who helped design the current proposal, argues that the New Zealand model was different because it tested job applicants at workplaces where drug testing was already required.
"The Government is not about making people clean for employment but ready to be employed when they don't know who their employer is. It is about remaining off drugs so that you can be clean to show up for a job interview."
Laming says technology has improved in the 12 months since New Zealand did its testing and costs have come down (the precise cost of the trial has not been disclosed because the Government says it is commercial in confidence).
"The economics of the issue have changed so you can't say, where is your evidence? It is a trial, with the intention of collecting fresh evidence."
Australia has a high number of non-working households, with generational unemployment a growing concern. One in 10 dependent children lives in a family where no one is employed, according to the Australian Bureau of Statistics.
Every effort must be made to prepare people for available jobs.
Methamphetamine addiction, meanwhile, is destroying families. A recent Queensland Child Safety Department study found 60 per cent of the children of ice-addicted parents suffered severe neglect. Almost one-third experienced "emotional harm", nearly 10 per cent were physically abused and 1.5 per cent sexually abused.
Waiting for people who abuse drugs to voluntarily seek rehabilitation could take time society can ill afford.
A drug-test trial of new welfare recipients is not a panacea, but if it identifies those Australians with a problem and puts them in touch with medical professionals who can help, if by disrupting negative patterns of dependency it assists them in taking greater responsibility for their lives, then it is worth due consideration.
Kylie Lang is an associate editor at The Courier-Mail.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Laming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Wodak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Allowance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Child Safety Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Human</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Drug Law Reform Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newstart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Lang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Alex Wodak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alcohol Research Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Drug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
