<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421028626985652</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/opinion/conrad-liveris-if-i-can-do-everything-else-in-this-country-why-cant-i-get-married/news-story/72aaa665cd7a0b2756882856392a7de3</url>
  <title>Marriage equality is a simple case of respect</title>
  <content>
FOR a lot of gay people like myself it can be hard to describe why marriage equality matters.
Except for marriage, we have the same rights and responsibilities as each and every one of you. We lead full and happy lives. Everyday we are more accepted in society, by our families and at work.
Like many Australians, we are confused why we don't have the full privileges of citizenship. We are your neighbours, friends, family and people you trust.
Except our politicians don't trust us with marriage.
When I came out to my parents they didn't bat an eyelid. They gave me a hug and then we got on with our life. My dad said that it didn't matter because "you're still our son and we love you".
It's an experience lots of my gay and lesbian friends have had, absolute acceptance and support.
Last week the issue came up with a friend of mine in his 60's, he told me about when his son came out. "He was nervous and anxious, but his mother and I had didn't care because he always was and always will be our son. So I put my hand on his and said he had nothing to worry about and we sat in silence knowing that our lives were about to become richer."
It was the sort of moment that pulls on the heartstrings.
But I didn't just come out to my parents. It was to my friends, at work, it's how I am sometimes introduced and part of how people characterise me.
Seeking marriage won't change that, but it will give me dignity of equality.
Some people will always have an issue with me being gay, and that's fine. I won't lose sleep over it. For now, I am not their equal and I am denied the same rights they have.
That's a hard feeling to describe, because it lingers at the back of my mind though I don't always think about it.
Not being equal doesn't impact my day to day life, nor does it consume my every being. Yet every now and then it hits me right in the face. It's when I'm called a faggot, when I see high-profile gay people targeted because of their sexuality and defined by it, or when I hear the vitriol people hold gay people in though it is just one part of who I am.
It reminds me that the country I was born in does not give me the same rights as my brothers, that I am prevented from living my life.
When LGBT people ask for marriage equality, we don't ask for anything more than the dignity and respect all other Australians have.
It boggles the mind that some politicians say that being conservative and opposing gay marriage go hand in hand. The former UK prime minister David Cameron told his party, similar to the Liberal Party, that "conservatives believe in the ties that bind us; that society is stronger when we make vows to each other and support each other".
Conservatives support marriage equality, social regressives don't.
It's a message that our politicians like Mathias Cormann, Christian Porter, Ken Wyatt and Michael Keenan should heed.
Standing in the way of marriage equality has no reasonable argument. Christian history and the Bible show that marriage has taken many forms and responds to the will of society. The economic benefits rank in the hundreds of millions if not billions of dollars. Socially, we become more inclusive and respectful.
For politicians, their jobs may rely on it too. Passing marriage equality takes an issue which is plaguing them off the table. We read that the polls are tight and seats are on the line, they could do with fresh air by dealing with a simple matter of equality before the law quickly.
And while the idea of a national vote on the issue appeals to many, the cost doesn't. The cost now sits near $200 million dollars because politicians won't do their job, I couldn't think of anything more pathetic.
If I can do everything else in this country, then why can't I get married?
Conrad Liveris is a corporate adviser on workforces and risk.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bible</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conrad Liveris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
