<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420517525865956</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4797913/change-is-not-pain-free-but-it-is-positive/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Change is not pain free, but it is positive</title>
  <content>
BE GONE: Talk of doing away with single-use plastic bags in supermarkets has created concern among many, but there are always solutions, argues one contributor.

IN response to Peter Howley (Letters, 3/8): I agree with some comments but not others. Firstly I am hoping that some of Peter's concerns will be addressed by businesses well before the dreaded single use plastic bags are phased out.

I believe biodegradable bags have been available in some states for years, so would it be so difficult for the consumer to pay an extra dollar to load their purchases in? I have noticed in Aldi's fruit and veg section that they have already introduced biodegradable plastic bags, no extra charge. Bunnings have completely discontinued the issue of plastic bags but offered customers cardboard boxes.
We have been operating almost plastic bag free since watching the wonderful War on Waste on ABC. Anything that can be composted goes in our green bin and our recycle bin is almost always full. Our red bin collects only a quarter of what it once did. Online, we sourced bags that clip onto the sides of a trolley and are reusable. Lots of alternatives out there, you just needs to look. Change comes very hard to some but perhaps we need to remember plastic bags were not available when some of us were young and we did OK, didn't we?
As for all those whinging about how they will pick up dog poo, I suggest newspaper and a rubber glove. It's about the environment and not about making our lives easier.
Denise Lindus Trummel, Mayfield

Partnership hurts workers

BRIAN Burston does not seem to realise the connection between One Nation's support for the Liberal Party's Australian Building Construction Commission (ABCC) legislation and the lack of apprenticeships in the building trades ('Burston brushes off attack', Herald, 2/8). When I was the secretary of the CFMEU in the '80s, the union ran campaigns which resulted in many hundreds of people obtaining apprenticeships. 
Since then, I think the Liberal state government has been undermining apprenticeship training by privatising TAFE and the federal Liberal government has been introducing legislation designed to allow employers to force workers on to individual contracts, which makes it difficult to take on apprentices. Last year, the Turnbull government re-established the ABCC with One Nation support. Under this legislation, when the union takes action, the employer can call the political 'police', who can interrogate workers without the legal representation.
By supporting the ABCC legislation, I believe One Nation has not only helped the Liberal Party undermine the basic workplace rights, but they have also undermined the unions' ability to help unemployed young people obtain an apprenticeship at a time when we have high youth unemployment and employers are bringing in 'skilled' workers from overseas instead.
Don McDonald, former director NSW TAFE, former secretary CFMEU

Question for independents

I READ with interest John Beach's confusing letter (Letters, 1/8) congratulating so-called "independent" candidate for Newcastle council Kath Elliott for her misguided stance on council rates. The fact is this, Newcastle council has been declared fit for the future, turning budget deficits into surpluses, while doubling investment into clearing the infrastructure backlog built up under years of "independent" leadership.
As a local union official, I'm concerned Ms Elliott's financial plans for council will risk local jobs and services. 
As a Tarro local, I know plans to cut council budgets will be bad for my community who have seen "independents" try to close Beresfield pool and golf course as well as voting to decrease funding for roads, parks and infrastructure upgrades. It should be noted it was Labor councillors who voted to save the Beresfield pool and the golf course. 
Regarding the Newcastle 500 race, when I speak to people, they are excited. The question Mr Beach should ask the independents is: Do you support the Supercars, or are you opposed to the race which will bring in investment and jobs over five years?
Tony Callinan, Australian Workers' Union NSW

Discussion welcome

THANK you Jeremy Bath for your explanation of council expenditure in Watt Street, and thank you for entering into a public discussion about the merits of the Supercars event (Letters, 2/8). It's a frank discussion and it should have taken place before the decision to host the race. 
Could you please explain how a safe noise level for council's field staff is set at 85 decibels, but for those children living on the track it may exceed 105 decibels, and how it came to pass that council ceded its powers over the closure of roads to Supercars? It would be timely for council to release the business case for the Supercars event. Did council pay for the right to hold the race?
All these actions involve public money and residents deserve a full accounting before the election. On the same day that, as I understand it, residents were promised a noise management plan, Supercars issued hyperbole-laden statements about ticket sales and opening the Nobbys hair-pin bend to the public. It was a classic distraction, to cover the failure to produce noise-control measures. It seems a new self-managing republic has emerged inside our city walls, with Supercars at its helm, and our council has allowed itself to be sidelined. Mr Bath has been left to put a glossy face to a disastrous situation, which could be avoided by moving the race to a non-residential area.
John Beach, Cooks Hill

No need for class divide

NEWCASTLE council's interim general manager chose the Herald (Letters, 2/8) to respond to John Beach's concerns over the Supercars race. It is unfortunate Mr Bath has chosen to be a partisan promoter/apologist for the event resorting to an imaginary and divisive east/west class distinction of Newcastle suburbs to justify council's actions. Regardless of where a citizen resides, they deserve an honest, respectful and impartial response to any legitimate concern over any council decision. Such a response is prescribed in its own Code of Conduct.
I recently wrote to the council suggesting one of their responses to the Newcastle East community group relating to council's assertion it was not the proper consent authority for a DA change regarding a liquor licence boundary variation application may have been wrong in law. I was abruptly directed to Destination NSW's website. If such an unhelpful response typifies Newcastle council's engagement style with its own residents, the race has yet to begin on how they should be properly treating all their "customers".

Tony Brown, Newcastle

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooks Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watt Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Howley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Bath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denise Lindus Trummel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party's Australian Building Construction Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Callinan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beresfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nobbys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Burston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Workers' Union NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Beach</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bath</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Code of Conduct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald, 2/8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Destination NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABCC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
