<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421419469017804</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/03/33/probe-into-melbourne-plane-crash-continues</url>
  <title>Probe into Melbourne plane crash continues</title>
  <content>
Air crash investigators will spend a second day in a Melbourne paddock where a light plane slammed into the ground leaving two people fighting for life.
The ultralight Bristell two-seater training plane crashed at Clyde North on Thursday morning, with one person, believed to be a man in his 30s, flown to Royal Melbourne Hospital in a critical condition.
A second man, thought to be in his 20s, was trapped in wreckage for more than an hour before being taken to The Alfred Hospital with facial, chest and spinal injuries.
He was initially in a serious condition but that was upgraded to critical on Thursday afternoon, a hospital spokeswoman said.
The aircraft was registered to Learn to Fly Melbourne based at Moorabbin Airport. One of the men on board was a student pilot and the other an instructor.
Recreational Aviation Australia will be investigating the crash as the governing body for ultralight aircraft and pilots.
"We will have two investigators on scene this afternoon and all day tomorrow," Mr Linke told AAP on Thursday.

Related Articles

It was too early to comment on the cause of the crash but investigators would look at environmental, human and mechanical factors to determine the cause, he said.
Witness Kane Loveday who was driving in the area, told the Seven Network: "It sounded like a lack of power basically and before I could see anything it was below the tree line."
Civil Aviation Safety Authority spokesman Peter Gibson said the ultralight was on a training flight.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clyde North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fly Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Linke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civil Aviation Safety Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bristell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Melbourne Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorabbin Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aviation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Loveday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
