<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651420654964822774</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/ibrahim-sister-jazz-dior-avoids-jail-over-gun-plot-20170803-gxoei4.html</url>
  <title>Ibrahim sister Jazz Dior avoids jail over gun plot</title>
  <content>
The sister of former bikie boss Sam Ibrahim, who admitted plotting with her de facto partner to supply guns, has avoided jail time for her crime.
Jazz Dior, 46, and Elvis Mileski, 44, on Thursday were sentenced to 18-month jail terms to be served by way of an intensive correction orders in the community.Photo: AAP
The couple had pleaded guilty in the District Court in Sydney to one charge of conspiracy with each other to unlawfully supply firearms in early 2014.
Judge Robert Toner said that, as part of Dior's corrections order, she must be of good behaviour and commit no offences.
She also has to reside at an approved address and not leave NSW without permission, submit to surveillance and monitoring, and do 32 hours of community service each month.
The same conditions were imposed on Mileski.

An agreed statement of facts tendered to the court revealed phone taps captured Mileski negotiating to obtain firearms and sell them with Dior's help between January and March 2014.
The couple were arrested in April 2014 after police raided properties in Sydney and the Illawarra region.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Police seized 18 weapons including an M1 military-grade assault rifle, a standard rifle, three pistols, two shotguns and 11 handguns.
According to the agreed facts, a February 2014 phone tap picked up Mileski telling Dior that he needed another $23,000 on top of the $10,000 he had for six "brand new things, in the boxes". He was referring to firearms.
Mileski told Dior the price of each was "five and a half" and he'd already "knocked off 15K on the deal".
Mileski was heard saying he needed to hire a car to pick up the goods rather than use his and Dior's car because he didn't want to take risks.
Later phone intercepts captured the couple discussing when Mileski planned to pick up the firearms.
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Ibrahim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Robert Toner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazz Dior, 46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis Mileski, 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mileski</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazz Dior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dior</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ibrahim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
