<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421256260257145</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/sonix-best-apple-iphone-cases-2017-8</url>
  <title>After using this $35 iPhone case for a year, I'll never buy from any other brand</title>
  <content>
Apple purists will tell you not to cover the iPhone's gorgeous design with a case.

If you need a case, though, fanboys will tell you the only acceptable cases to use are the ones made by Apple. 

But Apple's iPhone cases don't all come cheap, and realists will advise not to spend too much money on a case, since it's just going to get scratched or break anyway. 

But as someone who's been using its products for over a year now, I can safely say that  makes the best iPhone cases. 

I need a case on my iPhone, purely for peace of mind. I don't drop my phone often and I've never (knock on wood) cracked my screen. But I know that as soon as I get cocky and take my case off, I will immediately break my phone. 

Plus, iPhones are inherently boring to look at. They're beautifully designed, sure, but they're not really great at showcasing one's unique personal style. 

So when I stumbled upon Sonix totally by accident at my neighbourhood Urban Outfitters, I was delighted, since Sonix offers a major feature I look for in phone cases: Small-yet-necessary bumpers. The front edges of the case are almost imperceptibly higher than the screen, so that if I drop my phone directly on its face, the screen won't take all the impact. 

Plus, Sonix cases are almost entirely clear with prints overlaid on the back in bright colours or metallics. You get the best of both worlds by being able to show off your iPhone - they make cases for Samsung Galaxy S7, S8, and S8+, too - while still looking like an individual. 

I'm now on my second Sonix case, and I can't imagine ever switching to another brand. The cases are incredibly durable, scratch-resistant, stylish, and relatively affordable at $US35 per case. The only reason I've had to buy another one is because I switched from an iPhone 5s to an iPhone 6s (I still kept my old case in the event I ever switch back to a smaller phone). I bought my first Sonix case in a brick-and-mortar store, but they're also available online via Sonix's website and Amazon.

If there are any downsides to the brand, it's that it caters more toward women's tastes than men's. Plus, their cases seem to be , so you may see Emma Stone or Kylie Jenner toting the same phone case as you. But if you're someone who constantly drops their phone, or someone who simply wants something more exciting than what's sold in the Apple store, it's worth checking out what Sonix has to offer.

EXCLUSIVE FREE REPORT:

25 Big Tech Predictions by BI Intelligence.

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonix</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Tech Predictions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FREE REPORT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S$8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Outfitters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple's iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Jenner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung Galaxy S7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BI Intelligence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
