<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421831785885897</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/free-tennis-and-stroll-into-yesteryear-at-retro-fa/3207936/</url>
  <title>Free tennis and stroll into yesteryear at Retro Fantastic</title>
  <content>
THE Retro Fantastic on August 5 at the Mapleton Hall is an opportunity to join the members of the Mapleton Tennis Club for a genteel step back in time.
The club is taking part in the Retro Fantastic by opening the Mapleton Tennis Courts to all adults over 18 years for a free game of tennis.
You can make a day of it by playing a game and then wandering through the grounds of the hall, where the Retro Fantastic will be taking place from 9am-2pm.
The Retro Fantastic is a celebration of the 50th anniversary of the naming of the Sunshine Coast, and is part of the Sunshine Coast's Festival of Small Community Halls.
The theme of the day is 1967, and all visitors are encouraged to turn out in their best '60s fashions to help make the day even more authentic.
A huge array of stalls, activities, displays, and entertainment - all in the theme of 1967 - will be sure to delight.
There is something for everyone, including: a suitcase rummage (free sites); a 1960s fashion show; veteran cars; kids' activities such as kite making, face painting and old-time races; a craft table; a range of stalls from community groups with cakes, sweets, lucky dips, books, bric-a-brac and crafts; a '60-style kitchen, complete with milk shakes and spiders; devonshire teas; homemade ginger beer and lemonade; dance demonstrations; retro stalls; and musical entertainment.
In the evening, the hall comes alive with a double-bill concert featuring the continental sounds of Mzaza on the Children of the Road tour, and the gpsy rhythms of Vardos.
Visit  and
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapleton Tennis Courts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vardos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Children of the Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retro Fantastic</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapleton Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mzaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Halls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapleton Tennis Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast's Festival of Small</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
