<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421634217387020</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/447102/driver-in-cessnock-fatals-in-hiding/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Driver in Cessnock fatals in 'hiding'</title>
  <content>
THE driver involved in the fatal crash near Cessnock, which claimed the lives of two teenagers, is believed to still be in hiding after a threatening sign appeared at the crash site.

Belinda Duncan, 36, suffered minor injuries in the crash on Wednesday, which left Jayde Duncan and Cassandra Ford dead and another two teenagers badly injured.
It is believed Ms Duncan has moved out of town and has told police she fears for her safety following the Duffie Drive smash.
A handwritten sign, highly critical of Ms Duncan, was nailed to a tree at the crash site last week while Ms Duncan was still recovering in hospital.
Troy Parnell, the uncle of Brad Parnell, 16, who lost part of one leg in the crash, said he was not surprised Ms Duncan had apparently gone into hiding, considering the feeling in the community.
He said he felt "exactly the same way as what the sign says".
"People are dead, Brad has lost a leg and to make it worse he's constantly reliving the whole thing, going over it again and again," he said.
"People want answers to what happened."
Mr Parnell said Ms Duncan tried to visit his injured nephew in hospital on Friday but was refused by the teenager's mother and hospital staff.
Central Hunter duty officer Brad Slarks said police had not been notified about any threats to Ms Duncan's safety.
"At this stage we're not aware of anything like that, I've not heard of any threats being made against her," he said.
He said reports of any threats against her or anyone involved would be taken seriously.
Crash investigators are still looking into the incident. The car has been seized for testing.
Kurri Kurri Chamber of Commerce and Industry president Rod Doherty said the Coalfields community was coming to grips with the deaths.
"It's pretty awful," he said.
"A lot of people have been saying, 'Holy smokes, how can something like this happen?'.
"When these things happen they're very unfortunate."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Doherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Duncan</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Parnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayde Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duffie Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Parnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Parnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Duncan, 36</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Slarks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassandra Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
