<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421866145624865</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:23</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/shopping-centre-became-beating-heart-of-kawana/3207387/</url>
  <title>Shopping centre became beating heart of Kawana</title>
  <content>
WHEN then premier Joh Bjelke-Petersen opened the Kern-built Kawana Shoppingtown on October 23, 1979, retail became a player in the development of the coastal stretch between Mooloolaba and Currimundi.
The first major players to arrive were Woolworths, Big W and Rockmans.
Owners BHP and Shell had provided a shopping centre that was a destination for the Coast's residents and visitors.
It had easy-access carparks (staff were encouraged to park on the boundaries to make the centre look busy).
"The Town" traded as one and customers came from near and far to shop.
Kmart opened one year later in Maroochydore as The Sands, on what is now known as Sunshine Plaza.
Competition had begun between Maroochydore, Caloundra and even Kmart at Aspley.
Management became a new experience for the independent traders who were given an opportunity to trade there as they designed creative shopfronts and fit-outs, dealt with rents, interest rates and staff.
I believe the development of our community can be attributed to the fiscal and financial support these traders and their customers contributed over the years.
But while we now had a retail destination, we had no focalpoint: for example, no post office.
In the early days, we at the newsagency had to sell stamps bought from the Mooloolaba post office - all collected and on-sold for nil profit. There also was no main road signage anywhere. We had to make the Kawana identity.
The Kawana Chamber of Commerce was formed in 1986 in the foyer of the nearby Kawana Waters Hotel.
Then 1988 saw the major Nicklin Way upgrade, heralding traffic lights along the stretch, as well as the start of Expo 88 in Brisbane which meant the Kawana Shoppingworld carpark full as locals caught the bus to Brisbane.
The 1990s saw competition from Franklins against Coles and Woolies, a major centre extension and addition of a large food court, and the emergence of franchised shops.
But one of my fondest memories is the Kawana Time promotion in what I call the golden days of the chamber of commerce, which made Kawana truly the place to live, work and play.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana Time</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicklin Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expo 88</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kmart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aspley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana Waters Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockmans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana Shoppingworld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kern-built Kawana Shoppingtown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joh Bjelke-Petersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currimundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
