<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421844670788089</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/noosas-identity-has-slowly-evolved/3207388/</url>
  <title>Noosa's identity has slowly evolved</title>
  <content>
NOOSA'S Main Beach with its siren-singing Laguna Bay and lush green backdrop remains one of the most alluring places to just lie back and let the outside world wash over you.
Yet some older locals may not rate too highly Noosa Heads' transformation from what Noosa Parks Association stalwart Michael Gloster described as a "quirky little village" of the 1970s full of characters, to a cosmopolitan international destination full of high-end shopping.
It was just a year after Noosa officially became part of newly-named Sunshine Coast that work started on a rock wall along the Main Beach area. Noosa Sound was then built in the 1970s, triggering the creation of Noosa Spit as a real estate buffer as the place became more and more fashionable.
The battle for the shape and soul of Noosa was now heating up as early Noosa foodie pioneer Leonie Palmer said of those days: "Real estate agents rubbed shoulders with solicitors, rogues and cads".
The battle lines were drawn between the "greenies" (or "gan-greens", as some detractors called them) who had already saved the Noosa National Park and the "rip, tear and bust" mob who wanted to unleash progress at all costs.
The White Shoe brigade very much had designs on developing the hell out of Noosa, with even a Club Med earmarked for the Spit at one stage.
And the Noosa Heads surf club history Bush to Beach notes that by the 1980s, the push was on to move the clubhouse north to the rivermouth to allow the Noosa Resort developers to move in. They had plans to develop a Hawaiian-style resort in Hastings St with three storeys on the beach and six to eight levels on the other side of the street.
Of course, unwanted development was not unstoppable and the SGIO finally came in and built the Sheraton Noosa (now the Sofitel), which would dwarf the Seahaven and Netanya resorts and later be joined by the French Quarter.
Former long-time Noosa Shire councillor Ray Kelly and his late wife Dawn used to run the Pine Trees caravan park and service station in Hastings St.
"I was there in '82, I think, until 1988 when they pulled it down to build the Sheraton," Ray said.
"We used to hire boats out the back and the bicycles.
"It was mainly family (who stayed) - mostly we had people from the Gold Coast and Western Queensland come in.
"I was down there the other Saturday and it was so busy - back then the holiday system was in May (not June/July) and it wasn't too bad. But come February and March, you could have shot a gun down the street and not hit anyone.
"We never had anything like the crowds they've got today."
He said as neighbours, they had motels and a set of shops while "old Mr Kelly" used to have his house between the newer resorts.
"They redeveloped up on the corner where Thatcher's caravan park used to be."
Now the street is full of high-fashion retailers offering brands for a very discerning clientele.
"The two restaurants in the early days were Barry's On The Beach and the surf club," Ray remembered.
Another top eatery in the 1980s was Annabelle's, overlooking Main Beach. And then Noosa became one of the first destinations to adopt al-fresco or outdoor dining and its march to becoming one of the nation's top food streets became unstoppable.
Cafe Le Monde would become the crowd favourite it remains along with the likes of Berardo's and Bistro C and the new, very hip new kids on the block like Miss Moneypenny's.
One "cheap eats" famous diner for many a moon was Betty's Burgers, run by Betty Wallace, whose claim to fame was her $1 burgers. She had to shift as part of the wave of Hastings St renewal and, for a while, served her burgers out of a food van along the Spit.
Ray said the coming of the Sheraton and the shopping centre next door opened the whole place up as well as the Noosa cinema complex.
"All those things happened in the late 1980s and the early 1990s," he said.
The Noosa Junction development gathered pace, with Noosa Fair shopping centre arriving after Ray moved into Hastings St.
The Junction has its true, decades-old survivors like the new-age retailer Symbolic Journey and the popular Frank's Gym, otherwise known as Noosa Fitness.
Sadly, the Noosa Heads Bowls Club has burned brightly as a social hub and now is all weeds, waiting to be redeveloped.
In Noosaville, out the back the newest trendy eat street of Gympie Tce, is the Noosa Civic shopping centre, which more than a decade on has not ended the retailing world as we know it.
Ever since Noel Playford was elected shire chairman in 1988 to put the building brakes on and fit a population cap, successive councils have kept as tight a rein on all the big-city symbol excesses as possible.
Of course there was the forced amalgamation but Noosa stubbornly de-amalgamated and is back on its low-key track.
And still 50 years on, the big planning developers keep rolling along in to town.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofitel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Shire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thatcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SGIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastings St</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonie Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laguna Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bistro C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Playford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie Tce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Fair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty's Burgers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry's On</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seahaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Symbolic Journey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Med</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pine Trees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annabelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Parks Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cafe Le Monde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NETANYA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank's Gym</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June-July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaiian-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheraton Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Main Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Heads</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Fitness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Shoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Quarter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gloster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Civic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Sound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheraton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Moneypenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Heads Bowls Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Junction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
