<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421806016081688</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/logan-hospital-cladding-passes-initial-vetting/news-story/c2579ad735abf26bbb031433a356cf74</url>
  <title>Cladding passes initial vetting</title>
  <content>
AN audit taskforce, employed to vet cladding at public hospitals, has found nothing to indicate materials used at the Logan Hospital were of concern.
Housing Minister Mick de Brenni (ALP, Springwood) set up the committee to investigate cladding at all public buildings after 80 people perished in a tower block fire in London in June.
"Nonetheless, we are checking (Logan Hospital) as part of our cautious approach," he said.
"The government is acting with an abundance of caution and assessing all hospitals for potential nonconforming products."
The Audit Taskforce is undertaking reviews of certification and planning documents for all public buildings including Logan Hospital.
Government building surveyors will also inspect buildings.
The Audit Taskforce received results from Princess Alexandra Hospital this month after cladding was tested at a University of Queensland laboratory.
Mr de Brenni said the results confirmed the need for more detailed testing on a large section of the hospital's facade.
The taskforce removed about 80sq m of cladding and sent it to a specialist facility in Victoria.
Preparations are now under way to replace the PA cladding.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Mick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brenni</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Alexandra Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Audit Taskforce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Hospital</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
