<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421767361375300</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4183938/sydney-drug-boss-dung-thi-ngo-charged-with-murders-of-ice-cook-and-his-girlfriend/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Sydney drug boss Dung Thi Ngo charged with murders of ice cook and his girlfriend</title>
  <content>
Sydney drug boss Dung Thi Ngo charged with murders of ice cook and his girlfriend

Police believe girlfriend Thi Kim Lien Do was collateral damage. Photo: NSW Police

NSW Police arrest Kevin Ly over the alleged murders of drug cook Son Thanh Nguyen and girlfriend Thi Kim Lien Do in Canley Vale in 2013. Photo: NSW Police

exit

The "queen pin" of a Sydney drug syndicate has been charged with murder after allegedly ordering the killing of a drug cook and his girlfriend in 2013.
The bodies of Son Thanh Nguyen and his girlfriend Thi Kim Lien Do,were found bound and wrapped in sheets in separate locations in Sydney's south-west.
After detectives linked the pair, it emerged they were both allegedly killed at a drug house in Canley Vale on April 11, 2013, under the direction of feared crime figure Dung Thi Ngo.
Earlier this week, , 25-year-old Kevin Ly, with carrying out the double murder.
Mr Ly was allegedly acting as a henchman for Ngo, a mother-of-two who is already serving time behind bars for drug supply.
Homicide detectives arrested the 41-year-old at Silverwater jail on Thursday and charged her with two counts of murder.
She is expected to appear in Parramatta Local Court on Friday.
Her associate,  Anh Vu Pham, 29, was arrested in Bathurst on Wednesday and also charged with accessory after the fact to murder.
He was refused bail to appear at Campbelltown Local Court next month.
It is alleged the motivation for the killings was Mr Nguyen ripping off the ice he cooked for the drug syndicate in April 2013.
A statement of police facts tendered in court provide a chilling account of the alleged murders, carried out at the direction of Ngo.
Ngo recruited Mr Nguyen into her drug ring to work as a cook, producing ice out of a fibro home in Canley Vale.
Police allege Mr Nguyen, who had a history of stealing the product he cooked, broke into the drug house at night and stole some ice, according to the facts tendered in court this week.
When the rest of the syndicate found out about it, Ngo ordered that Mr Nguyen be brought to the drug house to answer questions about the theft.
After initially dodging calls from the syndicate members, Mr Nguyen, a 39-year-old father of three, went to the Canley Vale drug house with his 35-year-old girlfriend.
The pair were both bound with cable ties before being threatened and questioned about the whereabouts of the missing drugs.
At one point, Ngo allegedly said to Mr Nguyen: "Return it, if you return it [Ms Do] will stay alive. If you did it, you have to bear the consequences."
Ngo then allegedly instructed Ly and other men at the house to "just do it" and handed over a case of $50 notes as payment for the murders, the facts state.
Mr Nguyen's and Ms Do's bodies were then placed in black plastic bags and dumped in separate locations in the south-western suburbs.
on the night of his death.
Ms Do's body wasn't found until months later on a vacant block at West Hoxton by a man repairing his fence. Her brother had reported her missing on the day of the alleged murder.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Ly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGO</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silverwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Hoxton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dung Thi Ngo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MS-DOS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thi Kim Lien Do</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anh Vu Pham, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Nguyen</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canley Vale</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Son Thanh Nguyen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
