<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421552613006929</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/executive-investigated-for-spending-company-credit-card-2017-8</url>
  <title>Drug company executive suspected of letting an escort he met online spend $5.8 million on the company's credit card to buy plastic surgery and a mansion</title>
  <content>
A former pharmaceutical company executive and his escort are being investigated by the FBI for allegedly racking up millions of dollars on a company credit card. 

Scott Kennedy, who formerly worked for , a drug delivery company based in France, met Crystal Lundberg on a classified ads website called Backpage.com in 2012. He says he regrets what happened next. 

According to the , Kennedy solicited her services eight to 10 times between 2012 and 2015. In May 2015, Lundberg first texted Kennedy asking for money, and by November she had moved into his home with her children and pets. 

Kennedy allegedly gave her access to his company credit card, which sparked the beginning of 16 months of extreme spending. 

Nemera claimed it found more than 8,800 improper charges on the company credit card between November 2015 and mid-March 2017, according to the .

Lundberg spent nearly $US1 million on vacations around the world - including trips to France and the South Pacific - and over $US600,000 on clothing. She also allegedly used the card to pay for plastic surgery and bought a personal driver for her children. Over half a million dollars were also given to a medical spa, called The Royalty Room. On  Lundburg is listed as the president of this company. 

Lundberg reportedly talked Kennedy into giving her more money during their relationship by saying she would need to start selling her body again. 

Kennedy told the Chicago Tribune: "I wanted to be loved and cared for. My heart kind of overrid (sic) my head and said, 'Take a chance.' Well, it blew up in my face."

Although Kennedy has blamed Lundberg for the majority of the spending, he admitted to the FBI that he has also used the card to pay for some travel and hotel expenses. 

During their relationship, Lundburg has told Kennedy that she had a trust fund worth $US4 million. The FBI did not find evidence of this. 

Drug CEO 'let an escort he met on  spend $US5.8MILLION on his company's credit card'
- Daily Mail US (@DailyMail)

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US5.8MILLION</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lundburg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$600,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DailyMail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Backpage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Lundberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lundberg</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royalty Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago Tribune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Mail US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nemera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
