<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421990699678525</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4830112/mine-owners-fight-it-out/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Mine owners fight it out</title>
  <content>
Clash: Bengalla coal mine, which has objected to Mount Pleasant coal mine's expansion plans.

MOUNT Pleasant coal mine owner MACH Energy has spent almost a year fighting off environmental groups and the thoroughbred racing industry, and now it's facing an even tougher opponent - another coal mine.

Bengalla coal mine has lodged a strong objection to Mount Pleasant's plan to start mining next door and extend its approval until 2026.

Mount Pleasant's proposed modifications are for a "radically different" mine than originally approved in 1999; its environmental assessment does not adequately address environmental impacts; its modifications are so significant that a new development application should be required, and it would not deliver the economic benefits of the original proposal, Bengalla said in a submission to the Department of Planning.
It argued extending Mount Pleasant's approval from 2020 to 2026 would leave infrastructure in the path of Bengalla's approved mining expansion areas, which would have "profound, unacceptable, material adverse impacts" on Bengalla.

Allowing Mount Pleasant to extend operations to 2026, because it paid $220 million in 2016 for an approval that would otherwise lapse in 2020, did not take account of the considerable mining changes in the area since the original Mount Pleasant approval, Bengalla said.
It said large mines in the immediate vicinity of Mount Pleasant and Muswellbrook township included Mount Arthur mine, covering 6400 hectares and approved to mine 32 million tonnes per year, Mangoola (13.5 million tonnes) and Bengalla (15 million tonnes).

"The result is that the background environmental conditions today are significantly different to what they were in 1999," Bengalla said.

It said the new proposal would see 67 hectares of pit emplacement material located closer to Muswellbrook.
It questioned the economic benefits, saying the 1999 approval was for 197 million tonnes over a decade, while the current application is for 85.36 million tonnes.
Bengalla challenged MACH Energy's statement that it had an agreement with Bengalla over aspects of the proposed development, and questioned another statement about sourcing excess mine water from adjoining Bengalla and Dartbrook mines.

It said MACH Energy should be required to seek a new development consent to mine beyond the 2020 lease expiry date, "thus engaging the full and required environmental planning assessment needed for such a proposal".

Upper Hunter Shire Council objected to the modification proposals, saying Mount Pleasant, Australia Pacific Coal's Dartbrook and Idemitsu's West Muswellbrook proposals represented a "significant intensification of open cut mining in an area where surface mining has never before taken place".

"The impacts of five open cut pits concentrated within three neighbouring projects are likely to be severe," the council said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mangoola (13.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bengalla (15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Planning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muswellbrook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Idemitsu's West Muswellbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Pleasant</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dartbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bengalla</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Pacific Coal's Dartbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Shire Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MACH Energy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
