<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421818900983731</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/free-coast-nanny-service-makes-shopping-a-breeze/3208218/</url>
  <title>Free Coast nanny service makes shopping a breeze</title>
  <content>
AN EXCLUSIVE new service allows parents to take some time to themselves at the shops while their little ones are in capable hands.
Kawana Shoppingworld has announced the launch of complimentary service, Shopping Nanny, designed to make shopping with children a breeze.
In partnership with award-winning childcare service, Lullaby Nanny Share, the centre will offer Mums & Co. members a personal child-care service.
Mums & Co. is a local community program for mums, dads, grandparents, carers and anyone who looks after little people, with exclusive events, services, special offers and more.
The service will provide professional, qualified care for children while members shop, get their hair done, catch up with friends or simply sit and have a coffee.
Children will be cared for by fully qualified nannies and parents can choose to have the Shopping Nanny accompany them or have the children entertained in an interactive children's zone.
Shopping Nanny is available from Monday to Thursday between 11am and 3pm for up to two hours by booking in advance.
Centre manager Claire Torkington, said the service was just one of several making Kawana Shoppingworld a family friendly destination along with a calendar of events, a playground at the Aldi entrance and a five star rated parent's room.
"We are thrilled to launch our new exclusive Shopping Nanny service to our Mums & Co. customers," Ms Torkington said.
"We understand how hard it can be to find a few hours to yourself to get those little things done, especially for parents.
"Kawana Shoppingworld is a community orientated centre which understands the demands of family and that translates to providing services like the Shopping Nanny, which makes life a little easier."
For more information, visit www.kawanashoppingworld.com.au/Mums-and-co.
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanny Share</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Torkington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shopping Nanny</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana Shoppingworld</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Torkington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
