<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421161770975080</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/2555516/methadone-truckie-jailed-over-hume-hwy-crash/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Methadone truck driver Vincent George jailed for killing three in Hume Highway crash</title>
  <content>
The January 24, 2012 collision that killed all three occupants in the car.

A speeding truck driver who was on methadone when his B-double veered across the Hume Highway, killing three people, has been sentenced to almost 13 years in jail.
District Court Judge Stephen Hanley said it was "only a matter of time" before rogue truckie Vincent Samuel George, 34, caused a major fatality on the state's roads.
That day came on January 24, 2012, when George's red B-double veered across a grass median strip on the highway at Menangle, south of Sydney.
It collided head-on with a red Ford Mondeo carrying Calvyn Logan, 59, and his parents Donald and Patricia Logan, both in their 80s, who were on their way home from Canberra after visiting Calvyn's baby granddaughter (and Donald and Patricia's great-granddaughter} for the first time.

Vincent George in an earlier court appearance. Photo: Channel Ten

Their deaths forced George's employer, Lennons Transport, to ground all its vehicles and sparked a state-wide crackdown on the illegal tampering of speed limiters.
George was a drug addict, had lost his licence five times, had several speeding offences and often falsified his log books.
On the day of the accident, he was high on illegally obtained methadone, was speeding and had been driving for the past 22 hours with a break of only 4 1/2 hours.
Judge Hanley said George did not take amphetamines to help him to drive longer hours and meet deadlines but, rather, "he was a drug addict that took drugs that gave him a pleasurable effect".
He said George had been driving trucks for 17 years and "must have been fully aware of the responsibility and duty of care he owed to other users of the road".

Gary and wife Ines Logan leave the court on Friday with Robert Logan whose father Calvyn Logan was killed in the crash. Picture: Peter Rae
The fact he had not caused a fatal accident before 2012 was "a matter of good fortune", he said.
George's attempts to lie about his drug use and blame the crash on an L-plater in front of him were rejected by the judge.
However, Judge Hanley accepted he showed some remorse and has been depressed and preoccupied by guilt since the accident, telling a psychiatrist: "I still think about it all the time, it's not a good feeling."
Outside court, Patricia and Donald's surviving son, Gary Logan, said the sentence was fair.
"There's nothing that can compensate our loss but we are not here on a vendetta," he said.
Mr Logan had told a previous sentencing hearing that he began having crippling nightmares after a few belongings were returned to him from the wreckage.
"There was nothing of any consequence ... except the ring," Mr Logan said.
"My father gave it to [my] mother a few months before ... on their 60th wedding anniversary. It was then that the nightmares began."

The chaotic scene of the triple fatality.
He said the accident was "senseless and utterly avoidable".
"Death is inevitable in this world, but for my parents and my brother to be killed so senselessly and so violently is too shocking and too reprehensible to contemplate," Mr Logan said, crying.
"They were law-abiding, peace-loving and kind, and they did not deserve to die in such a horrific way." 
George's guilty plea to three charges of dangerous driving occasioning death was rejected by the Crown.
He was instead convicted of three manslaughter charges.
He was sentenced to 17 years in jail with a non-parole period of 12 years and nine months.
He said he did not intend to return to truck driving upon his release.

Read more: http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/methadone-truck-driver-vincent-george-jailed-for-killing-three-in-hume-highway-crash-20140912-10fwzh.html#ixzz3D4OwN3Ih
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lennons Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-19</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume Highway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calvyn Logan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calvyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-Double</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Logan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court Judge Stephen Hanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vincent George</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Logan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 24, 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menangle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vincent Samuel George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L-plater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ines Logan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Logan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Logan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Mondeo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Rae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Hanley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D4OwN3Ih</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
