<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421982109743865</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/frank-ocean-shirt-sold-thousands-but-idea-was-stolen-2017-8</url>
  <title>An iconic shirt Frank Ocean wore in concert has sold thousands for an independent shop, but the idea for it was stolen</title>
  <content>
Frank Ocean gave a great performance at  last Friday, but the resulting discussion around his set has centered not so much on his music - or the fact that filmmaker Spike Jonze filmed the show - but on the instantly iconic T-shirt that Ocean wore during the performance.

"Why be racist, sexist, homophobic or transphobic when you could just be quiet?" Ocean's plain-white shirt read, in capitalised black lettering. 

As  reports, the shirt was produced by , an independent online shop founded in 2016 by 18-year-old Kayla Robinson.

Over the weekend following Ocean's performance, the shirt became a viral hit on Twitter, and Robinson's site flooded with 5,500 overall purchases - a massive boon compared to her typical two-day sales of 100 orders.

The Times story goes on to detail, however, that the text of the shirt originated from the following August 2015 tweet, written by 18-year-old Brandon Male:

Male said he contacted Green Box Shop about the shirt earlier this year, and they initially disregarded him. After the shirt blew up following Ocean's performance, Robinson reportedly sent Male $US100 via Venmo - less than 1% of the revenue gained from the $US18.99 shirts in two days.

"It was an impulsive decision," Robinson told the Times. "I hadn't looked at the number of sales, and I wasn't thinking about it portionwise. It does look like I was just throwing money at him to keep him quiet."

Male could have filed a cease-and-desist against Green Box for using his tweet without his permission. Instead, the two parties have since agreed to avoid the nebulous waters of  by sitting down to negotiate a proportional profit for both sides.  

why be racist, sexist, homophobic, or transphobic when you could bE QUIET
- brandon (@avogaydro)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandon Male</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Ocean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US18.99</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Box</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Box Shop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venmo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayla Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spike Jonze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
