<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421857555690161</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/mannies-family-drapery-was-an-institution/3207378/</url>
  <title>Mannie's family drapery was an institution</title>
  <content>
WHILE the Sunshine Coast is now a bustling city of 350,000 people served by some of the biggest names in retail, it was founded on the back of small family businesses.
One of the best-known was Comino's Drapery in Caloundra's main street, which closed it doors for the last time in February 2016.
In 1967, when the "Sunshine Coast" was adopted as the official name for the region, the drapery had already been operating for many years.
Founder Cosmo Comino was an industrious Greek migrant who arrived in Caloundra in the late 1930s after firstly living in Cairns and then establishing a mixed business and newsagency at Forest Hill, near Gatton, in 1927.
He had two shops built at 26 Bulcock St and left Gatton in 1940 to establish a new business in the heart of what was then a small seaside town.
The Bulcock St Greek milk bar, cafe and fruit shop opened for Christmas trade in 1940 and operated until 1952. Due to stock shortages during the Second World War, the drapery side of the business could not open its doors until 1946.
The Greek cafe was popular with soldiers and tanks were often parked along Bulcock St as the soldiers went in for a drink or a snack. The marks of their hobnailed boots were still visible in the shop's wooden floors until the day it closed.
Cosmo's son Mannie took over the running of Comino's Drapery in 1957 after serving in the Royal Australian Navy. He continued on in the drapery business in the original shop for more than 55 years, until his death in August 2012.
The business was a success because of the honesty, integrity and friendliness of the Comino family.
Goods were wrapped in brown paper, prices were hand-written, a manual cash register was used and Mannie always had a lead pencil tucked behind his ear.
He was a Rotarian and lived by the Rotary motto of truthfulness, fairness for all, building goodwill and deciding whether a situation was beneficial for all concerned.
Mannie was known for keeping prices low and was proud that his shop had the cheapest haberdashery in Australia.
Customers were greeted with "good day, mate" and Mannie and his wife Florence were always ready for a chat.
They raised two children - son Cosma and daughter Elene - and Mannie's sisters Rene and Stella also worked in the store.
Mannie and Florence's grandson Dominic was the fourth generation of the family to work in the business.
Although she had hoped to continue the drapery after her husband's death, Mrs Comino made the hard decision to close it in February 2016.
"Business got very, very hard to do," she explained.
"The bigger shops are too much now for the smaller shops and I'm getting very tired. I've been here for 55 years and it's only because I'm tired. It's very hard to do.
"Personally, I would have liked to have gone on with it but my legs won't carry me."
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cosmo Comino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Second World War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comino's Drapery</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannie</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Comino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulcock St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cosmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cosmo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulcock St Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forest Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
