<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421848965755445</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/world/donald-trump-hammered-malcolm-turnbull-in-january-call-transcript-shows-20170803-gxp1b8</url>
  <title>Donald Trump hammered Malcolm Turnbull in January call, transcript shows</title>
  <content>
A new extraordinary transcript of a heated January phone conversation reveals precise details of Malcolm Turnbull being berated by an angry Donald Trump and how the Prime Minister still craftily persuaded the US President to accept refugees from Australia.
Mr Trump accused Mr Turnbull of making him look like a "dope" and "awfully bad", "killing" him politically and turning the US into a "dumping ground" for 1250 refugees housed in "prison", otherwise known as Australian offshore detention centres.
The President complained bitterly the refugee transfer deal, struck by predecessor Barack Obama, clashed with Mr Trump's refugee freeze and temporary travel ban on citizens from seven Muslim-majority countries.
At one point President Trump delivered the Prime Minister a jovial backhanded compliment, "you are worse than I am", after Mr Turnbull explained how Australia rejected any asylum seekers arriving by boat in order to deter people smuggling.

AP

A persistent Mr Turnbull badgered Mr Trump to honour the deal, submitting that it was a "very big issue for us".

The extraordinary word-by-word account of the 24-minute call, published by The Washington Post, records a rambling Mr Trump saying his previous phone call on the same day with Russia's Vladimir Putin was "pleasant" and fuming "this is ridiculous" and "crazy".
Quid pro quo?

Potentially embarrassing the Turnbull government, the transcript also appears to expose Mr Turnbull bargaining on a quid pro quo.
"We will then hold up our end of the bargain by taking in our country 31 [inaudible] that you need to move on from," Mr Turnbull is recorded as telling President Trump.

Andrew Meares

Mr Turnbull later added: "We are taking people from the previous administration that they were very keen on getting out of the United States. We will take more. We will take anyone that you want us to take."
That seems to clash with the Turnbull government's repeated public assurances that  was not linked to president Obama taking refugees from Manus Island and Nauru.  
The classified transcript, recorded by White House officials, is a fuller account of the acrimonious January 28 phone call, some details of which were reported by the Post in February.
The conversation began cordially, with both leaders exchanging pleasantries and talking about their connection to Australian golfer Greg Norman, a personal friend of the President.

Mr Turnbull, a former Goldman Sachs banker and internet entrepreneur, appears to butter up the real estate-mogul-turned-President, remarking on their "similar backgrounds" as businessmen.
Mr Trump says it is an "evil" time confronting the "brutal" Islamic State terrorist group, and talks about people being in "disguise", but "we are going to be very successful".
'Practical political realities': Turnbull

The Prime Minister then guides the conversation to immigration policy, revealing that a few days earlier he had earlier spoken to the President's son-in-law Jared Kushner. "Our policies have helped to inform your approach," Mr Turnbull says.

(President Trump this week backed a Republican Senate bill to move to , favouring the educated, skilled and English speakers.)
Seeking to build more common ground, Mr Turnbull tells the President 90 per cent of the 12,000 Syrian refugees Australia has accepted are Christian and compliments Mr Trump for similarly prioritising minorities in his immigration orders.
"It is not a sectarian thing. It is recognition of the practical political realities. We have a similar perspective in that respect," Mr Turnbull says.
The President, in just his ninth day in office, laments that it was previously easier for Muslims than Christians to be accepted into the US.

Mr Turnbull then opens up on the "resettlement agreement", saying he is aware the President had a "different point of view" to Vice President Mike Pence who had spoken to Foreign Affairs Minister Julie Bishop.
Mr Trump then begins to unload.
"I just called for a total ban on Syria and from many different countries from where there is terror, and extreme vetting for everyone else - and somebody told me yesterday that close to 2000 people are coming who are really probably troublesome. And I am saying, boy that will make us look awfully bad."
'Hear me out Mr President'

The President suddenly digresses, to talk of his "love" for Australia.
"I love the people of Australia. I have so many friends from Australia," Mr Trump says.
Mr Trump suggests the 2000 refugees could be the next group of terrorists, like Muslim attackers in San Bernardino, California or the hijackers who crashed two aeroplanes into the World Trade Centre in 2001.
He later refers to importing the next "Boston bomber", and Mr Turnbull argues those bombers were from Russia and not from the countries Australia's refugees are from.

"Can you hear me out Mr. President?" Mr Turnbull asks.
Mr Turnbull said the deal did not require the US to take 2000 refugees, "It does not require you to take any".
"It requires, in return, for us to do a number of things for the United States - this is a big deal, I think we should respect deals," Mr Turnbull pleads.
The Prime Minister argues they are "economic refugees" from Iran, Pakistan, and Afghanistan.
"The obligation is for the United States to look and examine and take up to and only if they so choose - 1250 to 2000. Every individual is subject to your vetting. You can decide to take them or to not take them after vetting. You can decide to take 1,000 or 100. It is entirely up to you."
'This is going to kill me': Trump

Mr Trump says he understands Mr Turnbull does "not want to destroy your country", cursing Germany's open-border policy for refugees.
"These people are crazy to let this happen. I spoke to [Angela] Merkel today, and believe me, she wishes she did not do it. Germany is a mess because of what happened," Mr Trump says.

Mr Turnbull responds, "I agree with you, letting one million Syrians walk into their country. It was one of the big factors in the Brexit vote, frankly.
The Prime Minister reinforces the importance of the US-Australia alliance, pressing the case that that "you will never find a better friend to the United States than Australia."
"I am asking you as a very good friend. This is a big deal. It is really, really important to us that we maintain it."
Mr Trump says he does "not understand" why this is so important to Australia.
"This is going to kill me. I am the world's greatest person that does not want to let people into the country," Mr Trump argues.
Mr Turnbull appears to coach Mr Trump on how he could sell the deal to Americans, arguing the people will be subject to "extreme vetting" and the 1250 people from Australia is consistent with the President's executive order tightening immigration.
"No, I do not want say that. I will just have to say that unfortunately I will have to live with what was said by Obama. I will say I hate it. Look, I spoke to Putin, Merkel, Abe of Japan, to France today, and this was my most unpleasant call because I will be honest with you. I hate taking these people."
'This is a stupid deal': Trump

Mr Trump was venting angrily, but he had just confirmed to Mr Turnbull that he would honour the deal.
The back and forth continues, with Mr Turnbull appealing to Mr Trump's business negotiating experience.
"There is nothing more important in business or politics than a deal is a deal. Look, you and I have a lot of mutual friends," Mr Turnbull says.
Mr Trump curses president Obama for signing the deal.  
"That is why they lost the election, because of stupid deals like this. You have brokered many a stupid deal in business and I respect you, but I guarantee that you broke many a stupid deal. This is a stupid deal. This deal will make me look terrible," Mr Trump laments.
Mr Trump says he has "no choice" but to say he is honouring his predecessor's "horrible" deal.
After some more whinging from Mr Trump, the US President suddenly moves to end the phone call.
"As far as I am concerned that is enough Malcom [sic]. I have had it. I have been making these calls all day and this is the most unpleasant call all day. Putin was a pleasant call. This is ridiculous."

'You can count on me': Turnbull

Mr Turnbull asks if he wants to talk about Syria and North Korea.
"....this is crazy," Mr Trump fumes.
"Thank you for your commitment. It is very important to us," Mr Trump says.
Mr Trump says: "It is important to you and it is embarrassing to me. It is an embarrassment to me, but at least I got you off the hook. So you put me back on the hook."
"You can count on me. I will be there again and again," Mr Turnbull says.
"I hope so. Okay, thank you Malcolm," Mr Trump says.
Since the fiery exchange, President Trump and Turnbull enjoyed a warm meeting and dinner together in New York in May, where the two leaders embraced each other and appeared to put the phone call behind them.

They also met at the Group of 20 in Germany in July.
The US has stalled the agreed deal after hitting its 50,000 refugee intake cap for this year, but the Turnbull government is still confident the refugees will eventually be shipped to the US after being vetted.
"We're disappointed that they haven't been able to move this month, which was my hope, but their new program year starts on October 1, and we're working with both the State Department and the Department of Homeland Security to ensure that we can get people off as quickly as possible," Immigration Minister Peter Dutton said on July 20.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Affairs Minister Julie Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abe of Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Homeland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President 90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. President</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>24</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Trade Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Bernardino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>23</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merkel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim-majority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
