<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421861850657505</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/hanson-hears-from-concerned-elderly/3208547/</url>
  <title>Hanson hears from concerned elderly</title>
  <content>
CONTROVERSIAL Queensland Senator Pauline Hanson played a rare second fiddle during a trip to Buderim as she sat back and listened to stories - some of horror - of life in aged care.

More than 200 residents packed the Buderim War Memorial Community Hall on Thursday to meet with Senator Hanson and Buderim MP Steve Dickson, with changes to the Retirement Villages Act a hot topic of discussion.

Mr Dickson has been advocating for sweeping changes to the Act to protect the wellbeing of the region's elderly.

He reiterated that push, calling for standardised contracts and promised the establishment of an ombudsman to assist residents in disputes.

Joanne Wheeler was one resident who was eager to see changes to the legislation.

"The Act is so ambiguous, it's badly written and leads to so many disputes because of the ambiguity," Ms Wheeler said.

She said key inclusions they were seeking included a compulsory buy-back to protect those leaving a retirement village and better protection for residents against redevelopment of retirement communities.

Senator Hanson said she'd been "amazed" with the concerns raised during the meeting and felt it was a serious issue for the Coast.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retirement Villages Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Wheeler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Senator Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim MP Steve Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wheeler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim War Memorial Community Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
