<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421818900983769</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/familys-timber-was-pivotal-in-nambours-development/3207429/</url>
  <title>Family's timber was pivotal in Nambour's development</title>
  <content>
FROM the 1890s, Nambour was defined by the imposing presence of the sugar mill - its impressive black chimney, piercing steam whistle and sweet full-bodied aromas invoking local residents' senses with a persistent reminder of its all-encompassing influence.
That the mill laid claim to the town was a truth difficult to ignore.
Currie St, part of the Bruce Hwy and Nambour's main thoroughfare, hosted the majority of the sugar town's retail businesses. They were strung out, fringing the ribbon of road streaming down Church Hill to the Petrie Creek bridge.
The mill interrupted this smooth flow with its main cane tram line cutting across Currie St, neatly slicing its retail centre into four pieces.
The compass bearings of the four corners helped Nambour residents identify local retail stores by using each quadrant's premier landmark, be it Bayard's Corner, The Bank of New South Wales, The Royal George or The Club Hotel.
Local retailers were unperturbed by the mill's apparent imposition as to a large extent their own livelihoods were dependent on its continued prosperity.
The sugar industry attracted a range of supporting industries directly and indirectly.
As Nambour's population grew, all that was needed to provide comfortable amenity for the population grew with it.
Early pioneer Walter Lanham, my great-grandfather, identified business opportunities developing in the fledgling community, as did a number of his contemporaries such as the Whalleys, Curries, Burys and Lows.
The town's business fathers - energetic, civic-minded and purposeful - earnestly set about creating a prosperous town by building successful businesses.
Establishing a steam-driven sawmill in Price St in 1910, Walter and his sons set about producing sawn timber for the boom in domestic and business construction.
Success was evident as the town grew and prospered so that by the 1940s, the sawmill relocated from the town's centre, opposite the railway station, into a Court Rd location known as Frog's Hollow.
Here it steadily re-invented itself from the roughneck Lanham's Sawmill into a modern retail timber and hardware store set up to keep pace with the changing demands of a new millenium. Its evolution reflected the changing face of Currie St's retail businesses adapting, disappearing or being superceded in change after change.
Eventually, even the imposing Moreton Central Sugar Mill fell victim to the winds of change. Its closure irrevocably uprooted any implied lingering vestiges relating to its commercial ownership of the town.
Nambour's current business challenges lie not in doggedly regaining what has been lost but in confidently seizing the phenomenal opportunities for growth.
The reinvention of its future naturally builds upon the solid and resourceful foundations laid by its founding fathers.
Perhaps it's a new day awaiting the energetic, civic-minded and purposeful community leaders to again rise and shine.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Price St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayard's Corner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Central Sugar Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whalleys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Lanham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frog Hollow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Church Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanham's Sawmill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Court Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
