<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421977814776513</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/rugby/sonny-bill-williams-cleared-to-play-bledisloe-cup-opener-after-surprise-appeal-win/news-story/cfa17706bbbda9f7d8b318db3f678b6b</url>
  <title>Surprise: Sonny Bill wins appeal</title>
  <content>
NEW Zealand star Sonny Bill Williams will be available for the All Blacks' Rugby Championship opener against Australia on August 19.
Williams has won his appeal against the details of his four-match suspension following his red card in New Zealand's 24-21 loss in the second Test against the British and Irish Lions last month.
Global governing body World Rugby revealed "surprise" at the decision of an independent appeal panel to deem New Zealand's August 11 encounter against Counties Manukau and Taranaki - with the All Blacks playing 40 minutes against each side - as meeting the regulations constituting a match.

Sonny Bill Williams decision a shambles. Disciplinary process needs sorting - loopholes and ways around bans sees it lose credibility

Sonny Bill Williams appeal decision smacks of 1 rule for NZ & another for everyone else. World Rugby correct to be unhappy with panel

"A game being played by New Zealand against Counties Manukau and Taranaki on 11 August that had been excluded from the suspension by the original disciplinary committee, has now been deemed to comply with the regulations' definition of a 'match'," read a statement issued on behalf of World Rugby.
"And, as such, that match will be included as part of the player's suspension. Accordingly, Williams is suspended from all forms of rugby up to and including 11 August."
World Rugby later responded by issuing its own statement, insisting it will respect Williams' right to face Australia next month - but that it will seek clarity on just what represents a match among rugby's complex rules and regulations.

Rugby: Sonny Bill Williams has been awarded a red card for this dangerous shoulder charge in the second game of the Lions test.

SBW's sensational red card
"While World Rugby respects the decision of the independent appeal committee to uphold the appeal by New Zealand's Sonny Bill Williams against the matches that counted towards his four-week suspension, it is surprised by the committee's interpretation of the definition of "match" (which is defined in Regulation 1 as "a game in which two teams compete against each other")," read World Rugby's statement.
"With the appeal process having been exhausted, World Rugby will refer the interpretation of the regulation to the Regulations Committee when it meets in September to examine the findings in the context of the game's regulations to ensure universal clarity and compliance with the meaning of the regulation moving forward."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks' Rugby Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taranaki</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regulations Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand's Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand's August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regulation 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counties Manukau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Rugby</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonny Bill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
