<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421428058952540</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/03/32/colosimo-s-drug-case-annoys-vic-magistrate</url>
  <title>Colosimo's drug case annoys Vic magistrate</title>
  <content>
Australian actor Vince Colosimo was interstate as a magistrate grumbled at lawyers in Melbourne over the slow progress of the star's drug-driving case.
The 50-year-old Underbelly actor was allegedly caught driving through Melbourne's CBD under the influence of ice only nine days after his licence was suspended.
Police spotted Colosimo's black Saab on Exhibition Street on March 5 and a check of the registration plate showed his licence had been suspended on February 24, because he had accumulated too many demerit points.
A saliva test at the scene showed Colosimo had methamphetamine in his system, according to a police brief released by a magistrate.
The troubled actor did not appear, and did not have to, when his case was mentioned in Melbourne Magistrates' Court on Thursday.
Colosimo has recently been in the Queensland town of Dalby shooting new Australian psychological thriller The Second.
Magistrate Ross Maxted confirmed the accused was not technically required to be in court but seemed annoyed because the "simple case" was not progressing.

Related Articles

"Your client has been given every opportunity to appear," he said to Colosimo's defence lawyer.
"We should progress this. It's a simple case.
"I don't want to be playing favourite to anybody."
Court documents outlined the police intercept that led to the two charges, including Colosimo's denial when asked if he had consumed illicit drugs.
The case was adjourned for a contest mention on November 3.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colosimo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Ross Maxted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exhibition Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Colosimo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
