<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421896210396451</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/les-murray-taught-australia-to-love-the-world-game-of-football/8770956</url>
  <title>Les Murray put his arm around Australians with his love of the 'World Game' of football</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

The last time I saw Les Murray, I broached a subject that had troubled me. One I had been hesitant to address for fear of offending a man I liked and admired and whose company was always warm and endlessly entertaining.
In recent years, the media had seized upon Les's role in Australia's failed World Cup bid, particularly his relationship with the controversial lobbyist Peter Hargitay and his seemingly compromised position on the absurdly oxymoronic FIFA Ethics Committee.
So, hesitantly, I asked Les how he felt about the bid now.
As I should have known, Les was not the least bit offended and, even more predictably, far from contrite.

External Link:

Richard Hinds tweets: Les Murray was funny, arcerbic, generous, flawed, kind and unique. Most of all, when most needed, he was Mr Football. #RIPLesMurray
As was his custom, Les put a paternal hand on my shoulder, drew me nearer and said in the beguiling, gruff, nicotine stained voice he employed off-air: ''You've got to understand Richard, this is just the way things work. You have to beat those bastards at their own game. Unfortunately, this time, the c***s changed the rules on us.''
It was classic Les. He did not expect to change my mind about the bid's ethical breaches, nor did he feel a need to defend himself. But, through sheer force of personality, he somehow had me back on side.
In a sense, that is what Les did to an entire country for more than three decades as SBS's football presenter, doyen and national treasure. He put an arm around us, drew us closer, and gently lured Australians into the exotic ''World Game'' with his dignified presentation, his linguistic gymnastics, his good humour and that whiff of cultured European charm.
The 'Molly Meldrum of football'

Most often, Les left the politics and the ideology to his sidekicks.
There was first the hot blooded romanticist Johnny Warren, then the fiercely dogmatic and combative Craig Foster. They fought back against those who had poured scorn upon their game and retarded its progress.
Behind the scenes, Les also fought fierce battles, made powerful allies and pulled every string possible for both football and his beloved SBS.
But, as the universally loved Molly Meldrum of football, he appealed to the non-believers because he did not take himself as seriously as the hot gospellers who demanded unconditional fealty to their one true code.
Les wanted you to call it football but he did not care if you said soccer instead. He was just happy that you watched, enjoyed and felt almost as enriched by the game's majesty as he did.

Privately, some experts would mutter that Les did not know as much about the game's modern machinations and tactical nuances as his long-winded dinner table dissertations and forthright opinions - always accentuated by amusingly profane exclamation marks - would suggest.
I doubt Les would have cared. I think he saw himself as merely the most prominent of those football lovers who gathered in large numbers at cafes across the country, ordered a short black, lit a cigarette and argued endlessly about the game's minutiae.
The gathering, as much as the game itself, was the thing.
While Les virtually invented football for many Anglo-Australians, the most heartfelt tributes I have heard come from migrants, and those from migrant families, who said he made them feel proud of their heritage, not inclined to conceal it.
Something as seemingly simple as correctly pronouncing ''difficult foreign names'' on national television was a sign of respect many had not previously enjoyed. To have football from across the globe presented intelligently and undiluted by local jargon was another previously unknown pleasure.
Les could be marvellously self-effacing, but he was certainly not without a sense of his status. Several years ago he rang to tell me someone was using his calling card, "The World Game". He asked me to sign a statutory declaration stating he was the original source.
It was like being asked to declare Lennon and McCartney wrote Hey Jude.
As SBS's most prized employee, he did not personally disconnect the smoke alarm in his office so he could smoke. He had his staff do that.
'We had to show that someone cared about them'

The only other time I challenged Les was after the 2010 World Cup in South Africa. As the Socceroos' campaign descended into chaos under the faltering leadership of Pim Verbeek, Les and Craig Foster wore Socceroos scarves on air.
It seemed an odd departure from Les's usual high standards of professionalism. Again, Les was unrepentant.
''The bloody management don't seem to care about what's happening to that team,'' he growled.
"We had to show that someone cared about them.''

I think Les's role in Australia's World Cup bid betrayed some impatience, perhaps even a sense of his own mortality. He had played an enormous role in popularising football in Australia. Now, as he left his SBS lectern, progress seemed to have stalled.
With his great friend and ally Frank Lowy, bringing the World Cup to Australia would, they decided, provide jet propulsion. Thus they played the FIFA game and, inevitably, got played.
The game has since reached a delicate point in its local history. The FFA is struggling with governance issues, the Socceroos are engaged in a tense qualifying campaign and the A-League is still fighting for space in an intensely crowded sporting landscape.
Similar battles were being played out in the 1970s. But because of Les, now millions more Australians know and care and thus the rewards for success will be far greater.
There are very few people in any walk of life who can say that their field would not be as advanced without their contribution. Les Murray was once such person.
Les, from those of us you put an arm around and gently drew into your beautiful game with its rich culture, its amusing eccentricities and its wonderful vibrant ethnicity, thank you.
Watch Offsiders with Gerard Whateley at 10am Sunday on ABC TV.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Games</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>20</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCartney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly Meldrum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Lowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglo Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lennon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIPLesMurray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watch Offsiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Jude</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Hargitay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Hinds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pim Verbeek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIFA's Ethics Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Whateley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
