<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421947750004853</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/suspected-bomb-made-it-airport-check-desk/3208612/</url>
  <title>Suspected bomb made it to airport check-in desk</title>
  <content>
NEW details have emerged about just how close alleged would-be bombers got to carrying an explosive device aboard an international flight from Sydney, as two men have been charged with terrorism offences.

Earlier on Thursday, Sydney's Daily Telegraph reported an unwitting passenger may have been used to smuggle a bomb on board a plane destined for the Middle East.

The plot to have the device detonated "without (the bomber) knowing they were part of a suicide mission" was aborted.

On Thursday afternoon, Fairfax reported the device made it as far as Sydney International Airport terminal's check-in area and that a passenger was "queried about the weight of the luggage at the check-in counter and learnt it was too heavy".

The report suggests the bag was never checked in.

Huge queues at Sydney Airports T2 Domestic Terminal as passengers are subjected to increased security, Sydney, Australia, Monday, July 31, 2017. Airline passengers are experiencing long delays at Australian airports as security is beefed up following a number of terror raids over the weekend. AAP Image/Dean Lewins

Neither NSW or Australian Federal Police would comment on the matter when contacted by news.com.au because the investigation is ongoing.

Meanwhile, police have charged a 49-year-old Lakemba man and a 32-year-old Punchbowl man with preparing to commit an act of terrorism. The sentence carries life imprisonment.

One of the initial four men taken into custody has been released, another remains in custody but has not been charged.

Australian intelligence received word last week about an apparent plan to smuggle an explosive onto a flight which led to dramatic raids over the weekend.

Police have remained tight-lipped about their investigations, however they are working with Etihad Airlines, who are assisting with inquiries.

On Tuesday, Abdul Merhi, 50, was released without charge. His lawyer, Moustafa Kheir, said his client felt he was "in a movie" when he heard of the allegations.

Police oversee as a car is removed from outside a crime scene in Surry Hills, Sydney. Picture: AAP Image/Joel Carrett.

"It's a very serious allegation to have against you," Mr Kheir said. "It's just unfathomable that he would be associated- with anything like this."

"He just wants to go back to as normal life as possible now," Mr Kheir said.

Police allege the group were plotting to use an unwitting person to bring down a plane. Picture: Darren Leigh Roberts

Police have called for photo identification to be reintroduced for issuing domestic plane tickets and for all airport employees to go through security screening.

The peak body for pilots has also called for greater security. AusALPA president Captain Murray Butt backed calls for all passengers to be required to produce photographic identification as they must in the US.

"We certainly don't want to alarm the public," he said in Sydney. "But we want to make sure we're providing the best service that we can and the safest service that we can."

Police are still searching properties in Lakemba, Wiley Park, Punchbowl and Surry Hills for evidence.
 

Police tow away two cars from a Sydney home.

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull addressed the media on Thursday afternoon. He said the alleged plot was foiled but Australians should remain vigilant about the threat of an attack.

"The threat of Islamist terrorism is a global one," he said.

"As I've said many times, nowhere is far away from anywhere else in the age of the internet.

"Our enemies, those terrorists, those Islamist terrorist organisations are global and they are connected."

He also said there will be fewer delays at Australian airports for travellers after authorities disrupted the aviation terror threat. ASIO has moved to restore the aviation threat level to what it was before the alleged plot to bring down a plane was uncovered.

That means a return to normal check in times for travellers, however plainclothes officers and extra training for cabin crew will remain in place.

While there will be fewer flight delays, Mr Turnbull said it didn't mean people should become complacent.

"There is no room for complacency," Mr Turnbull told reporters.

"No room for set-and-forget at all."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Leigh Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Image/Dean Lewins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airports T2 Domestic Terminal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kheir</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Image/Joel Carrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AusALPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July/31/2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Murray Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moustafa Kheir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
