<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421844670788109</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/nambour-has-long-been-the-heart-of-region/3207394/</url>
  <title>Nambour has long been the heart of region</title>
  <content>
IF Australia "rode on the sheep's back", it could be said that Nambour "rode the sugar cane train" as the industry was king and drove the local economy for more than a century.
The mill dominated the economic and social life of the town and surrounding shire, and both prospered as a result.
In the 1950s and '60s, the North Coast's development plans reflected the optimism of the region and of Premier Frank Nicklin, who was guiding its direction.
Kenilworth dairy farmer Eddie De Vere was elected Maroochy Shire chairman in 1967 - the same year the Sunshine Coast was officially named - and held the position until 1982.
A man of vision, he understood the importance of tourism and the rural industries to the newly-named Sunshine Coast.
There was no direct road between Maroochydore and the Maroochy Airport, meaning people had to travel into Nambour and out again.
But within a few years, the opening of the Maroochy River Bridge at Bli Bli, the airport and the David Low Way signalled the start of boom times on the Coast.
Mr de Vere played a key role in the airport's development.
In the 1970s, agriculture still played a big part in Nambour's economy, particularly pineapple farming and the sugar and dairy enterprises. In more recent years, that agricultural base has grown to include a variety of tropical crops such as macadamias, bananas and citrus fruits.
The Big Pineapple tourist attraction reflected the industry of growing tropical fruits and tourism perfectly and was once one of Australia's best-known tourist attractions.
Today, it is not as popular but still draws visitors keen to be photographed in front of the iconic fibreglass pineapple or visit the impressive new Wildlife HQ zoo.
The Big Pineapple Music Festival also attracts thousands of visitors to Nambour.
Other tourist attractions around Nambour over the years have included Thrill Hill Waterslide Park, the Big Cow and the Big Macadamia.
The Nambour Festival, which began as the Nambour Sugar Festival in the 1980s, has been held at Quota Park since 2008 while the Sunshine Coast Agricultural Show was first held in Woombye in 1905 and relocated to Nambour in 1909.
Today the Sunshine Coast Agricultural Show (known to locals as the Nambour Show) is three days full of agricultural, and community events.
By the late 1970s, urbanisation of the Sunshine Coast had gathered pace.
A new shire chambers was opened in Nambour in 1978, on the corner of Bury and Currie streets.
From 1980 onwards, the number of farms fell considerably due to development.
Tourism took over as the major industry in the mid-1980s and the coastal towns began to boom.
The face of Nambour also began to change and large shopping complexes were built.
Traffic was diverted and an alternative road was built that edged around the town centre. In 1990, the Nambour bypass opened, diverting more traffic away from the town's centre.
In December 2003, after more than 100 years of crushing sugar cane, the Moreton Central Sugar Mill closed its doors and the town said goodbye to an industry that had been a cultural and economic icon for so long.
Some shops on Currie and Howard streets are reminders of earlier days.
C-Square, previously known as Station Square, was a popular meeting spot with an important history. It contained the original Nambour Town Hall, which was twice damaged by fire and rebuilt.
In 1960, the new Civic Hall and the spacious auditorium (seating 1100 people) provided a venue for numerous theatrical and musical performances, meetings, dances and other social events.
Records show that on October 28, 1967, Civic Square hosted a reception for Miss Australia, Helen Newton. Crowds flocked to see the 20-year-old Nambour High School teacher, from Woombye, who was crowned Miss Australia after successfully representing the Maroochy-Wide Bay Zone in the Miss Queensland final.
Also in 1967, the Christmas Carols Festival in the Civic Hall attracted a large crowd to enjoy music by the Mercy Beats and Salvation Army Corps Band, together with choral numbers by the local senior and junior mixed choirs.
In 1991, the site was redeveloped by Seymour Developments and named Centenary Square. It contained specialty shops over two levels, a three-storey office block and the civic centre.
In 2015, the name was changed to C-Square.
Nambour lost its identity for quite some time with the loss of the sugar mill. Formerly a bustling agricultural town, it is no longer the hub of the Sunshine Coast - a title that now belongs to Maroochydore.
It may lie at the heart of the Sunshine Coast but it is not the "heart" any more. These days it is a more conventional suburban service stop rather than a booming town or coastal holiday destination.
Times have changed. It is now a town of supermarkets with a few historic buildings but the tracks which carried the cane trains to the mill are still clear and there are moves within the community to bring the trains back to the streets as a tourist attraction.
Celebrating the town's cultural heritage, through its culture, history, stories and places helps to promote and encourage interaction. Letting the past teach us how to deal with the future can help us to shape Nambour.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenilworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C-Square</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Pineapple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army Corps Band</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woombye</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Frank Nicklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercy Beats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Central Sugar Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Station Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildlife HQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seymour Developments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy-Wide Bay Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Newton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thrill Hill Waterslide Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2003</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Shire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Agricultural Show</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Sugar Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Low Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas Carols Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centenary Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Macadamia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quota Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie De Vere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Pineapple Music Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Cow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
