<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422192563145441</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/commuters-travel-free-as-brisbane-bus-driver-dispute-continues/8771784</url>
  <title>Brisbane bus drivers refuse to collect fares amid industrial dispute stalemate</title>
  <content>
Many Brisbane commuters can travel for free today, with drivers refusing to collect fares as part of a long-running pay dispute.
It is the fifth day of industrial action that has included
Brisbane City Council said last time drivers refused to take fares it cost ratepayers an estimated $515,000.
Lord Mayor Graham Quirk said he did not believe the hit would be as great this time, claiming less than half of drivers would take part.
"Not all drivers are performing that, so we would expect passengers to continue to pay a fare," Councillor Quirk said.
Council is refusing to budge on pay negotiations, arguing the current offer of a 2.5 per cent pay rise over three years is fair and reasonable.
Councillor Quirk said it would cost ratepayers $180 million if the drivers were to get the 3.5 per cent they were asking for.
"It is a lot of money - why should ratepayers be asked to fork out more," he said.
"The pay offer is not negotiable - it is time to put the swords down."
Rail, Bus, Tram and Bus Union spokesman Tom Brown said the pay rise would be on par with wages growth for minimum wage workers.
"We hope to continue the pressure on council so they will come to the table and start to negotiate and end this dispute," he said.
"But an agreement is closer but only a little bit closer than the other day."
He said it was "fake news" that half of bus drivers are not taking part in industrial action.
Mr Brown said they have no plans for further action after tomorrow at this stage.
The union also wanted more input into rostering and improved safety conditions for drivers.
Queensland Transport Minister Jackie Trad said talks needed to continue.
"I am urging all parties to get around the table to nut out an agreement in relation to this industrial dispute so we can provide the type of reliability and confidence that passengers really need," Ms Trad said.
The dispute came to boiling point on Wednesday, when hundreds rallied in King George Square along with other union supporters in a show of defiance in front of City Hall.
Other unions including the Australian Services Union (ASU) refused to rule out strike action for frontline council staff, including call centre operators, but said it would be used as a last resort.
ASU Secretary Neil Henderson said council needs to start bargaining.
"Because the workers are showing they're putting their money where their mouth is," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Transport Minister Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Quirk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASU Secretary Neil Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
