<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422110958765029</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4832229/bmx-soil-woes-almost-a-windfall/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>BMX soil woes almost a 'windfall'</title>
  <content>
NO WORRIES: The mayor Bruce Mackenzie and his deputy, Chris Doohan, at the Salt Ash equestian grounds in December 2015. Picture: Fairfax

Port Stephens Council this week  which prompted Kate Washington MP to ask "at what cost"?
'Not much if anything' the council has replied even  for improper procedure and nearly four times that in soil remediation costs.

"Council must come clean about how much this farce has cost ratepayers, and how council processes were ignored by the mayor and senior staff," Ms Washington said.
"This debacle has been seriously wrong from the get go."

Port Stephens Council has refuted that it's cost the BMX project anything with the "minimal cost" instead covered by the Raymond Terrace tip.

"We failed to have the soil tested before we transported it to the sportsgrounds, that [blame] is on me," the council's Facilities group manager Greg Kable said.
"The fine wasn't for acid sulfate soils at all."
After discussions with the NSW Environmental Protection Authority the council said it had two choices, one was to pay $600,000 to dispose of the soil.
"We came up with an alternative proposal that we treat it and use the clay to cap Raymond Terrace tip," Mr Kable said.
"We had to treat it before we could shift it and it cost about $150,000 to $160,000."
Clay capping old dump sites is a well established practice and Mr Kable said it came with its own costs.
"There are often councils in a position like us but having to buy capping clay," he said.
"Even by the time we've treated the soil [for Raymond Terrace tip] its actually worked out cheaper than if we'd had to buy ENM [excavated natural material] for the task."
From an accounting perspective Mr Kable said none of the costs were attributable to the BMX track project.
"When we decided to treat the soil, we could have said something, but we like to poke along quietly and do what we need to do."
The council wore the fine along alongside its consultant Cardno Pty Ltd, asked to pay $16,000 for providing misleading information about the soil after the fact.

DUMBFOUNDED: Port Stephens MP Kate Washington said it was laughable to think the soil could be thought of as a windfall.
"We acted in good faith on the nature of that advice," Mr Kable said.
"Because the clay was produced from a council site [Peppertree Road, Medowie] we would had to have paid to dispose of the soil in any case."
Mr Kable said some of that clay from Peppertree Road was used to build a car park at the Salt Ash Hall on Michael Drive.
He refutes that there was any acid sulfate soil at either the Hall or at the pony club grounds.
"We deal with acid sulfate soils from time to time but it wasn't active," he said.
"It had an elevated acid PH but it hadn't oxidised, when it starts to oxidise it produces run off that's harmful to the environment."
The decision to move the BMX project to Michael Drive, next to the hall, was made on "safety grounds".
The council has begun to adopt Safer By Design guidelines at its various facilities.

The NSW Police guidelines suggest infrastructure like toilets be placed in more visible places to reduce vandalism and loitering, like at Boomerang Park. With the BMX track, emergency vehicle access was said to be the issue.
"It wasn't until we started the detailed design that we could measure it against the guidelines and that's when it became clear," Mr Kable said.
This was after grounds users had raised safety concerns of their owns around the compatibility of horses, sudden movement and loud noises.

"Hindsight is a beautiful thing," Mr Kable said.
"To manage the risk of it being so far from the road [the track] would almost have had to be flat. Putting it next to the hall, it's much easier for an ambulance to gain access if there's an injury."
Ms Washington said it was incredible to think that the soil "left sitting there for so long" could actually been thought of as a good outcome.
"What council is trying to say happened can best be described as a case of creative accounting, trying to cover up the costs to ratepayers," she said.

"To say that having all that soil sitting there might have been beneficial is laughable."
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMX</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>pH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Washington MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Doohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Mackenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Kable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens MP Kate Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boomerang Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raymond Terrace</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardno Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Drive</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peppertree Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safer By Design</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ENM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Ash Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kable</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Environmental Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
