<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421118821301300</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/1911706/topics-forefather-close-to-being-real-mccloy/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>TOPICS: Forefather close to being real McCloy</title>
  <content>
TOPICS: Forefather close to being real McCloy

UNCANNY LOOKALIKE: The portrait of Newcastle's first mayor James Hannell, right; current lord mayor Jeff McCloy, left, who bears a close resemblance to Hannell.

exit
SINCE Newcastle lord mayor Jeff McCloy took office last year, more than one of our spies has suffered whiplash from seeing his dead ringer and performing a double-take.

The mayor's lookalike glares, sober as a marble, from a painting outside Mr McCloy's office at City Hall. Topics finds the resemblance uncanny. For the visitor, it's quite disconcerting.
So who is the man in the painting? Why it's Newcastle's first mayor James Hannell, painted by William Reay, and a man of means like the one now in office.
Hannell was certified as Newcastle's first auctioneer in 1839 before becoming publican at the Ship Inn, a pub on the corner of Hunter and Bolton streets.
He's credited with starting up the Newcastle Jockey, Regatta and Cricket clubs, and even had the name of his suburb changed to Maryville after his wife Mary, whose portrait also hangs in City Hall.
Which was probably for the best. It had been called Smedmore.
A gastronomical bill 
JOE Tripodi has questions to answer, according to ICAC. And also according to David Barrow, of Merewether.
As mentioned (Topics, November 15), the commission grilled Mr Tripodi this week about his 2007 trip to Newcastle during the Pasha Bulker crisis.
It was revealed at the time that Mr Tripodi and two staffers devoured $6683.10 in expenses over five days. They said they spent it on ''pies and pizzas''.
''Well back then,'' says David, our reader, ''the question was asked of Joe through the letters section to name the dastardly and unscrupulous fast food outlet so that we might put the shop on the blacklist.''
Six years on, David wants a reply from Mr Tripodi. And so do we, Joe, if you're reading. Which fast food joint whacked you for $400 per person, per day? 
Topics thought the NSW Labor ideas sessions were fuelled by the Golden Century Chinese restaurant in Sussex Street.
Reaching new heights
SEEN, on Scenic Drive at Merewether Heights: a man who appeared to be working on the outside of a house, walking around on stilts.
Our correspondent tried to get a better look, but had to keep driving. Are the stilts instead of a ladder? Is this a new thing?
Big prawn staying put
EVERYONE, remain calm. This prawn ain't for sale.
Topics was alarmed yesterday to hear talk that the big prawn of Catherine Hill Bay - a symbol of hope in the bushfire emergency - was to change hands.
Prospective buyers, rumour had it, were circling Our Prawn with a view to removing it from its burnt-out service station perch and trucking it down to Sydney. We kid you not. Topics jumped on the blower.
''It's definitely not for sale,'' said a spokeswoman for the prawn's owner, Westside Petroleum.
''There are no offers that I'm aware of.''
Phew. Westside has previously told Topics, in a world exclusive, it's in the process of seeking approval to rebuild the service station.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff McCloy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scenic Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smedmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sussex Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ship Inn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCloy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tripodi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McCloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Jockey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hannell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westside Petroleum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Century Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Reay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Hill Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Barrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pasha Bulker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tripodi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
