<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422235512819349</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/before-the-bell/flat-local-open-ahead-of-rba-economic-forecasts-20170803-gxp17s</url>
  <title>Flat local open ahead of RBA economic forecasts</title>
  <content>
by
Timothy Moore

Local shares are poised to open little changed as earnings season edges towards its peak amid high expectations. ASX futures up 3 points. The Australian dollar slipped 0.2 per cent ahead of the release today of the RBA's latest statement on monetary policy.
The focus on the statement will be on where the central bank sees economic growth, unemployment and inflation down the road. 
Not unexpectedly shares on Wall Street fluctuated overnight, and Apple retreated somewhat from its surge the previous session in what was seen as more profit taking. The Dow however edged higher, continuing to hold above the 22,000 mark. 
The seemingly renewed bull market in equities is once again challenging perceptions of valuations.

In an overnight comment, Capital Economics' John Higgins and Oliver Jones put forward the case for "rational exuberance". 

"Higher valuations have been supported by a structural decline in real interest rates, which we think is likely to endure," the analysts wrote. "This decline has cut the prospective return from 'risk-free' assets, demonstrated by the historically-low levels of developed-market government bond yields.
"In our view, this has driven the equilibrium valuations of risky assets some way above the long-run averages with which they are frequently compared. With this in mind, we believe that investors' exuberance for such assets is rational."
That said Mr Higgins and Mr Jones said they see limited upside for risk assets, and they expect the S&P 500 to end next year "a little lower" than where it is today. 
"But we judge that a major correction is unlikely before 2019. And even then, we suspect that it will be caused by the rising risk of a cyclical downturn in the US economy - not by markets collapsing under the weight of excessive valuations," they said.

The S&P 500 is at 2472 in early afternoon trade in New York. It's up 10.5 per cent so far this year. Twenty five of the S&P 500's members closed at record highs on Wednesday, according to MarketWatch.
Today's Agenda

Local data: Retail sales June, RBA Statement on Monetary Policy
Overseas data: German factory orders June; US non-farm payrolls July, unemployment rate, average hourly earnings, Trade balance June

According to a Reuters survey of economists, US nonfarm payrolls probably increased by 183,000 jobs last month after surging by 222,000 in June. The unemployment rate is seen falling one-tenth of a percentage point to 4.3 per cent.
Market Highlights

SPI futures up 3 points or 0.1% to 5668
AUD -0.2% to 79.43 US cents (Overnight range: 0.7915 - 0.7969)

On Wall St, Dow flat, S&P 500 -0.2%, Nasdaq -0.4%
In New York, BHP -0.9%, Rio +0.4%
In Europe, Stoxx 50 +0.2%, FTSE +0.9%, CAC +0.5%, DAX -0.2%
Spot gold +0.1% to $US1268.43 an ounce

Brent crude -0.4% to $US52.17 a barrel
US oil -0.8% to $US49.21 a barrel
Iron ore +0.9% to $US72.93 a tonne
Dalian iron ore +1.3% to 550 yuan
LME aluminium -0.5% to $US1916 a tonne
LME copper flat at $US6352 a tonne
10-year bond yield: US 2.22%, Germany 0.45%, Australia 2.66%
From Today's 
Financial Review

: Perhaps the worst aspect of the CBA case is what it says about the regulator.
: CBA is facing hundreds of millions of dollars in penalties and questions over the future of key executives including CEO Ian Narev.
: Rio Tinto has done the whole mining industry a $3.8b favour by offering full and early delivery on its new compact with shareholders.
United States

The S&P 500 and the Nasdaq fell on Thursday, weighed down by Amazon.com, Apple and other top-shelf technology stocks, while the Dow Jones Industrial edged up to a seventh straight record high.
Stocks lost a little ground late in the session after the Wall Street Journal reported that Special counsel Robert Mueller has impaneled a grand jury in Washington to investigate allegations of Russia's interference in the 2016 elections.
The S&P 500 information technology index, which has led other sectors in 2017, dipped 0.35 per cent. Apple lost 1.0 per cent after hitting a record high the day before. It and Amazon.com, down 0.90 per cent, weighed more than any other stocks on the S&P 500.
Silicon Valley electric carmaker Tesla jumped 6.50 per cent reporting quarterly results above Wall Street's expectations.

Analysts, on average, expect S&P 500 earnings to have grown 11.8 per cent and they project earnings up 9.2 per cent for the September quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S.
Europe

European shares inched up on Thursday as solid company earnings more than offset a weak energy sector and a slump in German industrial giant Siemens on delays to a planned unit listing.
The pan-European STOXX 600 index rose 0.08 per cent to 378.93 points and euro zone blue chips added 0.20 per cent, reaching 3466.37 points.
Siemens was the top weight to the STOXX after saying it would wait until next year to list its healthcare unit following the release of disappointing quarterly earnings.
Its 3.1-per cent slide dragged on the German blue chip DAX index, which fell 0.2 per cent, underperforming the rest of Europe and adding to a recent slide due to strength in the euro.
However strategists at Credit Suisse's wealth management arm upgraded German stocks to 'outperform' saying the rise in the single currency had opened an unmerited valuation gap.
"Earnings momentum and revisions have not been very strong in Germany but they are no worse than the middle of the pack, so the discount you are seeing relative to the rest of the euro zone is not fully merited," said Pierre Bose, head of European strategy at Credit Suisse Wealth Management.

Around 64 per cent of MSCI Europe companies have already reported results. Of them nearly two thirds have either beaten or met analyst expectations, pointing to a second-quarter earnings growth of more than 22 per cent, according to Thomson Reuters IBES data.
Asia

China stocks fell on Thursday after a private survey showed the country's services sector cooled in July and as a net drain of funds by the central bank renewed concerns about liquidity conditions. The CSI300 index fell 0.5 per cent to 3741.35 points by the end of the morning session, while the Shanghai Composite Index lost 0.2 per cent to 3277.19, slipping from Wednesday's eight-month intraday high.
China's services sector expanded at a slightly slower pace in July as new business growth eased, a private business survey showed on Thursday.
Materials firms continued to outperform, with a 0.8 per cent gain.
Aluminum Corp Of China, China's largest aluminium maker, leapt 7.3 per cent to a near two-year high. The stock has gained more than 60 per cent this year.
Material companies, in particular large state-owned firms, have been among this year's best performers as they are expected to benefit most from Beijing's continued supply-side reforms. Resources prices have risen as China works to shut older, inefficient plants in sectors with huge overcapacity.
Hong Kong stocks followed other Asian markets lower, as investors locked in recent gains. The Hang Seng index dropped 0.2 per cent to 27,566.80, easing from Wednesday's 26-month high. The Hong Kong China Enterprises Index lost 0.3 per cent, to 11,019.60.

Japan's Nikkei share average fell on Thursday as investors wasted little time taking profits in tech shares which rallied the previous day on Apple's strong quarterly earnings. The Nikkei ended 0.3 per cent lower at 20,029.26 points. The broader Topix ended nearly flat at 1633.82.
"The Japanese market rose ahead of US markets after Apple's earnings so investors were quick to lock in gains," said Norihiro Fujito, a senior investment strategist at Mitsubishi UFJ Morgan Stanley Securities
Currencies

The Czech central bank is teeing up more increases in interest rates after starting monetary tightening in Europe with its first hike in almost a decade. The koruna jumped the most in three months after the benchmark rate was raised to 0.25 per cent from a record-low 0.05 per cent in a unanimous decision on Thursday. 
Commodities

Physical iron ore prices recovered on Thursday amid expectations of a stronger steel market during winter when production may be restricted in China's steelmaking hub of Tangshan, Metal Bulletin reported.
While a number of iron ore sellers who have stocked up earlier were heard to be cashing in to take advantage of the relatively high prices at the moment, some traders are also enquiring about seaborne cargoes, especially for entire Capesize shipments of Pilbara Blend fines or Newman fines linked to the September average of indices, MB reported. Such shipments are being offered at premiums of $US1-2 per tonne, while joint cargoes of Pilbara Blend fines and lumps are generally available at premiums totalling no more than $US1 per tonne, according to sources.

Copper held near two-year highs and nickel rose for a 10th straight session, supported by expectations of stronger demand from top consumer China and a weak dollar though gains were limited by profit-taking. While the rally may have slowed, "the fundamentals remain quite strong. We've seen no real weakness in economic data." said ETF Securities analyst Nitesh Shah.
Benchmark copper on the London Metal Exchange ended unchanged at $US6352 a tonne, close to Monday's two-year high of $US6430 and up 14 per cent since early June.
LME nickel closed up 0.3 per cent at $US10,380 a tonne in its 10th day of gains after touching a four-month high of $US10,445 earlier in the session.
"Much of the recent strength across industrial metals has been financially driven (whether dollar related/money inflows)," brokers Marex Spectron said in a note, warning that physical metal demand may not justify gains and increased financial interest could cause price volatility.
Aluminium finished down 0.5 per cent at $US1916, zinc ended 0.3 per cent lower at $US2792, lead rose 0.6 per cent to $US2367 and tin closed up 0.3 per cent at $US20,650 a tonne.
Australian Sharemarket

The benchmark S&P/ASX 200 Index eased 0.2 per cent on Thursday to 5735, as early profits results threw up more losers than winners.​
Street Talk

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norihiro Fujito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Metal Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC +0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSI300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LME</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP -0.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European STOXX 600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hang Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US52.17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MarketWatch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi UFJ Morgan Stanley Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara Blend</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Nikkei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US20,650</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 -0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STOXX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX -0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSCI Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sharemarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters IBES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siemens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capesize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Economics' John Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2367</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pierre Bose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio +0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.66</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD -0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2792</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tangshan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq -0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikkei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse Wealth Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US72.93</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX 200 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETF Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1268.43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marex Spectron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong China Enterprises Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10,380</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Czech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US49.21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 2.22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6430</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Composite Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6352</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones Industrial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10,445</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nitesh Shah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corp Of China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE +0.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1916</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
