<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422068009091208</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/this-humble-hovel-could-be-brisbanes-best-renovation-project/news-story/bbd47631a3940b7d57edee96136738cb</url>
  <title>Hammer time for humble hovel</title>
  <content>
IT will take a brave buyer to see the potential in this fixer upper, but it may just be the best renovation project in Brisbane.
The humble hovel at 17 Bathurst Street, Red Hill, is in need of a major renovation, but most of the hard work is already done - it comes ready for redevelopment with approved architectural plans with current DA approvals.
And it's case of location, location, location, with the property perched in a quiet cul-de-sac just 3km from the CBD and surrounded by high-end homes, cafes and shops.

The house is on a 405 sqm, elevated parcel of land with leafy views.
Advertised as "a fun and rewarding project for 2017", the inner city gem has attracted strong interest from first home buyers, downsizers and builders ahead of its auction on Saturday.
Marketing agent Caroline Brown of Belle Property Paddington said at least 30 groups had inspected the property, including a number of young couples from interstate looking for a blank canvas on which to create their dream first home.
Ms Brown said the current owner was an architect who had wanted to design and build their forever home in Brisbane, but recently decided to expand their business in Melbourne.

Records show the home last sold in 2001 for $210,000.
"It's been a well loved home," Ms Brown said.
"And it's in such a beautiful area, flanked by high end properties."
The property is scheduled for auction at noon on Saturday, August 5.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Brown of Belle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Paddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
