<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422068009091229</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/next-generation-rollingstock-train-drivers-on-track-for-commonwealth-games/news-story/7a67edb84eff5ecf164713d21009e17f</url>
  <title>Light at end of tunnel after rail fail</title>
  <content>
ALMOST 60 new train drivers will be on the job before the Gold Coast Commonwealth Games next year.
Transport Minister Jackie Trad said there would be enough train crews to operate New Generation Rollingstock trains in service during the Games.
"We will have almost 60 new train drivers behind the wheel of the trains, making sure we have got enough drivers in order to meet the transport task of the Commonwealth Games," she said.
Ms Trad said the Cabinet's Commonwealth Games subcommittee had been briefed on the progress of driver training.
A shortage of drivers was the major factor in last year's rail fail which forced the cancellations of hundreds of services and caused the Christmas Day network meltdown.
The New Generation Rollingstock trains have been plagued with problems, forcing the State Government to announce in February it was not accepting further delivery until the issues were resolved. It has previously said the new trains would be in service by the end of the year.
Ms Trad said major progress had been made on fixing the faults but issues remained.
"We are completely focused on making sure these trains can get into passenger service well before the Commonwealth Games," she said.
The former Newman government ordered 75 of the new trains - built in India by Bombardier - at a cost of $4.4 billion, including maintenance.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Trad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabinet's Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Generation Rollingstock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bombardier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
