<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421677167060657</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/world/donald-trump-begged-mexico-president-to-pipe-down-about-border-wall/news-story/a7b7d18e29db2b249ad20e73b099b9d8</url>
  <title>Trump: 'This is going to kill me'</title>
  <content>
PRESIDENT Trump begged the Mexican president to stop saying his government would not pay to build a border wall "because I cannot live with that," according to a new report.
"You cannot say that to the press," Mr Trump told President Enrique Pena Nieto, according to a transcript of a January 27 call between the two leaders obtained by the Washington Post.
Mr Trump told Mr Nieto that the wall - a major campaign promise - was "the least important thing we are talking about, but politically this might be the most important."
Trump threatened to cut off communication with the Mexican leader if he continued to say he wouldn't pay for the wall,
"I​f you are going to say that Mexico is not going to pay for the wall, then I do not want to meet with you guys anymore because I cannot live with that​," Mr Trump said, according to the report.
He said the funding "will work out in the formula somehow," adding "it will come out in the wash and that is OK."
Mr Trump, who rallied his supporters during campaign events by chanting that he would build a wall and Mexico would pay for it, apparently was aware that his threats against Mexico put him in a box politically.
"I have to have Mexico pay for the wall - I have to," he told Nieto. "I have been talking about it for a two-year period."
He suggested how the Mexican leader could address questions about the wall.
"We should both say, 'We will work it out.' It will work out in the formula somehow," Mr Trump said. "As opposed to you saying, 'We will not pay,' and me saying, 'We will not pay.'"
But Mr Nieto baulked, saying Mr Trump's threats have put a lot of pressure on him and concluded that "my position has been and will continue to be very firm, saying that Mexico cannot pay for the wall."
Mr Trump countered: "But you cannot say that to the press. The press is going to go with that, and I cannot live with that."
The two also clashed over the flow of illegal drugs into the United States, with Trump calling drug cartel leaders "pretty tough hombres" and suggested providing help by the US military because "maybe your military is afraid of them, but our military is not."
"We have a massive drug problem where kids are becoming addicted to drugs because the drugs are being sold for less money than candy," Mr Trump said. "I won New Hampshire because New Hampshire is a drug-infested den."
But Mr Nieto said he understood that drug trafficking in Mexico is "largely supported by the illegal amounts of money and weapons coming from the United States."
This article was
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Hampshire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Enrique Pena Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nieto</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
