<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422076599025947</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/becker-hovering-ban-makes-chopper-use-impossible/3208561/</url>
  <title>Becker: Hovering ban makes chopper use 'impossible'</title>
  <content>
THE owner of a helicopter training school has criticised the new safety changes at Kybong Airport, saying it is now impossible for helicopters to use the site.

Becker Helicopters owner Captain Mike Becker said the ban on hovering was the same as stopping planes from taxiing.

"It's impossible for a helicopter, if it's going to land there, not to hover," he said.

"If it's upsetting residents who aren't at the airport because they were worried about helicopters flying over the top of them, that's got nothing to do with hovering does it?"

Having invested about $100,000 in purchasing 4ha at the site with the intention of moving some of his business there, the changes - which Capt Becker said his company was not consulted on - had left him wondering what to do now.

He said requests for an urgent meeting with the council had been turned down.

He also questioned the decision to allow residential development at the airport.

"You can't build a house in an industrial area," he said.

According to Capt Becker, the council had been made aware of incidents during a meeting in April 2016, and that the Australian Transport Safety Bureau recorded only seven incidents at the airport.

A Gympie Regional Council spokeswoman said the council was encouraging feedback from all members of the community through the airport draft master plan next week.

EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
Why our federal MPs want a plebiscite on same-sex marriage
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capt Becker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Becker Helicopters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Mike Becker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Transport Safety Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kybong Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Becker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
