<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422153908438921</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-04/islamic-state-indonesian-maids-in-hong-kong-being-radicalised/1691110</url>
  <title>Islamic State: Indonesian maids in Hong Kong being radicalised</title>
  <content>
A small but alarming number of Indonesian maids working in Asia are becoming radicalised and supporting the Islamic State (IS) group. Some have volunteered as suicide bombers.
Like thousands of poor Indonesian women, Ayu, whose name has been changed, left home to work overseas as a domestic maid.
In 2003 she moved to Hong Kong after abandoning her husband and daughter.
But after losing two jobs she found herself on the street where she sought refuge in alcohol and drugs.
By 2011, Ayu had hit rock bottom and turned to Facebook for guidance.
She joined Islamist forums and before long met her second husband, Abu, an Indonesian jihadi. They married in 2013 but Ayu stayed in Hong Kong.
As she became increasingly radicalised she befriended other Indonesian extremists online and in Hong Kong.
By 2014 she was raising funds for the IS group and providing money and assistance to Indonesian jihadists wanting to fight with IS in Syria.
Ayu is today one of more than 150,000 Indonesians living in Hong Kong. The vast majority are women who work as maids, domestic workers, nannies and elderly carers.
But an investigation by the Institute for Policy Analysis of Conflict has uncovered a tiny cell of about 50 radicalised Indonesian maids in Asia with 43 living in Hong Kong, three in Taiwan and four in Singapore.
"Some of these women were drawn in by jihadi boyfriends they met online," says Nava Nuraniyah, an IPAC researcher based in Jakarta.
"But some joined IS as a path to empowerment."
The IPAC investigation has found the number of Indonesian domestic workers in Hong Kong has risen exponentially from just 1,000 in 1990 to more than 153,000 today.
Indonesian women are often seen as cheaper and more pliant employees than the better-trained Philippine maids.
Although the IPAC report says their exploitation and underpayment is not a direct factor in their radicalisation.
"The search for a sense of community in an unfamiliar environment may have been more important," the report says.
"The growth of the Muslim community was accompanied by a rise in religious outreach [dakwah] activities by Indonesian clerics, starting with moderates but gradually coming to include the full ideological spectrum including Salafi and jihadi.
"Indonesian women found friends in these dakwah groups that often acted as surrogate families. When one was drawn into a radical circle, others followed."
For example, on Sundays when most Indonesian maids have the day off, numerous Islamic study circles have popped up in public places like Hong Kong's famous Victoria Park.
The demand for Islamic teachers has become so high that many Indonesians turn to the internet and social media for religious guidance, leading many to come into contact with extremist preachers.
In some cases, personal troubles led to a search for rebirth and renewal through "pure" Islam.
But IPAC says it was the war in Syria that has brought support for violent extremism to Hong Kong.
"Muslims were interested in the conflict, and jihadi social media had some of the most detailed news," the report says.
"They saw fighters as heroes and were eager to offer logistical and financial support."
Many women have developed personal relationships online with would-be IS fighters and then helped them travel to Syria or even travelled with them.
Other women were exploited by online boyfriends who saw the Indonesian maids as a ready source of funds.
"Often though Indonesian women extremists working abroad are not simply the victims of unscrupulous men," the report states.
"Some have reached out to men only after they have become interested in the jihadi cause themselves."
The report also highlights the important role social media has played in the women's radicalisation.
"Smartphones ensure that products, preachers and trends that become popular in Indonesia immediately find their way to Hong Kong," it says.
Ms Nuraniyah says Indonesian women in Asia appear to undergo radicalisation at a higher rate than Indonesians in the Middle East, perhaps because they face both a geographic and religious isolation in say Hong Kong.
"Only about a dozen radical maids in Saudi Arabia, Qatar and the United Arab Emirates are active on social media, for example," she wrote in the New York Times.
"None is reported to have joined jihadis in Syria."
In June this year, IPAC said four Indonesian women had joined IS in Syria while about 16 had returned home and mostly married jihadis. Another eight were deported from their host countries, or from Turkey as they tried to cross into Syria.
Last December, Indonesian police arrested two women - both former overseas workers turned would-be suicide bombers.
One woman, Ika Puspitasari, had also undergone a radicalisation while living in Hong Kong.
Like Ayu, she too had met her jihadist husband online and had allegedly volunteered to carry out a suicide bombing in Bali.
Her husband was connected to another Indonesian jihadist who joined the Islamist Maute group fighting in Marawi in the Philippines.
As of last month he was on the Philippine police's most wanted list.
IPAC says the arrest of the two women underlines the vulnerability of Indonesian migrants to extremist recruitment.
The organisation has urged Indonesian authorities to work more closely with overseas agencies to offer training and more awareness to women leaving to work overseas.
Specifically it recommends training modules that alert Indonesian women to the risk of exploitation by extremist men, and the support of Muslim leaders in Hong Kong, as well as Hong Kong authorities, to ban extremist clerics from the country.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>24</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Policy Analysis of Conflict</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marawi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Arab Emirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Nuraniyah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPAC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salafi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ika Puspitasari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nava Nuraniyah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jakarta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist Maute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayu</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
