<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422076599025953</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/teams-sitting-pretty-others-needing-an-nrl-miracle/3208327/</url>
  <title>Teams sitting pretty, others needing an NRL miracle</title>
  <content>
THE NRL top eight is starting to take shape with 10 teams still trying to qualify.

If you're a Storm fan, you are sitting pretty.

If you are a Roosters fan, you are also sitting in a great position.

Last year's premiers the Sharks are doing all the right things for a back-to-back assault.

The Broncos are sitting fourth but the loss of McCullough will really test them.

A Cowboys side without JT has been playing fairly good football but have a tough run home.

My beloved Eels are in a purple patch of form and will finally be playing finals' football.

The Sea Eagles were flying high before having their wings clipped recently.

The Dragons are slipping down the ladder at a fast rate.

Outside the eight, we have the Panthers who have underachieved but are starting a run.

The Raiders will need a minor miracle to qualify.

In five more weeks we will have all our answers.

Basketball coup

NBL owner Larry Kestelman has achieved a major coup by lining up three of his teams to play in the United States.

The Brisbane Bullets, Melbourne United and the Sydney Kings will travel to America to play some pre-season games against the Phoenix Suns, Oklahoma City Thunder and the Utah Jazz respectively.

This was a huge announcement by the owner and will benefit all three clubs and the players that get to make this trip.

Kestelman hopes one day that an NBA game will be played in Australia.

With his vision and dedication to the sport, no one would dare argue.

Ipswich review
ROUND 18: Brothers v West End - This game didn't reach any great heights but Brothers had too much firepower for a Bulldogs outfit that couldn't hold the ball.

Swifts v Fassifern: The red-hot Bombers were hoping to inflict a loss on the undermanned Bluebirds and that's exactly what happened. Swifts had no answers to a team that is building beautifully towards September action.

Cobras v Goodna: A tale of two halves. The first half was an even contest with the Eagles just having the upper hand. In the second half, Goodna put the pedal to the medal with a comprehensive display of power and speed.

Quick thoughts
HERO of the week 1: It's hard to go past the 350 gamer Cameron Smith. This man is as durable as they come and would be the first person picked in any team.

Hero of the week 2: St Kilda superstar Nick Riewoldt who announced earlier this week that this season will be his last. He will go down as a legend for the Saints and one of the greatest Queensland AFL players the state has produced.

Villian of the week: St George Illawarra coach Paul McGregor gets my nod this week after his spray of the referees. It's about time club coaches forgot the easy option and start to blame their players for losing.

Bomber's best: Another week another winning tip.

This week the streak will continues with the Brisbane Lions having the points start.

Who am I?

I scored three tries in the 2005 IRL grand final leading my team to victory. I could have scored four but I passed the ball over the line to one of my retiring teammates. I was the littlest player on the field weighing in at a modest 70kg.

Last week's answer: Aaron Saltner.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cobra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fassifern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma City Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCullough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluebirds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Saltner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swift</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
