<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422149613471552</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-04/marcus-hutchins-malwaretech-cyber-expert-who-ended-wannacry-attack-arrested-in-us/1691122</url>
  <title>Marcus Hutchins: MalwareTech cyber expert who ended WannaCry attack arrested in US</title>
  <content>
A cyber security researcher widely credited with helping to neutralise the global WannaCry ransomware attack earlier this year has been arrested by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, US officials say.
Marcus Hutchins,  a "kill switch" that effectively disabled the WannaCry worm in May, was detained by FBI officials in Nevada, a US Marshals Service spokeswoman said.
"We are aware that he was arrested. It is not our case, it is the FBI's case," she said in a phone interview, declining to provide further details.
Mr Hutchins, also known as MalwareTech, allegedly conspired to advertise, sell and profit from the Kronos banking virus dating back to 2014 and 2015, according to an indictment.
A US official said the Kronos allegations were unrelated to his role in helping stop the WannaCry attack.
Mr Hutchins, 23, along with tens of thousands of other hackers, was reportedly in Las Vegas for the annual Black Hat and Def Con security conferences.
Representatives at the FBI field office in Las Vegas and the agency's headquarters in Washington did not immediately respond to requests for comment.
A friend, Andrew Mabbitt, confirmed later on Twitter that Mr Hutchins was being held in the Las Vegas FBI field office.

External Link:

Hacking colleague tweets on Marcus Hutchins arrest
WannaCry  at car factories, hospitals, shops and schools in more than 150 countries.
Mr Hutchins , was praised for saving companies and governments millions of dollars, and has since worked for British intelligence.
His arrest in Las Vegas was first reported by the security website Motherboard.
A spokesperson from the UK's National Cyber Security Centre initially confirmed the arrest to Motherboard in an email.
"We are aware of the situation. This is a law enforcement matter and it would be inappropriate to comment further."
Reuters/ABC
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Hutchins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Mabbitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Bureau of Investigation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WannaCry</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MalwareTech</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kronos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Hat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nevada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF CON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hutchins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK's National Cyber Security Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters/ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hutchins, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marshals Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
