<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421861850657516</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sunshine-plaza-opening-was-a-night-to-remember/3207392/</url>
  <title>Sunshine Plaza opening was a night to remember</title>
  <content>
EVERYBODY who was anybody wanted to secure a ticket to the opening of Sunshine Plaza in November 1994.
As the Daily's Shopper publication editor at the time, I got a guernsey. But the dress code was far from "guernseys". While the program for the night was a well-kept secret, the dress code was strictly after-five. Every female searched high and low for "the" outfit. And as the Sunshine Coast attire was usually smart casual, we had to hunt high and low. I settled on a Mr K label ensemble: a black crepe skirt cut high at the side with a magnificently flouncy turquoise low-cut top (it was the Nineties!). We hired my husband's black tuxedo and bowtie for the night.
The air was thick with anticipation as the crowd more reminiscent of a Sydney or Melbourne gala charity ball gathered at a designated meeting place at the Riverwalk, ready to be sorted in groups for a first-release movie (mine was The Mask) to be shown in the big-screen Birch Carroll and Coyle on-site cinemas.
The Brasserie had been transformed into a South American nightclub - complete with big band - awaiting its VIP guests where we ate, drank and danced the night away with sambas, rumbas and tangos joining the best drunken dance steps you've ever seen.
It was just like something, well, out of the movies.
Sunshine Plaza was no ordinary shopping centre and the opening was certainly something out of the box. It stayed in guests' collective memories a long time.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily's Shopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BIRCH Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brasserie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 1994</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverwalk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
