<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421814606016403</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/did-accused-know-he-was-unsafe-before-fatal-crash/3208558/</url>
  <title>Did accused know he was unsafe before fatal crash?</title>
  <content>
WITNESSES and dashcam footage show Paul Gerard Crimmins' car did not slow or veer as it careened across a highway in a Bells Creek crash that killed a Sunshine Coast man.
Now a jury must decide if Paul Gerard Crimmins, 59, had any warning before he is believed to have lost consciousness, swerving across a Bruce Hwy median strip and ploughing into an oncoming car.
The crash on November 27, 2015, killed 69-year-old Noosaville man Graeme Warren and severely injured his wife Dianne Warren, Mr Crimmins and his wife Gail Crimmins.
Yesterday the jury at Maroochydore District Court retired to consider whether Mr Crimmins was guilty of dangerous driving causing death and grievous bodily harm.
Defence counsel Peter O'Connor told the jury the element in dispute was whether Mr Crimmins was driving dangerously.
Mr Crimmins had told police and the court he couldn't remember the moments before the impact.
"As a matter of certainty, he doesn't know and can't know what happened," Mr O'Connor said.
Mr O'Connor told the jury in his closing address it was common for victims of a serious car crash to lose their memories surrounding the events.
Both Mrs Warren and Mrs Crimmins were unable to remember the moments leading up to the crash.
Mr O'Connor said the only reasonable explanation for Mr Crimmins' swerve was that he lost consciousness at the wheel.
He said Mr Crimmins was "awake and fully attentive" just three minutes before the crash, when he spoke to his wife at the Roys Rd overpass.
"There's no evidence, reliably, that there was any warning," Mr O'Connor said.
Crown Prosecutor Mark Whitbread supported the inference that Mr Crimmins passed out, but said there were signs before the crash he was becoming drowsy.
He told the jury dashcam footage showed the Nissan Patrol was drifting to the left of the lane and may have passed the audible lines at one point.
"It seemed that he is losing concentration," Mr Whitbread said.
Mr O'Connor said suggestions from the prosecution that Mr Crimmins may have turned up the radio and began speaking less because he was drowsy were "mere speculation".
The jury will continue deliberating today.
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitbread</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Gerard Crimmins, 59</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Crimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roys Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Crimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nissan Patrol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAUL Gerard Crimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bells Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Mark Whitbread</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Connor</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dianne Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Crimmins</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
