<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422106663797686</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/council-needs-runs-on-the-board/news-story/17d3bafb8539c879c4cbc79ef3ef895d</url>
  <title>Council needs runs on the board</title>
  <content>
EDITORIAL: Hilton's decision to consider building one of its internationally renowned facilities here is a huge vote of confidence for Townsville.
The marquee brand has chosen the city as a potential location for a 4.5-star, seven-storey luxury hotel that would sit right next to the North Queensland Stadium.
While some local businesses still lack confidence, Hilton's call is a sign the times are turning.
It is only in its preliminary planning stage, but this proposal may motivate other investors to look no further than Townsville.
The 175-bed hotel would not only add a level of luxury to Townsville but it would bring a brand that has a renowned reputation for class around the world.
The hotel's proximity to the stadium could also help to attract larger events that would establish the city as an even stronger world-class tourism destination.
The stadium doesn't need to just be home to Cowboys games.
It could be home to a State of Origin match or host huge international musicians with audiences only having to walk just down the road to sleep.
However, while glossy concept designs of a hotel have been provided, the Hilton proposal is yet another concept that's being added to the list of potential developments that Townsville could secure.
It has merely emphasised the relevance of the Pure Projects report which outlined the need for a CBD rejuvenation.
What the region is longing to see are tangible results that provide a boost to the economy and create much-needed jobs. And as exciting as this announcement is, it does the region no good just sitting in a backlog of paperwork gathering dust.
The region constantly hears about how beautiful it is and what potential it has but residents are still waiting for the passing of what seems like countless feasibility studies.
They are looking for sods to be turned and companies to start offering jobs.
So, the time to act is now.
The council needs to get a win on the board.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pure Projects</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
