<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422110958765024</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/its-time-to-move-the-date-of-australia-day/news-story/95f73ef8ad74cddee21529883f3ebf9b</url>
  <title>It's time to move the date</title>
  <content>
IT SEEMS like politicaal correctness gone mad.
Who can forget that groan-worthy one from a couple of years ago about kids having to sing 'Baa, baa, rainbow sheep'? Madness!
In truth, most of these stories are completely overblown.
They're clickbait, specifically designed to get you clicking away to bump up web traffic on news websites and riled up enough to vent your frustration on social media so it spreads even further.
Very few of them have much credibility but they tend to make a mark in people's memories.
Even so, there are a lot of "controversies" that can easily be dismissed as the so-called PC brigade trying way too hard not to offend anyone when no one was actually offended in the first place.
But the debate about changing the date we celebrate Australia Day is not one of them.
This week, Triple J has stirred up the issue again by releasing a poll for listeners to have their say about whether or not the famed Hottest 100 should be held on another date.
The move has come amid growing backlash from listeners who believe the date of our national day is disrespectful to indigenous Australians who see January 26 as "Invasion Day".
The Hottest 100 and Australia Day have gone hand-in-hand since forever. It was in 1993 that what is now the world's biggest music poll first hit the airwaves.
One year later, we celebrated the Australia Day public holiday for the first time. You heard that right: 1994.
The date marking Captain Arthur Phillip's arrival at Sydney Cove wasn't even recognised in all states and territories as our national day until the mid-'30s - and it was only 23 years ago that we began to mark the day with an Aussie-as-a-meat-pie day off for a barbie.
So how can critics of the "change the date" push claim "tradition" as a reason to ignore the problem?
The latest research suggests that indigenous people were here 60,000 years before the British arrived. How's that for tradition?
Unfortunately we have a long tradition of ignoring the uncomfortable truth about history.
But we can't continue to avoid the serious conversation about January 26 by passing it off as tradition, especially when we haven't made any real progress on reconciliation.
Indigenous Australians still aren't recognised in our constitution and there's still no sign of a treaty.
Australia Day would be a great place to start bridging the gap.
The Australia Day conversation isn't just the latest cause of the month from "loony lefties".
It's not about pandering to the somehow ludicrous idea of not wanting to offend people. It's a problem that's not going to go away and it can't be pushed aside forever.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hottest 100</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 26</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invasion Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Arthur Phillip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
