<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421823195951137</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/classic-month-of-entertainment/3207944/</url>
  <title>Classic month of entertainment</title>
  <content>
ONE of the country's most successful touring entertainment groups, The Ten Tenors is returning to the Sunshine Coast.
The Ten Tenors has more than 2500 live shows to their credit and in excess of 90 million people worldwide have witnessed their unmistakable charm, camaraderie and vocal power.
This year marks the 20th anniversary of the group's creation and in that time, the members have cemented their place as one of the world's most loved classically-based contemporary music groups.
Celebrated for their wonderfully vast repertoire, breathtaking arrangements and powerful live performances, The Ten Tenors respectfully tip their hats not only to the great classical tenors and composers, but also to contemporary music's most popular pop and rock artists.
Don't miss the chance to see them live at The Events Centre, Caloundra, on Thursday, August 10, at 7.30pm. Book at
Julius Caesar
LOYALTY. Power. Conspiracy. Betrayal.
Contemporary civilisation as we know it has collapsed. Amid the ruins and dust, a group of storytellers present Shakespeare's Julius Caesar to warn of the perils of political corruption and greed.
In Shakespeare's tale, Caesar has won the hearts of the people and thus becomes a threat to the power brokers. He cannot be allowed to succeed. As the story unfolds, we are witness to Caesar's downfall and the ensuing chaos.
Through a dynamic and brutal portrayal, this rendition thrusts Shakespeare's classic work into the 21st century.
In a time of political megalomania and media frenzy, Shakespeare's words hold striking relevance.
Directed by Jo Loth - head of drama at the University of the Sunshine Coast - and featuring a cast of local actors, this gripping production of a canonical text is not to be missed at The Events Centre, Caloundra, on Saturday, August 12, at 7.30pm, Thursday, August 17, at 11am and 6.30pm, and Saturday, August 19, at 7.30pm.
Book at
FuRY A Dance Installation
LJ PROJECTS presents the most ambitious youth dance production the Sunshine Coast has seen.
FuRY A Dance Installation features a cast of more than 90 talented dancers from across the Sunshine Coast and Brisbane in a stunning youth dance work performed in the round. Conceived and choreographed by Melissa Lanham, this event is general admission and has a mix of standing space and seating. Don't miss seeing what happens when one incredible mind brings nearly 100 dancers together in one space at Lake Kawana Community Centre on Saturday, August 19, at 7.30pm. Book at
Seniors Week ballet
TO CELEBRATE Seniors Week, Queensland Ballet is presenting four exciting workshops.
Around the world, adults of all ages are discovering what Queensland Ballet has known forever - that dance is a great way to increase fitness, improve stamina and have a whole lot of fun.
As we get older, keeping our bodies strong and agile becomes even more important. Queensland Ballet's Seniors Week classes are designed to stimulate the body and the mind of active older people, with a range of pace, progression and participation to suit you perfectly - no matter what your previous experience may be.
Book in for one or more sessions covering ballet, tap and Zumba on Monday, August 21, at Lake Kawana Community Centre.
Visit  or call
5413 1400.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Free tennis is on offer at Mapleton as part of Retro Fantastic
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caesar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ballet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Lanham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ballet's Seniors Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retro Fantastic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Loth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zumba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CELEBRATE Seniors Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare's Julius Caesar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ PROJECTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julius Caesar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dance Installation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Kawana Community Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Event Center</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
