<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422149613471528</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-04/donald-trump-hits-out-at-nauru-deal-in-leaked-transcript-of-call-with-malcolm-turnbull/1691128</url>
  <title>Donald Trump hits out at Nauru deal in leaked transcript of call with Malcolm Turnbull</title>
  <content>
Donald Trump called Malcolm Turnbull's immigration policies "worse" than his own during a heated phone call between the pair in January, a leaked transcript has revealed.
The Washington Post has obtained a transcript of the call that .
"This is a big deal. It is really, really important to us that we maintain it," Mr Turnbull said during the call according to the transcript.
Mr Trump insisted the deal will make him look like "a dope" after proposing a ban on refugee resettlement in the US.
Mr Turnbull reputedly stressed that Mr Trump doesn't have to actually accept any of the individuals on Nauru or Manus Island to honour the deal, saying he only has to vet them for resettlement.
"Suppose I vet them closely and I do not take any?" Mr Trump asked later in the call.
"That is the point I have been trying to make." Mr Turnbull replied.
"How does that help you?" Mr Trump asked.
"Well, we assume that we will act in good faith," Mr Turnbull said.

Photo:(AP: Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
Mr Turnbull asked him to honour the deal as a deterrent to people smugglers and repeatedly explained Australia's immigration policy to the US leader.
"It is not because [the refugees] are bad people. It is because in order to stop people smugglers we had to deprive them of the product," Mr Turnbull said.
"The problem with the boats it [sic] that you are basically outsourcing your immigration program to people smugglers and also you get thousands of people drowning at sea."
Mr Trump then expressed admiration for the Australian policy.
"That is a good idea. We should do that too. You are worse than I am," he said.
In exchange for sticking to the deal, Mr Turnbull promised to take more refugees the US doesn't want to resettle.
"We will take more. We will take anyone that you want us to take.

External Link:

Donald Trump tweet: Thank you to Prime Minister of Australia for telling the truth about our very civil conversation that FAKE NEWS media lied about. Very nice!
"The only people that we do not take are people who come by boat."
The President repeatedly refers to the refugees on Manus Island and Nauru as being "in prison" as Mr Turnbull tries to reassure him they are not "bad people".
"They are basically economic refugees from Iran, Pakistan and Afghanistan," Mr Turnbull said.
"The only reason we cannot let them into Australia is because of our commitment to not allow people to come by boat. Otherwise we would have let them in. If they had arrived by airplane and with a tourist visa they would be here."
Throughout the call Mr Trump calls the deal "ridiculous", "rotten", and "stupid".
Mr Turnbull repeatedly pushed the President to uphold the US side of the deal and tried to give Mr Trump advice on how to save face while still honouring the agreement.
"I think that what you could say it he Australian government is consistent with the principles set out in the executive order," Mr Turnbull says, referring to the president's refugee ban.

Photo:(Reuters: Ludovic Marin)
"No, I do not want to say that," Mr Trump replied.
During the phone call Mr Trump shows a limited understanding of both the deal and broader immigration policies.
"What is the thing with boats? Why do you discriminate against boats? No, I know, they come from certain regions. I get it." he said.
Mr Trump became increasingly frustrated and vented at how the deal would make him look politically.
"I will be seen as a weak and ineffective leader in my first week by these people. This is a killer," he said.
Later in the call Mr Trump reiterated his frustrations with the Prime Minister.
"I have had it. I have been making these calls all day and this is the most unpleasant call all day. Putin was a pleasant call. This is ridiculous," he said.
According to the transcript, Prime Minister Turnbull tried to turn the conversation to less controversial topics including Syria and the DPRK.
Trump replies, "this is crazy" and the call abruptly ended after brief goodbyes.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPRK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ludovic Marin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pablo Martinez Monsivais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
