<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421896210396473</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/peter-oneill-relected-in-png-but-challenges-lie-ahead/8770894</url>
  <title>Papua New Guinea Prime Minister Peter O'Neill re-elected, but the real challenges lie ahead</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Elections in Papua New Guinea are a brutal business, but the real challenges are those that lie ahead for the re-elected Prime Minister.
On Wednesday, the country's Parliament  as Prime Minister for a second five-year term with a healthy majority, 60 to 46.
However he did not live up to the expectations of his first term, and retains leadership of a country facing significant and immediate challenges.
The past few years have been difficult for our nearest neighbour.
One of the most natural resources-dependent countries in the world, the economy has been hammered by the collapse of global commodity prices.
The Government was slow to react to this new reality, and is facing significant pressures on the monetary and fiscal fronts.
Cash has been in short supply, and cracks are forming across the public sector.
Cracks have also formed around the Prime Minister. Numerous allegations of corruption against Mr O'Neill came to a head last year with student protests that ended in violent clashes with police.
These allegations are still slowly making their way through the courts, but have no doubt distracted the Prime Minister from the task of managing Papua New Guinea's significant development challenges and weakened economic position.
Masterful politician prevails

Despite the problems, Mr O'Neill entered the ninth general elections in a position of significant strength.
A masterful politician, Mr O'Neill had built a coalition government that held 93 of 111 seats, and from the outside appeared unbeatable.
But alliances are tenuous in PNG politics where there are no permanent enemies or friends, only permanent interests.
Papua New Guinea elections also typically turn over 50 per cent of sitting MPs, making them incredibly unpredictable.
This election was no different, with Mr O'Neill suffering major defections and losing a third of his coalition.
While it was closer than many could have predicted, Mr O'Neill has prevailed.
Now the Prime Minister will have to respond to the widely-held frustrations about the manner in which this year's election was carried out.
Elections in PNG are never a clean process, and in many ways are a tremendous celebration of the democratic process.
But this election has been marred by pockets of violence, malfeasance, and even the attempted kidnapping of newly elected MPs.

The most critical issue across the country was the poor state of the electoral roll, which independent observers have called "alarming".
Tens of thousands of Papua New Guineans were disenfranchised and ineligible to vote after finding their names not on the list.
This is yet another symptom of the cash shortages in government, which led to the Electoral Commission being consistently underfunded in recent years.
A new opposition force

Despite the numerous concerns about the conduct of the election, the results have been fascinating.
A legitimate threat to Mr O'Neill emerged in a new coalition, calling itself The Alliance.
Made up of prominent opposition members, former members of Mr O'Neill's ministerial team, and a former prime minister, The Alliance got within striking distance of toppling the Prime Minister.
If they can convince their members, many of whom are independents and first term MPs, to resist the lure of joining the Government and benefiting from lucrative perks, they have the potential to become a force in Parliament.
This would restore some much needed legitimacy to a legislative process that under Mr O'Neill's first term, saw the opposition at one point reduced to three MPs and merely a rubber stamp.
On a disappointing note, this Parliament will retain zero female parliamentarians, down from three in the last parliament.
Mr O'Neill has also lost a number of his senior Cabinet ministers in this election.
Despite his thinned ranks, he will need to move fast on the issues that he left behind as he entered the election campaign.
Chief among these will be the fiscal challenges that his Government faces.
The APEC leaders' summit to be hosted in Port Moresby in 2018 and the Bougainville independence referendum in 2019 will also both have to be delicately managed.
And the courts will be overwhelmed with cases contesting the results and legitimacy of the election. The electoral process must be reviewed. He will have to do something to address corruption concerns that are resonating throughout the country.
Adding to these already daunting responsibilities is the ever-present need for MPs to service the unrelenting demands of their constituents.
All of this on top of the ever-present challenge of steering Papua New Guinea onto a more stable development path.
Australia needs to be a good neighbour

And where does Australia fit within all of this?
Mr O'Neill is a known entity to our politicians and bureaucrats, and we have a strong working relationship with him.
Our obsession with Manus Island, combined with the shrinking role that our aid program plays in the country, has dramatically reduced our influence in the country.
Australia needs to work harder to move beyond an approach that can often feel benevolent and transactional.
We should work in partnership to assist our nearest neighbour and former colony to tackle its challenges, as good neighbours should.
Prime Minister O'Neill and his government have an unenviable task ahead of them.
We should all hope that this Government can learn from the challenges of their first term, and find redemption in their second.
Jonathan Pryke is a research fellow in the Melanesia Program at the Lowy Institute.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Pryke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bougainville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea Prime Minister Peter O'Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melanesia Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister O'Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowy Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Neill</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Electoral Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Moresby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
