<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422072304058596</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/tributes-flow-for-wellknown-helicopter-pilot-brent-acton/news-story/6166700a09c85e4fcd4167ee0aa88f7a</url>
  <title>Town mourns 'great bloke'</title>
  <content>
THE small northwest Queensland community of Cloncurry is in mourning following the death of well-known helicopter pilot Brent Acton.
The 40-year-old father of two was killed , about 20km north of Cloncurry, on Wednesday.
It's understood Mr Acton was flying to another property to muster when, for reasons still being investigated, the chopper crashed and burst into flames, killing him instantly.
Mr Acton, related to the Acton Super Beef family dynasty, has been remembered as a beloved member of the Cloncurry community. He will be honoured this weekend at the Curry Merry Muster Festival.
"We'd like to take a moment and acknowledge Brent. He was a large part of this community," festival president Janessa Bidgood said.
"The Curry Merry Muster wouldn't feel right going on with our celebrations without taking a moment to acknowledge Brent and what a large part of Cloncurry the Acton family is."
Cloncurry Mayor Greg Campbell said Mr Acton was a dedicated family man and devoted to his wife Shona and sons Ned and Robert.
"He was also a great pilot, knowing that first hand from flying with him many times. Overall, he was just a bloody good bloke," Cr Campbell said.
"I am sure I can speak for the Cloncurry community (and) grazing and aviation industries when I say Brent is going to be greatly missed and his family will be supported in whatever ways are needed.
"I would like to thank the police (and) fire (services), Ergon and SES for their professionalism as most of these people were friends with Brent. Our support and thoughts extend to the team at Cloncurry Mustering Company.
"At this time, I would ask that people respect the family's right to grieve together privately and we continue with our thoughts, prayers and have our support ready when the family needs it."
Mount Isa MP Robbie Katter said Mr Acton's loss would be felt throughout the region.
"He was a very hard working family man in Cloncurry, a person you'd never hear a bad word against," Mr Katter said.
"One of those blokes that worked hard in the background and a good family and community man.
"He will be sadly missed in Cloncurry."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ergon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloncurry</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Acton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Acton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janessa Bidgood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Isa MP Robbie Katter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloncurry Mustering Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acton Super Beef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry Merry Muster Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloncurry Mayor Greg Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Katter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry Merry Muster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
