<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422076599025992</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/marco-turns-heat-new-reality-show/3208247/</url>
  <title>Marco turns up the heat in new reality show</title>
  <content>
MARCO Pierre White is no stranger to our screens. The intense stare of Britain's godfather of modern cooking has rattled many MasterChef contestants.
Now he's turning his attention to an eclectic mix of Australian and international celebrities in Hell's Kitchen Australia.
"What's special about Australia is the people. They are wonderful, truly kind and honest," he says.

"But secondly, they serve good food and really good coffee. I'll get on a plane for a really good coffee. I can't say that about many countries."
Ten celebrities ranging from athletes to actors, reality TV stars and a quiz show super nerd will be put through their paces in the kitchen, where they'll compete in service challenges. The last star standing will win $50,000 for his or her chosen charity.

The celebrity contestants of Hell's Kitchen Australia, from left, Willie Mason, Jess Fox, Gary 'Gaz' Beadle, Candice Warner, Issa Schultz, Debra Lawrance, Sam Frost, Lincoln Lewis, Pettifleur Berenger, David Oldfield and host Marco Pierre White, centre.Channel 7
White says he has no expectations of his famous apprentices.
"I have zero expectations. Because if you step into that arena with expectations, then you'll be let down," he says. "What's important is allowing people to be themselves.
"I always lead from the front, and it's up to them whether they wish to follow."
Can any of the celebrities actually cook? Viewers will have to tune in to find out.

Hell's Kitchen Australia premieres on Sunday at 7pm on Channel 7.
 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pettifleur Berenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debra Lawrance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lincoln Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaz Beadle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Candice Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hell's Kitchen Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willie Mason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Issa Schultz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kitchen Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
