<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422068009091240</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/university-of-sunshine-coast-team-find-no-take-fish-zones-falling-short-of-protection-targets/news-story/79f20d983fc6a643f2fd3660a2f6fa10</url>
  <title>Zones 'falling well short'</title>
  <content>
A STUDY of shallow estuarine "no take" reserves in the Moreton Bay Marine Park (MBMP) has cast doubt on their effectiveness in protecting popular fish species.
New USC-led research looked at the MBMP, along the coastline from Pumicestone Passage to the Gold Coast, to find the preferred environments of estuarine fish species.
The team led by Research Fellow in Coastal and Marine Ecology Dr Ben Gilby compared the number and diversity of fish in six estuarine 'no-take' areas with that of 16 other estuaries where fishing is permitted.
The six dedicated estuarine reserves were at Pumicestone Passage (Bribie Island, Tripcony
Bight), Redcliffe (near Hays Inlet), Nundah, Pimpama and Coomera.
"We found that the 'no-take' areas were falling well short of protecting fish that consumers
like to catch and eat, such as bream, whiting and mullet," he said.
"Paradoxically, fish targeted by anglers were more abundant outside the six protected
reserves, in the estuaries where fishing was allowed.
"The only fish consistently found in greater numbers inside the 'no-take' reserves were
species that people did not consume, such as toadfish and catfish."
Dr Gilby said the study's results initially puzzled the USC marine research team.
"We examined the habitat features of the protected areas and found two major shortcomings - they were too shallow and they were poorly connected to the main channel or sea.
"The reserves appeared to have been chosen mainly to protect mangrove habitat, but they
unfortunately lacked sufficient water depth and had large areas drying out at low tide."
Dr Gilby said the joint study broke new ground in identifying the environmental factors
contributing to fish biodiversity in estuaries.
A Queensland Parks and Wildlife Service spokeswoman said the zoning plan for Moreton Bay Marine Park was scheduled for review in 2019.
"Dr Gilby's findings are interesting and, when combined with other studies, will be invaluable in informing the review process," she said.
"The review of the Moreton Bay Marine Park zones will examine current use and expectations along with contemporary science to determine the effectiveness of the existing zoning at meeting the objectives of the Marine Parks Act 2004, that being, the conservation of the marine environment.
"Green zones form the core of Queensland's marine protected area estate in the same way that national parks protect and conserve key habitats and biodiversity on land."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pimpama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bribie Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBMP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coomera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New USC-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildlife Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Parks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Parks Act 2004</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Ecology Dr Ben Gilby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redcliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hays Inlet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Research Fellow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Gilby</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tripcony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nundah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay Marine Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pumicestone Passage</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
