<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421423763985197</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/six-figure-salary-not-top-1-percent-2017-8</url>
  <title>A $100,000 salary doesn't put you in the top 1% of income at any age</title>
  <content>
A lot of people are overjoyed to cross the $US100,000 threshold in annual income. And they should be - a six-figure salary is nothing to sneeze at.

But as income inequality in the US , a $US100,000 salary creeps ever-closer to being an upper-middle-class income, not a sure sign of wealth.

In fact, according to a Business Insider analysis of US Census data, the $US100,000 distinction isn't enough to put anyone, at any age for which there is reliable data, in the top 1% of personal incomes.

Here is the full breakdown.

Business Insider analysed data from the
, an annual survey by the US Census Bureau that talks to 1% of all US households about various economic, social, and housing demographics.

Specifically, we used individual-level data from the , a project of the Minnesota Population Center at the University of Minnesota, which allowed us to estimate the cutoffs for being in the top 1% of earners among  for each age in 2015.

Ultimately, the data showed $US116,000 at age 25 was the smallest six-figure salary you could have in order to be in the top 1% relative to your peers. But that number quickly jumps to $US200,000 by the time you reach your 30s and $US300,000 by the time you pass 35.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Census Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$100,000</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Minnesota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Census</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US116,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US200,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minnesota Population Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$300,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
