<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422196858112774</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/council-yet-to-name-special-committee/news-story/9fa639866d7817b4105238e154c9390a</url>
  <title>Council yet to name special committee</title>
  <content>
A DEVELOPMENT corporation approved by Townsville City Council in June is still to be finalised, with two independent directors to be named.
The development corporation, one of Mayor Jenny Hill's election commitments in 2016, was set up to boost economic activity in the city.
Cr Hill said finalisation of the group was nearing completion, with the two independent directors to be revealed by the end of next month.
"Once established, the corporation will be primed to start unlocking the best development options for council-owned land within the Priority Development Area and other strategic areas," she said.
It comes after the Pure Projects masterplan tabled at the council's June meeting detailed ideas to rejuvenate the CBD and some of the city's outer suburbs such as Rowes Bay. A Crystal Lagoon, parklands and a concert hall were among some of the options.
Two independent directors with "strong community and business backgrounds" will be part of the board that includes Cr Hill, the council's chief executive officer Adele Young, chief financial officer Matt Thomson and director of planning Eber Butron.
"All board members have a strong interest in ensuring that the development of Townsville is done in the best interest of the community," Cr Hill said.
"Strategic" sites would be transferred to the development corporation, which would then negotiate their development. Any decisions would be based on business cases and have to be approved by the board and the council.
The corporation is being established under provisions for councils to form beneficial enterprises under the Local Government Act 2009.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowes Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Jenny Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Hill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eber Butron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pure Projects</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Lagoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government Act 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priority Development Area</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
