<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422235512819341</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/sunshine-coast-university-hospital-orthopaedic-surgeons-fails/8772790</url>
  <title>Sunshine Coast University Hospital to be stripped of training accreditation for orthopaedic surgeons</title>
  <content>
Australia's newest hospital has failed to meet criteria to train specialised surgeons and will be stripped of accreditation from next year.
The $1.8 billion Sunshine Coast University Hospital opened earlier this year, but due to a lack of access to surgery - among other problems - no trainee orthopaedic surgeons will rotate through the facility from February 2018.
A letter obtained by the ABC shows the hospital failed to meet several accreditation criteria set out by the Australian Orthopaedic Association (AOA), which rotates its trainee surgeons through several hospitals around the country.
AOA chairman of education and training, Omar Khorshid, said it was uncommon for the association to take this type of action against a hospital.

"It's reasonably rare for us to withdraw accreditation, and it's only done where we have significant concerns about the quality of the training," Dr Khorshid said.
"We don't apologise for having reasonably strict criteria because we want to provide a high-quality workforce for the future. It's a wake-up call ... it's a message."
He said the issues were uncovered during a recent inspection and they did not expect them to be fixed soon.
The major problem identified was that trainees would not have enough time in surgery, or enough contact with orthopaedic patients, to meet their learning requirements.
"The one that was of most concern was around access to actual surgery, to adequate numbers on theatre lists, and to beds to put patients in, to make sure there's enough volume of surgery happening to achieve the surgery outcomes that we require," Dr Khorshid said.

Trainees not having access to study rooms was another problem identified by inspectors.
"Access to cases, beds and theatres is generally not easy to fix in a matter of a very short period, so I don't think it's likely that this hospital will be accredited for 2018," he said.
The problems have surfaced just months after , because of the Federal Government's refusal to fund student placements.
Hospital disagrees with decision

The Sunshine Coast Hospital and Health Service said it was disappointed and disagreed with the AOA's decision.
In a statement, acting chief executive Scott Lisle said the hospital intended to work with the AOA to address the issues raised, and potentially correct misunderstandings that may have led to the decision.
"I can reassure the community that there will be absolutely no impact on our ability to provide orthopaedic surgery or any other service at SCUH," Mr Lisle said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omar Khorshid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Khorshid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lisle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Lisle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Orthopaedic Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AOA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
