<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422153908438937</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/04/06/20/justine-memorial-wear-blue</url>
  <title>Wear blue to remember Justine Ruszczyk</title>
  <content>
Attendees of Justine Ruszczyk's public memorial are being encourage to wear bright blue colours - one of Ruszczyk's signature hues - to pay homage to the slain Australian spiritual healer.
Guided meditations and the sounds of a didgeridoo will also be part of the public memorial being planned for 6pm on August 11.
The formal service will begin at 7pm, her family has announced with those attending able to gather early to hear music, write chalkboard messages and view a multimedia presentation.
after she called police to report what she believed was a sexual assault near her Minneapolis home.

Each detail of the event is being carefully planned with Ruszczyk in mind, Carolyn Vinup, who is planning the memorial, told the  in Minneapolis.
"We're creating a sacred space for people to come into," Vinup said.
The memorial will host special speakers, time for meditation, music and performance art involving a maypole.

Related Articles

Silent reflection and walks around Lake Harriet will close the gathering.
In lieu of flowers, the family said donations can be made to the , which supports social justice causes that were important to Ruszczyk and has currently raised $12,260.

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Harriet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vinup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolyn Vinup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruszczyk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINNEAPOLIS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justine Ruszczyk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
