<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422115253732392</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/uber-honda-vezel-recall-fire-risk-singapore-2017-8</url>
  <title>Uber knowingly rented cars that were at risk of catching fire to its drivers in Singapore, a report says</title>
  <content>
Honda recalled its Vezel SUV last year because it could catch fire - but Uber continued to lease the cars to drivers in Singapore.

The news comes from a  report that says internal emails show Uber managers in Singapore were aware of the April 2016 recall but continued to rent the cars to drivers without fixing the defect. It's unclear whether Uber executives in San Francisco or then-CEO Travis Kalanick knew of the recall.

Uber did not immediately return Business Insider's request for comment.

An Uber driver's Vezel did catch fire on the job after the ride-hailing giant ignored the recall, according to the report. The incident prompted managers in Singapore to add new safety measures and address the issue after the fact. Uber bought the cars from a dozen auto importers and not directly from Honda, the report noted.

The fire is one of many crises that unfolded while Kalanick held the to job at Uber.

Uber has been under the spotlight since Susan Fowler, a former Uber engineer, published a  in February where she alleged that she had experienced gender discrimination at the company and was propositioned for sex by a male manager.  described a litany problems plaguing Uber's work culture.

Five of Uber's major investors demanded Kalanick resign in June following the string of scandals. Kalanick's resignation was the culmination of a four-month investigation that resulted in 20 firings and 215 complaints about Uber's work environment.

Kalanick has reportedly been  to Uber, but general counsel Salle Yoo  the ride-hailing giant is still looking outward,  reported. A decision on Uber's next CEO is .

Visit  for constantly updated market quotes for individual stocks, ETFs, indices, commodities and currencies traded around the world.

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vezel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Travis Kalanick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Fowler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalanick</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETFs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vezel SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salle Yoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
