<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421831785885965</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/plainly-speaking-were-ripping-off-peter-pan/3207951/</url>
  <title>Plainly speaking, we're ripping off Peter Pan</title>
  <content>
I THINK most people on Earth today would be prepared to form a circle, hold hands and agree that we live in weird times.
Times when insurance companies strive to put their policies into plainspeak, yet terms and conditions for home-delivering a pizza require a team of High Court judges to make sense of things.
Speaking of plainspeak, I can't recall who I'm quoting, nor if exact, but it went along the lines of: "In my day, we didn't have euphemisms - everybody said what they meant".
It was obviously an era that would have had little appeal to today's Spin-Meisters, nor their bosom buddies, the Convoluters.
Take the now much-used TV, screen and stage euphemism: re-imagining.
"We've re-imagined blah-blah" has far more panache and drips with far more honey than the bald, truthful "we've ripped off blah-blah".
And let's face it right here and now, the Spin-Meisters have cleverly re-imagined all the plainspeak words themselves, to the point where nobody has any idea what the heck's being said.
Which leads me, heading a one-man revolt, to admit that I'm ripping off J.M. Barrie's wonderful children's tale Peter Pan. Ripping it off with gay abandon in order to prepare a new script for The Indee's summer pantomime, the title of which I'm re-imagining as Peter P and Hook and Smee. Whether this will cause JM to turn in his interment, I don't know, but I re-imagine that he's already turned dozens of times before this.
Which further leads me to mention that The Indee at Yandina is seeking potential young actors to train towards the January school holidays production.
A rather large cast is needed and the only cost is membership of The Indee Young Players ($10 per financial year, $25 families) and all costumes are supplied. Inquiries to Carol on 5472 8200.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Free tennis is on offer at Mapleton as part of Retro Fantastic
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter P</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee Young Players ($10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retro Fantastic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J.M. Barrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Convoluters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spin-Meisters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
