<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422072304058556</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/sport/cricket/crickets-pay-stoush-each-side-will-think-itself-the-winner-in-truth-there-are-two-losers-20170803-gxoqrw.html</url>
  <title>Cricket's pay stoush: Some shares are more equal than others</title>
  <content>
The body language of the two tall men who sat down together at a hastily set table in the MCG nets was its own announcement about the outcome of the cricket pay saga. James Sutherland, the board's man, was deadpan, although to be fair, he would always have been. Alistair Nicholson, the players' man, only just managed not to look like the cat who got the cream. Against the backdrop of hostility between board and players these past 10 long months, that effort not to appear triumphant amounted to a mark of respect.
Because cream for the players it was. The spoken language made that clear. Sutherland artfully avoided uttering the words "revenue sharing" until he was asked. Finally, he admitted that in the heads of agreement just signed, there appeared this term: "Player payment and revenue sharing principles." "Revenue sharing," intoned Nicholson as often as he earnestly could. The former Melbourne full-back still knows how to spoil.

Up Next

Neymar leaving Barca, Spanish superclub confirms

00:42

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

War of words that turned cricket's pay war ugly

The cricket pay war, now resolved, turned nasty as rival parties traded verbal barbs.

Well could he smile. When Cricket Australia and the Australian Cricketers Association began to talk last October, the board under David Peever made it abundantly clear that it believed revenue sharing was redundant. It is the profits that should be divided up. On Thursday, Sutherland revised this history a little, saying that in CA's proposal in March this year, the grail was "modernised", "modified" revenue sharing, loosening up funds for grassroots.
Sutherland maintained that is what ultimately was agreed: a 30 per cent share of revenue from some streams but not others, amounting to a pool of $459m for the players - male and female, international and state - for the next five years, plus a fund for grassroots of up $30million. The players will also get back pay, residual payments from the last MOU, a voice in scheduling henceforth and to keep some of their newly staked out commercial rights.Photo: Simon Schluter
Sutherland said neither side got all it had sought. Nicholson said the players had asked only for what they had previously - that is, revenue sharing and its corollaries - and got it.
As industrial battles go, this was hardly the waterside workers dispute of 1997. Rather, it was how a rich sport was going to divide its spoils between mostly well-paid athletes for the next five years, leaving a bit for park players and kids, and yet it dragged on for longer than Patrick Stevedoring versus the Maritime Union of Australia.

First, last and always, the issue was revenue sharing. All week, lawyers and accountants from both sides have been poring over the paperwork, alert for catches, convolutions and time bombs. As late as Thursday morning, the ACA's forensic people were still at it, convincing themselves that it was indeed revenue sharing.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Would that every workforce in the land had the luxury of bickering over the device by which they will be paid more, substantially, in some cases lavishly. Of course, the cricketers do not see themselves merely as a workforce. But the board was tactless in being seen to treat them merely as hired hands.
Elitism acted as a tripwire for both sides. The cricketers moaned about being "unemployed", but instead of manning picket lines, posted on Instagram updates from exotic Pacific islands and exclusive Californian retreats. Meantime, the board heavies scarcely budged from their ivory castle. When anyone did deign to explain, it was through such organs and in such a way as to make clear they were speaking first to the business community whose fears they needed to allay. Whether shared or doled out, there still had to be revenue.
Both sides talked about respect, but at times displayed only contempt. They underestimated one another, as individuals and organisations. It is pretty clear that CA thought the players would cave in once they were not being paid. But it is also clear that the players expected CA to soften in its hard line once commercial realities began to pinch. Meantime, trust and respect went by the wayside, and so did an "A" tour to South Africa.
Deductively, this became the crunch. Sutherland did not enter negotiations until late, but once he did, the focus sharpened and the pace quickened. In 1997, when the ACA was formed, the players had proved stronger and more indivisible than the board had anticipated, and now they were again. They were as thoroughly unionised as few unions are now, though some would blanche to think it. Sutherland must have seen and weighed this.
Sponsors and broadcasters wanted answers, and now there stood in the balance a Test tour of Bangladesh, no-one's idea of Shangri La, but if cancelled would cast Australia poorly in the eyes of the cricket world, since it hardly ever stoops to play there. Cricket needed to be winner.
As late as Thursday morning, the ACA's forensic people were still at it, convincing themselves that it was indeed revenue sharing
Greg Baum

And so, suddenly, it was. But even as Sutherland and Nicholson put on their faces, the figures released in emails separately from CA and ACA did not quite tally.
The ACA won because revenue sharing has been neither bastardised nor scrapped. But CA will convince itself that because the model has been modified, the door is open to further massaging in the future.
The fall-out will be measured by Geiger counter. Between players and board, the bruising will fade, because they have few usual dealings anyway. Board men do not much go to the the changeroom, nor do players stalk mahogany row. But philosophically, they remain poles apart. Both preach the gospel of grassroots, but have radically different ideas how to fund them adequately. CA still thinks too much of its money is committed to the elite, the players that CA would have more for grassroots if it did not squander what it had so egregiously in the first instance.
Notionally, these become matters for next time. In truth, the work needs to begin now, with new protocols and better mutual understanding, because a prosperous sport usually so blessed with public favour should not again be so demeaned by its own hand.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Baum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Peever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geiger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sutherland</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Stevedoring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Schluter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Union of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shangri-La</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
