<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421848965755441</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/in-business-through-good-times-and-bad/3207396/</url>
  <title>In business through good times and bad</title>
  <content>
WE opened the True Value Coastal Hardware on February 1, 1990. Everyone said we were mad as we were having "the recession we had to have", according to the then prime minister.
The interest rate on loans was 18% and overdrafts was 22%.
While inflation was high, everyone seemed to be working and we could still earn enough money to make it worth starting a business.
True Value Coastal Hardware opened its doors on Mooloolaba's Brisbane Rd, in the shop now used by Cycle Zone. In 2006, we moved to Nicklin Way at the Amart Sports complex where the old Spotlight building used to be before it was burnt down.
We did get some building-trade customers in the early days but we didn't have timber and all the large items they required, so it it was nails, bolts, screws and cement.
In 1991, Mitre 10 held a three-day trade show down the Gold Coast. We went down and there were more than 100 suppliers showing their wares. I thought: "I would love to open this to the public for one day on the Sunshine Coast."
One day I was talking to Ashley Robinson, when he was manager of the old Mooloolaba Hotel, and he asked me, "What can we do to get this place going?"
I said I could put on a hardware show in the spare block behind the hotel and he agreed. I didn't know what sort of a job I was putting my hand up for. I had to talk the suppliers into coming, as well as helping with the costs.
We put up a large tent and filled it gear for Father's Day 1992. It went great. We sold so much product the suppliers were chasing me to know when we were having another one.
It was agreed we needed a bigger tent, so I got a circus tent for the next Father's Day. Unfortunately, it was a complete flop and cost us a lot of money.
While we were still licking our wounds, more suppliers started contacting me, wanting to be part of it. I realised we would have to shift to another site. At that stage, the church site near Alex Surf Club was still vacant, so we hired that.
We put a large Hockadome tent on the site, filled it with everything and ran the show over Friday, Saturday and Sunday. Our determination paid off.
The police came at 9.30am and warned me to go to the bank every hour because there was so much money that they believed it was a robbery waiting to happen. They kept calling in during the day to make sure we were all right.
We ran the shows until 1996 and they were my proudest achievement while in business.
The strong support of local tradespeople was important for my business and in better times, weekly orders would provide tens-of-thousands of dollars in reliable income.
I remember supplying more than 100 prawn trawler operators and fishermen with boat-repair materials before that industry contracted and so did the orders.
In the 1990s, there were a lot of prawn trawlers and fishing boats and there were a lot of visiting yachts from all over the world calling into Mooloolaba. That was an interesting job, trying to serve them when most didn't speak much English.
In the early days, no one opened on Sundays but I thought people must want to buy hardware all weekend, so I did. I didn't get any nice words from the other hardware stores.
It became tough competing against the multinationals. A lot of people in the construction trades turned to outlets such as Bunnings, making competition very tough for independent hardware franchises like mine.
I could match them on prices but not on variety. It's hard for independent hardware businesses to match the convenience of hardware superstores, especially when customers expect to be able to find anything they need in one trip.
But Bunnings didn't beat me. I would have kept on in the hardware trade if I was younger but I was 70 years old and had a broken leg. The lease on my building was up for renewal and my wife and I couldn't commit to another 10 years.
We are proud that we were local people giving local service and wanted to stay that way. I've got a lot of fond memories.
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicklin Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cycle Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hockadome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Surf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba's Brisbane Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father's Day 1992</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>True Value Coastal Hardware</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitre 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amart Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father's Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Value Coastal Hardware</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
