<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421857555690121</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/some-dam-good-fishing-offered/3208018/</url>
  <title>Some 'dam good' fishing offered</title>
  <content>
THE Sunshine Coast plays host to some great dams and some changes to the successful permit system for freshwater fishing will now ensure these dams are regularly stocked with species that will not reproduce in impoundments.
The money from anglers who pay for stocked impoundment permits goes to local stocking groups so they can buy native fish fingerlings and cover the scheme's admin costs.
Permits are available at Davo's Tackle World Noosa, Australia Post outlets or online. The local dams mentioned, with the inclusion of Borumba, all require a fishing permit.
Lake Macdonald: This dam is in the Noosa hinterland and is part of the south-east Queensland water supply. Lake Macdonald (Six Mile Creek Dam) was built in 1965 and then raised in 1980 to increase its storage capacity. It's a typical un-gated dam - meaning at 100% capacity, the water safely overflows down the spillway. Powered and non-powered boating are allowed along with walking, picnicking and fishing. Fish species include Mary River cod, saratoga, Australian bass, golden perch, eel-tailed catfish, snub-nosed gar and spangled perch.
Ewan Maddock Dam: This is a tributary of the Mooloolah River and is un-gated like Lake Macdonald. It was constructed in two stages: one in 1976 and the second in 1983. It's located on the southern end of the Coast and is a popular recreational area for walking, horse riding, boating and fishing. This is a non-powered dam - meaning only electric motors, manual propulsion and sailing are allowed. Fish species include Australian bass, golden perch, Mary River cod, saratoga, spangled perch and eel-tailed catfish.
Borumba Dam: The dam is just south of Gympie. It supplies drinking water and provides water to the Mary Valley irrigation. Although not on the Sunshine Coast, it's relatively close and is one of the busiest of our local dams. We find this is because of the initial release of about 200 saratoga has established a self-sustaining population throughout the lake. It is un-gated and provides a great range of recreational facilities including camping, boating (petrol outboards allowed) and fishing. Fish species include saratoga, Australian bass, Mary River cod, golden perch and silver perch.
Baroon Pocket Dam: This dam is between Maleny and Montville on the Blackall Range. It provides recreational facilities and it part of south-east Queensland water supply. Once again, it's un-gated and great for sailing, kayaking and fishing. This dam allows electric-powered and manual boating activities only. Fish species include Australian bass, golden perch, eel-tailed catfish, Mary River cod and spangled perch. This lake has been discarded by anglers in the past due to its high level of catfish. Now that the lake has joined in the SIPS, this will change over time and the fishing of our favourite native species will improve.
Now for all the latest information log on to www.fishingnoosa.com.au for up-to-date bar and fishing reports. Don't forget to drop into Davo's Tackle World in Noosa or Davo's Northshore Bait and Tackle at Marcoola to find out where the fish are biting, and remember: tight lines and bent spines.
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davo's Tackle World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary River</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davo's Northshore Bait</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackall Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macdonald</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolah River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davo's Tackle World Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcoola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Six Mile Creek Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borumba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ewan Maddock Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baroon Pocket Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borumba Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
