<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421509663333017</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/barcelona-transfer-news-psg-paris-saint-germain-neymar-200-million-buy-out-clause-2017-8</url>
  <title>Barcelona confirms Neymar has paid his £200 million buy-out clause  --  he's now expected to move to PSG</title>
  <content>
Barcelona forward Neymar has now paid his €222 million (£200 million) buy-out clause in full, according to a statement issued by the club.

The Brazilian, who told Barcelona he wanted to leave the club on Wednesday, is embroiled in a protracted world record smashing transfer to Paris Saint-Germain.

Neymar's legal team deposited the transfer fee at Barcelona's offices, having been rebuffed earlier in the day when they attempted to pay the sum at the headquarters of La Liga.

earlier on Thursday, a decision that angered the Ligue de Football Professionnel (LFP) which said it would take legal action to get the Neymar transfer done.

: "Neymar's legal representatives visited the club's offices and made the payment of €222 million in the player's name, with regards to the unilateral termination of the contract that united both parties."

With the transfer fee now confirmed, .

Barcelona stated it will "pass the details" to UEFA due to concerns the transfer could be a breach of Financial Fair Play, a regulation established to prevent clubs from spending more than they earn.

"The club will pass on to UEFA the details of the above operation so that they can determine the disciplinary responsibilities that may arise from this case."

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ligue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Fair Play</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Professionnel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
