<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421548318039544</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/victoria/groping-osteopath-loses-bid-to-keep-firefighting-job-20170803-gxol90.html</url>
  <title>Groping osteopath loses bid to keep firefighting job</title>
  <content>
A disgraced osteopath-turned-aspiring firefighter has lost his bid to be reinstated by the Metropolitan Fire Brigade which sacked him for failing to reveal he once groped patients.
Garth Duggan took his fight to the Federal Court after the full bench of the Fair Work Commission found the MFB had followed due process in not keeping the recruit after his probationary period.Photo: Paul Jeffers
Duggan started work with the MFB early in 2016 but failed to tell his new employer that he had been deregistered in NSW as an osteopath for sexually assaulting three female patients.
In 2012 Duggan was cleared of criminal charges relating to the patient complaints, but the Health Care Complaints Commission started proceedings in the NSW Civil and Administrative Tribunal in 2015.

Duggan did not attend the 2016 NCAT hearings, which were held at the same time as the MFB recruitment process.
He was notified NCAT found his touching of the patients was not clinically justified and that he was prohibited from providing any health services.

But Duggan did not declare the finding to the MFB, which instead learnt of the news from fellow recruits.
The brigade advised Duggan it was inappropriate he continue beyond probation and he would be stood down.
The United Firefighters Union took the matter to the Fair Work Commission and a commissioner briefly reinstated Duggan, before the MFB appealed which was upheld by the full bench.
On Thursday the Federal Court refused Duggan's application to review the full bench decision.
The MFB and UFU have been contacted for comment.
AAP 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFB</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Firefighters Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Duggan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan Fire Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Care Complaints Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCAT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duggan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
