<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421943455037525</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/miner-came-home-to-find-friend-and-ex-girlfriend-n/3208588/</url>
  <title>Miner came home to find friend and ex-girlfriend naked</title>
  <content>
THE front door splintered as Andrew Draper Doyle kicked it in, making his way into his mate's home.

Tearing into the bedroom, the furious miner spotted his friend and his naked ex-partner, who had arrived back at the residence after a night out together at the pub.

Seeing red, Doyle launched a brutal and prolonged attack, punching the pair ruthlessly and repeatedly before he trapped his ex in a frightening chokehold.

Doyle left the man and woman battered and bruised, each sporting a broken nose, a court was told.

The 31-year-old Proserpine man was arrested on the day and appeared in Mackay District Court for sentencing about a year later, on Thursday.

Doyle pleaded guilty to two counts of assault occasioning bodily harm (one marked as a domestic violence offence), entering a dwelling by break and committing violence, and choking or suffocation, which was also listed by the court as a domestic violence offence.

The attack occurred at Mount Julian (near Proserpine) on July 30 last year, in the midst of Doyle and his ex-partner's relationship breaking down.

Crown prosecutor Matt Hynes, who provided the facts, said Doyle had prior convictions for violence, including grievous bodily harm.

He said the latest offences were aggravated by Doyle's "background of violence".

However, Mr Hynes did concede Doyle entered an early guilty plea.

The prosecutor told Judge Douglas McGill that Doyle had spent 370 days in prison, dated to his arrest on the day of the attack.

A victim impact statement was not provided.

Defence barrister Paul Rutledge said Doyle was a young man when he committed his prior violent crimes and the attack last year was motivated by feelings he still had for his ex-partner.

He described Doyle, a long-time mining worker with good work history, as "deeply regretful" and said on the night in question he simply lost his cool in the face of a difficult situation.

Mr Rutledge said Doyle, who'd completed a substance intervention course in prison, had been drinking before the attack.

The barrister added Doyle, a "loving father" of two, would likely have a job available on release from prison.

Mr Rutledge also handed up references from several of Doyle's mining colleagues.

Judge McGill described Doyle as "unreasonably possessive" at the time of the attack.

He said the circumstances surrounding Doyle's actions provided understanding, but did not excuse his behaviour.

But the Judge did take into account Doyle's cooperation with police, early plea, rehabilitative efforts and 370 days already served.

Doyle was sentenced to seven and a half years jail on all charges, but he was granted immediate parole.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Julian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Rutledge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Draper Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Hynes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hynes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rutledge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge McGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Douglas McGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Proserpine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doyle</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
