<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421982109743837</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4832324/peak-health-body-scathing-on-mesh-history/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Peak health body scathing on mesh history</title>
  <content>
Determined: Women pelvic mesh victims leave the Federal Court in Sydney as a six-month class action against pelvic mesh manufacturer Johnson & Johnson takes place. A Senate inquiry is considering how mesh was cleared for use in Australia.

AUSTRALIA'S peak health care commission has told a Senate inquiry that up to 3000 Australian women have been left with injuries ranging from very serious to catastrophic after pelvic mesh surgery that is no longer recommended as a front line treatment.

The Australian Commission on Safety and Quality in Health Care was highly critical of specialist training, information to women about pelvic mesh risks, the treatment of women after serious mesh complications and the failure of doctors to respond when they sought help.
"The women have reported these problems. For anyone to suggest they haven't reported them is nothing short of nonsense. It's what people have done with those reports, or haven't done with them, that is the issue," commission chief executive, Adjunct Professor Debora Picone told the inquiry during a public hearing in Melbourne.

Commission clinical director Dr Robert Herkes said 40 women interviewed during consultations in four Australian cities had complications that were "undoubtedly overwhelming those women's lives".
"The bulk of the women were separated or divorced. Only one woman held down a job. For those women the complications were catastrophic," Dr Herkes said.

Many of the women did not know they had been implanted with mesh devices until they searched for explanations for complications including chronic infections, disabling pain, erosion of the mesh into other organs and an inability to have sex.

- Associate Professor Debora Picone
"We've been extremely concerned by the issues raised by the women we've talked with about the informed consent process, and particularly the informed consent process in relation to mesh surgery to treat prolapse," Professor Picone said.
"In fact some of the conversations we've had with women, informed consent has really been absent. There's no question about that in our minds."
She described "so-called patient information leaflets" about pelvic mesh surgery as "hopelessly inadequate", and said the commission felt very strongly that "major steps" needed to be taken on credentialing of doctors who implant mesh devices.
The Senate inquiry into pelvic mesh was called after Australian Pelvic Mesh Support Group founder Caz Chisholm and other members spoke with Victorian Senator Derryn Hinch. He campaigned for an inquiry into "one of the greatest scandals against women in Australian history".

It is hearing evidence from women who received mesh implants through the vagina for prolapse treatment - now not recommended as a front line treatment after complication rates of at least 10 per cent - and mesh for incontinence, with lower complication rates and recognised evidence of safety and efficacy.
At the first hearing day two doctors who gave evidence conceded they should have declared they were to appear as expert witnesses for Johnson & Johnson in the company's defence of a class action brought by more than 700 women after mesh surgery for incontinence and prolapse treatment.

Dr Anna Rosamilia told the inquiry she "should have disclosed" that she would be giving evidence for the company after appearing as a representative of Monash Health at the inquiry.

"I wasn't aware that I needed to," she said.

Dr Peter Dwyer, who will also give evidence for Johnson & Johnson, told the inquiry most of these companies have got strict ethical protocols that they stick to, before conceding he was an expert witness for the company.

Dr Dwyer told the inquiry that specialist training on mesh surgery was "falling between the gaps a bit".

"If they're placed in the wrong place... I mean, patients have died from these devices. They've got to be placed correctly," he said.

Mesh manufacturers, which have been training doctors, should not be left to train them, he said.

Medical colleges had been "very happy to pass this on to special interest groups to manage these problems", he said.

In response to a question from Mr Hinch about mesh company representatives being present in operating theatres while women are being implanted with mesh devices via the vagina, Dr Dwyer said "on occasion the rep does come into the operating theatre".

"It's not unusual for them to come into theatre at times. As long as they're not directing the operation or interfering in other ways," Dr Dwyer said.

The inquiry will hold another public hearing in Perth on August 25.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Senator Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adjunct Professor Debora Picone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Peter Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Debora Picone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Pelvic Mesh Support Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Herkes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health-care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Picone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Anna Rosamilia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caz Chisholm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Robert Herkes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Dwyer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
