<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421836080853321</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/time-for-rockin-pub-techno-with-the-presets/3207993/</url>
  <title>Time for rockin' pub-techno with The Presets</title>
  <content>
ELECTRONIC music pioneers The Presets are gearing up for a return to the spotlight, starting with the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival.
The duo, Julian Hamilton and Kim Moyes, will take a break from working on their highly-anticipated new album to headline the second annual MMVAF on August 26.
The duo promises a rocking set and a few surprises for the one-off show, which will be one of only a few chances to see the band perform this year.
Q: It's great to have you back on the stage doing live performances. What about the Maroochydore Music and Visual Arts Festival appealed to you?
A: Thanks! We are really looking forward to getting back on stage at MMVAF. It's been a little while since we played the Sunny Coast. Travelling interstate and getting to perform for fans and friends we don't get to see very often, that's a huge part of the appeal in choosing to play a festival like this one in Maroochydore. It will be our first time at this festival but we have heard some really great reports. The line-up looks tight and I am definitely looking forward to checking out some of the visual artists work and the light installations.
Q: It's been nearly five years since the release of Pacifica. Why has it been so long between drinks?
A: Yep it's been a while. We've been working fairly steadily on an album since about 2013. There has been a few other projects that we've been involved in, for instance Timeline - our piece with the Australian Chamber Orchestra. That was a huge task and ate up a fair chunk of time. Other than that I've made a couple of records with some other artists and Julian is always working with artists on songs as a co-writer. After Pacifica, we released a couple of stand-alone singles: Goodbye Future and No Fun. And aside from that, there has been a couple of big changes for us with record labels and management. We are all settled in now and getting geared up for a big 2018.
Q: Will festival-goers get to hear any new music at MMVAF?
A: We are going to try really hard to get something ready in time for the festival but at this stage, I'm not sure. If we can, then definitely. So come check us out on the day to find out for yourself. You might be in for a surprise.
Q: What else can fans expect from your Maroochydore set?
A: Just another dose of highly reliable break-neck party-rocking-acid-laced- pub-techno that you've come to expect from a Presets live set. A typical f***ing good time. No questions asked.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Free tennis is on offer at Mapleton as part of Retro Fantastic
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Moyes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Chamber Orchestra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMVAF</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retro Fantastic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunny Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacifica</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
