<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421840375820761</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/big-top-site-was-a-focal-point-of-business/3207382/</url>
  <title>Big Top site was a focal point of business</title>
  <content>
IN 1978, more than 10 years after the Sunshine Coast adopted its new name, there were no Coles or Woolworths supermarkets in Maroochydore.
Cliff Butt operated a supermarket where the Big Top shopping centre now stands, with an entry off Duporth Ave.
It was a quadrangle set-up and attracted tenants such as Henricks and Moles shoe shop. Mrs Butt had the drapery store, Kevin Burns was our jeweller and Mr Atkins ran the newsagency.
Sadly, these business men and woman who played an integral role in the making of Maroochydore have passed on.
Howard McDonald operated North Coast Plumbing where the M1 building stands today.
One of my fondest memories of Butt's supermarket was my first Easter as manager of Chifley's Hotel. I had under-estimated the amount of Coca-Cola we would sell over the Easter period.
With trepidation, I visited Mr Butt's supermarket to purchase more of the drink.
"How much do you want, young fellow?" he asked.
"Could I have a pallet please, Mr Butt, and how much do I owe you?" I replied.
I was surprised when he advised me to return the stock after Easter and there would be no charge. I never forgot his generosity and he received a bottle of scotch every Christmas.
The Sunshine Coast was changing and the time was ripe for an entrepreneur like Christopher Skase to make his presence felt by buying the entire complex, plus Howard McDonald's North Coast Plumbing premises.
With the erection of four vinyl-covered domes over the quadrangle and the building of a two-storey carpark, the Big Top shopping centre was ready for the next stage of our retail development.
It was a period when people were more relaxed and friendly towards one another and you were served by the business owner who was also a member of your golf or service club.
Cliff Butt, Howard McDonald and Peter Moles were past presidents of Maroochydore Rotary Club; Kevin Burns was a life member and past resident of Horton Park Golf Club; and the Hendricks brothers retain a strong involvement in lawn bowls on the Sunshine Coast today.
Howard McDonald has sadly passed away but his children still are at the helm of North Coast Plumbing.
When I reflect on the business people who have played a pivotal role in the making of the Sunshine Coast, I am proud to have known them.
I'm sure when the history of the Sunshine Coast is written, their names will loom large.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henricks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hendricks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chifley's Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Moles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Rotary Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard McDonald</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cliff Butt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard McDonald's North Coast Plumbing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horton Park Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Coast Plumbing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Butt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Top</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Skase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coca-Cola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duporth Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Atkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Burns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
