<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421857555690188</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-business-has-come-a-long-way/3207373/</url>
  <title>Coast business has come a long way</title>
  <content>
WE'VE come a long way since the mid-1800s, when timber was the first industry operating in what is now known as the Sunshine Coast.
By 1967 - when the area was officially branded as the Sunshine Coast - it had three councils, Noosa Shire Council, Maroochy Shire Council and Landsborough Shire Council anda population of between 30,000 and 36,700 people, and timber had been surpassed by the tourism and agriculture industries.
Buderim Ginger, the Big Pineapple, Bli Bli Castle, Montville Village, Eumundi Markets and North Coast Plumbing (now NCP Bathrooms) and Hall Contracting were just some of the current local businesses starting to appear.
In an amazing growth of 400%, the Sunshine Coast's population increased to between 142,000 and 170,000 by 1992.
Local government was still represented by three councils, however by this time, Landsborough Shire Council had become Caloundra City Council.
Tourism, retail and wholesale, construction and finance and business services were the major regional industries and were fast becoming the main job-generating industries. Dairy, agriculture and forestry and mining experienced a steady decline in total employment.
Fast forward to 2017 - the year of the 50th anniversary of the naming of the Sunshine Coast - and the region's population has doubled in just 25 years, with an estimated population of between 320,000 and 350,000.
The Sunshine Coast region now also has only two councils - Noosa Shire Council and the larger Sunshine Coast Council.
While it's fair to say that much has changed in the past few decades, I think a lot is also still much the same. The Sunshine Coast basks in the glory of its history as a community of many communities: a safe, relaxed, green and family-orientated region.
However, now it is the future that occupies our thoughts.
How does the region protect the richness of its culture and way of life and its natural environment while continuing to grow and evolve as it inevitably must?
Bernard Salt recently referred to the Sunshine Coast as an "accidental city" that has grown like Topsy over the past 50 years. Mr Salt asked us to imagine what the Sunshine Coast could be in the next 20 or so years, and the vision put forward is of a region that will take its position as a modern and globally-connected city, supported by modern infrastructure, modern knowledge and learning industries.
We will be an innovative, inquiring and caring culture that will attract and retain the brightest of minds and a place that offers opportunity and choice for those who live and work here.
There has been much work undertaken over the past decade to lay the foundation for the Sunshine Coast to evolve into such a place. We are already debating key infrastructure requirements; how we future-proof the region by making sure our investment decisions today are relevant to the needs over the next 50 years; how technology will change the way we live, work and play; and what impact driverless cars will have as well as what that will mean in terms of future infrastructure.
As a broader community, I think we are passionate and generally aligned about the need to protect the rich, natural environment; about building a sustainable future; and the need for modern essential infrastructure to support health, education, transport, innovation and creative arts.
Some of this will come at a cost but there are already discussions about how we minimise that cost and impact.
It's crucial we find a way to protect the things that matter, while sustaining a resilient regional economy that allows people to live healthy lives full of opportunity. We need to continue to ask ourselves what legacy we are leaving for future generations. It's a significant, but achievable, challenge.
We're currently engaging in meaningful discussions as a region with good steps taken in working together and listening better, so I envision the next 50 years and beyond will be just as eventful and hopefully just as bright and prosperous.
Sandy Zubrinich is chair of the Sunshine Coast Business Council.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Zubrinich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Pineapple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topsy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eumundi Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall Contracting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montville Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Shire Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Salt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Coast Plumbing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCP Bathrooms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Business Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Ginger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landsborough Shire Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Shire Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernard Salt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
