<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651421861850657544</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-has-a-tradition-of-customer-service/3207371/</url>
  <title>Coast has a tradition of customer service</title>
  <content>
LONG before giant supermarkets came on the scene, men like Cliff Butt and Mannie Comino were the face of retailing on the Sunshine Coast.
"It was a period when people were more relaxed and friendly towards one another and you were served by the business owner who was also a member of your golf or service club," Bill Glasson writes in his tribute to Mr Butt.
The pace of life was slower and the crowds smaller.
Mannie Comino, Cliff Butt and scores of others like them had the time and the inclination to provide customer service - also often with a chat about the issues of the day.
It was the same with the Erbacher brothers out at Diddillibah and Ian Rae behind the counter of his hardware store.
Times weren't always prosperous but they felt friendly.
You could walk down the main street of Nambour and wave to half a dozen shopkeepers whom you knew on a first-name basis. Noosa's Hastings St was still very much like the main street of almost any country town, albeit with a stunning beach as a backdrop.
This book does not pretend to be the "ultimate guide to retail and business on the Sunshine Coast" but, rather, a snapshot of the past 50 years through the eyes of the men and women who lived them.
And the future? Sandy Zubrinic, chair of the Sunshine Coast Business Council, predicts an "innovative, inquiring and caring culture" and a place that offers "opportunity and choice" for those who live and work here.
Cliff Butt and Mannie Comino would be proud.
Firefighters report smoke coming from building and are investigating
Controversial Senator 'amazed' by concerns from elderly
Allegations: Man came into bank armed, demanded money
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannie Comino</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Zubrinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cliff Butt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Glasson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa's Hastings St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Business Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Rae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erbacher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diddillibah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
