<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422540455503664</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/could-a-council-shift-to-cbd-kill-nambour/3208646/</url>
  <title>Could a council shift to CBD kill Nambour?</title>
  <content>
THE expected announcement today of inclusion of a new Sunshine Coast Council headquarters as part of its SunCentral CBD development appears a smart move to drive interest in the $450m project.
The project head John Knaggs has already signalled plans for a major building announcement due to start in 2018 with today's stage-managed event likely to include information about other interest which may help boost confidence in the ambitious project.
The council announced early this year a study into the feasibility of shifting up to 70% of its staff into a new 11,000sq m building in the CBD.
There has been no public release of information about that study since then.
There may be very good arguments in favour of centralising the council's operations in Maroochydore as a catalyst for further commercial interest in the precinct.
They are yet however to be publicly canvassed by the council to allow broader community debate nor detail provided of the potential cost.
The relocation of a large number of well-paid council staff from both Nambour and Caloundra is likely to have a significant impact on their economies. That is particularly so in Nambour which continues to struggle economically since the 2002 closure of the Moreton Mill.
The council yesterday ignored questions about whether that impact had been measured or whether plans were being developed to fill the economic hole its departure will leave. It is to be hoped they are answered today.
Man believed to be unconscious before horror highway smash
House of horrors in Queensland described to jury
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
ROZ White has been inducted into the IGA Hall of Fame.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Knaggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IGA Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roz White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunCentral CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
