<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422360066873452</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/best-performing-townsville-state-school/news-story/ff40fb7a08d8b39f8582327090a29416</url>
  <title>Best performing Townsville state school</title>
  <content>
THE night before the big test, 12-year-old Thomas Smith studied alone before heading to bed early.

The next day he was one of thousands of Townsville students who took part in the National Assessment Program - Literacy and Numeracy standardised test.

Thomas is among the Pimlico State High School cohort which had the highest NAPLAN results among the city's state schools, with an average score of 548.5.

Thomas, 12, said he revised his learnings from throughout the year, confident in his preparations.

"I wanted to make sure I understood it again.

"In the morning I made sure I had a proper breakfast and got to school again."

Thomas said being well slept and fed helped him think clearer.

"I was focused more," he said.

"I felt kind of nervous but I told myself, even though it was a test, I had been working on it throughout the year and wouldn't be surprised by anything in the test."

His fellow student Hannah Cameron was also well prepared.

"I found most of aspects of it all right but some of the maths questions I found confusing," she said.

Students across Australia take the NAPLAN in Years 3, 5, 7 and 9, aimed at determining student outcomes.

"I remembered what it was like last time and the first couple of times I did it I was nervous but now I know what it's like," Hannah said.

"I remembered not to be too nervous, just to relax."

Her advice for students is to listen carefully during classroom lessons.

"Most of the things that are on the test you'll already have done in class. Don't freak out about it, just relax," she said.

Pimlico State High School principal Joel Buchholz said there was a link between what the students learned in class generally and the NAPLAN results.

"Essentially the test is testing students in relation to the Australian curriculum," he said.

"If our teachers are being really strategic and purposeful and targeted in what they're teaching and how they're supporting students through their subjects, then our students are going to be prepared for NAPLAN.

"If they're confident they know what they're being assessed on is what they've been taught and what they're working on in context in class that to us is the best approach."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Buchholz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas, 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pimlico State High School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Assessment Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
