<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422531865568749</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/energy/oil/andy-hall-tagged-as-god-in-oil-markets-to-close-main-hedge-fund-20170803-gxp1sx</url>
  <title>Andy Hall, tagged as 'God' in oil markets, to close main hedge fund</title>
  <content>
by
Nishant Kumar, Javier Blas and Suzy Waite

Andy Hall, the oil trader sometimes known in markets as "God," is closing down his main hedge fund after big losses in the first half of the year, according to people with knowledge of the matter.
The capitulation of one of the best-known figures in the commodities industry comes after muted oil prices wrong-footed traders from Goldman Sachs to BP's in-house trading unit. Hall's flagship Astenbeck Master Commodities Fund II lost almost 30 per cent through June, a separate person with knowledge of the matter said, asking not to be identified because the details are private.
"I'm shocked," said Danilo Onorino, a portfolio manager at Dogma Capital in Lugano, Switzerland. "This is the end of an era. He's one of the top oil traders ever."
Hall shot to fame during the global financial crisis when Citigroup revealed that, in a single year, he pocketed $US100 million trading oil for the US bank. His career stretches back to the 1970s and includes stints at BP and legendary trading house Phibro Energy, where he was chief executive officer.

"Andy Hall is one of the grandees of oil trading," said Jorge Montepeque, a senior vice president of trading at Italian energy major Eni SpA.

A representative of Astenbeck Capital Management LLC declined to comment. The Southport, Connecticut-based company managed $US1.4 billion at the end of last year, according to a Securities and Exchange Commission filing.
Hall is the latest high-profile commodity hedge-fund manager to succumb to the industry's low volatility and lack of trending markets. At least 10 asset managers in natural resources have closed since 2012, including Clive Capital and Centaurus Energy. Goldman Sachs reported its worst-ever result trading commodities in the second quarter.
Oil hedge funds such as Astenbeck wagered earlier this year that production cuts led by Saudi Arabia and Russia would send prices climbing. Yet,  as US shale producers boosted output and Libya and Nigeria recovered from outages caused by domestic disturbances and civil war.
Hall consistently pushed against the bearish tide on oil this year, using investor letters to cast doubt on data showing rising crude supplies and arguing that a sustained rally was on its way.

Then last month he changed tack, telling investors that the global crude market had "materially worsened" and that prices may be stuck around $US50 a barrel or below. Brent crude fell 22 per cent from the start of the year to a low in June, and though it has since rallied, it's still only about $US52.
The fund closure shows "how the world of forecasting the oil market changed after the shale revolution", said Anas Alhajji, an independent analyst and former chief economist at private-equity group NGP Energy Capital Management.
Hall, 66, is also a prodigious collector of art who, with his wife and their foundation, owns more than 5000 pieces by several hundred artists including Andy Warhol and Joseph Beuys. They exhibit some of it at Schloss Derneburg, a 1000-year-old castle in Germany they bought in 2006.
"This is sad news," said Jean-Jacques Duhot, chief investment officer at Arctic Blue Capital, a commodity trading adviser with nearly $US200 million in assets. "Andy Hall has been one of the most respected risk-takers in the energy markets over the past few decades."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citigroup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dogma Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anas Alhajji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LUGANO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phibro Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall, 66</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nishant Kumar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danilo Onorino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schloss Derneburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigeria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Warhol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGP Energy Capital Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzy Waite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean-Jacques Duhot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arctic Blue Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eni SpA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Switzerland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Hall</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connecticut-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jorge Montepeque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astenbeck Master Commodities Fund II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astenbeck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Beuys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javier Blas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clive Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astenbeck Capital Management LLC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exchange Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$52</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centaurus Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
