<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422579110210092</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/lena-dunham-calls-out-american-airlines-employees-for-alleged-transphobic-talk-20170803-gxp236.html</url>
  <title>Lena Dunham calls out American Airlines employees for alleged 'transphobic talk'</title>
  <content>
Transphobia does not fly with Lena Dunham.
Though the Girls creator and star says her flight was delayed at New York's JFK airport on Wednesday, she tweeted the "worst part" of the night was actually overhearing two American Airlines employees allegedly engage in bigoted conversation.Photo: AP
"Not gonna call out the airline who delayed cuz s--- happens BUT I did just overhear 2 @AmericanAir attendants having a transphobic talk [sic.]," the Lenny Letter co-founder tweeted.
"At this moment in history we should be teaching our employees about love and inclusivity @AmericanAir," she continued. "That was [the] worst part of this night."

Replying to her tweet, American Airlines urged Dunham to message the company. "Your comments have us concerned," the airline wrote. "Please meet us in DMs with your record locator and details."
Dunham then shared screenshots of her conversation with the airline, describing the alleged incident. "I heard 2 [sic.] female attendants walking [and] talking about how trans kids are a trend [and that] they'd never accept a trans child and transness is gross.

"I think it reflects badly on uniformed employees of your company to have that kind of dialogue going on," she continued. "What if a trans teen was walking behind them? Awareness starts at home but jobs can set standards of practice."
After finding out the specifics of Dunham's location, the airline expressed their gratitude.
"Thanks for the info, Lena," the airline wrote. "We're passing this along to our team to review."

For those who followed my airport saga yesterday, here's my takeaway: these days it's the little things. A smile. Offering a seat. Respect.

We can't afford to treat each other like cattle when we have a government that does. Being trapped at the airport filled me with love!

USA Today
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Airlines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AmericanAir</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York JFK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA TODAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lena Dunham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DMs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lenny Letter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
