<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422445966221188</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/tyler-wright-sally-fitzgibbons-bow-out-at-us-open-20170803-gxp20n.html</url>
  <title>Tyler Wright, Sally Fitzgibbons bow out at US Open</title>
  <content>
It has been a day to forget for Australia's women at the US Open of Surfing in California.
Reigning world champion Tyler Wright was the first to fall when she lost to Hawaiian Coco Ho in the quarter-finals.

Up Next

War of words that turned cricket's pay war ugly

01:05

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Plays of the Week

Nail-biting finishes, ripping yorkers and hat-trick heroes, these are the plays of the week.

Ho left it late, taking a heat-turning wave with less than two minutes on the clock to record her best result since September.
The 26-year-old, whose opening 7.83 set the tone, said she relished being in the company of surfing's elite.
"They can manufacture scores on very average waves but in the same sense it pushes you, it makes you want to go harder and that's what I tried to do," she said.
"I'm stoked, I want to find my feet on the tour and stop doing the QFs (qualifying) but it's such a tight little nook of girls from like No.7 to 13, everyone's really close. We're only half way through the year and I feel better than ever."
Sally Fitzgibbons then came up against Sage Erickson of the United States. The American's opening 6.67 was enough to see her through to the semi-finals with Fitzgibbons unable to get out of second gear, recording 4.17 and 4.93.
Tatiana Weston-Webb won a tight quarter-final over France's Johanne Defay while the final last-eight match-up between Courtney Conlogue and Pauline Ado remains on hold for the men's action.
AAP 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open of Surfing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzgibbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sage Erickson of the United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtney Conlogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatiana Weston-Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QFs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France's Johanne Defay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler Wright</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Ado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Fitzgibbons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaiian Coco Ho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
