<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422540455503668</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/mornington-police-seniors-community-register-an-victorian-regional-achievement-and-community-award-contender/news-story/26f9450a10a4322f43d40c5f91c700c1</url>
  <title>Safe elderly project up for a state gong</title>
  <content>
A LONG-RUNNING group making the elderly feel safe has been nominated for a regional title.
The Mornington Police Seniors Community Register is in the running to take out a Victorian Regional Achievement and Community Award.
The register was set up by police 20 years ago and is run by volunteers who regularly visit or phone 2500-plus elderly people in Mornington, Mt Eliza and Mt Martha to make sure they are OK.
Co-ordinator Linda Coaker said the idea dated back to 1995, and they had helped over 4250 people since its inception.
"We want to reassure people who may be lonely we are looking out for them," she said.
"We visit them or phone them, keep an eye out for them.
"It is a safety identifier, a help for people who live on their own."
Ms Coaker said she got involved nine years ago after joining the register herself.
"I joined as a member with my husband, and then became a volunteer," she said.
"Helping the elderly is very important to me, it is very important to the community."
The group also has regular get-togethers, day trips and other outings, lunches and events, and runs a newsletter.
Registration forms are available from the Mornington Police Station and the Mornington Community Information and Support Centre.
The Victorian Regional Achievement and Community Awards are designed to encourage, acknowledge and reward the valuable contributions regional and rural individuals, communities and businesses make.
Winners will be announced at a gala dinner on October 13.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Coaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Community Information</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Eliza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Police Seniors Community Register</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LONG-RUNNING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-ordinator Linda Coaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Awards</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Support Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Regional Achievement</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MT MARTHA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
