<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422579110210162</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/darwin-rovers-back-on-field-following-ffa-cup-loss-to-sydney-fc/news-story/cbf913725fb9ed5e91df1f245a758992</url>
  <title>Little time for Rovers to refocus after loss</title>
  <content>
DARWIN Rovers will have to back up for a Norzone Premier League match 48 hours after losing to A-League giants Sydney FC in the FFA Cup.
Football NT boss Bruce Stalder yesterday told Rovers manager Jimmy Culligan tonight's scheduled match with Mindil Aces must go ahead to prevent a potential logjam of rescheduled games in the five weeks leading into the finals.
Stalder has already penned in midweek games right through to the first week of the finals.
"I've told Jimmy the game must go ahead despite his side's heavy schedule with the FFA Cup game,'' Stalder said. "FFA rules recommend games be played 72 hours apart, but in our case we've got no choice.
"Football clubs of all persuasions often find a two-day break much more suitable to four and Mindil is obviously keen to play.''
Culligan said his club would play the match, but he will run a full bench of substitutes in a bid to get through the 90 minutes unscathed.
"We're only a few points off second spot ... so it's a very important game for us,'' he said. "The players were superb against Sydney FC despite the scoreline and I call on them to lift themselves up for one more mighty effort against Mindil.''
The Aces can close to within a point of Rovers with a win tonight, but they have played two more games than their rivals, which will suit their opponents in the run home.
Hellenic's unbeaten run will be tested by an enthusiastic Casuarina side in tomorrow night's game at Darwin Football Stadium.
The Blues' three-pronged forward half of Geoffry Lino, Helio Carvalho and Sulav Maskey should be the catalyst for another win.
Darwin Olympic's bid for a top two berth in the finals should gain some more momentum in tomorrow's twilight game against the Port Darwin Wharfies at DFS.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Football Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helio Carvalho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Stalder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sulav Maskey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Culligan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stalder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Darwin Wharfies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Culligan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mindil Aces</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffry Lino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hellenic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DFS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norzone Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mindil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casuarina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
