<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422325707133901</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/cfmeu-faces-11-more-queensland-lawsuits-after-300k-fine/8772372</url>
  <title>Construction union faces 11 more Queensland lawsuits, after copping $300,000 fine</title>
  <content>
After the construction union was fined $300,000 for unlawfully strikes at Brisbane building sites, the ABC can reveal it is facing another 11 lawsuits in Queensland.
The full Federal Court issued the fine against the Construction, Forestry, Mining and Energy (CFMEU) union over a three-day strike in 2011 at the Lady Cilento Children's hospital and two other projects.
The court found the CFMEU was plainly aware the strike was unlawful and noted the union's "lamentable" history of flouting industrial laws.
"As for the position of the CFMEU itself, the commissioner tendered schedules of prior cases involving the CFMEU that on any view reveal a lamentable, if not disgraceful, record of deliberately flouting industrial laws," Justices Dowsett, Greenwood and Wigney said.
The Communications, Electrical and Plumbing Union was also fined $130,000 over the strike at the children's hospital, the Queensland Institute of Medical Research and Brisbane Convention and Exhibition Centre.
The Australian Building and Construction Commission brought the action and Commissioner Nigel Hadgkiss said there was more to come.
Eleven of 12 matters currently before the courts in Queensland involves the CFMEU for alleged offences including coercion, right of entry and freedom of association.
Mr Hadgkiss said coercion was considered an even more serious offence than unlawful industrial action.
"The ABCC will commit to bring an end to the flagrant disregard for the law," Mr Hadgkiss said.
"Where there is evidence sufficient to bring about proceedings and it's in the public interest we will continue to add to that number of prosecutions."
He said in its ruling yesterday, the Full Court said the CFMEU's record of past transgressions meant there was no reason to afford it any particular leniency.
"The ($300,000) fine is a reflection of the unlawful behaviour in question," Mr Hadgkiss said.
The ABC has contacted the CFMEU for comment.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forestry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Cilento Children</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justices Dowsett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Institute of Medical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hadgkiss</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wigney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exhibition Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Full Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Nigel Hadgkiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plumbing Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Building</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
