<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422321412166533</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4830851/influenza-a-has-hit-the-hunter-hard/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Influenza A has hit the Hunter hard</title>
  <content>
Flu blues: There have been 1200 cases of influenza in the Hunter Region so far this year. No current data was specifically available for man flu, however.

INFLUENZA has hit hard and fast in the Hunter this year, as NSW experiences it worst flu season on record.
In the Hunter New England Health region, there have been about 1200 cases of influenza to date this year.

This time last year, there had been 399.

But Hunter New England Health physician Dr Craig Dalton said while there was a lot of influenza in circulation, it had been a "moderate" season that had landed early.
"If you're looking at flu lab notifications, it looks high, but that's because of more testing," Dr Dalton said.
"Influenza testing has almost doubled over the past few years, so that makes the numbers look very high.
"But our flu tracking data shows there is certainly an early increase. It has come early, it's more than we would normally have in July.

"It has mostly been influenza A, but there is some influenza B around too."
Dr Dalton said the flu vaccine covered both influenza A and B.
"We don't track fatalities here in our unit, but there is no doubt that there are fatalities every year from influenza," he said.

"Anyone in the high risk groups, with underlying medical conditions, should get vaccinated if you haven't already. Please don't visit hospitals or aged care institutions if you have any kind of respiratory infection or cold, and ensure hand washing if you cough or sneeze, because flu can be spread from hands to objects."

Dr Dalton said flu could be deceptive.

"It can have mild and severe forms, so even if you have a mild cold it could still be flu and be fatal in someone else," he said.

Dr Dalton encouraged Hunter residents to join flutracking.net to help track influenza in the region.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter New England Health</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Dalton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Craig Dalton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Region</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
