<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422368656808269</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/04/council-should-remove-tent-city-police</url>
  <title>Council should remove tent city: police</title>
  <content>
NSW's top cop and the minister for social housing will meet with Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore to discuss the growing tent protest in Martin Place.

50 MINS AGO  UPDATED 15 MINS AGO

Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore will sit down with NSW Minister for Social Housing Pru Goward and Police Commissioner Mick Fuller to discuss the growing tent city protest in Martin Place.

Dozens of tents have been erected in the CBD forecourt since December with the number continuing to grow despite attempts by authorities to move people on.

Mr Fuller pointed the finger at the City of Sydney on Thursday, saying it should use its powers to find a solution.

The state's top cop said the problem would persist as long as council provided facilities like mobile showers.

Mr Fuller said police were prepared to help council remove the tents, barbecues and gas bottles from the camp.

But a spokesman for Cr Moore reiterated calls to find a long-term solution and urged the state government to accept a proposal for a development comprising 150 new affordable and social housing units.

Ms Goward told AAP she expects Friday morning's meeting to be "constructive".

Yes, it is true we had to apply for a permit to erect a tent to help those who were homeless in Martin Place, it's ludicrous
- Pru Goward (@PruGoward)

"No-one should have to sleep in a tent in Martin Place and yesterday Family and Community Services were there in Martin Place for the 43rd time, offering services and accommodation," she said.

"We hope that others will join the more than 60 people formerly sleeping rough who are now in permanent housing."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 15 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PruGoward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fuller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Housing Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
