<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422622059884000</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/entertainment/confidential/matty-j-upset-with-the-bitchiness-from-women-as-animal-welfare-agencies-lash-out-after-piglet-challenge/news-story/f78b97c8883a1ed9b89b52de61707d26</url>
  <title>Bachelor nastiness and piglets angers viewers</title>
  <content>
TELEVISION Bachelor Matty J Johnson says he is "disappointed" after watching the first few episodes of the reality dating show. The 30-year-old Sydney marketing exec has been surprised at the level of bitchiness from women vying for his attention.
"I knew there were friendships forming and I knew there were tensions forming between certain people, I just didn't know the ins and outs. That's what I am discovering ... It's always disappointing to see a group of people not getting along," Johnson told Confidential.
"It was tricky at times when you're competing against each other, in a sense, for the same person, but we were able to put that behind us and just get along. But for some reason it's not as simple for the girls, particularly my season. And I don't know why that is?"
This fifth season of The Bachelor has been labelled the most bitchy yet, with some criticising the nastiness seen so far.
"I was always playing pretty close attention to all the people in the house, not only when I was with them one on one but in a group environment as well because I was aware that someone could be on their best behaviour in front of me, but then who they were around others would be their true colours," he said.
"I was aware of how their personalities would unravel ... now that the show has ended I feel like I've got a very accurate reading of people in the house, but at the time I had to give people the benefit of the doubt."
RELATED:

Meanwhile, Channel 10 and production company Warner Bros were yesterday  in a group date challenge on Wednesday night.
Contestants were challenged to chase small piglets around an enclosure, catching them and placing them in a pen in a bid to win a place next to Matty J at a banquet table.
"RSPCA NSW did not approve the use of piglets in the filming of the Bachelor as claimed by Warner Bros," the organisation said in a statement. "We have requested the full unedited footage and Warner Bros are yet to supply it. RSPCA NSW takes any potential breaches of animal welfare very seriously and will be formally investigating this incident further."
RELATED
PETA associate director of campaigns Ashley Fruno was also outraged. "Pinning down piglets to win a date is ridiculous, and hardly romantic," Fruno said.
"Pigs are intelligent, curious, sensitive animals who can recognise their own names, love being scratched and cuddled, and can even learn to play video games. They would be terrified, and not amused, by having yelling, boisterous, fully grown adults chasing, grabbing and falling on top of them. The next time The Bachelor producers wish to include pigs in an episode, we suggest they visit an animal sanctuary and get to know these gentle creatures on their own terms."
Viewers also vented disgust on social media. "Traumatising and frightening innocent piglets, apparently it's entertainment these days. Disgusting," one wrote. Another described producers as "heartless money-hungry monsters".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner Bros</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fruno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor Matty J Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Fruno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
