<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422325707133907</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/crime/record-cocaine-haul-bound-for-australia-seized-in-south-pacific/news-story/221544b30068529b47b044d841f2a21e</url>
  <title>Record cocaine haul bound for Australia seized in South Pacific</title>
  <content>
Officers from the French Navy's frigate Vendemiaire arrested the four crew members during Australia's largest cocaine bust. The South American criminal masterminds behind the smuggling plot dispatched the drugs on-board a yacht named Afalina.

Liz Burke and AAP

Share

A MASSIVE cocaine haul bound for Australia has been intercepted by the French Navy in the South Pacific before hitting our shores.
The record-breaking 1.464 tonnes of the drug was seized near New Caledonia just last week on July 27, after authorities discovered the stash hidden in the hull of a yacht.

What $322 million worth of cocaine looks like. A record haul of the drug seized from a vessel in the South Pacific. Picture: The Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission/AAPSource:AAP
Four crew on board the yacht Afalina were arrested, believed to be Lithuanian and Latvian, the Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission (ACIC) said.
ACIC officials worked closely with French authorities to foil the plot, which is believed to have been organised by a South American crime syndicate.
The agency's executive director of intelligence Colonel Blanch last night congratulated the French teams involved.

The South American criminal masterminds behind the smuggling plot are believed to have dispatched the drugs on-board a yacht named Afalina. Picture: The Australian Criminal Intelligence CommissionSource:Supplied
"Congratulations to the Marine Francaise and Gendarmerie Nationale for their efforts in relation to this record seizure of cocaine," Mr Blanch said in a statement.
"We are thankful for the action taken by French authorities which has stopped a significant amount of drugs reaching the streets of Australia."
The drugs have an estimated street value of $322 million.
The vessel has been towed to Noumea for further investigation and testing.

The haul eclipsed the previous record seizure of Australian-bound cocaine, which was 1.422 tonnes found on a New Zealand yacht earlier this year.

Officers from the French Navy's frigate Vendemiaire arrested the four crew members. Picture: The Australian Criminal Intelligence CommissionSource:Supplied
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACIC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Criminal Intelligence CommissionSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afalina</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lithuanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Caledonia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Navy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonel Blanch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blanch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission/AAPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Pacific</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vendemiaire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Francaise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOUMEA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gendarmerie Nationale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latvian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
