<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422411606482107</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/tattoo-convention-is-all-about-art/3207823/</url>
  <title>Attention tattoo lovers: The ink event of the year is here</title>
  <content>
DAMIEN Wickham was born into the industry of art and tattoos.

Mr Wickham's father was a tattoo artist and Damien was just a toddler when he first showed a talent for drawing.

Now, the internationally acclaimed artist is preparing to host the third annual Ink Tattoo Convention in Marcoola.

Mr Wickham said he decided to start the annual convention after seeing a gap in the industry.

"There are so many people who get tattoos and a lot of young people often complain about having nothing to do on the weekends, so we saw a need," he said.

"When we first started, people were a bit standoffish, but they are a bit more open now.

"There is still (stigma) and I don't think that's ever going to change... Television shows and things like that haven't helped.

"For me it is art though. I'm very into 16th and 17th century style art, and photo realism.

"I would love to see a television show about the art."

The tattoo convention, which has grown every year, will showcase some of the best tattoo artists from the region and around the world, along with a variety of stalls and entertainment.

Appointments will be available each day and tattoo artists are invited to enter the 'tattoo of the show' competition for the best work completed at the convention.

Mr Wickham is certainly an appropriate host of the convention, with an impressive 56 worldwide wins under his belt.

"Apparently I started drawing in lipstick when I was just a toddler, and I won my first major art competition when I was 12," he said.

"That was against adults, and since then I have done heaps.

"I started entering (tattoo) competitions five years ago and have even got to a level now where I have sponsors.

"It is quite rare what I do."

The Ink Attack Tattoo Convention will be held at Surf Air, 923 David Low Way, Marcoola, from August 11-13.

Doors open from 2pm on the Friday and from 10am on Saturday and Sunday.

For more information, find the event on  or visit .

Man believed to be unconscious before horror highway smash
House of horrors in Queensland described to jury
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surf Air</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wickham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcoola</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAMIEN Wickham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Low Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
