<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422321412166417</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/exqantas-boss-home-among-845-auctions-scheduled-for-take-off/news-story/23a3439ca8a8cbe9da64efc331f0b13a</url>
  <title>Ex-Qantas boss' home among 845 auctions scheduled for take off - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, is set to go under the hammer on August 5.

FORMER Qantas chairwoman Margaret Jackson will be hoping to find a buyer for her European-inspired Armadale home when it goes under the hammer this weekend.
Her luxurious four-bedroom house at  is one of 846 homes scheduled for auction across Melbourne this week.
Ms Jackson, who is also formerly Spotless Group chairwoman, and her husband, Roger Donazzan, are offering the three level home on a 699sq m landscaped block at auction on August 5, with price hopes of $4.9-$5.39 million.

Stay warm by the fire in the loungeroom.

Marshall White, Stonnington, selling agent Mark Harris said the couple was selling to downsize after raising their children at the house.
RELATED:

, is going to auction on August 5 with a price guide of $3.3-$3.6 million.

Enjoy views of the bay from the balcony.

Meanwhile, two sports stars are hoping to score buyers when their homes go to auction south of the city on Saturday.
Australian Supercars driver Rick Kelly is selling his resort-style property on Carrum Beach, while former Olympic sprinter and now Melbourne Storm performance coach Adam Basil is sending his renovated 1920s california bungalow under the hammer.
Kelly's beachfront three-bedroom Amanpuri at  has a price guide of $3.3- $3.6 million.
Basil's four-bedroom house at  has a price guide of $1.19-$1.25 million.

, is set to go to auction on August 5 with a price guide of $1.19-$1.25 million.

CoreLogic Victorian director Geoff White said there 846 properties set to go under the hammer this week, about 100 fewer than last week.
Despite the drop in numbers, he believed the market was healthy and the auction volumes would start to lift in the coming weeks, with agents eager to auction before the AFL Grand Final.
"I anticipate numbers will increase in the later part of August and into early September," he said.
Mr White said it had been an interesting winter with clearance rates pushing above what some industry commentators expected.

Adam Basil's home at 15 Bernard St has an outdoor entertainment area with a pizza oven.

Last week, Melbourne recorded a clearance rate of 75.6 per cent from 956 auctions.
"A lot of people forecast that the clearance rates would be lower than what they have been for the first two months of winter," Mr White said.
"It shows an underlying strength and confidence in the property market from buyers and sellers.
"Buyers are obviously not deterred, they are out bidding.
"I'm hearing of many auctions with many bidders and we should have a reasonable run into spring."
Mr White said Melbourne had the busiest suburbs in the country for auction volumes for the fifth week in a row.
"We are at the top of the table for auctions at the moment," he said.
Craigieburn is the busiest with 17 auctions scheduled, followed by Reservoir with 16, Bentleigh East with 15, and Kew and Mill Park with 13 each.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernard St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrum Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark.Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marshall White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European-inspired Armadale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Basil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr White</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanpuri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Grand Finals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Supercars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mill Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigieburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Donazzan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
