<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422579110210090</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/local-afl/nt-thunder-win-away-to-sydney-university-would-go-a-long-way-to-securing-a-home-final-in-darwin/news-story/cc1cc9590dbfb69471300fd5c26bc1b0</url>
  <title>NT Thunder eyeing home final</title>
  <content>
NT THUNDER defender Tom Davies knows a win against Sydney University at Henson Park tomorrow would all but guarantee his team a home final.
The fourth-placed Thunder will then have a bye and an away game against the sixth-placed Aspley to finish its home-and-away NEAFL season. Gold Coast is a win behind the Terrtory outfit in fifth, and after its bye this weekend, the Suns will finish their regular season with tough assignments against Brisbane and Sydney.
The Swans (56 competition points) and the Lions (52 points) have all but wrapped up the top two places, meaning they will have a break in week one of the finals.
The third and fourth teams will host the sixth and fifth-placed sides respectively in week one of the finals in elimination games.
"Knowing that (the chance of hosting an elimination final) will get us up for the challenge," Davies said.
"It would be a big advantage to host a side in the finals in conditions we know well."
But before then, it will be a huge challenge away to Sydney University tomorrow.
That team sits in third spot and inflicted a heavy 68-point defeat on the Thunder in Darwin back in Round 10.
"They moved the footy really well in that game, are a well-drilled side and hit the scoreboard often," Davies said.
After a hot-and-cold 47-point win over Southport last Saturday, Davies knows his team cannot afford a similar performance against a quality University outfit.
The Thunder kicked seven goals to one and then a whopping 10 majors to one in the first and second quarters.
But the Sharks produced a stunning nine goals to one comeback in the third quarter.
The fourth term was split at two goals each.
"We played a really solid first half, and they got us after changing up some things in the third quarter," Davies said. "But we rode it out."
Thunder hitman Michael Coombes (hamstring) is out for the next 1-2 weeks, while captain Shannon Rioli has a knee injury to be assessed.
Jared Erlandson also picked up an elbow injury last week which will be assessed.
Damian Williams is 1-2 weeks off a return.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrtory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Rioli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Erlandson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lions (52</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henson Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aspley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damian Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans (56</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Thunder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Coombes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davies</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunder</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
