<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422403016547353</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/reality-star-who-committed-worst-fashion-faux-pas-of-this-century-responds-to-haters/news-story/f7643d855a9f228ce74cd6bbecaaea84</url>
  <title>Reality star fires back at haters over that dress</title>
  <content>
GEMMA Collins hits back at online trolls that mocked her for wearing a shoulder pad dress, telling her haters she doesn't have to answer to anyone.
The Only Way is Essex star, 37, became the subject of online abuse when she wore the outfit to an ITV party last month - but insists she's still in love with the dress that sparked mass online attention.
In an exclusive interview with , she said: "I am Gemma Collins. I don't have to answer to anyone about my fashion choices.
"I loved that dress - I wanted to express myself that night and I did exactly that. I can take the mick out of myself so whatever anyone has got to say about me I still find it funny. I even loved the memes.
"You will absolutely see more of that in the future. If Celine Dion can rock it then why can't the GC?"
The reality star sent the internet into overdrive when she attended ITV's party wearing the eye-catching dress.

Gemma Collins dress is hands down the worst fashion faux pas of this century 😭😭
Collins also reveals she fancies Freddie Flintoff and would pursue a romance with the cricketer if he wasn't already married.
She mistook her crush for English footballer Peter Crouch when they met at the bash, but says Flintoff approached her for a chat first.
The star added: "I really fancy Freddy Flintoff. He said hello to me at that party. It's a shame he's married because he's gorgeous."
Flintoff was quick to tell his followers about the hilarious moment, posting a snap of Collins clasping a hand over her mouth.
He captioned the image: "No, I'm not Peter Crouch, but lovely to meet you."
This article was originally published on
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celine Dion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freddy Flintoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ITV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gemma Collins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Crouch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freddie Flintoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flintoff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
