<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422579110210096</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/tennis/bernard-tomic-set-to-tumble-out-of-worlds-top-100-rankings-due-to-injury-and-indifference/news-story/42144b1d8aa5bbc164469abe4959b7e5</url>
  <title>Tomic set to tumble out of top 100</title>
  <content>
BERNARD Tomic faces a rankings drop out of the top 100 for the first time since 2014 if he cannot play key US Open warm-up events.
Tomic this week dropped 20 places in the rankings to No. 93 and the ATP said it had no update on when a foot injury would be healed to permit his tournament return.
If he is unable to defend 180 of his remaining 570 ranking points earned in a quarter-final exit at the ATP Canada tournament 12 months ago, Tomic will be ranked about No. 140 by the end of the month.
If Tomic does not arrest his rankings slide in the rest of the year, he would need wildcards for the Brisbane International, which had an entry cut-off of No. 79 last summer, and Australian Open and Tennis Australia would likely be loath to reward him.
The one-time world No. 17's motivation for tennis will be fully challenged by having to qualify for bigger tournaments such as this month's two tier-two, ATP 1000 events in Montreal and Cincinnati.
The only two tournaments he indicated he would be playing in July, at Atlanta and Washington DC, have come and gone without him.
Tomic said last month he was "bored'' by tennis and played it only for money, but said he expected to regain his motivation later this year.
Whether he can do this and excel at ATP 250 tournaments or even smaller Challenger events remains to seen.
The main draw entry cut-off for next week's Montreal tournament is No. 44, emphasising how hard a ranking slide can hit players.
Meanwhile, Sam Stosur still hopes to play one or two tournaments before the US Open starts on August 28.
Stosur resumed hitting this week after resting a right hand injury since the French Open and hopes to play the WTA Cincinnati event from Monday week.
"I am pretty certain she will be OK for the US Open,'' Stosur's manager Paul Kilderry said.
"She is hoping for Cincinnati and New Haven prior to the US Open, but Cincy is not certain.''
@PMalone - CMail
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMalone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATP Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Stosur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Haven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WTA Cincinnati</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cincy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BERNARD Tomic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATP 1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Kilderry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CMail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stosur</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cincinnati</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennis Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATP 250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlanta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomic</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montreal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
