<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422411606482121</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/04/key-points-trump-turnbull-phone-call</url>
  <title>Key points of Trump-Turnbull phone call</title>
  <content>
The key points of the leaked phone conversation between US president Donald Trump and the Australian prime minister Malcolm Turnbull.

Source:

SBS World News, AAP

10 MINS AGO  UPDATED 9 MINS AGO

I'm a businessman too

Turnbull: I believe you and I have similar backgrounds, unusual for politicians, more businessman [sic] but I look forward to working together.

Trump: That is exactly right. We do have similar backgrounds and it seems to be working in this climate - it is a crazy climate.

Australia-US refugee deal

Turnbull: This is a very big issue for us, particularly domestically.

Trump: Somebody told me yesterday that close to 2,000 people are coming who are really probably troublesome. And I am saying, boy that will make us look awfully bad ... geez, that is a big ask.

Extreme vetting

Trump: Suppose I vet them closely and I do not take any?

Turnbull: That is the point I have been trying to make...

Trump: Does anybody know who these people are? Who are they? Where do they come from? Are they going to become the Boston bomber in five years? Or two years? Who are these people?

Turnbull: We know exactly who they are. They have been on Nauru or Manus for over three years and the only reason we cannot let them into Australia is because of our commitment to not allow people to come by boat.

What's with the boats?  

Turnbull: We will take anyone [refugees] that you want us to take. The only people that we do not take are people who come by boat.

Trump: What is the thing with boats? Why do you discriminate against boats?

Turnbull: The problem with the boats is that you are basically outsourcing your immigration program to people-smugglers and also you get thousands of people drowning at sea.

Worse than Putin

Trump: Look, I spoke to Putin, Merkel, Abe of Japan, to France today and this was my most unpleasant call because I will be honest with you. I hate taking these people (refugees). I guarantee you they are bad. That is why they are in prison right now. They are not going to be wonderful people who go on to work for the local milk people.

Man or dope?

Turnbull: Mr President, I think this will make you look like a man who stands by the commitments of the United States.

Trump: Okay, this shows me to be a dope. I am not like this but, if I have to do it, I will do it, but I do not like this at all.

Goodbye

Trump: I have had it. I have been making these calls all day and this is the most unpleasant call all day. Putin was a pleasant call. This is ridiculous.

Turnbull: Do you want to talk about Syria and DPRK?

Trump: This is crazy.

Turnbull: Thank you for your commitment. It is very important to us.

 Trump: It is important to you and it is embarrassing to me. It is an embarrassment to me, but at least I got you off the hook. So you put me back on the hook.

Related Reading

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 9 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suppose I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS World News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPRK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia-US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abe of Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merkel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
