<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422317117199105</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/older-kids-new-tool-in-anti-smoking-message-for-indigenous-youth/8763404</url>
  <title>Indigenous smoking rates: Older kids a new tool to break cycle in Northern Territory</title>
  <content>
In 2014, then seventh grader John sat in a classroom with his mates listening intently to the instructors in front of them.

Key Points:

Program uses 'peer leaders' to tell children that smoking is not good for them
Children from remote communities taking up smoking at an early age
Researchers seeking to break the smoking cycle

The message: smoking is not cool.
A point had been laboured many times before by parents and "old people", but this time the instructors were not teachers, they were fellow students, just a couple of years older than John (not his real name) and his classmates.
"It was pretty effective," John said.
"You're there with your mates ... it was fun."
Smoking a big issue among Indigenous people

The session was part of a feasibility study targeting smoking and asthma at two schools in Darwin with high Indigenous populations.
The burden of respiratory disease among Indigenous Australians is huge, with Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders twice as likely to die from its associated conditions than their non-Indigenous counterparts.
Smoking and asthma are key elements in the sad statistics.
Asthma is more common among Indigenous people and they are at greater risk of dying from asthma than other Australians.
Forty-four per cent of Indigenous Australians aged 15 and older smoke, which is two-and-a-half times the non-Indigenous rate.
Children aged 12 and 13 taking up smoking

John, who enjoys playing footy, said he had never smoked, but lamented that peer pressure made it tough for others his age.
Dr Gabrielle McCallum from Darwin's Menzies School of Health Research said most young people took up smoking aged 15, but in remote communities there were children aged 12 and 13 who were taking up the habit.
"We want to try and reach this age group before peer pressure starts ... and to really create that environment where young people can have the power to say, well, actually, I don't want to smoke," Dr McCallum said.
Dr McCallum hopes that targeting children will help break the smoking cycle before they become adults.
"We really want to target all children, but particularly our young girls where we still have high rates of smoking in pregnancy, in some of our work we've seen between 50 and 60 per cent of our mums still smoking.

"If we can prevent our young girls taking up smoking from the start, their lung health and their future children's lung health will be much better," Dr McCallum said.
Program not just about smoking

As part of the study, older students at a middle school and high school were chosen as peer leaders to undergo a one-day training program based on modules and scripted lessons.
They then gave four lessons over time to fellow students in seventh grade.
"The aim of the program is to create an environment where it's cool not to take up smoking, but also teaching young people about asthma, what to do in an asthma emergency," Dr McCallum said.
"Afterwards it actually built that relationship between the older students at the school and the younger students, so it built these positive relationships, which the teachers also told us was really effective."
Hopes to expand trial internationally

Dr McCallum said the program was shown to be feasible in the Northern Territory and it led to the diagnoses of some children with asthma, and one with another condition called bronchiectasis.
But she said but they still needed to prove it was effective and the best way forward for schools.
There have been two other small randomised control trials in NSW and in Jordan that showed the program helped improved asthma outcomes and reduce the uptake of smoking, Dr McCallum said.
"We have some evidence but there's not enough evidence across different population groups," she said.
Dr McCallum and her team hope to expand the program into a large international trial, encompassing a minimum of 20 schools in NSW, the Northern Territory and in Canada.
"They have very similar rates of asthma and tobacco issues in Canada. So, by doing the project in these two countries, we will be able to strengthen that evidence globally."
The institute will know in October if their funding application with the National Health and Medical Research Council has been approved, but the program would still be subject to government approvals before it could be implemented in schools.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin's Menzies School of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Gabrielle McCallum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medical Research Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr McCallum</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
