<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422793858578644</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832693/double-denyer-on-jeans-for-genes-day/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Jeans for Genes Day ambassadors Grant and Chezzi Denyer | video</title>
  <content>
Double Denyer on Jeans for Genes Day

Bathurst couple Grant and Cheryl 'Chezzi' Denyer have signed on to be Jeans for Genes Day ambassadors this year. Photo: Chris Seabrook

Jeans for Genes Day ambassadors Cheryl 'Chezzi' Denyer, Grant Denyer, Nadia Bartel (fashion and lifestyle blogger), Steve 'Commando' Willis (Biggest Loser trainer), Sophie Falkiner (Sydney Weekender presenter), Libby Trickett (former Australian Olympic swimmer and gold medalist) and Jessica Yates (Fox Sports presenter). Photo: SUPPLIED 080417jeans2

Jeans for Genes Day ambassador Grant Denyer. Photo: SUPPLIED 080417jeans1

Jeans for Genes Day ambassador Cheryl 'Chezzi' Denyer. Photo: SUPPLIED 080417jeans3

exit

DOUBLE denim is back, Grant Denyer says, as he and wife Cheryl 'Chezzi' prepare to be Jeans for Genes Day ambassadors.
The couple were asked, along with a number of other identities, to be the face of the charity on its fundraising day on Friday, August 4.
The national denim fundraiser for the Children's Medical Research Institute (CRMI) helps find treatments and cures for the one in 20 Australian children with birth defects and diseases such as cancer, epilepsy and other genetic conditions.
Each year, 300 children in Australia lose their lives to childhood disease.
While the couple's two daughters Sailor, 6, and Scout, 23 months, are happy and healthy, the duo have seen first-hand when their friends' children have become unwell.

Grant and Cheryl 'Chezzi' Denyer are Jeans for Genes Day ambassadors
"I know a lot of friends who have had premature babies and that was a reason to sign on [as ambassador]," Mrs Denyer said.
"I have a very close girlfriend that watched her daughter die of cancer.

"We've had a really lucky life, both our children are healthy and we want to pay it forward."
Mr Denyer said Jean for Genes Day was an easy fundraiser to support.
- Cheryl 'Chezzi' Denyer
"If you don't know which charity to support, this one it ticks a lot of boxes," he said.
The couple said they put some time into deciding which denim clothing items they would wear on the day t9o promote the fundraiser.
"Everything we have in our wardrobe we'll put on," Mrs Denyer said.
This year, Jeans for Genes is marking its 24th year of supporting CMRI to research treatments and cures to give children the chance to live a long and healthy life.

So far, the iconic fundraiser has raised more than $67 million, and it currently helps to fund ACRF-ProCan, a world-first cancer research initiative that will allow doctors to better diagnose their cancer patients within 24-36 hours and determine the most effective treatment for that individual. 

ProCan uses specialised equipment that will analyse 70,000 cancer samples from all over the world over the next 5-7 years.

To support Jeans for Genes Day, people are encouraged to wear denim clothing and then donate online to register your support at .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Denyer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHRIS SEABROOK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CMRI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Yates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACRF-ProCan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Weekender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Children's Medical Research Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chezzi Denyer</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheryl</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Denyer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Falkiner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genes Day</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chezzi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ProCan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggest Loser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nadia Bartel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUPPLIED 080417</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commando' Willis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libby Trickett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scout, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Denyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
