<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422321412166425</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832504/6-million-boost-for-regional-nsw/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>The NSW Government has a plan to attract more dollars to rural and regional areas</title>
  <content>
John Barilaro. Photo: Katherine Griffiths

The state's conferencing industry will get a major boost today, underpinned by a $6 million announcement.

It's hoped the NSW Government's 'Regional Conferencing Strategy and Action Plan', will drive more business events and visitors to rural and regional NSW.

Deputy Premier John Barilaro and Minister for Tourism and Major Events Adam Marshall will launch the strategy in Tamworth this morning.

They say it will help to secure more conventions, meetings and business events for rural and regional NSW.

Mr Barilaro said the conferencing industry was currently worth $145 million to regional NSW each year.

"Through this Strategy, we want to increase that contribution - by bringing more conferences and visitors to regional NSW, and in turn boost local economies and create more jobs in our regional communities," he said.

Mr Marshall said the business events sector presented a significant growth opportunity for regional destinations.

"From the bush to the coast, we want every conference planner to know that regional NSW can offer delegates both an opportunity to do business and the chance to explore our fantastic tourism offerings," he said.

Already steps have been taken to implement the plan.

Including the establishment of a Regional Conferencing Unit within Destination NSW, which will work closely with industry and the Destination Networks to build capacity and increase the number of business events held in regional NSW.

A website portal has been launched. 'Meet in Regional NSW' will showcase the array of business event venues and destinations in regional NSW.

Trade and business event suppliers will also be able to access a NSW Regional Conferencing Toolkit, which offers tools and tips of the trade. 

While a pilot NSW Regional Conferencing Development Grants Program has also been established, to provide investment on a matched-dollar-for-dollar basis to attract more conventions, meetings and business events in rural and regional NSW. An initial investment of $500,000 has been allocated to the pilot program.

Tamworth MP Kevin Anderson said the New England region would be among those to benefit.

"The Strategy will help attract more visitors to enjoy everything Tamworth has to offer, and will equip local businesses with the tools and resources they need to ensure visitors have the best possible experience while they're here," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamworth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Destination Networks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Events Adam Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Regional Conferencing Toolkit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Conferencing Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamworth MP Kevin Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Action Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Barilaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Premier John Barilaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Regional Conferencing Development Grants Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Barilaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Destination NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Conferencing Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
