<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422750908905124</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/athletics/world-athletics-championships-2017-kurtis-marschalls-mighty-jump-was-no-fluke-20170803-gxp0d8.html</url>
  <title>No fluke this time as Australia calls for a Marschall </title>
  <content>
Kurtis Marschall thought it was a fluke. It was a fluke he was happy with, but a fluke none the less.
He was 19, a pole vaulter and had a bit of promise. Then, out of nowhere, he jumped 5.70 metres. It was high enough to get him on the team for the Olympics. He went to Rio and did OK, but the whole time he had this uneasy feeling of "What am I doing here?".Photo: Daniel Pockett
Doing something once could be a fluke. When you keep doing it it no longer becomes a quirk but the new normal. For Marschall, 5.70 metres is the new normal. 
Twelve months on from Rio and Marschall is regularly clearing the height, and has gone a smidgin higher for his personal best - 5.73.
He is only 20. It is only 12 months ago that he was in Rio but he insists he felt like a kid then and an athlete now.
Part of the change is that he has regularly jumped 5.70. The other difference is he is contending with the world's best in Europe and holding his own. Recently at the Monaco Diamond league meet, he beat the world and Olympic champion and world record-holder Renaud Lavillenie from France. That got a few people thinking about the boy who is coming in a rush ... not least of all Marschall.

"That was pretty unexpected because he is the world record-holder and world-renowned for being one of the consistent guys on the circuit. It's probably not the best year he has jumped but you know anyone's scalp is there to take, I guess, and his was on that day," Marschall said.
"We will see come world champs time if he will come back up to form.
"It was huge for me though, it was a real confidence-booster knowing I am not one of the guys filling the field, not just a participant. I came fourth in the Lausanne Diamond League and sixth in the Monaco Diamond League and jumped higher than heaps of these guys who are so well respected, so it was pretty well up there with one of the best experiences I have had, along with Rio last year.
"I thought jumping 5.70 last year was a fluke to get me into the Rio team but after jumping in Adelaide once and Cairns once and Lausanne and Monaco I am now stringing together a fair few 5.70 vaults."
Stringing together performances is what head coach Craig Hilliard wants, not just the athlete who on rare occasions can pull something out of the hat.
Sprinter Matt Shirvington a while back addressed a group of athletes and touched on this idea that an athlete is defined by the average of their performances not their best effort. Your PB is not who you are, you are what you put out there week in week out.
Marschall is trying to work along a similar line that if you put out good jumps regularly then the really big one will come anyway.
Steve Hooker remains the best pole vaulter Australia has produced - world outdoor and indoor champion, Olympic gold medallist - but Marschall does not peg him against Hooker, he instead tries to compete with Hooker's predecessor Paul Burgess.
"He [Hooker] wasn't an early bloomer like me. He picked up the pole a little bit later and progressed a little bit later. But [Burgess] had all the national records before me, and I equalled his under-18 national record and I beat his under-20 national record so I am sort of comparing myself to him because we are on the same sort of path and he jumped six metres in the end."
That said, he'd like Hooker's career achievements.
And in London next week at the world championships he wants to hit one of those 5.7-metre jumps and get through to the final.
"Whatever happens happens but I can be confident I have jumped 5.70 heaps of times in the past and that is what it is going to take to get into the final. If I do that, then when it comes final time whatever else I have in the tank I put that out there.''
When the Olympics were on in London he was a 15-year-old who had started jumping a year earlier. His best jump then was 4.5.
"And now I am going into the world champs in the same stadium jumping 5.73, it's pretty crazy."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lausanne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Hilliard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall, 5.70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco Diamond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lausanne Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renaud Lavillenie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Shirvington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
