<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422879757926245</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/food/eat/pizza-hut-giving-margherita-fans-free-pizza-in-response-to-dominos-remove-it-from-their-menu/news-story/ef3cc7b32aaecc80d4a7282609ebfb95</url>
  <title>Pizza Hut giving Margherita fans free pizza in response to Dominos remove it from their menu</title>
  <content>
Pizza Hut will giveaway 10,000 free margherita pizzas this weekend in response to Dominos removing the pizza from their menu. Picture: AP Photo/Alan Diaz.

Share

YOU might want to put that diet on hold this weekend - especially if you're a pizza fan.
In response to - rival fast food chain Pizza Hut will be flogging 10,000 freebies all weekend.

Pizza Hut lovers can grab a free Margherita this weekend.Source:Supplied
According to their , Pizza Hut will be handing out free Margherita's to the first 10 customers in to each store around the country from Friday until Sunday. So around 10,000 pizzas across the country will be given away.
There's no real catch with this giveaway - except that you will need to go in store to place your order.
Queues are expected to start from 11am around the country - so if you want to avoid - get in line early.

Earlier this week, Domino's pizza announced they will no longer be selling the Margherita from Monday, because people are no longer buy it.
Speaking to news.com.au, Domino's chief executive Don Meij said the business had to make a call - because they can't keep adding options without taking something away.
"It's like any business, if pizzas don't sell, they get deleted," he said.

Dominos will be removing the Margherita from their menu from Monday. Picture: AP Photo/Charles Krupa.Source:AP
The Margherita, along with a number of other pizzas, will be deleted in every market except Victoria, which has a "different pizza culture", according to Mr Meij.

, who have around 600 stores plotted across the country. Their franchise accounts for almost half of the sector, with Pizza Hut coming in second.

Pizza Hut CEO Lisa Ransom and Collaroy store franchisee Michael Cooper. Picture: Adam Yip/ The Manly Daily.Source:News Corp Australia
Last year, Pizza Hut brought out a significant portion of the troubled Eagle Boys pizza chain after they went into administration, and begun converting some of their stores with Pizza Hut's own branding, boosting their overall store count to more than 320.
Research by IBISWorld predicts revenue growth of 2.3% in the pizza industry from $3.5 billion in 2013-14 to $3.9 billion in 2018-2019.
- with Frank Chung
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Meij</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collaroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP Photo/Alan Diaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margherita</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Daily.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Meij</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle Boys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pizza Hut CEO Lisa Ransom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP Photo/Charles Krupa.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Yip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pizza Hut</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Chung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IBISWorld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
