<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422793858578613</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/afl/afl-mercy-rule-prompts-coach-to-quit/news-story/d4df8a9bec922184c9431e58d60de2bc</url>
  <title>AFL 'mercy rule' prompts coach to quit</title>
  <content>
Dockers ready for Ablett
1:59

AFL: The Freemantle Dockers are looking at this weeks game against the Gold Coast Suns as a learning experience for their young players.

August 3rd 2017
10 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/AFL/

Development is more important than results at junior level.

Share

A JUNIOR football coach says he will never carry the clipboard again after his side was penalised for winning a match by too many points.
Two clubs in Western Australia's Southern Districts Junior Football Association (SDJFA) were not awarded competition points for recent victories because their winning margins were deemed too big. This outraged Albany Eagles coach Russ Clark, whose Under-13 team won a game by 95 points.
Various junior leagues across the country have capped winning margins so losing sides aren't demoralised by poor results. The WA Football Commission (WAFC) introduced a rule in 2008 that put the ceiling of winning margins at 60 points for the Under-12s through to the Under-16s so youngsters wouldn't become disheartened and stop playing football.
Clark says he will never coach again because of the penalty.
"I can assure you I will never coach again, and maybe even from today onwards," he said, . "It's not fun anymore.
"They couldn't get a coach at the start of the year for this side because people don't want to do it."
Clark penned a column for the Albany Advertiser where he clarified what happened in his team's game and why he believes the penalty was too harsh. He said his side went to great lengths to be fair to the opposition and limit its scoring when it became clear it was the dominant outfit.
"The facts are that at quarter-time the score was one behind to zero. In the second quarter our team kicked five goals. One player kicked three of these and he was 'rewarded' by me at half-time by being put to full-back," Clark wrote.

Junior footy is all about development.Source:News Corp Australia
"In an effort to keep our winning margin to a minimum, we played four different ruckmen, four different centre half-backs, four different full-backs, four different centre half-forwards, four different midfield rotations and every other player played forward and back for the day. I moved players who kicked goals to defence but those that replaced them kicked goals too.

"The player voted by the umpires as the best-on-ground after the game spent the third quarter on the bench to get him out of the game, while our second-best was put in the forward pocket. Unfortunately, he then kicked two goals so he was put on the wing to keep him out of the play."
Clark says the penalty of stripping points is unfair to the entire club because his team may miss out on the finals because of it. He also says he and other coaches of stronger sides do their best to achieve close results and is now "at a loss to know how I can further embrace 'the spirit of the game'" after the latest decision.
A junior Mount Barker team also had its points stripped after winning a match by 75 points.
WAFC acting general manager of engagement Troy Kirkham said winning has to be "secondary to the development of the player" while SDJFA president Michael O'Dea was happy with the penalty.
"We as a committee, we had sort of had enough," he said, per the ABC. "It's basically a warning, I suppose, to the coaches to say, 'Just slow down a bit, curb your ways.'"
West Coast Eagles premiership player Peter Wilson last month slammed the "mercy rule", saying tough losses only made him more determined to become a better player.
"I've been in a lot of games where we've been towelled up," Wilson said. "I wasn't happy about it, but has it left any scars because we weren't that good? Absolutely not. Did it teach me to be a bit stronger and try a bit harder? Absolutely."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Football Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ablett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia's Southern Districts Junior Football Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany Advertiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russ Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Kirkham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freemantle Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SDJFA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael O'Dea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clark</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
