<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422879757926252</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/lauryn-eagle-charged-with-driving-with-illicit-drug-in-her-system/news-story/30e35540696623b6eba18a2e9ba651c7</url>
  <title>Glamour boxer charged with drug driving</title>
  <content>
SPORTS star and swimsuit model Lauryn Eagle has reportedly been charged with driving with an illicit drug in her system, despite an emotional denial on television three weeks ago.
The boxing and water skiing champion returned a positive result for methamphetamine during a random drug test in Sydney on July 12.
The 29-year-old was visibly distressed while claiming she was on prescription medication during an interview on the Today show a few days later.
"I have been diagnosed for a couple of years now with narcolepsy, depression, and also ADHD," she said, claiming that the two medications she'd been prescribed had been the cause of the positive drug result.
"I relayed all the information over to them (the police) about my doctor ... I let the police know and they have got all the information. I went back to the station and did another test which needs to be sent to the analytical laboratory."
The former reality TV star added that the situation was "heartbreaking".
"Just the allegations of my name being on illicit drugs, like you can imagine in the industry I'm in, like it is heartbreaking."
But after a second test came back positive, the  reports police have charged Eagle, who is expected to appear in court on September 26.
Eagle's lawyer, Adam Houda, continues to stress his client will be proven innocent.
"My client's position hasn't changed," Houda tweeted. "Her prescription medications have brought about the positive result. The medical evidence will prove it ...
"Police are reviewing the case before the matter comes before the court in September."

Lauryn Eagle says illicit drugs allegations are 'heartbreaking', after she tested positive to driving under the influence of drugs. Courtesy: The TODAY Show/Channel Nine

Lauryn Eagle says illicit drugs allegations are 'heartbreaking'
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Houda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauryn Eagle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADHD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TODAY Show/Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
