<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422634944786143</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:22</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/record-numbers-of-young-aussies-prefer-homecooked-meals-to-moving-out/news-story/68fc1cbd5f7339f49eb22c3d1082e699</url>
  <title>Girls just want to have mum</title>
  <content>
IT was once young blokes who were unable to cut the apron-string connection to mum, but these days that dubious honour is increasingly going to young women.
More women in their late teens and early twenties are now living with their parents than men of the same age.
A snapshot of Aussie families by the annual (HILDA) report found a sharp rise in the number of women aged 18 to 21 living at home, up from 67 per cent in 2001 to 86 per cent in 2015.
For men the figure increased from 75.5 per cent to 81 per cent.
Northern beaches university student Kyla Bolterstenj, who lives with her parents in Beacon Hill, said that most of her girlfriends still lived at home too, and it was the men in her social circle who had moved out.
"I did look at the possibility of moving out but found it was way too expensive with trying to study and only working part-time," the 20-year-old said.
"I'm not ready to leave home," she said, adding her parents "were willing to have me for as long as I need".
Slightly older Australians, aged 22 to 25, are also enjoying living with mum and dad, with numbers for women jumping from 27 per cent to 48 per cent, and the proportion of men of the same age still shacked up at home rising from 43 per cent to 60 per cent.
This is a huge jump from 1979, when just 35 per cent of all Australians aged between 20 and 24 remained living in the family home.
Social trend researcher Rebecca Huntley said a gender gap in salaries of young adults could be a factor.
"Engineers are more likely to be a boy and paid more than nurses," Ms Huntley said.
"The other thing to look at is women from certain ethnic backgrounds where it is expected they will stay home until they are married."
said his research found rising housing costs were a significant factor, along with more young people going to university.
"The decline in full-time employment among young adults may also be making it harder for them to move out, although this is partly a result of growth in university attendance," Prof Wilkins said.
"There is also a broader social trend to doing things later in life - getting married, having children and so on - which may be contributing to the trend."
The HILDA report is a long-running survey of Australia's population by Melbourne University which has followed more than 17,000 people since 2001.
It also found families are spending more on childcare - up 74 per cent since 2002 - while their -incomes have flatlined-.
And Aussies are retiring later - with men aged 60 to 64 now 40 per cent less likely to retire than in 2001.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyla Bolterstenj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beacon Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Huntley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Huntley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
