<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422759498839827</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sunshine-coast-hospital-to-be-stripped-of-training/3208665/</url>
  <title>Sunshine Coast hospital to be stripped of training accreditation</title>
  <content>
THE Sunshine Coast University Hospital will be stripped of its accreditation to train orthopaedic surgeons, after it failed to meet criteria.

An inspection by the Australian Orthopaedic Association revealed the hospital was failing to meet several accreditation criteria including a lack of orthopaedic patients undergoing surgery, the ABC reported.

The association found trainees were not getting enough time in surgery, enough contact with orthopaedic patients or access to study rooms, among other issues.

The hospital will have no trainee orthopaedic surgeons from February 2018.

Association chairman Omar Khorshid told the ABC taking such action against a hospital was rare.

"It's reasonably rare for us to withdraw accreditation, and it's only done where we have significant concerns about the quality of the training," Dr Khorshid said.

"We don't apologise for having reasonably strict criteria because we want to provide a high-quality workforce for the future. It's a wake-up call ... it's a message."

He said he did not believe the problems identified could be solved before 2018.

Acting chief executive Scott Lisle said in a statement that the hospital disagreed with the decision, and would work with the association to address issues and correct any misunderstandings.

"I can reassure the community that there will be absolutely no impact on our ability to provide orthopaedic surgery or any other service at SCUH," Mr Lisle said.

Two Gold Coast men held hostage at Gympie camp
Man believed to be unconscious before horror highway smash
Doctors said Jazmin would be dead before she was three
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omar Khorshid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Khorshid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lisle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Lisle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazmin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Orthopaedic Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
