<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422450261188493</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4832613/police-officer-hit-by-car-prior-to-mayfield-arrest/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Police officer hit by car prior to Mayfield arrest</title>
  <content>
A man has been arrested and charged after a police pursuit which started in Port Stephens on Thursday.
About 9.15am  police attempted to stop a Holden sedan in Medowie.
As police exited their car, one officer was struck by the Holden sedan and suffered minor injuries. The officer attempted to detain the driver but was unsuccessful. 
A police pursuit was initiated but had to be terminated a short time later in nearby Williamtown.
Police again caught up with Holden in Mayfield, where the car had come to a stop due to mechanical issues. The driver fled the scene, while two passengers, a 17-year-old boy and 20-year-old woman, were arrested.
A man, believed to be the driver of the Holden, then entered the cab of a nearby truck and assaulted the driver. Local police assisted by the Police Dog Unit pulled the man from the vehicle and placed him under arrest.
Industrial Drive, Mayfield, was closed for about 15 minutes during the police operation.
All three arrested people were taken to Waratah Police Station. The woman and 17-year-old boy were released without charge.
The 19-year-old man was taken to the Mater Hospital for treatment to minor injuries before returning to the police station.
He was charged with 18 offences surrounding the pursuits and resisting arrest. He has also been charged with eight outstanding warrants.
He has been refused bail and is due to appear before Newcastle Local Court on Friday.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mater Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Dog Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratah Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williamtown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
