<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422450261188568</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-04/outback-queensland-multi-million-dollar-battle-prickly-acacia/8770686</url>
  <title>Queensland's multi-million dollar battle against prickly acacia</title>
  <content>
Hidden in the paddocks of north Queensland, a weed infestation is quickly turning into a problem too big to eradicate.
Prickly acacia is one of Australia's most expensive weeds, and it costs one landholder $140,000 a year to stop it from encroaching on his pastures.
Despite his concerted efforts to try and eradicate it, Julia Creek cattle grazier Robert Hacon said the problem had become worse over the years.
"When we first bought the place in the '90s it was nothing like this," he said.

"It's like a slow growing cancer. You don't know you've got it until it really starts to affect you."

In response, Mr Hacon and two employees have been spending about three months a year bashing through paddocks, spreading herbicide to stop further encroachment.

Robert Hacon and two employees poison prickly acacia trees that grow along water courses.

Robert Hacon and two employees poison prickly acacia trees that grow along water courses.

ABC Rural: Eric Barker

He said the introduction of residual herbicide pellets that stayed in the soil and stopped new plants from growing was a revolution in his fight against prickly acacia.

"Anybody can do it as long as you've got a bit of energy and a peg bag and spoon," he said.

'Cheaper to buy a new place'

About 50 kilometres south of Mr Hacon's property is Garomna Station, which has one of the biggest prickly acacia infestations in north Queensland.
Garomna owner Nigel Simmons said trying to eradicate prickly acacia from his property was not feasible, and the strategy was to stop it from spreading to new areas.
"It's there for life pretty well I think. They've done cost analyses on trying to get rid of it completely when it's that thick, and it's almost cheaper to buy a new place," he said.
"I try and keep it off fence lines and bore drains where it grows well. We just spray them every year for ease of mustering."

Nigel Simmons says it would cost less to buy a new property than to try to eradicate the weed.

Nigel Simmons says it would cost less to buy a new property than to try to eradicate the weed.

ABC Rural: Eric Barker

Although he was fighting an uphill battle at Garomna, Mr Simmons said it was possible to keep the weed out of his other properties in the Julia Creek area and the Gulf of Carpentaria.
"There's opportunity to get rid of it because we don't want it to get like those other places where there's too much of it," he said.
Coordinated approach needed

While several landholders in the area are trying to manage the problem, prickly acacia seeds are easily transported in the movement of cattle and river flows.
Southern Gulf Natural Resource Management project officer Charles Curry has been working with landholders to try and eradicate prickly acacia for the past 15 years.
He said there had been a feasibility study done on eradicating the weed in the early 2000s, but the spread had become worse since then.
"I was told it would cost $160 million to get rid of prickly acacia across our region or across Queensland, but I think that figure is much multiplied," Mr Curry said.

Some landholders are making progress on their prickly acacia infestations, but it will take a combined effort to eradicate the weed.

Some landholders are making progress on their prickly acacia infestations, but it will take a combined effort to eradicate the weed.

ABC Rural: Eric Barker

He said to eradicate the weed from river catchments, it would need to be a focus of all landholders in the catchment.
"Just the spread of the weed has made it virtually impossible for governments to clean it up," he said.
"We'd need a concerted effort by all landholders, local government, state government, Commonwealth government."
Keeping land clear for next generation

Mr Hacon said the real reason he was putting in so much effort to try and beat the spread of prickly acacia was so the land would be viable for his children to run cattle.
He said if landholders kept doing nothing about the spread, there would be nothing for the grandchildren.
"It's just ruining the country and we should not do that," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Curry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garomna Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Hacon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Barker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Rural</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulf of Carpentaria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Simmons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Gulf Natural Resource Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Simmons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garomna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Curry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hacon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
