<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422793858578616</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/excfmeu-boss-dave-hanna-charged-with-destroying-documents-20170803-gxp24i.html</url>
  <title>Ex-CFMEU boss Dave Hanna charged with destroying documents</title>
  <content>
Former CFMEU national president Dave Hanna has been charged with destroying documents that were possibly required by a royal commission.
The 52-year-old was due to front court on Friday, after he was handed a notice to appear for the allegations, dating to April 1-4, 2014.Photo: AAP
Almost two years ago, the Royal Commission into Trade Unions heard the ex-CFMEU boss paid cash to have a truckload of CFMEU documents dumped in landfill, after first trying to burn them at his property.
Royal commissioner Dyson Heydon said former Queensland state secretary
A notice to produce evidence was emailed to the CFMEU at 4.16pm on April 1, 2014, but both men denied seeing it until at least the following day, denying that anything important was thrown out.
Staff at the union's Bowen Hills headquarters were accused of removing a large number of documents, with cameras in the office covered, on the same day.

The royal commission heard "two horse float loads of material" were taken to his property and that  to take it away and dump it later in the week, after first trying to set the documents alight.
"I think because of the nature of what was in the truck and the dockets and all that sort of stuff and, you know, possibly not to have any trace of it," Mr Hanna said, when asked why he deliberately paid cash for what he considered to be mainly insignificant archive files.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The Australian Federal Police confirmed a 52-year-old man had been issued a summons to appear in the Brisbane Magistrates Court on Friday.
"He is expected to be charged with allegedly destroying documents or other things, contrary to section 6K(1) of the Royal Commissions Act 1902 (Cth). Police will allege the documents were, or may have been, required in evidence before a Royal Commission," a spokesman, said in a statement.
Mr Hanna and Mr Ravbar both blamed each other for the alleged destruction.
- With staff reporters and AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ravbar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hanna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissions Act 1902</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-CFMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dyson Heydon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K(1) of the Royal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Hanna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trade Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
