<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422536160536121</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Tech Guide</source>
  <url>http://www.techguide.com.au/news/huawei-watch-2-smartwatch-sim-card-launches-australia/</url>
  <title>Huawei Watch 2 - the smartwatch with it own SIM card - launches in Australia - Tech Guide</title>
  <content>
Related Articles

Huawei has released Australia's first 4G SIM-enabled smartwatch which will be available through the Vodafone network with full functionality independent of a smartphone.

Huawei Watch 2 users will be able to make and receive calls and messages and use apps without a phone in sight.

It will be available from Vodafone on August 16.

The SIM card tray is located on the edge of the watch where the band links to the device.

So now you can head out for a run or enjoy a night out without your phone and still be connected to use apps like Uber and Facebook Messenger.

It is running the Android Wear 2.0 operating system and integrates Google Assistant so it will respond to voice commands and questions.

The Huawei Watch 2 has a classic watch design with a 1.2-inch circular face that's covered in Corning Gorilla Glass. It is also IP68 water and dust resistant.

On the design side, the device is smaller and thinner than the first-generation Huawei Watch.

Also onboard is dual-mic noise reduction so the telephone experience is clear.

The antenna is actually part of the upper watch case to connect to the 4G network.

Other built-in connectivity includes wi-fi and Bluetooth along with GPS and NFC.

Huawei Watch 2 is an ideal training partner and includes sensors to collect data like distance travelled, speed, steps and heart rate.
And with its own SIM card it can also generate a report on your run and advise on recovery time and training effects without having to carry your smartphone with you.

Users can also add music to their workout playing stored tracks or cached tracks on third party music apps.

Android Wear 2.0 also allows users to pair the watch to an iPhone as well as Android smartphones.

The watch can also be used for Android Pay for secure and convenient transactions.

The Huawei Watch 2 will be priced at $599 from Vodafone stores on August 16.

Stay tuned to Tech Guide for a complete review of the Huawei Watch 2.

Related Posts

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Assistant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G SIM-enabled</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android Pay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android Wear 2.0</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huawei Watch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIM</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huawei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Guide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook Messenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IP68</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluetooth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corning Gorilla Glass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huawei Watch 2</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
