<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422969952241324</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/end-the-naplan-blame-game-and-look-for-the-positives-instead-20170803-gxofys.html</url>
  <title>End the NAPLAN blame game and look for the positives instead</title>
  <content>
When I started teaching there was an overwhelming sense of fear within my graduate friends, colleagues, parents and students whenever NAPLAN season came along.
I will never forget investing time preparing for NAPLAN preparation sessions, feeling like I had printed out a forest's worth of sample tests and generally freaking out about the possible judgment that would befall me later in the year.Photo: Cathryn Tremain
Throughout those stressful years, my concept and knowledge of assessment was minimal. I didn't actually know why we assessed kids. The purpose behind assessment was unknown and unclear. Matter of fact, often "the kids" didn't seem to get mentioned that much.
If we don't know the purpose behind our assessment there really is no point progressing.Photo: Glenn Hunt/AAP
Which leads us back to NAPLAN. Usually when people start speaking about NAPLAN, all hell breaks loose. Well, as much as all hell can break loose in a staff room of primary school teachers.
Usually, when it comes to NAPLAN people search for someone or something to blame.

Teachers, parents, students, cohorts, policymakers, state governments, federal governments, unions, class sizes, media beat-ups, principals, school systems and even the kitchen sink (let's be honest, when has it ever helped us improve our mathematical reasoning?).

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Instead of throwing around blame and distraction, we need to get back to the heart of the matter, the moral and social purpose behind education:
Having the knowledge, understanding, skills and values necessary for a productive and rewarding life for citizens in an educated, just and open society.
That purpose is from .
I don't know about you, but that purpose fits quite contentedly with my purpose for getting out of bed to teach every morning.
While our nation's 10-year data of NAPLAN shows small gains, before we move into the usual blame game, there is something you need to know.
In Australia we are incredibly lucky with the teachers we have. But they're unknowingly being held back because we also have teachers who are constantly getting focused on what isn't working, instead of building up knowledge of what is working.
Yes, the gains might have been small over 10 years, but why aren't we talking about what has worked? Why aren't we talking about the five and 10-year trends that show growth?
Why aren't we asking questions about what we can learn from those trends to shape the future we want? Yes, there is room to improve, but here's something you might not realise - there will always be room to improve when it comes to learning (even Einstein battled with this).
If we are serious about providing our future citizens with the necessary knowledge, understanding, skills and values, shouldn't we invest in better understanding what could help them do that? Isn't that a better investment in all of time?
Now isn't the time to simply start targeting the gaps. Now is the time to target our greatest strengths and explore how we can use these within every area of education.
Like we say each and every day in my class - let's use our best strategies to maximise our learning.
It isn't 10 years of loss - it's 10 years of knowledge we can tap into. If we are brave and willing enough to stop naysaying.
Daniel Steele is a primary school educator, advocate and founder of the positive education blog .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathryn Tremain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt/AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Einstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
