<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422927002567381</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/peninsula-food-and-market-businesses-welcome-new-outdoor-smoking-bans/news-story/2402389e8a15957c6e9dfd8249a9b1b4</url>
  <title>Butting out won't bust business, say traders</title>
  <content>
PENINSULA smokers have been forced to butt out around diners after tough new anti-smoking laws came into effect last week.
But food and market businesses say they aren't expecting much of an impact on trade from the changes to the Tobacco Act 1987, which ban smoking in all outdoor dining areas.
The Victoria-wide ban ends smoking on footpath dining areas, courtyards and beer gardens, at food fairs where the main activity is supply and consumption of food and "within 10 metres of a food stall or vendor at an outdoor event" such as farmers markets.
The ban became law on August 1 and will be enforced by councils.
On-the- spot fines may be issued under the ban, with penalties of up to about $1550 for individuals and almost $8000 for companies if the matter ends up in court.
"Inspectors authorised under the Tobacco Act" can issue on-the- spot fines of $155 to individuals or about $310 to venue owners or managers who flout the law.
If the matter is taken to court, a person who smokes in an outdoor area can be fined up to $775.
In the case of venue owners or managers, or a company being charged with an outdoor smoking violation, individuals can be fined up to $1550 and companies $7,750.
Crafts Market Australia (CMA) event organiser, Bridgette Larsen, said she did not expect much of an impact on CMA-run markets, such as at Mornington Racecourse and Red Hill.
"Our events are family-friendly and we don't see smoking in great numbers," Ms Larsen said.
A Portsea Hotel spokeswoman said the impact was minimal.
"People can't smoke in the beer garden any more and we've set up an area for smoking away from where food is served."
Mornington Peninsula Council mayor, Bev Colomb, said: "Smoke-free dining will protect the community from second-hand smoke, and make the Mornington Peninsula's diverse and unique dining culture better for all to enjoy."
BUTT OUT
● Ban applies to e-cigarettes and shisha tobacco;
●Fines are set by the State Government. One penalty unit equates to $155.46;
●On-the- spot fines will be issued by local government employees;
●Smoking is also banned in outdoor drinking areas "unless separated by a wall of at least 2.1m high;
● The ban applies to all restaurants, cafes, takeaway shops and licenced premises.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridgette Larsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bev Colomb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUTT OUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobacco Act 1987</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Larsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobacco Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CMA-run</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portsea Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smoke-free</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Market Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria-wide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Racecourse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
