<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422922707600028</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/stage/be-your-self-review-australian-dance-theatres-exploration-of-the-body-is-timeless-20170802-gxo9m4.html</url>
  <title>Be Your Self review: A timeless exploration of the body </title>
  <content>
DANCE
BE YOUR SELF ★★★Photo: Chris Herzfeld
Australian Dance Theatre
Southbank Theatre
Until August 5​
Bodies are magnificent, frustrating things aren't they? They grow up and old, develop and decay.

Australian Dance Theatre's Be Your Self is unique in its exploration of the human body, searching for meaning and clarity in our physical, emotional, somatic, and systematic selves.
The nine dancers' high energy and sometimes bombastic movement vocabulary varies throughout this full-length work. The most pervasive rhythm sees them shift positions in increments, rather like the sequences in a Muybridge​ film. The sense here is that time is continuing to pass between these snapshots; lifetimes worth of circulation, cellular regeneration and sex taking place.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

There is tight integration of sound, light and movement. Brendan Woithe's​ sound design showcases the thumps of beating hearts, gasps of laboured breaths, and the sizzling of electrical currents.
In response, the dancers bounce on and off the floor like fish out of water, embodying both the electrical currents and their impact on the human body.
Later, as the work becomes increasingly abstract, the performers offer a curated​ presentation of body parts, aligned in unusual ways.
In taking on the breadth of the human experience physically, emotionally and sensorially, director Garry Stewart shows real ambition. At times, however, it is almost as though the work gets lost in its own complexity, and in its desire to encapsulate and explore many interpretations of the "self".
Since it first premiered seven years ago, Be Your Self has toured the world. This is the first time the work has been presented in its entirety in Melbourne.
In its use of projection and the linking of sound and movement, the work feels like a relic of its time. However, it raises interesting questions about who we are, how we function, and what that means - questions that are essentially timeless.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Dance Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Woithe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Dance Theatre's Be Your Self</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southbank Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Herzfeld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muybridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
