<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423051556620949</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/boss/busting-the-boys-club-with-an-algorithm-of-course-20170704-gx4ezb</url>
  <title>This algorithm picks the start-ups that look set for success </title>
  <content>
The four founding partners of venture capital firm   reside in Sydney, Tel Aviv, Beijing and Palo Alto. Their diverse experience and global scope is ramped up with a unique algorithm, Raving Fans, which they claim can predict which businesses will be successful.
Andrey Shirben

It all started with Curt and I meeting up three years ago in Sydney. We were both thinking of setting up a venture fund in Australia. The energy was positive so we thought of joining forces.
I flew to Israel, where I had lived for 20 years. I grew up there, but was born in Russia. Eliav and I had met in the high-tech sector. He deals with consumer behaviour and psychology research and what drives purchase decisions. I was intrigued.

He said he'd been putting together this algorithm that can analyse consumer behaviour and find out the trends, or the products, that drive irrational behaviour. He told me it would make sense to apply it to investments, but it would need a fund. And I said, "Well I am actually building a fund, what would you say about joining us?"

I met Ajoy in Sydney, at an event he was speaking at. He was sharing his experience running large corporate venture arms, at Cognizant, at Odesk [now Upwork]. He was a founder there. His experience and the way he does stuff resonated with me. Eventually I convinced him to join me as well and leave a lucrative corporate job. That was 2015.
We are all equal partners in the fund so all voices are equal in terms of decision-making. Each partner works in his respective vertical: Curt is specialist in lifestyle, gaming, entertainment; Eliav is consumer; and Ajoy is enterprise. I am a little bit of everything and have invested in about 100 companies.
We share information and the deal flow. We generally have one partner who discovers the deal, then he brings in a second partner who is typically the subject matter expert. When these two guys are convinced that it's something good, then they bring it to the rest of the partners for a decision.
Our decision-making is fairly quick. We don't like to muck around too much. We've been investing for 10 months and we have done 15 deals. For us, that is a slow pace; we'll accelerate quite substantially.

We will probably be able to deploy, over the next five years, close to $100 million in Australia. We are now expediting our international fund. It will be at least the same size as the Australian fund, if not a bit bigger.
I have been part of this start-up and investors game for 20 years. I started building my own companies when I was 19; I crashed most of them. When I made a little bit of money, I decided to invest in start-ups. I have interacted with quite a lot of other investors: angels, micro-VC, VCs, private equity etc. I was quite unsatisfied with the experience.
I didn't want to be part of this industry. But many people pointed out that it was a natural progression and it made sense to scale up, so I thought if I am to do it, I will do it my way. There is no other fund I know of that operates truly internationally.
We make the same decision irrespective of the territory, in the same exact way and we are all equal partners. There is no politics, no arm wrestling. It took us quite a long time to raise funds, because the investors said, "How do you operate, you live in four different places, you barely meet?" So we had to prove to them that we can actually pull it off.

The way that the venture capital industry works is it's much more subjective than objective. So it's all about, who do you know, where do you live, where did you study, where did you work? Sometimes it's also about what language you speak and what's the colour of your skin. This is not necessarily because the venture capitalists are racists: it's simply because they don't know any better.
Tier 1 funds receive 10,000-20,000-30,000 unsolicited deals a year which they can't process. Most of them pile up in a big pile that no one touches. If someone doesn't know someone who can introduce them to the right person in the fund and vouch for them, the chances of them raising funds is probably 1 per cent, compared to the person who knows the right people and went to Stanford or Harvard.
As someone who never even graduated from university, I found it quite disturbing that a uni degree matters that much because it's highly theoretical. The new-generation stuff is not really in the books. The economists can't really explain bitcoin and all the cryptocurrencies. But that's one of the things that connects to the Raving Fans principle: we are not here to invest in rational things, we are here to invest in irrational things because people are irrational creatures.
Eliav Alaluf

We believe there are two kinds of customers: the customer that makes an informed and rational decision, who makes sure he does the right thing; the other type is the irrational consumer, who makes the spontaneous decision, the one who is addictive, compulsive.
We believe the second type, the irrational consumer, if you can get enough of them you have a critical mass and you can have a winning product. Once you have enough of those customers, you will have what we call an emotional monopoly over a significant consumer segment and these people will not consider an alternative product.
Behind this rationale is an algorithm: a server running the program searching for patterns in data. The data comes from users' behaviour in a product or service - it could be an app or website. We are looking for abnormalities. One of the greatest insights we had was that the best companies in the world - Google, Facebook, Apple, WhatsApp, Pinterest - draw you to them emotionally, not just with the best product, or the best price.
Typically, they don't have the best offerings. But the value of the company is its connection with its customers. Facebook bought Instagram because it managed to capture those raving fans and they started posting their photos on Instagram and not on Facebook.

Network effect has some bearing, but the point is it's not the network effect; it is an emotional connection between you and a brand. We know when a connection is formed with a brand and when there is a large enough group of raving fans.
The data set is divided into 200 data points. In general, if 20 per cent of your customers are raving fans, that's a very powerful position. The best companies have double that. We call them algorithmic companies.
The difference between algorithmic companies and network effect is that network effect shows how the value of the product increases the more people use it. With an algorithmic company, the more you use the product so it adapts to you. Netflix is such a company; any company that uses a recommendation system and a prediction system is an algorithmic company.
The idea is to give investment managers a tool to filter opportunities. The most important resource of an investment manager is time. Raving fans gives you a tool. It's like a radar system. It doesn't replace the manager, it gives the manager another tool to see further and deeper into something that most people don't really look at.
People doing analytics are asking what is your average daily usage or average monthly usage churn? But we don't think the average is significant because the average between rational and irrational customers is not relevant. What you really want to know is how many irrational customers this company has.
Ajoy Mallik

For the past 14 years I was building and running corporate venture capital, the last one was for Tata, and there were three or four years with Cognizant.
I have the experience of dealing with Fortune 500 clients where the investment thesis is not for returns but for strategic reasons: how do we gain market share or make a bigger footprint in a geography or how do we compete with our competitors' base on innovative offerings?

My thinking became a lot more about what people need rather than what people have. Rather than a typical venture capital model, which is what's your pitch and then worry about who is going to buy it, the thinking became more, are you actually trying or hoping to solve a problem? So you know this problem exists, has somebody told you that they will actually pay you money, for it?
The perspective I bring to the team is the enterprise mindset. I've been in Silicon Valley for a long time, I have been in the deal flow and have my own private investment company. Silicon Valley is a lot of Chinese mafia and the Indian mafia, I mean mafia in a good way: the community. I am plugged into the Valley ecosystem, the Indian ecosystem, and the deal flow point of view. For me investing is 5 per cent of the fun, 95 per cent is helping the company scale and grow in the US market or the European market.
Curt Shi

I migrated to Australia in 2000 but I live in China. My family will be moving here soon, I think. My background is as an investor, entrepreneur, fund manager.
In Australia I had some very good luck in 2013 and 2014. I thought I could do more in these markets but I'd need some like-minded people with good local networking to find more interesting opportunities.
What I'm trying to do is help bring the Chinese network and investors. There are probably some windows for Australian companies to access the Chinese capital market in the coming five to 10 years.
What I like most about Australia is deep technology, very deep. It's very good at one specific vertical of solving expensive problems in a cool way, in a good way, and could be considered one of the best, in terms of solution technology.
A lot of things were invented here: Wi-Fi, ultrasound, the black box flight recorder. One thing Australia lacks is the market. It's too small a population. So from day one entrepreneurs need to think globally. The world is becoming like one village so why not the venture capital industry.

Andrey Shirben, Eliav Alaluf, Ajoy Mallik, Curt Shi and Yifat Shirben spoke to Joanne Gray.
Like Leadership with the Financial Review on . Follow us on . Join the  conversation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>VC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ajoy Mallik</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curt Shi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Well I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raving Fans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eliav Alaluf</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tier 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WhatsApp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yifat Shirben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ajoy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinterest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tel Aviv</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrey Shirben</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Odesk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palo Alto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortune 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eliav</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upwork</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
