<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422965657273940</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/more-news/there-is-hatred-between-the-power-and-crows-according-to-port-adelaide-midfielder-ollie-wines/news-story/ed5bf47e23af7b3df1026f0a2758d71a</url>
  <title>It's probably hatred: Wines</title>
  <content>
Port Adelaide onballer Ollie Wines has used the word hatred to describe the feelings between the Power and Adelaide.
Speaking on Fox Footy show AFL 360, Wines said he did not comprehend the depth of the fierce rivalry when he arrived at Alberton from Victoria. But he said there was probably hatred between the two clubs.
"Once we cross the white line and probably in general seeing them play, you want to do better than them, want to win more games," Wines said.
"There is a lot of animosity between the two clubs. It is something hard to understand unless you are a stakeholder in one of the teams, a supporter, players, support staff.
"Coming over from Victoria you never understand the rivalry and how much it means to either club. You have two opportunities a year to take them on and the boys are hungry, we want to spoil their party."
With the Crows chasing top spot on the ladder and the Power a top four berth, Wines said the game was one of the "bigger ones for a while".
He admitted most people doubted the Power would win, but noted Showdowns historically did not reflect the form of teams and each derby was a 50-50 contest.
Stopping the Crows attacking weapons was the key to a Power victory, according to Wines.
"If Eddie Betts is back, there is Taylor Walker, Richard Douglas is kicking a lot of goals, (Mitch) McGovern on the weekend (against Collingwood), they have a lot of avenues to goal," Wines said.
"That is Adelaide's big weapon, their scoring power. We are coming up against the best team in the comp, they are on top for a reason.
"We have not won a Showdown this year and want to avenge that (round three loss) and try and finalise a top four spot. This is a big opportunity for us."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ollie Wines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
