<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423051556620915</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/brisbane-traffic-evacuations-serious-delays-as-tanker-catches-fire-on-the-m1/news-story/6fd9d357baa27127e293648c21864d71</url>
  <title>Brisbane traffic: Evacuations, serious delays as tanker catches fire on the M1</title>
  <content>
Oil tanker up in flames on M1 in Logan
0:19

An oil tanker carrying a "volatile substance" has burst into flames on the M1 at Loganholme.

August 4th 2017
8 minutes ago

A truck carrying chemicals caught fire on the M1. Picture: Abbey Madde

Jack McKayThe Courier-Mail

Share

AN EMERGENT situation has been declared after a truck carrying a "volatile substance" reportedly burst into flames on the M1 at Loganholme.
Both directions of the motorway remain blocked as fire crews work to extinguish the blaze, which is understood to be under control.

A truck carrying chemicals caught fire on the M1. Picture: Abbey MaddeSource:Supplied
An exclusion zone, which encompasses a 1km radius around the crash site, has been established amid fears the truck was carrying a "volatile substance", which police have since confirmed is hydrochloric acid.
Police have urged motorists to be mindful of delays and have encouraged nearby residents to stay indoors.
Police have declared an emergency situation following a truck fire earlier this morning in Loganholme.
Scientific officers have also been called to the scene.
Emergency services were initially called to the incident about 8.40am when the truck caught fire.

Traffic is backed up in both directions following the truck fire on the M1 in this screengrab taken at 9.50am.Source:Supplied
Beenleigh - Pacific Mwy M1 - Logan River Bridge

Motorists trapped behind the vehicle on the southbound lane should exit via Bryants Rd.

The truck fire on the M1. Picture: Jodie O'BrienSource:The Courier-Mail
A Queensland Ambulance spokesman confirmed a man, who managed to escape the vehicle, has been assessed by paramedics and is uninjured.
"

So this road trip stalled quickly

Police have also asked occupants of nearby businesses to evacuate amid fears the tanker is carrying a "volatile substance".
Motorists should exit at Bryants Rd.
A Queensland Ambulance spokesman has confirmed a man, who managed to escape the vehicle, has been assessed by paramedics and is uninjured.
Scientific officers have also been called in to assess the situation.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbey Madde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beenleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie O'BrienSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Mwy M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryants Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loganholme</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbey MaddeSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan River Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack McKayThe Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
