<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422965657273883</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/my-relationship-with-adam-is-awesome-matt-priddis-insists-theres-no-rift-with-adam-simpson/news-story/dc96d1683217f4310c3ea1c977b844ea</url>
  <title>'My relationship with Adam is awesome'</title>
  <content>
WEST Coast champion Matt Priddis yesterday stressed that there was no rift between he and Adam Simpson as intrigue built over whether he would play against St Kilda on Sunday.
Priddis was named on a seven-man West Coast bench for the clash at Etihad Stadium which will determine the finals hopes of both teams.
The emotion-charged match - the first St Kilda's Nick Riewoldt will play since announcing his retirement this week, and possibly the last game Sam Mitchell plays in front of fans from his days at Hawthorn - will eliminate the Saints from finals reckoning if they lose.
A loss would leave the Eagles alive, but facing an uphill battle to force their way into September, with little prospect of hosting a final.
Priddis shocked WA football last week by announcing he would retire at the end of the season, saying he had been contemplating the move for 10 weeks despite the fact that a one-year contract extension was announced in early June.
Yesterday, speaking on Mix94.5, he stressed that the decision was not part of any clash with Simpson, but did confirm that the decision was a mutual one between he and the club and that it was, in part, about list management.
"It (the decision) is taking everything into consideration," Priddis said.

"My relationship with Adam is awesome. He is a mate.
"It is a really unique situation and I understand how tough it would be for him at times as well.
"One thing I tried to make as clear as I possibly could was, 'let's just be honest mate'.
"That is where we have got to go and it was a mutual decision and I am really comfortable with it.
"It takes into account list management, my form, my role going forward.
"There are plenty of exciting times ahead. Over the next four weeks we have got to enjoy that and hopefully we can play some finals footy."
The bench will be cut by three today.
Priddis, who missed West Coast's 68-point win against Brisbane last Sunday with what was described as a quad strain, is one of four inclusions to the squad along with Chris Masten, Josh Hill and ruckman Nathan Vardy, who missed the Brisbane match with a strained glute.
Defender Tom Barrass (groin) could not be considered.
All four inclusions for the game were named on the bench, as were tagger Mark Hutchings, forward Malcolm Karpany and midfielder Dom Sheed.
Barring injury, Sheed looks a certain starter after impressing against Brisbane, while young midfielder Luke Partington will play again after a 16-disposal debut against the Lions.
The Saints named Riewoldt at centre-half-forward and added Tom Hickey, Koby Stevens and Nathan Wright to their bench.
Jack Lonie's poor form led to his omission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hickey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Masten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Partington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mix94.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Barrass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Lonie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda's Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Hutchings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koby Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Vardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Karpany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
