<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423094506294577</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/rugby/sonny-bill-williams-cleared-to-play-bledisloe-cup-opener-after-surprise-appeal-win/news-story/cfa17706bbbda9f7d8b318db3f678b6b</url>
  <title>Sonny Bill Williams cleared to play Bledisloe Cup opener after surprise appeal win</title>
  <content>
SBW cleared for Bledisloe
0:49

Rugby: Sonny Bill Williams has had his suspension reduced making him available for the Bledisloe Cup.

August 4th 2017
2 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/

Sonny Bill Williams is free to play in the opening Bledisloe match after the panel's 'surprising' decision.

IAIN PAYTEN

Share

WORLD Rugby will look to tighten up their rules about what constitutes a match after Sonny Bill Williams was cleared to serve out his suspension in an 'invented' All Blacks' warm-up game.
SBW will be free to play in the opening Bledisloe Cup game on August 19 after the Kiwis successfully appealed World Rugby's decision to not include the All Blacks' trial against Counties Manukau and Taranaki in his four-match suspension for a shoulder charge in the Lions series.
​Williams was shown a red card for a shoulder charge on Lions wing Anthony Watson in the second test in Wellington last month​.

Sonny Bill Williams is free to play in the opening Bledisloe match after the panel's 'surprising' decision.Source:Getty Images
​​World Rugby ruled an All Blacks trial where they play a half each against Counties Manukau and Taranaki was not a real match and could not be counted, meaning SBW would be suspended for the opening Bledisloe​ in Sydney​.
​The Kiwis appealed and an independent appeals panel ruled the trial did meet the criteria of a "match".
World Rugby were quick to point out their disapproval of the decision.
Sonny Bill Williams decision a shambles. Disciplinary process needs sorting - loopholes and ways around bans sees it lose credibility
Sonny Bill Williams appeal decision smacks of 1 rule for NZ & another for everyone else. World Rugby correct to be unhappy with panel
World Rugby vice-president Agustin Pichot tweeted: "I disagree with the decision of the independent disciplinary commission on SBW.
"Inventing games is not in the code of conduct​. Games counted should be meaningful games."
He later clarified that was his personal opinion and he respected the independent appeals panel's decision, but World Rugby also indicated they would tighten up the rules and shut the loophole.

SBW's sensational red card
1:00

Rugby: Sonny Bill Williams has been awarded a red card for this dangerous shoulder charge in the second game of the Lions test.

July 1st 2017
a month ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/

​"​While World Rugby respects the decision of the independent appeal committee to uphold the appeal by New Zealand's Sonny Bill Williams against the matches that counted towards his four-week suspension, it is surprised by the committee's interpretation of the definition of "match" (which is defined in Regulation 1 as "a game in which two teams compete against each other")​," it said in a statement.​
​"​With the appeal process having been exhausted, World Rugby will refer the interpretation of the regulation to the Regulations Committee when it meets in September to examine the findings in the context of the game's regulations to ensure universal clarity and compliance with the meaning of the regulation moving forward.​"
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taranaki</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regulations Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand's Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBW</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agustin Pichot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAIN PAYTEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regulation 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counties Manukau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Rugby</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
