<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422974247208631</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/rba-economic-forecasts-august-somp-2017-8</url>
  <title>HERE COMES THE RBA'S UPDATED ECONOMIC FORECASTS...</title>
  <content>
The Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) is about to release its quarterly Statement on Monetary Policy (SoMP), a report that will include updated forecasts for Australian inflation, GDP growth and unemployment looking out to December 2019.

As a recap, here are the RBA's forecasts from it May SoMP.

In it's August released three days ago, the RBA provided a few hints as to what changes it may make to its forecasts today.

"Over the next couple of years, the central forecast is for the economy to grow at an annual rate of around 3%," it said, a slight deviation on the view communicated in May, prior to the release of its previous SoMP, that "growth is expected to increase gradually over the next couple of years to a little above 3%".

So that suggests its forecasts for GDP growth over the next couple of years may be trimmed by a quarter-point today.

In relation to inflation, the bank said that it is "expected to pick up gradually as the economy strengthens", something that suggests its underlying inflation forecasts are likely to be much the same.

However, it also said that "an appreciating exchange rate would be expected to result in a slower pick-up in economic activity and inflation than currently forecast".

That suggests that given recent strength in the Australian dollar, there's a risk that its underlying inflation forecasts may be trimmed slightly today.

Whether that occurs or not will likely be determined by the assumptions the RBA applies to its updated forecasts.

Previously it saw the AUD/USD averaging 74 US cents and 64 in trade-weighted terms. It also uses market pricing for interest rates in its forecasts, so these will reflect that markets expect a rate increase to occur in late 2018.

On the final key area for policy focus - labour market conditions - the bank said earlier this week that "the unemployment rate is expected to decline a little over the next couple of years", implying that its forecasts may be lowered fractionally from those issued in May.

The SoMP will be released at 11.30am AEST.

This page will be updated with when the new forecasts hit the screens.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA'S UPDATED ECONOMIC FORECASTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SoMP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May SoMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD/USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
