<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423223355315636</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/get-over-it-home-and-away-legend-defends-sam-frost-20170803-gxooh2.html</url>
  <title>'Get over it': Home and Away legend defends Sam Frost</title>
  <content>
Sam Frost has earned a surprising defender in the controversy over her casting in Home and Away.
Debra Lawrance, who played Pippa Ross on the long running soap from  1990 to 1998, has one thing to say to the Sam Frost haters: get over it.Photo: Ben Timony
The former Bachelorette star  last month after she was cast in Seven's long-running soap opera. Fans and even industry professionals described Frost's upcoming role as a "publicity stunt" and an "insult to trained actors". 
However, Debra Lawrance - who played the iconic Home and Away character Pippa Ross during the 90s - has come to Frost's aid. Photo: Supplied
"They're lucky to have her," she told Fairfax Media. "She's amazing." 
Lawrance described the reality TV star as a "natural performer" and said it was ridiculous for people to slam her lack of formal training. 

"Melissa George had no training, Isla Fisher had no training, Kate Ritchie had no training," she said. "You learn on the job. There's a joke in Hollywood that there's two drama schools in Australia - NIDA and Home and Away. Neighbours is the same."
Lawrance said people need to take a step back and realise there are "plenty" of people on the Home and Away set who will help coach the former Bachelorette star. And having spent time with Frost filming Seven's new reality show Hell's Kitchen, Lawrance said she knows firsthand that the TV and radio personality is a fast learner. Photo: Supplied
"It's this snobbish idea that you have to go to drama school," she said. "It's great if you do, because you can go and do Shakespeare and project to the back of a stage of a 2000-seat theatre - and I revere actors like that, and I guess I might be one of those - but we are entertainers [first and foremost]. It's just show business." 
Lawrance isn't the only former Home and Away star to come out in support of Frost in recent weeks. Pippa's on-screen foster child, Kate Ritchie, used her radio show on Nova to defend the former Bachelorette. 
"There have been a lot of people who have joined that show without any training," she said. "What's everyone meant to do? Turn down opportunities because they're worried about what everyone is going to think of it?" 
Frost isn't due to appear in Home and Away until at least the end of the year. Seven has said she will play a recurring character instead of a guest role. 
- with Lauren Muscat
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debra Lawrance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pippa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nova</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frost</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Ritchie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hell's Kitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Muscat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pippa Ross</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawrance</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Timony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isla Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
