<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423051556620941</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4830482/tarnya-davis-feeling-spent-consider-buying-time/?cs=316</url>
  <title>Tarnya Davis | Feeling spent? Consider buying time</title>
  <content>
I find shopping centres eerie, strange places, but no more than on a Sunday when it's a beautiful day outside. What are all these people doing, wandering from shop to shop, looking to buy happiness, when it would seem it's outside the walls of that artificial world? 
How we choose to pursue happiness is an individual, as well as a broader, cultural trend. Australia's Clive Hamilton talks about our society's misdirected quest for happiness, leading us to search for more and more stuff to buy.

This stuff, in the end, buries us. It sucks away our time in more and more work, shopping and maintenance of the stuff.

It clutters our homes, creating an empty feeling leading us to, you guessed it, buy more stuff. 
I'm as sucked in as the next person on the joys of a new 'thing', but research on the idea of buying happiness suggests that rather than buying things to find happiness, buy yourself some time.  
Ashley Whillans, a social psychologist with Harvard University, collaborated with researchers in British Columbia and the Netherlands to survey more than 6000 respondents in four countries about spending money to save time. They found that the people who outsourced domestic tasks, regardless of how affluent they were, had higher satisfaction with life than those who didn't.  
The researchers gave people $40 and told some to spend it on a time-saver (cleaner, lawn mowing etc.) and others to buy something. Those who saved the time were much happier than those who bought something. Yet, when they also asked people what they would do if given $40, it was rare that someone would choose to spend it on saving their time. 
It seems we aren't good at knowing what might make us happy, and this research suggests that buying time, rather than buying things, might be part of the answer.  

Of course, there is some joy that comes from completing a task yourself, but in a world where we seem to pride ourselves on our busy-ness, buying some rest from this could be a solution to our frenetic pace.   

The risk is that the time we save is filled with more work so we don't even notice it. More next week. 

Tarnya Davis is a clinical and forensic psychologist and principal of NewPsych Psychologists. Her book of columns, All Things Considered, is sold at theherald.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Columbia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarnya Davis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Things Considered</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Whillans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Clive Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NewPsych Psychologists</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
