<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423227650282964</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/sydney-terror-is-link-to-alleged-plot-to-bring-down-plane-with-explosive-chemical-device/news-story/2d3546e7dfe73ba0057c117091892c52</url>
  <title>ISIS link to Sydney 'terror plot'</title>
  <content>
A Sydney-based terror plot to bring down a plane involved a fully functioning IED which had been assembled from components under the instruction of an Islamic State commander, the Australian Federal Police will allege.
The components were allegedly sent via post from Turkey in one package, deputy commissioner Michael Phelan said at a press conference today.
The men are accused of planning a terrorist act between July 16 and July 29 this year, according to a police charge sheet.
Police also allege in court documents that Khaled Khayat, 49, of Lakemba, and Mahmoud Khayat, 32, of Punchbowl, prepared or planned a terrorist act at Lakemba, in Sydney's southwest.

Mr Phelan said police will allege it was one of the most "sophisticated plots" attempted on Australian soil, claiming one of the men is a "senior member of ISIL in Syria".
"This is one of the most sophisticated plots that has ever been attempted on Australian soil," Mr Phelan said.
"We could very well have had a catastrophic event.
"One of the two gentlemen charged, the brother we're alleging is a senior member of ISIL in Syria and he indeed introduced another person, who we call the controller, to one of the people that has been charged.
"He was inspired and directed directly from ISIL in Syria and this advice was coming directly form a senior member of Islamic state."
The AFP will allege the components were assembled here under instruction from that commander and the IED was functional when it was allegedly planted on an unaware relative who was due to take an Etihad flight on July 15, but the attempt was abandoned after the luggage proved too heavy to take aboard the flight.
The man who was to take the IED aboard the flight was unaware of what he was carrying and continued to board his flight.
He has not yet returned to Australia but is not believed to be a part of the alleged plot.
Mr Phelan confirmed that two search warrants were still ongoing.
The men, who are due to face Parramatta Local Court this morning, are charged with two counts of preparing or planning for a terrorist act.
One charge outlines how the pair allegedly planned and act between July 16 and 29 and another charged alleges they planned a terrorist act between April 13 and July 16.
They have been charged over an alleged plot to bomb an Etihad Airways flight out of Sydney.
Both men will face the charges, which carry a maximum penalty of life in jail.
They are two of the four men arrested in raids across Sydney last Saturday.
Their brother-in-law Khaled Merhi remains in detention being questioned by police under specific provisions of the Commonwealth Crimes Act, which police said "recognises that terrorism investigations are inherently complex and that there can be legitimate reasons for extended periods of detention for suspects in such matters".
Mr Merhi, who lives with his parents at Surry Hills, has not been charged. The fourth man, Khaled Merhi's brother Abdul Merhi, 50, was released without charge on Tuesday.
Police confirmed they have been searching six homes across Sydney following the raids on homes in Lakemba, Surry Hills, Wiley Park, Bankstown and two homes in Punchbowl.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bankstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Phelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IED</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 16</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Crimes Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Phelan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Merhi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Khayat, 32, of Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
