<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423008606947489</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/sophisticated-traveller/cruising-antarctica-in-style-aboard-ponants-le-boreal-20170529-gwfhze</url>
  <title>Take an Antarctic adventure with Wi-Fi all the way</title>
  <content>
Skimming across white-capped waves in a black Zodiac, the eight of us are rugged up against the wind, heading for our first shore landing, New Island in the Falklands. It's seven degrees and overcast as we walk across a grassy, treeless field filled with birds - kelp goose and Falkland steamer ducks - to a spectacular  rookery. High on a bleak, blustery ridge above cliffs plunging into the sea, the colony is dotted with hundreds of the squawking birds.
This is the first and, as it turns out almost two weeks later, the least spectacular landing during our 15-day voyage around the Antarctic. But we don't know it then. New Island is the western-most inhabited island of the Falklands and part-owned by a nature trust. There's a small museum and shop run by an English couple, artist and ornithologist Ian Strange and his wife.
"We are British," they say proudly, when asked if they speak French. The Falklands are used to being fought over, after all, having been claimed over the decades by Argentina, Spain, Britain and France.
A couple of hours later, we're back in the Zodiacs heading to Grave Cove, a burial site for 19th-century whalers. It's an impressive entrance: a wide channel bordered by land on both sides. This time we are met by a French couple who own part of the island. Here is another impressive penguin colony, this time , surfing the waves onto the beach. The boiling sea is wild with lethal currents pounding onto the wide, sandy beach and, in the distance, there's a stone promontory named, fabulously, Death Head.

Dan Fairchild Photography

It's only our second day at sea since we sailed out of our cruise starting point of Ushuaia, Tierra del Fuego, at the southern tip of Argentina. We're on what's known as the Austral Loop - comprising the Falkland Islands, South Georgia, the Weddell Sea and on to the Antarctic Peninsula at Brown Bluff and then Deception Island. We'll eventually return via the Drake Passage, the quickest route from Argentina to the Antarctic continent, and one of the roughest sea journeys on the planet.

The French-flagged  carries just under 200 passengers on our trip. She has capacity for 264, plus 140 crew. A number of expedition leaders, including 12 naturalists - biologists, experts on cetaceans, birds, vegetation and geology - are also on board. It's billed as an expedition rather than a tourist jaunt, which explains why we don't stop at the Falklands capital, Stanley.
As with all cruise lines, some fairly adventurous semantics are employed to describe the ship's luxe amenities. Rest assured that the ship is indeed equipped with ample creature comforts, including two restaurants and a retinue of chefs and wait staff, an observation deck with bar and a pool, gym and sauna.
All mod cons

Modern ships are also blessed with a range of sophisticated equipment, allowing the captain and crew to predict weather patterns, winds and the size of the swell with reasonable accuracy.

Nathalie Michel

While they update passengers on what to expect, gazing over the boundless ocean you can't help but be impressed by the efforts of early Antarctic explorers in their wooden ships without any modern aids - no aircon, French wine, satellite television, or Wi-Fi. And it's a sure bet they didn't have a dance troupe of athletic young people called Paris C' Show.
During the HMS Beagle's voyage in 1833, Charles Darwin visited the Falklands for a month, but the 24-year-old was not impressed. "It had an air of desolation" and was "one of the quietest places we have ever been to", he remarked.
During our journey almost two centuries later, we spend slabs of days at sea to cover vast distances. Steaming towards South Georgia, the time is filled with lectures by the naturalists and detailed preparations for the landings. These are rare, fragile environments and great care is taken to ensure we don't take ashore anything that might upset the ecosystem. Boots are disinfected and our outer clothes vacuumed for stray seeds or debris. The naturalists are well-informed, seasoned Antarctic expedition veterans and able to answer just about all of our questions.
The long days at sea are otherwise enlivened by moments of great excitement as pods of whales and dolphins are sighted off the ship. We're accompanied by majestic albatross and petrels scooping in the wind.

Supplied

Smaller ships have the advantage of being able to make several shore landings in a day. It's also possible to stop and change course to observe or follow wildlife. Not the sort of nimble flexibility a larger ship can afford.
By day six, we close in on South Georgia, one of the highlights of any cruise to Antarctica. We make several landings along the coast to see penguin and seal breeding sites: effectively nature's knocking shops, with speed-dating for fur seals.
Like something out of a David Attenborough documentary, there are 60,000 breeding pairs of penguins in the one colony, we are told, and 150,000 in another we visit.
Sobering sight

Patrick Endres / Design Pics

When we sail through King Edward Cove to reach Grytviken, a former major whaling port turned scientific research station, it's our first sighting of civilisation in days. But as the ship anchors, it's death, not life, we spot first in the form of a small cemetery with a neat white fence where the great Antarctic explorer Sir Ernest Shackleton was buried in 1922, following a heart attack aged 47.
Shackleton is remembered in an inscription on a simple stone column in this austere graveyard where numerous Antarctic pioneers are buried.
On shore, the ship's staff has set up a table with whisky shots. Passengers mill around Shackleton's grave as Le Boreal's captain, Etienne Garcia, gives a short, heartfelt speech about the solidarity the sea creates among crew and passengers, and the extraordinary bravery of the early explorers. With that, we toast Shackleton.
Grytviken has a museum displaying photographs by the Australian photographer Frank Hurley (1885-1962), who participated in a number of Antarctic adventures. There's also a shop and, remarkably, a postal service.

Tony Wheeler

From the late 19th century into the early 20th, this was one of the busiest centres for the huge whaling industry in the southern oceans. It made great fortunes, supplying the world with whale-oil-based products, and quickly upscaled into slaughter on an industrial scale that almost wiped out some whale species. Today, all that's left of the industry are some mangled, rusting remnants.
We move on from South Georgia, passing by Gold Harbour, Cooper Island and the entrance to the Drygalski Fiord with its snow-dusted mountains and extraordinary hanging glaciers. Spectacular tabula icebergs (flat on top and massive, some higher than the ship) surround us, glistening in the sun like stuccoed castles at sea.
After two days on the ocean, we arrive at Brown Bluff on the northern part of Antarctica, to set foot for the first time during the cruise on the Antarctic Peninsula. We're directed to the toughest hike yet, across a gravelly hill to the edge of a massive glacier. More penguins. This time a species we haven't seen, , named by the French explorer Jules Dumont d'Urville after his long-suffering wife, Adelie, who had to put up with his protracted absences.
On with the show

It's another blue-sky morning as we sail into Andvord Bay and on to Neko Harbour on day 12. It's filled with floating sea ice and the captain urges all passengers on deck even though it's early. "I hope no one is sleeping in their cabins," he chastises us. "The show is on the outside."
Later that day, we land at the Chilean naval base of Gonzales Videla, claimed in 1948 by the Chilean president as part of the jostling for sovereignty over the Antarctic.
The base is uninhabited at the moment except for a large colony of gentoo penguins. The small buildings look like a toy town and carry amusing names on their sign boards, such as museo (museum) and casa dos botes (boathouse).
Later in Wilhelmina Bay, the captain points out a large shelf of sea ice. It's probably a kilometre wide, stretching from the land, and much more in length.

Frank Hurley Courtesy Scott Polar Research Institute

The area is glaringly white and whisper quiet. Zodiacs are launched from the top of the ship for reconnaissance, to determine whether it's safe to land and walk on the ice shelf. Only a few people at a time are allowed on the ice shelf but everyone who wants to go ashore does so eventually. Le Boreal stays put on the edge of the shelf.
At 6.45am on day 13, we enter the sunken caldera of Deception Island, part of the South Shetland Islands. It's snowing lightly and the black volcanic soils provide dramatic contrast to the landscape of the past few days. Everything here is black and white as we anchor in Telefon Bay and step ashore for our final landing of the cruise.
It's the most arduous hike yet across the beach and snow to the side of a volcano crater high above, which affords a spectacular view of the coast.
Volcano in waiting

This is one of the active volcanoes of the Antarctic, erupting some 10,000 years ago to form the caldera, a cave that subsequently filled with seawater and created the entrance to the bay. It erupted again in the late 1960s, causing extensive damage to nearby scientific research stations, and is regarded as an ongoing threat.
Next, we head along the eastern coast, past Livingston Island, towards the Drake Passage on our way back towards Ushuaia.
The swell picks up in the evening and it's decided to close one of the two main restaurants on the top deck. The crew tie down anything that can move. The ship starts to roll and the captain counsels caution as metal doors are closed on both sides of the ship. The swell picks up to seven metres plus.
In my cabin everything is rolling around. Books slide along tables, the wardrobe doors fly open and shut like a scene from a horror film until they are secured, as the furniture on the balcony moves up and down with the ship. It's like being on a roller coaster, only you can't get off. Not for nothing is it called the Drake Shake.

Lorraine Turci

By early morning, the sea has calmed. At breakfast the captain rates the passage about a five or six out of 10. We make full speed for the safety of the sheltered Beagle Passage towards docking overnight in Ushuaia.
As we sail along the Beagle Channel, with Argentina on one side and Chile on the other, there's one last excited announcement from the bridge. Large pods of dusky dolphins follow the ship on both sides and ride the bow: a fitting farewell from nature.
The writer travelled as a guest of Ponant.
Take me there

The Great Austral Loop (aboard Ponant L'Austral) is a round trip from Ushuaia, from November 20, 2018, to December 5, 2018: 16 days/15 nights is priced from $15,150 a person in a Prestige Stateroom Deck 4 with private balcony. Return charter flights from Buenos Aires/Ushuaia/Buenos Aires and airport-to-ship transfers are included in the price. Contact your travel agency, or Ponant directly on 1300 737 178; reservations.aus@ponant.com;
FLY
Latam/Qantas and Air New Zealand/Aerolineas Argentinas fly from Australia to Buenos Aires. You then fly to Ushuaia in southern Argentina, where you join the ship. Ensure you leave plenty of time to check in as the flights are heavily booked and the airports busy. Australians travelling to Argentina need to pay a $US100 ($130) tourism entry fee (Tasas de turismo). Make the payment online, print the receipt and take it with you. You won't be permitted to leave Australia without it.
BUENOS AIRES BOUNTY

This upbeat city is the perfect stopover to shake off jet lag ahead of the voyage. The pick of the hotels is the , but the , the  and  are also good, with the best locations being Retiro and Recoleta, both walking distance to the city centre and other key sites. Don't miss Recoleta Cemetery and the tomb of Eva Peron, as well as art museums including the modern artspace, MALBA, and Puerto Madera, a former dock that has been revitalised. The  is the reverse of the Sydney Opera House - not so spectacular on the outside but magnificent inside. The renowned Cafe Tortoni in the city centre is also fun, plus there's a Sunday market in San Telmo, on the outskirts of the central business district, that stretches for miles.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air New Zealand/Aerolineas Argentinas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctic</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MALBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gonzales Videla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neko Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Strange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retiro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 5, 2018: 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Fairchild Photography</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chilean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shackleton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cafe Tortoni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jules Dumont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ushuaia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weddell Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ponant</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUENOS AIRES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andvord Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Design Pics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buenos Aires/Ushuaia/Buenos Aires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctic Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French-flagged</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris C' Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilhelmina Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recoleta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recoleta Cemetery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 20, 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etienne Garcia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austral Loop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorraine Turci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUENOS AIRES BOUNTY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beagle Channel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tierra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Telmo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown Bluff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Island</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Georgia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puerto Madera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latam/Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drake Shake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telefon Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grytviken</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falklands</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drygalski Fiord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eva Peron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Wheeler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beagle Passage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Death Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Austral Loop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathalie Michel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drake Passage</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Shetland Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Attenborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TASA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prestige Stateroom Deck 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US100 ($130</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMS Beagle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ponant L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Ernest Shackleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grave Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Hurley Courtesy Scott Polar Research Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falkland Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deception Island</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Edward Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctica</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Endres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Livingston Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Boreal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
