<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422583405177512</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/music/alison-moyet-on-why-she-relishes-being-invisible-20170803-gxob4j.html</url>
  <title>Alison Moyet on why she relishes being 'invisible'</title>
  <content>
 It's been 30 years since veteran British singer Alison Moyet last toured Australia but she's hoping she'll enjoy this visit more than her last trip.
That 1987 tour came on the back of her early success with synth-pop duo Yazoo and 1984's monster-selling solo effort Alf. It was the era that spawned some of her biggest hits, including Love Resurrection, All Cried Out, Invisible and That Ole Devil Called Love.Photo: Steve Gullick
But it was a far from a happy time.
"The time I played there [Australia] before was, in the whole of my career, the least connected time that I felt to live music," she says. "I've been playing live since I was 15. It's probably the forum in which I feel most comfortable and that tour was just a bit horrible. It was a big band. We weren't connecting with one another. It was a bit joyless. I feel that I'm at the top of my game now."
She will be promoting her critically acclaimed ninth solo studio album, Other, released in June.
Cinematic in scale, it's a celebratory, triumphant work from a fruitful partnership with songwriter and producer Guy Sigsworth. But it's an album about observation rather than emotion.

Moyet says as a "middle-aged, invisible woman" she can decipher the world around her without distraction or judgment.
"[It's] a state I really, really love. I f---ing love it," she says.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

At 56, she's far removed from the record company treadmill and the spotlight. Her home is in a suburban street in Brighton, where she lives a relatively normal life having downsized from her country home and all its trappings a few years ago.
With Other, she says, her intention was to make an album that was authentic and purely for its own sake.
"I'm 56, you know. I've got no expectation of having an audience and that actually becomes very, very liberating when you've got no one in your ear telling you what they think you should be doing. You're just working with your own agenda," she says.
"And I think people have responded to [Other] well because it is quality and it is interesting and it's not cliched, and I think that people are starting to finally get that about me.
"I think it took a long time to get people away from the idea that I was this kind of nostalgia act whose narrative was just romantic and even a soft-bodied woman; this assumption that you are then going to be asinine and quite a moderate temperature. They've been disabused of that idea."
She's frustrated by constant references to a "comeback" - her last album, 2013's The Minutes, was hailed by some critics as the best of her career - but she's learned to ignore them.
"It is a tiresome thing that just really does happen with pop musicians. Were I an author of a book, no one would say I was 'coming back', every time I wrote a book. They would just say 'this is your next book'."
There have been many moments out of the spotlight along Moyet's path and she has spoken openly about a long-running battle with agoraphobia. There was also a deal with Sony that went awry in the 1990s that meant she didn't record for the best part of a decade.
"There was a time when I wished I hadn't gone and sold-out to a big record label," she says. "Having said that, had I not made that money, I wouldn't have been able to spend 10 years going, 'No, I'm not going to do that, no, I'm not going to do an '80s revival tour', because I'm a cheap date and I could afford to keep myself. I didn't have to earn a living."
As well as making music she's been studying for a diploma in sculpture.
"I would have done it from school but I had no qualifications to go to college and so I did the next easiest thing which was sing," she says.
Moyet says she doesn't really stand out among her classmates.
"I'm quite low-rent, I'm low-maintenance and, you know, if my hair gets brushed in the week time, that's amazing."
And this new-found "invisibility" is very refreshing.
"I've always been remarkable, and I'm not saying that as a compliment," she says. "People have always had something to say about me. I always stood out like a sore thumb and I don't anymore and I really am enjoying that place.
"I really enjoy the fact that instead of feeling that I've got to close myself in or protect the external me because I was being observed, now I'm in this brilliant place where I can observe. I see what's going on. I can people watch now.
"My ambition is no larger than the fact I want to carry on learning and apply myself. The fact that I've found a way of doing that, the fact that I've finally managed to escape the drain that is celebrity is my greatest achievement."
Alison Moyet is at the Riverside Theatre, Perth, October 4; AEC Theatre, Adelaide, October 6; Margaret Court Arena, Melbourne, October 7; Enmore Theatre, Sydney, October 9; and Convention Centre, Brisbane, October 10. See .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Cried Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverside Theatres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Convention Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Love Resurrection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moyet</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEC Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enmore Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Gullick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yazoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ole Devil Called Love.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Sigsworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison Moyet</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Court Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
