<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422974247208649</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/terror-1100ft-dubai-high-rise-tower-engulfed-flame/3208694/</url>
  <title>Terror at 1100ft: Flames engulf Dubai's 'Torch Tower'</title>
  <content>
ONE of the world's tallest residential buildings is engulfed in flames in Dubai.

Firefighters are battling to bring under control the major blaze at the 86-storey Torch Tower in the United Arab Emirates holiday hotspot.

Shocked onlookers have shared harrowing videos on social media of the fire, which quickly spread up one side of the structure.

Burning debris is raining down on the streets below, sparking small spot fires, according to reports.

It marks the second fire at the skyscraper in the world-famous Marina district, with an eerily similar incident two years ago.

A fire swept through the same building in February 2015 and its flammable cladding was blamed for the rapid spread of the flames - a chilling similarity to the Grenfell fire tragedy in London.

Twitter image showing a massive fire a Dubai skyscraper.Source:Twitter

Cara Spillane tweeted: "Terrifying to see Torch Tower, in the area I live in (Dubai Marina) on fire now. Hope everyone gets out OK."

Claire Hopkin added: "One of the skyscrapers near me is on FIRE! God! Hope everyone can get out. Scary seeing it!"

A man at the scene, John O'Nolan, said on Twitter that at least 15 floors appeared to be well alight.

The cause of the fire and the current state of evacuation is not yet known.

During the fire in 2015, there were no fatalities and seven people were treated smoke inhalation.

Dubai's glittering skyline has seen a number of similar fires in recent years.

More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torch Tower</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grenfell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Arab Emirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara Spillane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John O'Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Hopkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
