<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422488915895069</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/07/31/australia-needs-missile-defence-shield</url>
  <title>Australia needs to plan for a missile defence shield to protect country from China and North Korea: security experts</title>
  <content>
Australia must begin planning for a missile defence shield to counter China's expanding missile arsenal, a former nation security adviser has warned.
Andrew Shearer, who advised prime ministers John Howard and Tony Abbot, told  China's growing intercontinental ballistic missile footprint potentially poses a greater long-term menace to defence bases in northern Australia than North Korea.
Shearer - who is now a Washington-based adviser on Asia-Pacific security for the US Centre for Strategic and International Studies - said the government needs to begin planning for continental missile defence.
A former defence strategist for George W. Bush's administration and now chief executive of the US Centre for Strategic and Budgetary -Assessments joined Shearer's call that Australia should be planning for a longer-term continental missile shield for Australia.
In an article the pair wrote in The Australian today, they argue:
"Highly accurate cruise missiles and hypersonic anti-ship -missiles are proliferating in the -region and pose an increasing menace to deployed forces, such as Australia's large amphibious ships.
"Australian military planners (also) need to grapple with the -incipient threat posed to the mainland - particularly to defence -facilities in northern Australia used by the ADF and rotating US forces - by China's increasingly large and sophisticated long-range nuclear and conventional missile force."

Related Articles

The pair cite the Pentagon's most recent report to congress on China's military power which found that Beijing already possessed 75 to 100 ICBMs, many with the range to strike northern Australia.
The comments follow former prime minister Kevin Rudd breaking with Labor party policy last month to suggest the North Korean threat -warranted Australia planning for ballistic missile defence program.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull said the short-term priority was missile -defence for force deployment but did not rule out mainland defence. 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shearer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pentagon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George W. Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Shearer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Center</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Studies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
