<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423008606947472</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/saint-laurents-new-rollerskate-high-heels-are-the-item-we-never-knew-we-needed-20170803-gxp3e4.html</url>
  <title>Saint Laurent's new rollerskate high heels are the item we never knew we needed</title>
  <content>
Photo: Saint Laurent
Just when you thought you couldn't read one more article about why every woman needs to own another pair of black pointed toe pumps (an investment! They go with everything! All very true and all but zzz) along comes Saint Laurent with the most gloriously impractical pair of heels. Perhaps of all time.
They're rollerskates, but also high heels and they are so deliciously, fabulously OTT (not to mention kind of dangerous) they're enough to make any minimalist want to break free from their camel coat confines and go to a roller disco in sequins and hot pants.
Besides, who among us hasn't envied those kids with the sneakers with an in-built wheel (note, the heels also come in a more gravity friendly sneaker version too).
The Anja 100 Patch Pop Pump Roller stilettos are part of Saint Laurent's autumn winter collection and as Harper's Bazaar , they have an element of Roy Lichtenstein pop art to them with graphic prints spliced with a touch of animal and snakeskin (of course).
Priced from around $3300 you're probably not likely to get the cost-per-wear down (but then again, what doesn't go with a pair of bedazzling rollerskates, they'd enliven any ensemble!).
Plus you get the added bonus of an element of risk every time you wear them.

Then there's the life possibilities that a pair of shoes like this would create - i.e. imagine the first impression you'd made should you wear them to, say, a job interview? Or a Tinder date?
You'd be unforgettable. Therefore, these shoes/wheels are priceless. 
You just might want to work on your stopping ability first (though you could also crash tackle into a gorgeous stranger on the train which could end up being the best  meet-cute of all time?).
Can the same be said about today's other internet discovery, thanks to Jezebel, that is, - a towel created for women with breasts of a certain heft to wear while they're getting ready for a hot date to stop sweat building in certain crevices?
Obviously!
What a time it is to be a woman.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint Laurent</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OTT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Lichtenstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper's Bazaar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anja 100 Patch Pop Pump Roller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jezebel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
