<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422965657273888</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/mornington-peninsula-mayor-bev-colomb-takes-part-in-sleep-in-your-car-to-raise-money-for-fusion-to-help-homeless-youth/news-story/176af5645171c559b0294f1b858a378f</url>
  <title>Mayor to spend chilly night in car for good cause</title>
  <content>
MORNINGTON Peninsula mayor, Bev Colomb, is going to get a taste of homelessness last Saturday night.
Cr Colomb will leave her warm bed behind her and sleep in her car at Mornington Park to experience temporary homelessness and raise money for Fusion, a nationwide, Christian, youth and community organisation focused on housing at-risk youth.
Around 80 others will join her for the 'sleep in your car' event, run by Fusion for Homelessness Week.
They will be sponsored to rest in vehicles or 'sleep rough' in the park overnight. Fusion aims to raise $30,000 through the event.
Cr Colomb said: "I've always felt so lucky to have a home. There are so many hardships related to homelessness and we need to do what we can, wherever we can."
Fusion housing co-ordinator, Stuart Bell, said an estimated 2000 youth and other people were considered homeless on the Mornington Peninsula, with the problem exacerbated by a very tight rental market.
"With the closure of caravan parks across the peninsula, what has traditionally been an affordable and accessible form of accommodation is largely no longer available," Mr Bell said.
"Young people, often on very low incomes, may find successfully accessing a tenancy extremely difficult, if not impossible.
"Some may be lucky enough to get emergency housing.
"Others may end up in a boarding home, which are often exploitative and sometimes even unsafe places to live."
The sleep in your car event will also feature Mornington Peninsula Council's youth services team, information about local services and support systems, art and music.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bev Colomb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Colomb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homelessness Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
