<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422841103219704</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/teams/bulldogs/greg-alexander-says-bulldogs-must-call-time-on-des-hasler-as-coach/news-story/e5e2a66ab3bfbaab230f5a1796678ba4</url>
  <title>'They need someone new in there'</title>
  <content>
MATCH REPORT:
OOPS:

FORMER Dally M Medal winner Greg Alexander says it is time for the Bulldogs to move coach Des Hasler on and find someone new.
Alexander, who played more than 230 matches for the Penrith Panthers, made the call this morning following another dismal performance by Hasler's men last night.
The  to register their fifth loss in six outings.
The opening try to the Eels spoke volumes of the Bulldogs desire and form when Daniel Alvaro forced his way through the entire Canterbury front row of James Graham, Aiden Tolman and Moses Mbye to score.
Alexander said each woeful performance added weight to arguments it was time for Hasler to leave Belmore.
"They've got no idea and they're going out there trying not to lose rather than trying to win," Alexander told Sky Sports Radio's The Big Sports Breakfast.
"I think the way things are going you need a change.
"He's a great coach (but) he's been in the same place for too long with the same players.
"You would just think they need someone new in there."
The Bulldogs board and club chairman Ray Dib are under increasing pressure over the Hasler situation considering they extended his contract to the end of the 2019 season in April.
Hasler's tenure with the Bulldogs could have been over at the end of the 2017 season but now the club will be forced to pay him out if they want to show him the door.
The Bulldogs sit 13th on the NRL ladder following last night's loss, having managed just seven wins this year and 13 losses.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aiden Tolman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Des Hasler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasler</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith Panthers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Dib</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moses Mbye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dally M Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Alvaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Sports Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
