<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423146045903145</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-04/star-tiger-doesnt-find-what-hes-looking-for</url>
  <title>Star Tiger doesn't find what he's looking for</title>
  <content>
Damien Hardwick says Jack Riewoldt should return next week against Geelong

STAR Richmond forward Jack Riewoldt sought a third opinion on his injured right eye in an unsuccessful bid to be declared fit for Sunday afternoon's clash with Hawthorn at the MCG.

Riewoldt, 28, missed last week's win against Gold Coast after he suffered a knock to the eye and needed stitches to the white part and top of an eyeball at training.

He didn't have vision in that eye for six hours because of blood in the socket, and Tigers coach Damien Hardwick said at Punt Road on Friday morning that Riewoldt should be available for Saturday week's game against Geelong.

"He was pretty close. A couple more days and some training and he might have been available to play," Hardwick said.

"It's a pretty delicate area of the body that we're really wanting to make sure we look after.

"Not only went to one doctor, he went to two, then he was looking for a third to try and get the response he was after.

"That's how desperate he was to play. He's an important player for us, so we didn't want to risk any further damage. Should be available to play next week."

More to come.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Hardwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Tiger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STAR Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punt Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
