<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423137455968413</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/neymar-to-psg-making-sense-of-transfer-that-will-change-football/8773550</url>
  <title>Neymar to PSG: Making sense of the transfer that will change football</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

The biggest and most expensive transfer in history, twice as much as the next closest, and now the great hope of one of Europe's largest and wealthiest clubs -
And in pushing for the move, Neymar has accepted and welcomed the responsibility. Pressure is nothing new to him though, it comes as a given at Barcelona and especially as Brazil's main man.
It's a transfer that will change football, thanks both to the ground-breaking fee and the shifting of such a quality player from one European giant to another.
But though the paperwork has been filed and the money exchanged, the shape of the football world moving forward is unclear. What exactly has happened here, and what will happen next?
Why did Neymar want to leave Barcelona?

His true motivations will only be known to Neymar, but it is widely believed that the 25-year-old saw this as more than just an opportunity for a pay rise.
At Barcelona, though beloved by the fans and a crucial part of the team, he could only ever have hoped to be number two or three at the club - the shadow of Lionel Messi is all-encompassing, and not even Neymar could hope to move out of it.

A player approaching the very peak of his powers, it makes sense that Neymar would want to be the number one at his club, and have the team built to play around him. He would never get that luxury at Barcelona.
At PSG, Neymar could have the freedom to become the best player in the world. Paris will be his city and PSG his team.
Why were PSG prepared to pay such a ridiculous fee?

Because Neymar is an exceptional footballer, who is still improving and whose best we probably haven't seen yet.
Even at Barcelona, where he played second fiddle to Messi and had to spend a lot of his time grafting for both the Argentinian and Luis Suarez, he became the third-best player in the world behind two of the greatest of all time.

He is a complete player. Quick and skilful, as good technically as anyone and willing to put a shift in defensively - though he will probably be hoping he will have someone to do the dirty work for him now he's the main man.
PSG has long been trying to establish itself as the biggest club in Europe, but despite years of extreme spending and some very good teams, Champions League glory has been beyond the Les Parisiens.
This is an ambitious and aggressive attempt to change that. If successful, the transfer fee will be chump change for the club.
Will it work?

Any transfer is a risk. As the old cliche goes, he could go and get injured in his first training session in Paris. But injury aside, it's difficult to see Neymar not scoring more than the 13 goals he scored for Barca last season.
He will be allowed the sort of freedom he gets when playing for Brazil, where he has played some of his most thrilling football, and it's fair to expect Neymar will enjoy a better season individually

But what about PSG? Well, they'll probably walk to the Ligue 1 title as they usually do, but the Champions League is the real prize.
Ironically it was largely Neymar's brilliance that saw Barcelona overturn a 4-0 deficit to knock PSG out of the competition in the round of 16 last season, and PSG will be relying on similar performances in the coming campaign.

But expectations will be sky high. Anything short of an appearance in the final will likely be considered a failure for Neymar and PSG.
What next for Barcelona?

The Spanish giants are loaded with cash and could just about attract any player in the world. So what do they do?
They could stay at home and look to bring through young players like Paolo Alcacer or the recently-returned Gerard Deulofeu, but that seems like way too much of a risk for a club expected to win trophies every season.

It seems Liverpool's Philippe Coutinho is top of the wish list, but the Premier League club won't give him up easily. Rumours of a move for Borussia Dortmund's Ousmane Dembele have also surfaced, and the youngster wouldn't come cheap either.
Regardless of where they decide to throw the cash, the chain reaction has now begun. Players will be moving, the fees will be gigantic and this crazy new era of the game will continue apace.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Deulofeu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borussia Dortmund's Ousmane Dembele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentinian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paolo Alcacer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Parisiens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Suarez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool's Philippe Coutinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ligue 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
