<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423270599956625</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/south-west-beaches/a-historic-home-which-apparently-claims-adelaidess-first-bathroom-was-sas-top-seller-of-last-week/news-story/61f7590fbac6b108dee3bcec89463051</url>
  <title>A historic home which apparently claims Adelaide's's first bathroom, was SA's top seller of last week. - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
32 High St Glenelg is said to have SA's first indoor bathroom. The house sold for $1.4 million.

A CHARACTER federation villa believed to contain Adelaide's first indoor bathroom, fetched the highest sale price in South Australia last week.
According to CoreLogic data, the four-bedroom, two-bathroom home at 32 High St Glenelg sold for $1.4 million, exceeding the suburb's median house price by $567,500.

32 High Street, Glenelg

Sold by Kathryn McCann Real Estate, the property was described as a `unique and rare opportunity'.
"The home still has most of the original features and also has some historic significance in that it is claimed the villa is home to South Australia's first home built with an indoor bathroom," Ms McCann said.
While it has been updated over the years, the bathroom still has a heritage feel with a high ceiling and chequered floor tiles.
Other heritage features of the home include grand entrance, high ceilings, open fireplaces, stained-glass windows, tessellated tiles and a cellar. The floorplan also included a study/maid's room close to the laundry and kitchen.

32 High Street, Glenelg

"The property sold by registration of interest," said listing agent Kathryn McCann.
"We had three open homes which were all well attended and we had multiple offers.
"All I can say about the buyers is that they made the highest offer."
Ms McCann said the home's character features, history, location and large block size were what attracted buyers.

32 High Street, Glenelg

The second highest sale of last week in South Australia was 4 Dashwood Rd Beaumont which sold for $1.02 million.

4 Dashwood Road, Beaumont

The five-bedroom, three-bathroom home sold to the sole bidder at auction, according to the property's listing agent Suellen Salt of Harris Real Estate.
"We only had one very keen bidder on the day but I think we achieved a great result," she said.
"The buyers were attracted to the home because of the size and school district it falls into."
Ms Salt said the property had been a well-cared-for family home for the past 18 years.
"The sellers raised their children in this home and have now left, so they are looking to downsize and decided to sell," she said.
"Most homes in the suburb are much like this - tightly held and family owned."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dashwood Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suellen Salt of Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High St Glenelg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathryn McCann Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathryn McCann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Street</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Salt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dashwood Rd Beaumont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenelg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McCann</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaumont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
