<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423188995576737</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/passengers-terror-as-ryanair-plane-plunged-hundreds-of-feet-during-massive-electrical-storm/news-story/e77adfa51ef8f9a09b0c356e75d00f02</url>
  <title>Passengers' terror as Ryanair plane plunged hundreds of feet during massive electrical storm</title>
  <content>
The bumpiest plane landings ever!
0:57

While air travel is, statistically speaking, the safest method of transportation, a bit of turbulence can put even the most seasoned journeyman at the edge of their seat. Hereas a collection of our favorite aviation clips. Credit: Various via Storyful

May 18th 2017
3 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Finance - syndicated/

Passengers' terror as Ryanair plane plunged hundreds of feet during massive electrical storm.

Alun PalmerThe Sun

Share

PASSENGERS on board a Ryanair flight were left terrified after their plane was battered by a massive electrical storm over Britain, according to one of those on board.
They reportedly suffered a five-and-a-half hour flight from hell as they circled inside the terrifying tempest.
One man described how holiday-makers on their way back from Ibiza screamed, vomited and prayed to land safely as the plane reportedly plunged hundreds of feet in the storm.
"I put my hands together and prayed for God to keep my children and family safe first," passenger Alex Rayner, 38, said.
"Then I thought why am I praying for them, I am on my way out! It shows how much they mean to me because I was thinking I wouldn't get through this.
"Then I thought it might be good for God to help me so I offered up a small prayer asking if he could keep me safe. Luckily it worked."
The 9.30pm Ryanair flight from Ibiza was meant to land at the Essex airport at 11.30pm. But within minutes the plane is said to have hit heavy turbulence and storms.

Passengers on board a Ryanair flight from Ibiza endured the flight from hell.Source:istock
Father-of-four Mr Rayner, the chief executive of an events company, said trouble began before the drinks trolley had served three aisles.
"We kept plunging for what seemed like a hundred feet and then went up again, we were being thrown about like a toy plane," he said.

"One of the frightening things about the ordeal, which lasted five hours, was the engines would be screaming loudly before they edged back to a normal rate every time it hit an air pocket.
"It was a very frightening feeling."
But just when they thought they had reached Britain and could finally land, Mr Rayner said they ended up circling the airport for two hours as a fierce electrical storm raged around them.
The weather was reportedly so bad the airport was closed, leaving the passengers stranded in the air as the plane was tossed about in the storm.
"There was lashing rain, huge streaks of lightning. Every ten seconds lightning went really close to the aeroplane and every time it struck it lit up the plane like something out of a horror movie. The lightning was just 50m (160ft) away," Mr Rayner said.
"This broke everyone. It was like being on the most terrifying roller coaster. By the end of it people were screaming every time there was a bolt of lightning.
"The woman behind me was praying. One passenger was holding her talisman and kissing her cross."
Eventually the plane hit smoother air and came in to land - only for the co-pilot to calmly announce they had diverted to East Midlands Airport.
Mr Rayner said several passengers begged to be allowed off but were told to remain on-board.
After refuelling the plane went back to Stansted, hoping the weather had calmed and the airport was open.
But instead the storm was still raging.

Passengers were screaming, vomiting and praying as the plane plunged 'hundreds of feet'.Source:istock
After circling again the plane is said to have come in to land but 200ft from the ground, with the plane bucking up and down, the pilot pulled up.
Mr Rayner, from London, said: "The storm was in full rage and everyone is broken and couldn't face it again.
"We came in for a landing and we got to within 200ft off the ground and suddenly the pilot whacked on the engines and we took off again.
"Very calmly the first officer said, 'The pilot has decided not to land at this time'.
"The woman behind me is praying, crying and screaming, people were holding hands."
Eventually the pilot made another attempt at a landing, this time successfully.
Mr Rayner said: "We came in really fast and heavy and we landed five hours late. Out of that three and a half (hours) were spent circling an airport in the centre of a storm.
"People cheered when we hit the ground, they cheered again when we slowed down and again when we stopped.
"When I stepped off the plane my knees buckled."
A spokesman for Stansted Airport said five planes were diverted away from the airport because of the storm and four returned later after refuelling.
A spokesman for Ryanair told Sun Online: "This flight from Ibiza to London Stansted (18 Jul.) was unable to land at Stansted due to thunderstorms.
"The aircraft diverted to East Midlands, where it landed normally and returned to London Stansted once the weather improved.
"Ryanair sincerely apologised to all customers affected by this weather diversion, which was entirely beyond our control."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Stansted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ibiza</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Finance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryanair</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stansted Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Stansted (18 Jul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alun PalmerThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Midlands Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Rayner, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rayner</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stansted</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Midlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun Online</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
