<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422415901449456</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/beauty/the-best-waterproof-makeup-for-when-spring-has-finally-sprung-20170802-gxo7af.html</url>
  <title>The best waterproof make-up for when spring has finally sprung</title>
  <content>
With the hint of spring in the air, now seems a good time to think about a trans-seasonal make-up update, and to try out some of the latest long-wearing waterproof products around to see how well they might fare on my oily skin.
The golden rule of thumb, no matter what the season, is to slather on an SPF50+ before applying any make-up. As far as a base is concerned, opt for a waterproof tinted moisturiser for a lighter finish or a waterproof foundation for more coverage.
Incidentally, international make-up artist  favourite waterproof foundation is niche brand  - and it really does offer quite an immoveable and miraculous level of coverage.
If you do plan on hitting the beach with your make-up on, don't forget to pack some  to mop up any excess oil.The long-wearing winners to add to your make-up kit, no matter what the season/emotion

·     
gives great, long-lasting coverage. You can dial up or down the coverage to go as light or intense as you like.

·     
is a durable powder highlighter that will certainly last the distance now matter how "glowy" you get.

·     
is highly pigmented and stays put all day.

·     
goes the distance on those hot, humid days.

You will now receive updates from

Daily Life Newsletter

Daily Life Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

·     
is packed with matte pigments for colour saturation and long-lasting weightless wear. This is smudge resistance at its best.

·     
is fab for a matte nude lid and acts like a cream shadow. It will set and last all day long.

·     
This collection of long-lasting lip shades was created for the Parisian Aquatic Ballet and tested underwater for five hours. We're sold.

·     
even stays on after a dip in the pool.

·     
is created from Amazonian river clay that has been baked in the sun. As a result, the clay component helps minimise oil. It really lasts the distance.Getting it off

Waterproof mascara is the best choice if you're looking at long-lasting mascaras, but it can be a challenge to get off. The things we love about it, like its ability to add volume and length and last all day, are countered by its reluctance to come off. This is due to the ingredients, which often include isododecane, an ingredient responsible for the longevity.
As the mascara is waterproof, use the opposite of water - oil - to get it off. Oil helps break down the waterproof ingredients, so the mascara will slide off your lashes. Soak a cotton pad in  to remove. You could even use olive oil in a pinch.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazonians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parisian Aquatic Ballet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPF 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
