<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423270599956661</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/gambling/tabcorp-expects-tatts-deal-vote-in-october-20170802-gxo9dv</url>
  <title>Tabcorp expects Tatts deal vote in October</title>
  <content>
A shareholder vote on the $11 billion merger between wagering giant Tabcorp and Tatts Group has been delayed until October. 
A scheme booklet for the proposed merger is now expected to be provided to Tatts' shareholders in September, and the meeting of Tatts' shareholders to vote on the deal iin October, the companies revealed on Friday morning.
The deal is subject to an appeal by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission and rival corporate bookmaker CrownBet,
The full bench of the Federal Court  will hear both the ACCC's and CrownBet's applications on 28 and 29 August. 

Tabcorp on Friday released its 2017 financial results, revealing earnings before interest, tax, depreciation and amortisation of $504.1 million, down 2.3 per cent from the previous year but with guidance given the market in June.

It had then revealed it would miss previous consensus profit forecasts for the 2017 financial year thanks to tougher trading conditions and a bigger-than-expected loss for its Luxbet corporate bookmaker business.
Tabcorp recorded a net profit of $178.9 per cent, down 3.8 per cent but fell to a statutory loss of $20.8 million due to $199.7 million of significant items after tax.
That figure included $61.8 million related to Austrac money laundering investigations, $53.9 million of costs associated with the Tatts deal and an operating loss of $47.6 million and impairment of $20.7 million for t 
Tabcorp chief executive David Attenborough said the main plan for the company in the 2018 financial centred on completing the Tatts deal.

"At the same time, we have a clear set of priorities to drive performance in our core businesses and benefit from the strategic initiatives we delivered in 2017. We will continue to focus on maintaining a disciplined approach to operating expenses and capital expenditure and delivering sustainable returns for our shareholders and partners." 
Tabcorp will pay a final dividend 12.5 cents per share, fully franked, taking the full year ordinary dividend to 25 cents per share.
More to come

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatts Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrownBet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luxbet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Attenborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
