<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422845398187145</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/gws-could-use-twin-towers-to-topple-demon</url>
  <title>GWS could use twin towers to topple Demon</title>
  <content>
Deledio speaks, Lever link, Sam's call
The Footy Feed team with all the latest news

Shane Mumford could return to face Max Gawn in the ruck on Saturday

GREATER Western Sydney coach Leon Cameron is contemplating using two recognised ruckmen in a bid to quell the influence of Melbourne big man Max Gawn.

With Shane Mumford (ankle) injured last week, the Giants used Dawson Simpson as their number one big man, and he worked well with Rory Lobb for support. But with Mumford a chance to be fit to face the Demons in Canberra, Cameron said he's been doing plenty of thinking about the make-up of his 22.

Simpson had 44 hit-outs in his first senior game since round 15, 2015, and made sure the Giants didn't miss the significant physical presence of Mumford against the Dockers.

A team that includes Mumford and Dawson, along with Lobb and Jonathon Patton as permanent forwards, could leave GWS top-heavy, but Cameron said throwing two big bodies at the 2016 All Australian could be the best way to stop his influence.

"Dawson was terrific last week in his first game in three years and that's what we need, so it's not cut and dry, (even) if Mumford pulls up well," he said.

"He's 211cm and Gawn is 208, so there's no doubt that's going to be a big duel.

"Gawn is an outstanding player and watching him down in Tassie (against North Melbourne last week), he had 58 hit outs and can feed their onball brigade whichever way (he wants).

"Whichever way we go, I mean we might go both, but if we go with one, then one is going to be unlucky.

"If Mumford doesn't pull up well then he won't play, but if he does then we've got a big decision.

"We've just got to work out if we go in with two ruckmen or just the one."

Mumford and fellow veteran Steve Johnson both hit the track with the main group on Wednesday and completed the 90-minute session, but Johnson had an ice pack strapped to his troublesome right knee after training.

The forward also missed last week's 12-point win over Fremantle after his recurring knee problem flared up after the Giants' round 18 loss to Richmond.

The 2007 Norm Smith medallist has responded well to rest earlier in the year, but Cameron denied Johnson could be left in Sydney to give his knee another week off.

"We can't worry about what's going to happen down the track. Melbourne want to win and we want to win to keep our finals hopes alive," he said.

"It's a huge game, the winner could go on to secure up a spot in the top eight by the end of the weekend, but the loser could be starting to scramble.

"We'll be picking the best 22 available to play against the Demons."

Draftee Will Setterfield looks set to miss the clash after being concussed against the Dockers, with the midfielder still feeling the effects of the heavy knock on Wednesday. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Setterfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footy Feed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Lobb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawson Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lobb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norm Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumford</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
