<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423352204336367</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/fire-tears-through-residential-skyscraper-torch-tower-in-dubai/8773662</url>
  <title>Dubai fire: Huge blaze tears through 86-storey Torch Tower apartment block in Marina neighbourhood</title>
  <content>
Fire has torn through a high-rise residential tower in Dubai in the middle of the night, sending plumes of smoke into the air and debris falling below.

Key points:

No injuries yet reported
Authorities say fire is under control
A massive fire swept through same building in 2015

Dubai's police said firefighters were on the scene and that no injuries had been reported so far in the blaze at the Torch Tower, located in Dubai's popular Marina neighbourhood.
The Torch Tower is one of the world's tallest residential towers at more than 80 storeys high.
Dubai's Civil Defence announced at 3:30am (local time) that the blaze was under control.
"Cooling operations are underway," Dubai's official media office said on Twitter.
More than 40 floors of the 86-storey Torch Tower were burning on one side of the building, an Associated Press journalist near the scene said.
Authorities later shared a photo of the charred and blackened tower but it was no longer in flames.

Officials said they were now working on providing shelter for those affected.
Dubai police cordoned off several blocks around the building, keeping people away from the fire's falling debris.
.
Fires have affected several skyscrapers in the United Arab Emirates, including a towering inferno that engulfed a 63-storey luxury hotel in Dubai on New Year's Eve in 2016.
Building and safety experts have cited a popular type of cladding covering the buildings that can be highly flammable.
Earlier this year, Dubai instated new fire safety rules requiring buildings with quick-burning side panelling to replace it with more fire-resistant siding.
Authorities have previously acknowledged that at least 30,000 buildings across the UAE have cladding or panelling that safety experts have said accelerates the rapid spread of fires.
and prompted Britain to order more thorough testing on the cladding systems of its towers.

External Link:

mira majbour tweet: #dubai#fire#marina#torch#building

External Link:

Dubai fire tweet: #Dubai torch tower is currently burning in Dubai Marina @gulf_news

External Link:

Dubai fire Facebook video: Yet another building on fire in Dubai ...
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torch Tower</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Arab Emirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UAE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai Civil Defense</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Year's Eve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
