<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423309254662795</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/leaders/leaked-transcript-shows-turnbull-trump-spar-over-controversial-refugee-deal/news-story/9529dd0a015424cef832c8ab71443e73</url>
  <title>Leaked transcript reveals loophole in controversial refugee deal</title>
  <content>
Refugee deal makes me look bad: Trump
3:54

The infamous January phone call between US President Donald Trump and Malcolm Turnbull has been leaked.

August 4th 2017
2 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

US President Donald Trump told Turnbull he would be "killed" over the refugee deal. Picture Kym Smith. Picture Kym Smith

Victoria Craw and Debra Killalea

Share

AMID the lengthy transcript of a leaked phone call between President Trump and Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull is a critical passage that's easy to miss.
As Trump thinks through the implications of upholding an Obama-era deal that could allow 1250 refugees from Australian detention centres into the US in exchange for taking people the US wants to deport, he appears to spot a loophole.
"I hate having to do it, but I am still going to vet them very closely. Suppose I vet them closely and I do not take any?" Trump asked.
"That is the point I have been trying to make," Turnbull replied.
"How does that help you?" Trump asks.
"Well, we assume that we will act in good faith," Turnbull said.
So the truth is, Trump is under no obligation to actually accept any refugees as part of the deal.

US President Donald Trump and Australian President Malcolm Turnbull seemed on good terms at the G20 in Hamburg. Picture: Kym Smith.Source:Supplied
When Trump - who is clearly not across the finer points of Australian immigration policy - asked how he will know "who these people are", Turnbull explained.
"We know exactly who they are. They have been on Nauru or Manus for over three years and the only reason we cannot let them into Australia is because of our commitment to not allow people to come by boat."

"Otherwise we would have let them in. If they had arrived by aeroplane and with a tourist visa then they would be here."
The Prime Minister said the people involved in the potential swap are "economic refugees" and are "not in that league" of "World Trade Centres" or "Boston Bombers" as Trump suspects.
"The only people that we do not take are people who come by boat. So we would rather take a not very attractive guy that help you out then to take a Nobel Peace Prize winner that comes by boat. That is the point," Turnbull said.

At the G20 with Vietnam's Prime Minister Nguyen Xuan Phuc and his wife Tran Nguyet Thu. Picture: John MacDougall/AFPSource:AFP
The comments cut to the heart of the debate around Australia's controversial immigration policy that sees those arriving by boat transferred to offshore detention centres on Manus Island and Nauru.
The Turnbull government claims the policy is the only way to deter people smugglers and secure Australian borders. Critics say it is a "draconian" with  calling to end "abusive offshore detention" and resettle those found to be refugees in Australia.
Either way, the controversial phone call reveals the desperation for both leaders to save face over promises they had made to their respective publics.
Turnbull also promised to "take more" and "take anyone that you want us to take" rather than accept people he has previously admitted are "economic refugees."
'ALL ABOUT TRUMP'
According to Dr David Smith, a senior Lecturer in American Politics and Foreign Policy at the United States Studies Centre and the School of Social and Political Sciences at the University of Sydney, the transcripts said everything about the President's view on foreign policy.
Dr Smith said it showed Trump had no idea how to talk or deal with world leaders.
He said it also showed he was more concerned with fulfilling his campaign promises than using negotiating skills he should have mastered in the business world.
"The transcripts are useful in showing what Trump thinks about foreign policy," he said.
"It's actually more useful than any statement or analysis made by supporters or detractors."
Dr Smith said the PM tried to appeal to the President's business sense and played the negotiating card by suggesting ways he could save face over the deal.
The problem was the President was having none of it and instead was focused on the message he spouted on the campaign trail which was that the US getting the raw end of deals.
"Turnbull is aware of this and very early on tries to appeal to the President's business sense," he said.
"But all Trump was concerned with was how the US is being abused by dumb deals.
"In his discussion with the Mexican President (Enrique Pena Nieto) it was also all about how other leaders were taking advantage of the US."
Dr Smith said it was clear Mr Trump was unwilling to negotiate after the PM tried several times to explain how the refugee deal could work.
"Trump's message is the is US is copping the bad deals and other leaders aren't as good as negotiating as he is," he said.
"The problem is negotiations hit a standstill because neither Trump or Nieto are obliged to fulfil Trump's campaign promises."
Dr Smith he said it was also ironic for Trump to question why Australia discriminated against boats when his executive order discriminated against an entire religion.
"Really this transcripts reveal more about Trump than anything else," he said.
"Turnbull is using his business skills to try and negotiate with Trump but all Trump is doing is repeating his campaign rhetoric."
In a tweet, Dr Smith's fellow USSC fellow Ashely Townshend described the dialogue between the two leaders as "unbelievable". That just about sums it up.
Unbelievable dialogue btw Trump and Turnbull over Australia's contentious "refugee deal"
.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama-era</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashely Townshend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Craw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tran Nguyet Thu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enrique Pena Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debra Killalea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian President Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kym Smith.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston Bombers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr David Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Studies Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USSC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Political Science</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kym Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>School of Social</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam's Prime Minister Nguyen Xuan Phuc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Trade Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Smith</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Politics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John MacDougall/AFPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nobel Peace Prize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
