<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423274894924041</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/mark-cropps-devast8-tattoo-not-coming/3208738/</url>
  <title>Mark Cropp's Devast8 tattoo not coming off</title>
  <content>
The man with the famed Devast8 tattoo has done a U-turn on removing it.

Mark Cropp, 19, shot to fame globally after Herald Focus interviewed him last month about his plea for a job on Facebook.

But he has decided not to get rid of it.

His brother tattooed the nickname "Devast8" on his face during a heavy night of drinking in jail.

"Once it was started, I thought, I can't go back on it now.

"I wish I had stopped while the outline was there to be quite honest," he said.

Cropp had been serving a two-year, three-month sentence for pulling a knife on a tourist over a drug deal gone wrong.

He initially said he had hoped to keep the tattoo and for a potential employer to look past it, but he changed his mind overnight when he became an international sensation, and accepted an offer from Sacred Laser in Kingsland to have it removed for free.

Herald Focus went to Cropp's first laser removal session, where a section of his tattoo was worked on and partly lasered off.

On Wednesday, Cropp told Focus he was working night shifts and things were going well so had put the laser removal on hold until he got used to his hours.

However, on Thursday, when asked about his progress, Sacred Laser said Cropp had rejected their offer and wouldn't be having further sessions.

The parlour expressed disappointment, but said their offer to remove it for free still stood if Cropp were to change his mind.

Cropp has not responded to calls from Herald Focus today.

Two Gold Coast men held hostage at Gympie camp
Man believed to be unconscious before horror highway smash
National Park mascot 'Hilaire' caught and being treated.
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cropp</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilaire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U-turn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Cropp's Devast8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Focus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devast8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sacred Laser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Cropp, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
