<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422707959231520</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-gws-giants-lock-up-defender-harry-himmelberg-for-another-two-years-20170803-gxohmq.html</url>
  <title>Giants lock up Canberra's Harry Himmelberg for another two years</title>
  <content>
The Greater Western Sydney Giants have locked in former Eastlake Demons star Harry Himmelberg for another two years as they edge closer to a maiden AFL premiership.
Himmelberg says it was a "no-brainer' to re-sign with the Giants until the end of 2019 as he looks to repay the faith shown in him by the title contenders.Photo: Elesa Kurtz
​The Giants will look to edge closer to locking up a spot in the top four when they host the Melbourne Demons at Manuka Oval on Saturday afternoon.
Himmelberg is set to travel to Canberra as an emergency but will likely play for the Giants' NEAFL team against the Canberra Demons in his hometown of Wagga Wagga on Saturday.
He is desperate to use the reserves clash as a platform to launch himself back into the senior side on their run to the finals.
"It's a really good feeling. The Giants put their faith in me to draft me and I'm just trying to repay the club for their faith me," Himmelberg said. 

"I'm obviously really excited to be here for another two years. At this stage I was just really happy here and I love Sydney.
"It really felt like home so it was really a no-brainer at the moment for me. It was definitely good to get it done."
Himmelberg played the last of his 10 AFL games for the Giants in a 60-point drubbing of the Brisbane Lions in June this year.
The 21-year-old was drafted as a forward with pick No. 16 in the 2015 AFL draft, but shifted into defence during pre-season last year.
Himmelberg would be "over the moon" if he received an AFL recall having spent the past two weeks in the NEAFL on the comeback trail from a finger injury.
"If I do have to play NEAFL again this week I'll just put my head down, bum up, do the work and try to get back into the senior side," Himmelberg said.
"I grew up in Wagga so it'd be good to see everyone that I grew up with down there, but the main goal for me at the moment is to play AFL footy so it'll be about having a solid game and keep knocking the door down.
"If I can get back into the team over the next couple of weeks I'll be over the moon."
Himmelberg says making the move from Wagga to Canberra shaped him as not only a footballer, but a person, and it held him in good stead when he made the leap to Sydney.
He moved to Canberra as an 18-year-old and gained exposure to NEAFL football when he was on the books at Eastlake.
"It made me really mature as a player and as a person, living out of home. I think that put me in good stead," Himmelberg said.
"It's obviously a lot different to the country but I've adapted pretty well over the last couple of years. It's really a good place to be, Sydney, so I'm happy to be here."
Himmelberg is living with GWS teammate Matt Kennedy in Sydney and says their tight bond is an indication of the "family club" the Giants have quickly become.
The group is tight off the field and Himmelberg believes that is what has helped the Giants fight back in the "patches where it's been really tough and we've been up against the wall".
The Giants have managed to stay in third on the ladder amidst an injury crisis but Himmelberg knows things will only get tougher as they edge towards the finals.
AFL ROUND 20
Saturday: GWS Giants v Melbourne Demons at Manuka Oval, 1:45pm. Tickets available from .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Himmelberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastlake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra's Harry Himmelberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL ROUND 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Himmelberg</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastlake Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giants' NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elesa Kurtz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga Wagga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
