<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423103096229437</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/dont-be-fooled-by-pizza-huts-free-margherita-pizza-giveaway/</url>
  <title>Don't Be Fooled By Pizza Hut's 'Free Margherita Pizza' Giveaway</title>
  <content>
Pizza Hut has announced it will be giving away 10,000 margherita pizzas between August 4 and August 6. According to the company, there's "no catch" - just free pizza. However, before you start salivating at the thought of a delicious cheesy lunch, there's something you need to know from the small print.

Pizza Hut's free margherita pizza giveaway has caused a bit of a stir online, with the  generating hundreds of likes and comments. Here's the post's opening line:

Because we love the most classic pizza, we're giving away 10,000 FREE Margherita pizzas this weekend from Friday to Sunday!

And here's the accompanying video:

It's not difficult to see why people are getting excited. Who doesn't love free pizza?

Unfortunately, anyone who bothered to read the second line would have had their enthusiasm immediately dampened. (Emphasis ours):

To get your free pizza simply head to your local Pizza Hut and be one of the first 10 customers each day (Fri, Sat & Sun) to order your free Margherita, but remember you must be in the store to pick it up!

This is a bit rubbish. It means you need to order your pizza as soon as your local store opens. Lunchtime and dinner are not an option. On top of this, the nature of the promotion means you'll just have to take the franchisee's word for it if they tell you they've already sold ten pizzas.

By limiting the deal to the first ten customers, Pizza Hut has managed to stretch the promotion over an entire weekend to maximise social media buzz. This might make sense from a PR perspective, but most people expecting to score a free pizza after watching the above video are going to be disappointed.

It's a timely reminder that "going viral" on social media .

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Free Margherita Pizza' Giveaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margherita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FREE Margherita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pizza Hut</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fooled By Pizza Hut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
