<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423399448977328</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/business/gaming-operator-crown-resorts-sale-of-macau-stake-offsets-slide-in-highroller-revenue/news-story/a6a127e45f05d13f81bde1acc38ab8ad</url>
  <title>Crown's Macau cash eases high-roller headache</title>
  <content>
CASINO and hotel owner Crown Resorts has reported a 96.7 per cent surge in full-year net profit as proceeds from the sale of its stake in Macau-based Melco Resorts and Entertainment offset a slump in revenue from high-rollers.
Crown reaped $1.7 billion from the sale of its Macau stake, which marked a major change in strategy as it sought to reduce its exposure to the Chinese high-roller market following the arrests in China of some of its staff in October last year.
The Macau windfall made up the bulk of its $1.87 billion net profit in the year to June. Stripping out significant items, net profit was down 21.5 per cent to $308.9 million.
Crown's revenue for the 12 months to June 30 was down 7.5 per cent to $3.34 billion, while revenue at its Australian resorts was down 12.7 per cent, reflecting "difficult trading conditions", it said.
Main floor gaming was down 1.4 per cent and Crown's VIP turnover at its Australian resorts was down 49 per cent.
After adjusting the result against the overall win-rate, Crown's normalised net profit was down 15.5 per cent to $343 million and its normalised gambling revenue was down 12.7 per cent.
"Crown's Australian operations full-year result reflected difficult trading conditions," Crown
executive chairman John Alexander said.
The results offered the first insight into how the crackdown on gambling in China had affected Crown's business. Prior to the arrests of its employees, Crown had enjoyed lucrative returns from Chinese high-rollers, who had accessed its casinos in Macau, with gambling ruled illegal in mainland China.
In the wake of the arrests, Crown has pulled back on its international projects in favour of its Australian assets, including a new hotel at its Southbank complex in Melbourne and a luxury hotel resort at Barangaroo in Sydney.
Apart from selling out of Melco, Crown, which counts tycoon James Packer as its major shareholder, also exited a Las Vegas casino deal.
Crown declared a final dividend of 30c, down 9.5c on a year earlier, but in line with the company's policy of paying 60c a share for its full year.
Shares in the group were up 0.2 per cent to $12.80 in early trade on Friday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macau-based Melco Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macau</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown's Macau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barangaroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown's VIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
