<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423408038912129</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/another-witch-hunt-pauline-hanson-fuming-after-abc/3208744/</url>
  <title>'Another witch hunt': Pauline Hanson fuming after ABC report</title>
  <content>
ONE Nation leader Pauline Hanson has declared reports her party made multiple breaches of Queensland electoral laws are nothing more than a "witch hunt" by the public broadcaster.

The ABC reported on Thursday that Senator Hanson's One Nation Party Queensland branch had failed to disclose some spending, lodge returns on time and advise donors of their disclosure requirements.

Documents obtained through Right to Information detailed investigations being conducted by the Electoral Commission of Queensland, as well as some of the party's explanations of the breaches, which included IT problems and Tropical Cyclone Debbie.

Senator Hanson, in Buderim yesterday with State Leader Steve Dickson, hit back at the reports.

"That's another witch hunt by the ABC," she said.

She explained she'd appointed a new staffer last year to run the office and deal with the Australian Electoral Commission and his appointment had brought the party "up to speed".

She said a new computer system had been installed since she took over leadership of the party and an untimely office closure due to Cyclone Debbie - the time the electoral commission wanted the documents - had been the reason for the reported breaches.

"We actually submitted the required documentation within a couple of days after that so everything was above board," Senator Hanson said.

"We work very well with the electoral commission, we give them all the information they need.

"We have a great working relationship so there's been no problems whatsoever."

PAULINE Hanson's One Nation Party leader, Senator Pauline Hanson.Patrick Woods

The ABC reported more than 130 pages of documents were released to them as part of the investigation, but "dozens more" were withheld as they related to ongoing investigations and inquiries into the party.

Senator Hanson took another swipe at the ABC, saying it had "dragged up" emails and documents dating back to February-March.

"This is months later, have they actually reported that everything's been clarified and everything's been done? No, they haven't," she said.

"All my disclosure matters are finalised."

The Australian Electoral Commission continues to investigate the ownership of a Jabiru plane used by One Nation, exercising its coercive powers to gather evidence.

"I want to see the end of this," Senator Hanson said.

"I want to know why they (electoral commission) are dragging their feet and not bringing down the final decision to do with this.

"I want it finalised and I want to prove to the people of Australia that I am not a liar as I have been accused of and I have always been up front and honest with the people."

Senator Hanson said if she didn't have an answer within the next couple of weeks she would "have to apply to the courts" because they "need an answer on this".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jabiru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Electoral Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Electoral Commission of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tropical Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Pauline Hanson.Patrick Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAULINE Hanson's One Nation Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Leader Steve Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February-March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson's One Nation Party Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
