<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422965657273944</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/kim-fui-gosling-scores-spot-on-southern-peninsula-sharks-team-in-victorian-junior-basketball-league/news-story/6faa968b844169a4327e6eba9754bcf2</url>
  <title>Kim on a roll towards basketball stardom</title>
  <content>
IN a sport best known for players taller than six feet, Rosebud basketballer Kim Fui Gosling stands at less than five.
But what he misses out on in height, Gosling makes up for in leaps and bounds in leadership and sportsmanship.
The 15-year-old plays for the Southern Peninsula Sharks in the Victorian Junior Basketball League and is captain of the under-16 second boys team.
Coach Darren Dobson said Gosling has such passion for the game he "radiates dedication to the sport, team and club".
"He's a natural leader and has embraced being team captain, and is a fierce competitor," Dobson said.
"But he helps injured players regardless of if they're on his team or the opposition.
"Kim Fui always shakes his opponents' hands after a game, no matter the result."
He said Gosling also trained hard to improve his skills, asking for additional training outside of the team's regular schedule and encouraging other players to join the extra practice sessions.
"He constantly speaks to all of his teammates in a positive and encouraging manner to help them understand what roles they need to fulfil and the work they need to do for the side."
Gosling is a Leader Local Sports Star nominee in the Junior Sports Star, Individual category.
Leader Local Sports Stars medallists will be named in seven categories including juniors, teams, individuals, and encouragement.
The program is now a national celebration, and junior category winners will be judged for national awards.
Cash prizes as well as vouchers from our sponsor Sportsmart are up for grabs.
For full details and to nominate an athlete, click .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Junior Basketball League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Dobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Fui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Peninsula Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Fui Gosling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Local Sports Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Sports Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosling</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junior Sports Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sportsmart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
