<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422458851123353</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/authorities-blind-to-the-bat-problem/3208349/</url>
  <title>Authorities 'blind' to the bat problem</title>
  <content>
ROBYN Richards says an area near her home is infested with flying foxes but continues to fly under the radar while authorities focus on Wallace Park.

Ms Richards said Noosa Council needs to address the bat problem in Pinaroo Park at Noosa Junction collectively with other areas in the region.

"This is an epidemic," Ms Richards said.

"We need to show the shire this area, we need to say Pinaroo Park and Wallace Park when we're talking about this problem."

Ms Richards said the number of flying foxes had "quadrupled" in the past two years and it's causing her serious health problems, as well as destroying the local habitat and wildlife.

"My asthma's come back after 20 years," she said.

"I can't open my windows most days because of the smell, especially if we get a southerly.

"All it's taken them is two years and they've devastated the area. There's thousands of them."

Meanwhile, a resident living near the Wallace Park flying-fox colony has compared living with the protected creatures as putting up with "an advanced case of tinnitus".

Norah Lilley said the flying-foxes had re-settled near the Ivory Palms resort and were close to neighbouring homes.

"The smell is becoming increasingly hard to bear," Ms Lilley said.

"The mess is causing people to have to clean their cars, driveways and outdoor furniture every day.

"Although I am told the sprinkler system is now in place I have been advised that it has not yet been used."

A Noosa Council spokesperson said action is being taken to relieve residents of the flying-fox problem.

"The sprinkler system and subsidy scheme are designed to lessen their impact on the residents who live near Wallace Park," the spokesperson said.

"The subsidy scheme provides eligible residents free car and washing line covers, as well as free solar panel cleaning.

"Council has received very few complaints in relation to flying foxes at Wallace Park since this scheme and the sprinkler system were introduced.

"Previously, flying-fox roosts have been recorded at Lake Doonella, Weyba Creek, Noosa Heads, Lake Weyba, Goat Island and in rural areas such as Cooran. Sites may be permanent or temporary."

Man believed to be unconscious before horror highway smash
House of horrors in Queensland described to jury
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lilley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weyba Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallace Park</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goat Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Richards</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Doonella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinaroo Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norah Lilley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBYN Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Weyba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivory Palms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Junction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
