<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422836808252341</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/city-meets-suburbia-in-the-eastern-suburbs/news-story/c0314739b8fd8b3b3fd02b0e37196d1e</url>
  <title>City meets suburbia in the eastern suburbs - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Kirra Green is auctioning her home in Norman Park. Photo: Annette Dew

WHEN Kirra Green looked for a new home in 2015, location was top of her list.
"I want something that felt like I could be in the city in a few minutes, but also something that felt a little bit suburban, peaceful and quiet as well."
She found it at - a three-bedroom, two-bathroom cottage on a 407sq m block in one of Brisbane's most desirable eastern suburbs.

440 Bennetts Road, Norman Park Brisbane is in a quiet and convenient location.

Ms Green wasn't afraid of a little hard work either. She said a previous owner's renovation attempt was short of the mark.
"It looked like they'd done a renovation in the 1990s just from the colours and some of the design choices and they hadn't maintained it," she said.
The next owner will get to enjoy Ms Green's handiwork with a stylish kitchen and bathroom, new paint job, polished timber floors and high-end fittings.

The hard work has been done.

The owner's tasteful approach should ensure plenty of auction interest.

"Down the track there's the option to raise it too - it's all concreted underneath - it's got side access as well and there's room for a pool," Ms Green said.
Ms Green and her partner have enjoyed spending time in rooms with great natural light and orientation.
"I really do like the lounge room that has the sunroom come off it.
"We get really great morning light because we're east facing. Right now the front bedroom and the sunroom are all lit up - it's really bright and it's a good start to the morning," she said.

An easterly orientation ensure the home catches plenty of natural light.

"We spend the most amount of time out on the deck. It's a really good size, close to the kitchen. Once the afternoon sun comes in - especially with winter at the moment - all afternoon we're pretty much sitting out there," Ms Green said.

The back deck the perfect spot for seeing out the afternoon.

She said the location had been perfect with convenient access to community facilities such as Balmoral Park and the Oxford Street cafe strip.
"That whole precinct was a real surprise with everything that's there," Ms Green said.
"I was talking to my mum on the phone and I was walking after work down to the park and mum was like, 'What are you doing walking at night?' and I said, 'Mum, there are hundreds of people out. It's summer. It's still 27 degrees and everybody's outside walking with their kids and dogs.' It's just a really nice community that was a real surprise."
"We are going to miss this area," she said.
The home will be auctioned on site Sat 5th August at 10:00am by Place Bulimba.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balmoral Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Place Bulimba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennetts Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sat: 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman Park Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirra Green</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Green</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annette Dew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
