<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423309254662843</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/real-estate/queensland/townsville/getting-a-handle-on-equity-is-an-essential-key-to-securing-your-dream-home/news-story/b90483b1915ed46d9773efc6d4faa93c</url>
  <title>Getting a handle on equity is an essential key to securing your dream home - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Generic image.

IF YOU are considering selling your property a question that will come up is what level of equity you have in your home.
It is important you fully investigate your equity position before making any decisions about selling or buying another property.
There are some common traps associated with using equity in your home and it's important you do the sums early so you understand your position.
Equity is the difference between the market value of the property and the owner's unencumbered interest in the property. In other words, it's what would be left over if you sold the property today and paid off all the associated debts with the home (that is the mortgage).
The equity (or "net profit" as it can sometimes be called) is often what people use to fund activities such as renovations.
To have equity in your home the market value of the property should be growing.
But what happens when the value of the property falls and the potential sale doesn't clear the associated debts?
It is well documented that regional Queensland property markets are doing it tough and Townsville is no exception.
Unfortunately, it's possible that there may be owners who have bought property in Townsville in the past five to 10 years who are paying off a property that has a lower market value today than it did when they bought it.
When a property owner is considering selling the property and they have negative equity it's likely they may need the bank's approval before they can sell. It's important you thoroughly investigate your financial position before you make any decisions.
Many experienced agents who have seen a few property cycles in their time (and I'm one of those) will know to ask the equity question early to avoid any heartache down the track.
If you're serious about selling start by finding out from the agent what costs are associated with the property sale and then talk to the bank to find out how much equity you have.
It's much better to ask this question early and avoid potential tears and disappointment down the track when you've fallen in love with your dream home only to find out you don't have as much equity as you thought.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
