<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423356499303705</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/montmorency-house-to-challenge-the-suburbs-2m-record/news-story/6a764eac52da5b592cecac3addc9904f</url>
  <title>Montmorency house to challenge the suburb's $2M record - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
There is plenty of room to store all the toys in this Montmorency garage.

WITH room to park up to five cars in the garage, this modern Montmorency family home could challenge the suburb's price record.
Set on a 798sq m block, Buckingham & Company, Diamond Valley, agent Ryan Buckingham said the two-year-old house measured about 558sq m and stood out from the 1950s weatherboard-style properties typical of Montmorency.
RELATED:

21 Grand Blvd, Montmorency, has a price guide of $1.8 million-$1.9 million.

Described as a Hamptons-style residence,  has a price guide of $1.8 million-$1.9 million.
CoreLogic figures show 12 Ripper St holds the price record for the suburb.
The four-bedroom, three-bathroom house with a pool changed hands in June last year for $2 million.
Mr Buckingham said 21 Grand Blvd stood a chance to break the record.
"There has been a lot of interest, so it has a possibility to break the record," he said.
"There has been a mixture of buyers, some looking at downsizing from acreage properties, others are executive type buyers who have a number of cars and love the garage.
"It is a low-maintenance house, so you can travel overseas without worrying about the garden."

The kitchen has a butler's pantry and stone benchtops.

Mr Buckingham said it was a "quality-built house" with state-of-the art appliances in the kitchen, hadronic heating throughout and a gas log fire in the living room.
The heart of the house is an open-plan kitchen, dining and living area that flows out to the undercover outdoor entertainment area.
A butler's pantry, dishwasher, breakfast bar and stone benchtops are features of the kitchen.

Enjoy seamless indoor-outdoor living at this Montmorency house.

The main bedroom has an ensuite with a bathtub and walk-in wardrobe.
The two minor bedrooms have built-in wardrobes and the use of the main bathroom.
Accessible from the garage is an upstairs rumpus room with a storage room and balcony.
A kitchenette and powder room are also features of the garage.
The property is for private sale with offers closing at 6pm on August 22.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ripper St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montmorency</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamptons-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Buckingham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Buckingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Blvd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
