<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422622059883996</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/amelias-mma-dream-begins-as-the-underdog-in-fight-v-jemma-byard/news-story/2f56d74c598f60aacdfc6d7596a6ae44</url>
  <title>Powerful Amelia eyes MMA dream</title>
  <content>
FOUR-ounce MMA gloves and a mouthguard are all that Darwin's Amelia Dickson will have to protect herself in tonight's prestigious CMT 10 Show in Brisbane.
The super excited 31-year-old will battle against the highly-regarded Jemma Byard in a three-round, 58kg Muay Thai challenge.
Byard is based on the Gold Coast and comes from a kickboxing background with a strong reputation, and she loves to throw a lot of punches.
"I know I am the underdog but it is a massive show and opportunity for me to get my name out there," Dickson said.
The Wayne and Angie Parr-promoted event provides fighters with a modified version of Muay Thai.
Boxing gloves are replaced with lightweight MMA gloves in addition to an octagon-caged ring instead of the traditional square ring.

Muay thai fighter Amelia Dickson dreams of competing in the MMA one day

NT Muay Thai fighter hopes to join MMA
Dickson, who works in Darwin as a property manager, acknowledged that a shift in training techniques and strategy were applied in preparation for the modified fight.
"It is very different. The hands become quicker and fighters can attack you from a variety of angles which increase the chances of a knockout," she said.
The ambitious Victorian-born Dickson prides herself on aggressive punches and is yet to taste defeat from four fights.
MMA, more interstate fights and potentially some overseas fights in years to come is the dream.
"I have always dreamt about MMA. It has so many more elements and it is my ultimate goal," she said.
For the time being, however, Dickson will continue her gruelling training regime at the Lukphinong Gym in Howard Springs with head trainer Astro Rodrigues who sponsors her.
Daily 5am starts plus afternoon sessions in the gym with Rodrigues and fellow Muay Thai fighters such as Le Tan are the norm for Dickson.
"I would not be where I am today if it was not for the incredible support I have received from the gym," Dickson said.
Byard trains with Nick Atkins from Wanna Be A Kickboxer and six-time world champion John Wayne Parr's gym Boonchu. She has had seven fights with five wins, one loss and a draw.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astro Rodrigues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Tan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Wayne Parr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Atkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian-born Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin's Amelia Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lukphinong Gym</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodrigues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angie Parr-promoted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CMT 10 Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boonchu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jemma Byard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelia Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanna Be A Kickboxer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muay Thai</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Muay Thai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
