<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423498233226997</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/opinion/how-the-nrl-is-failing-every-junior-rugby-league-player-big-and-small/news-story/260b2a4d5093c0e70474ebca5100213b</url>
  <title>NRL is failing kids in weight debate</title>
  <content>
Sydney's seven year old gentle giant of rugby

BIG or small, every kid who wants to play rugby league should be able to play rugby league.

Small kids shouldn't have to beg their parents to do so or convince them it's a good idea.

The parents of bigger kids shouldn't worry their child may become internet fodder in the age vs. weight debate because of their size.

Earlier this week footage of an under 8's player made waves in league circles.

The gentle giant towered over his teammates and had their measure on the scale, two if not three times over.

It has since been reported the boy won't be playing footy with his mates this weekend.

His parents were devastated by the things people were saying about their son online so have decided to withdraw him from the game.

As someone who has coached junior rugby league, I know most kids don't want to be turned into a speed bump by a kid twice their size. And parents don't like seeing it happen.

But let me make it clear, this conundrum is not the fault of any junior player.

They can't help their size.

The reality is the NRL is failing kids, big and small, when it comes to age vs. weight dilemma.

They are failing them in terms of safety and they are failing to protect kids like the 'gentle giant' who unwittingly found himself at the centre of this debate. He deserved better.

SAVAGE:

RETRO ROUND:

This conversation could not have come at a worse time for the game in general. Throw in the damning report from the US on the impact of concussion and heavy contact can have on the brain, and parents are worried.

On the face of it the solution to all of this seems simple.

Introduce weight divisions rather than competitions based on age.

The problem is you can't have seven year-olds playing against teenagers just because they are a similar weight.

The gap in the level of skill in these weight divisions could lead to injury, exactly the thing they are trying to prevent.

A better solution is to group age competitions and then split those groups into weight divisions.

For example, under 7's and under 8's become one grouping and then within that age grouping are divided by weight.

It's not perfect but it's better than seven-year olds playing against teenagers.

But will the game move to make the appropriate changes?

We know how reactionary those in charge can be, but surely they cannot wait until a child is seriously hurt during a game because of a weight mismatch before something is done.

Junior rugby league cannot afford the PR nightmare tied to these types of injuries.

Registrations are already down by 15 per cent in certain parts of rugby league's heart land in Sydney's west.

Stalling on this issue can only be a deterrent to junior rugby league and in turn the future of the game.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
