<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423450988585834</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:32</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/lifestyle/feasibility-study-gives-thumbs-up-to-proposal-for-cable-car-on-sheffields-mt-roland/news-story/30b539d35887e4781c02b8065bb3df7c</url>
  <title>Mt Roland cable car an 'attractive' option</title>
  <content>
WHILE debate rages about a proposal to construct a cable car on Hobart's Mt Wellington, another to carry tourists to the top of Sheffield's stunning backdrop is quietly gaining traction.
The idea of building a cable car to take people to the top of Mt Roland was first mooted by Sheffield tourism stalwarts Brian Inder and John Sinclair in 2013.

Last year it was costed at $13.8 million.
Now, an independent feasibility study has given the Mt Roland Cable Car Project the thumbs up.

Another study has supported building a network of mountain bike trails down Sheffield's most recognisable attraction to capitalise on the cable car venture.
Director and project lead Justin Carman said both studies had returned pleasing results.
"Our first study focused on the cableway system itself, to transport passengers (and sporting equipment) to and from the mountain top," Mr Carman said.
"It found the cableway proposal to be 'both technically and financially feasible and attractive for its economic and external benefits to the communities involved'."

We are excited at all the opportunities this project creates within the region, a region we argue is one of the most beautiful on this planet. - project lead Justin Carman
The second study looked at the merits of developing a mountain bike park, made up of a network of 12 trails from the mountain top to the cableway base station.
"The study found Mt Roland had the potential of offer a 'truly unique and iconic mountain biking experience', one which we think should be pursued," Mr Carman said.
"The studies provide us with confidence to progress the project into the second stage of design and planning applications. And we are excited at all the opportunities this project creates within the region, a region we argue is one of the most beautiful on this planet."
The proponents will now approach the State Government seeking support for the ventures.
Costed designs will also need to be produced and a development application lodged with the Kentish Council.
"Ongoing communication with the community is a given," Mr Carman said.
Tourism experts have already backed the project saying it would open up the mountain to hundreds of thousands of visitors who marvel at it, but often bypass it, as they travel to the region's main attraction, Cradle Mountain.
Plans floated in the 1990s to construct a road up Mt -Roland did not eventuate and the development of a cable car was highlighted in a 2011 Kentish Council -report on Mt Roland's tourism potential.
Tourism Industry Council Tasmania chief executive Luke Martin described Mt Roland as "extraordinary".
"If the Cradle Mountain vision is realised, 400,000 visitors a year will see Mt Roland and if they have a reason to stop - something to do - they will," he said last year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheffield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cradle Mountain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Carman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Carman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Sinclair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Industry Council Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Roland</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart's Mt Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kentish Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Roland Cable Car Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Inder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
