<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423188995576796</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/view-from-the-street-our-speculative-property-market-has-a-body-count-20170803-gxoqml.html</url>
  <title>View from the Street: Our speculative property market has a body count</title>
  <content>
Inequality is finally becoming an issue in Australian politics as Labor leader Bill Shorten makes addressing it the centrepiece of his future election campaign, and Treasurer Scott Morrison counters by angrily insisting that it doesn't exist and no you shut up.
And it's being blithely reported upon as "hey, get ready for increased financial stress" as though everyone's in a position to handle yet another major pressure on their lives, so let's just make this explicit: the 2017 housing market is costing lives.Photo: Rob Homer
As you'd no doubt be acutely aware, the last few months of headlines have been up and down about how the future is looking for Australians with an interest in not dying of exposure. And, as ever, it's those at the bottom that get hurt the most. 
The proposed launch of the first swathe of rental bidding apps seem guaranteed to put upward pressure on rents, unless regulated to the point of not actually having them. 
Most people are fairly resilient most of the time, but housing isn't a luxury which people can choose to take or leave: everyone needs a roof over their head, and anything that makes that harder adds enormous, urgent pressure. And if you're already doing it hard, that can be the literal final straw.
Even the strongest of us is only a handful of tragedies away from being in a state of genuine crisis: how many people can expect to weather a sudden death of a loved one, or an unexpected business collapse, or a shocking break-up with complete equanimity? Now add housing uncertainty to the mix and you have a recipe for a complete breakdown.

And for the large number of us - myself included - who battle with depression or other mental illnesses that slope between coping and not-coping is steep and slippery.
For example: some years ago I moved into the smelliest, hottest, most rodent-adjacent place I have ever lived following a break-up. It was a dark, noisy hell hole next to a train station and above a cafe and I - correctly, as it turned out - predicted I would never enjoy a full night's sleep within those walls.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Why did I move there? Because I looked at my solo finances and established that I had a choice of living somewhere godawful that was near my friends and support networks, or somewhere liveable but a long way out into the suburbs. And I figured that for my own mental health it was vital that I not become isolated and lonely, because I knew what the likely upshot would be while I was already feeling vulnerable.
If a similar situation was to happen now, I wouldn't have that option. Indeed, there's now not even any area left where most of my friends live: we've all scattered further and further afield, and not coincidentally many of us are finding our lives a little more lonely and a little more isolated than we did five years ago. 
As our cities become more competitive and more expensive, people are under more pressure. And if you're already stretched taut, it doesn't take much of a pluck for things to snap.
Sadly this isn't news for Ned Cutcher from the Tenants' Union, who is acutely aware that there is "an incredible amount of strain on households. Rental insecurity means people live without stability, and having to frequently move - either because of rising rents or because owners decide to develop their properties - means people lose that closeness with their community."
And yes, we all need to prioritise self care and make responsible decisions to advocate for ourselves, but that assumes that we all have the resources to make those decisions - and that the options aren't all intolerable.
Moving is always stressful, and uncertainty about the future terrifies the best of us. But when the financial stakes are as uniquely high as they are, something as simple as being priced out of one's community can end in tearful eulogies and heartbroken families.
So whenever you see a politician or economist blithely talking about how belts must be tightened and tut-tutting about those living in the age of entitlement, remember that for a number of Australians it's not merely numbers on a spreadsheet; it's a death sentence. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tenants Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Homer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned Cutcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
