<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423524003031096</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/news-and-views/the-local-milk-people-have-emerged-as-the-meme-of-the-trumpturnbull-leaks-20170804-gxp5ts.html</url>
  <title>The 'local milk people' have emerged as the meme of the Trump-Turnbull leaks</title>
  <content>
Almost like a built-in stress ball, news stories about President Donald Trump tend to be accompanied by a resulting Internet meme.
Today, it is all about the "local milk people".Photo: AP
The US President used the phrase in his January phone conversation about immigration policy with Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull, which was Washington Post.
According to the transcript, Trump, in response to some confusion about Australia's immigration policy (turns out Trump thinks detaining people based on their mode of transport is pretty arbitrary: file that in your one-sleeve folder labelled, "things Donald Trump and GetUp! agree on"), asserted that he did not think the economic refugees former president Barack Obama had agreed to accept from Australia were the kind of people he wanted in Trump's America.
"I guarantee you they are bad," he said. "That is why they are in prison right now. They are not going to be wonderful people who go on to work for the local milk people."
But, who exactly are these local milk people who attract only the most wonderful of employees?

To start, there's an adjectival ambiguity: are the employers referred to local people associated with milk, or people of any origin associated with local milk?
Moreover, are the jobs they provide necessarily milk-based, or do they just like milk? Lots of people like milk. It's a great source of calcium. How much local milk does an employer need to consume before they can be considered a certified Local Milk Person™? Is there an accreditation process where state agents conduct random checks of your business to monitor the number of employees that take their tea white?
Are Green Card-holding breastfeeding mothers local milk people? What if they don't have proper documentation, but they began lactation on US soil? What then?
Perhaps narrowmindedly, the consensus appears to be that Trump was talking about the US Dairy industry. But, don't be too sad(!), the good (local milk) people of Twitter were quick off their mark with the jokes and memes. Here are some of the best.

Why do I suspect that "local milk people" didn't include any chocolate milk people?

You must learn to speak English to come to America. Words like "bigly,""covfefe" and "local milk people."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Card-holding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Milk Person</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Internet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Dairy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GetUp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
