<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423395154009925</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-04/tennessee-jail-surveillance-footage-shows-police-officer-repeatedly-tasering-teenager-who-is-tied-to/1691214</url>
  <title>Tennessee jail surveillance footage shows police officer repeatedly tasering teenager who is tied to chair</title>
  <content>
A teenager has filed a federal lawsuit after he was tied into a chair and tasered by police officers while in custody at Cheatham County jail in Tennessee, last November.
Newly released surveillance footage captured 18-year-old Jordan Norris restrained and then stunned with a taser by three police deputies.
The officers involved have been put on administrative leave, according to local news outlet The Tennessean.
Norris was arrested on November 3, 2016, and held at Cheatham County jail on drug-related charges and possession of prohibited weapons.
Two days later he was still held in the booking cell over behavioural issues and placed on suicide watch, according to The Patch.

External Link:

Tennessee police repeatedly use taser on teen
CCTV footage and footage taken from the camera on the taser capture the incident.
In one video, taken from the taser camera and matching the time period shown in the first video, an officer is heard saying, "I'll keep on doing that until I run out of batteries".
The footage is reminiscent of the Australian case of
The Four Corners investigation into Mr Voller's case sparked a  in the Northern Territory.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheatham County</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Norris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Voller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennessee</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennessean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
