<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423524003031091</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/trump-turnbull-transcript-refugee-deal-human-rights-groups/8774180</url>
  <title>Trump-Turnbull phone call transcript exposes 'gaping holes' in refugee deal, human rights groups say</title>
  <content>
The leaked transcript of Malcolm Turnbull's fiery January phone call with Donald Trump has drawn a furious political reaction from human rights groups, who say it has exposed "gaping holes" in the US refugee deal.
shows Mr Turnbull repeatedly pressed Mr Trump to stick with the agreement while the .
But the Prime Minister also emphasised the US was not obliged to take any refugees under the deal, and simply had to vet them for resettlement.
Daniel Webb, director of legal advocacy at the Human Rights Law Centre, said the refugee deal was "full of holes".
"The best proof, as they say, is in the pudding," he said.
"It's eight months since this deal was announced and not one single refugee in Manus or Nauru has received safety under it.
"That doesn't look like it's changing any time soon ... it looks like Malcolm Turnbull was pre-occupied with maintaining the facade of this deal."
Coalition frontbencher Josh Frydenberg denied that outright.
"The Prime Minister stood up for Australia's interests, he stood up for the deal he agreed with the Obama administration, and he made that point very forcefully as we already knew," Mr Frydenberg said.
"Quite clearly that is what we expect of our Prime Minister and that's what he's done."
But Mr Webb said the transcript highlighted the ongoing uncertainty about the agreement, which would take a psychological toll on refugees.
"When this deal was announced, for the first time in years you could hear some fleeting hope in the voices of the men on Manus and the families on Nauru," Mr Webb said.
"They thought finally the Government was acknowledging it couldn't just abandon them indefinitely. Having those hopes dashed again will be deeply painful."

Greens senator Nick McKim said the transcript also exposed that the US refugee deal was part of a people swap, despite the Government's denials.
The Government has agreed to resettle refugees from Central America, but has maintained that was not connected to the US refugee deal.
In the leaked transcript Mr Turnbull tells Mr Trump that Australia would take "anyone that you want us to take" if America honoured the refugee deal.
"Malcolm Turnbull has spent 10 months denying that Australia's engaged in a people swap with the US. This transcript ... puts the lie to what Mr Turnbull has said about this deal," Senator McKim said.
"The inhumanity with which Malcolm Turnbull speaks about refugees is absolutely shocking."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Law Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Webb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator McKim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick McKim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
