<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423524003031109</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/new-data-shows-just-how-close-an-air-canada-plane-was-to-causing-one-of-the-greatest-aviation-disasters-in-history/news-story/19930a6ef5aa501f9bab895a15e9fcbd</url>
  <title>New data shows just how close an Air Canada plane was to causing one of the greatest aviation disasters in history</title>
  <content>
Timelapse shows Air Canada's new livery being painted
1:29

This timelapse video shows Air Canada's new livery being painted. Courtesy: Vimeo/Air Canada

February 10th 2017
6 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Travel - News.com.au/

New data shows just how close an Air Canada plane was to causing one of the greatest aviation disasters in history.

AP

Share

NEWLY released data and photos show how shockingly close an Air Canada plane came to triggering one of the worst disasters in aviation history.
Last month, an Air Canada pilot narrowly avoided disaster when he almost landed on a crowded taxiway at San Francisco airport.
The Air Canada pilot mistook the taxiway for the runway next to it and flew their jet to just 59 feet (18 metres) above ground before pulling up to attempt another landing, according to National Transportation Safety Board information released this week.
That's barely taller than the four planes that were on the taxiway when the incident occurred late at night on July 7.

This new image reveals just how close an Air Canada Flight came to landing on the taxiway, where four other planes were grounded. Photo: NTSB via APSource:AP
Pilots in a United Airlines plane alerted air traffic controllers about the offcourse jet, while the crew of a Philippine Airlines jet behind it switched on their plane's landing lights in an apparent last-ditch danger signal to Air Canada.
NTSB investigators said they have not determined probable cause for the incident that came within a few feet of becoming one of the worst disasters in aviation history.
"It was close, much too close," said John Cox, a safety consultant and retired airline pilot.
The investigators said that as the Air Canada jet approached the taxiway just before midnight after a flight from Toronto, it was so far off course that it did not appear on a radar system used to prevent runway collisions.
Those systems were not designed to spot planes that are lined up to land on a taxiway - a rare occurrence, especially for airline pilots. But the Federal Aviation Administration is working on modifications so they can, agency spokesman Ian Gregor said.

Both pilots of the Air Canada Airbus A320 jet were very experienced. The captain, who was flying the plane, had more than 20,000 hours of flying time, and the co-pilot had about 10,000 hours.
The pilots told investigators "that they did not recall seeing aircraft on taxiway but that something did not look right to them," the NTSB said.
Investigators could not hear what the Air Canada captain and co-pilot said to each other during the aborted landing because their conversation was recorded over when the plane made other flights, starting with a San Francisco to Montreal trip the next morning. Recorders are required to capture only the last two hours of a plane's flying time.
Peter Fitzpatrick, a spokesman for Air Canada, declined to comment, citing the ongoing investigation.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Canada Flight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Transportation Safety Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JULY 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vimeo/Air Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NTSB</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Canada</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Fitzpatrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Gregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Canada Airbus A320</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Aviation Administration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippine Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montreal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
