<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423524003031125</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/11/42/victoria-melbourne-weather-extreme-snow-blizzard-wind</url>
  <title>Melbourne shivered through coldest day in 19 years and there</title>
  <content>
Melbourne, hold on to your hat.
While the capital won't see winds as strong as last Saturday, gusts of up to 90km/h are still expected with warnings in place for the weekend, the Bureau of Meteorology has advised.
Damaging winds in coastal parts of Victoria and Melbourne are forecast for Saturday, Sunday and early on Monday, senior forecaster for BoM's extreme weather desk Scott Williams said.
"It'll be mainly Saturday night and Sunday, and the wind won't go away until Monday," he said.
Melbourne shivered through its coldest day in almost 20 years yesterday, reaching a top of just 9C. It was the coldest August day since 1970.
The morning started at just 3C, with heavy fog blanketing the city throughout the day.
"By far the strongest system will come through Saturday night in from the west. The biggest impacts will be up in the Alpine parts - a substantial amount of snow is expected," Mr Williams said, adding 1m of fresh snowfall and winds of 90-110km/h would be likely with poor visibility.

Related Articles

The worst affected area -with blizzard conditions - will be Mount Hotham, Mr Williams said.
Falls Creek and Mount Buller will also get a substantial amount of snow.
It comes after gusts of up to 130km/h swept through Victoria last Saturday, prompting hundreds of calls to the State Emergency Service.
The heaviest rain is set for the north-east parts of the state, and the south-west including the Grampians. Around 50mm is forecast for the south-west coast.
 The State Emergency Service said it was a reminder that winter "is still well and truly with us".
"Exercise caution if you're at the snow, take the advice of mountain ski patrols, and please play it safe. It's going to be big dumps.... Blizzards can pose dangers and we don't want anyone going missing," he said.
"We're paying attention to coastal areas in the south-west and through to the Mornington Peninsula, and obviously the Alpine areas."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Buller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Hotham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Emergency Service</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grampian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Williams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alpine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C. It</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
