<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423485348324881</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/world/what-trumpturnbull-leaks-really-reveal/news-story/6870c637a0a26f235b3e39fb232ca3cb</url>
  <title>What Trump/Turnbull leaks really reveal</title>
  <content>
THE stark and damning take-out from the leaked Donald Trump transcripts is how little the President has grown into the job.
Seven months ago he struggled with facts, was absorbed in cushioning his ego, and was cavalier about honouring agreements.
They remain elements of the Trump style and swagger, without the reasonable excuse he has just started to learn the job.
He continues to be worried he will be seen as a fool, almost as much as he is apprehensive about damage to the US. He wants to play news media with his own version of events.
And he continues to readily blame predecessor Barack Obama for his problems.
The unauthorised release of the late-January transcripts of telephone calls by President Trump to Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull and Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto obviously established something in addition.
Since he was sworn in on January 20 Mr Trump has been fighting leaks and leakers, and this embarrassing release through The Washington Post showed he has failed.
He has sacked eight prominent staff members and administration officials, harassed media outlets and individual reporters, and cut the flow of public information.
Yet he has not been able to halt the parade of revelations humiliating him and his family.
The conversations with both the Australian leader (24 minutes) and the Mexican leader (53 minutes) were illuminating and remarkable for simply bring made public.
World leaders rely on free and confidential exchanges without the public looking over their shoulders. Without that confidentiality there might be no room for negotiation, compromise and progress.
So the publication of the transcripts was extraordinary in itself as a glimpse into the dynamics of discussions at the highest political level.
The frankness will shock some.
"You cannot say that to the press," Mr Trump said again and again to President Nieto on his refusal to pay for a wall with the United States.
With Malcolm Turnbull the issue was a standing agreement for the US to take asylum seekers now on Manus and Nauru.
"I look like a dope," the President bleated. He had just issued an executive order halting the arrival of citizens from seven Middle Eastern nations.
And further: " This will make me look terrible."
The gnawing impression, however, is he had little idea what they were discussing, despite brushing up from his Vice-President Mike Pence and administration officials.
Mr Trump kept referring to 2000 asylum seekers and Mr Turnbull kept correcting him with the figure of 1250.
"I've also heard like 5000 as well," the President persisted.
He said: "The only way that I can do this is to say that my predecessor made a deal and I have no option than to honour the deal," the President said.
"I hate having to do it, but I am still going to vet them very closely. Suppose I vet them closely and I do not take any?"
Mr Turnbull replied, possibly with a tone of exasperation: "That is the point I have been trying to make."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 20 Mr Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
