<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423231945250419</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/jayde-kendall-memorial-walk-spread-vital-message/3208709/</url>
  <title>Murdered schoolgirl's family to spread safety message</title>
  <content>
IT'S BEEN almost two years since the murder of Gatton schoolgirl Jayde Kendall rocked the Lockyer Valley but time has done little to dent the determination of her family to find a source of hope from the tragedy.

Led by grandfather Denis Morrissey her loved ones are channelling their despair at her loss towards helping create positive change.

On August 14 - two years to the day since Jayde went missing - friends, family and members of the community will take to the same streets that she once walked down for the Jayde Kendall Day of Awareness Walk.

Mr Morrissey said the event held in her honour had an important message aimed at raising awareness about personal safety.

A massive crowd showed their support by walking in the Jayde Kendall Day of Awareness Walk on Sunday, August 14.Tom Threadingham

"We want people to be aware of where they are, of what they are doing, of who they are with and the circumstances that they might be putting themselves in and to always tell someone where they are going," Mr Morrissey said.

"(Jayde's death) shouldn't have happened but we're focused now on the young people and we hope that we'll get generational change in people's attitudes."

He spoke of the support and generosity of the Lockyer Valley towards his family at such a difficult time.

"It's just been tremendous - we can't speak highly enough of everyone here and this is also an effort to give something back to the community and help improve things as well as a way that people here can share it and help reinvigorate the message each year," he said.

He estimated that up to 200 people attended last year's event and encouraged people to put on some purple and join the walk again this year.

"The day will bring a mixture of emotions. Not just to me, but everyone I think.

"There will be happiness, but also sadness."

The walk will start at 4pm from the Lockyer District State High School side gate on High View Avenue and make it's way towards the Jayde Kendall memorial at the Lockyer Valley Cultural Centre.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>S BEEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14.Tom Threadingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockyer Valley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrissey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockyer Valley Cultural Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayde Kendall Day of Awareness</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denis Morrissey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High View Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockyer District State High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayde Kendall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
