<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423481053357488</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/cranbourne-secondary-colleges-sene-smelley-beatboxing-in-victorian-state-schools-spectacular/news-story/b6067a5831cbc0e5223dee4a59ca3e41</url>
  <title>Sene shines in State School Spectacular</title>
  <content>
CRANBOURNE Secondary College's Sene Smelley is not only school captain and undertaking year 12 studies - he's also a rapper and beatboxer who's part of the Victorian State Schools Spectacular.
Smelley, 18, said this year would be the third time he'd taken part in the spectacular and he'd be
performing as principal vocalist and beatboxer in Hey Ya by OutKast.
"Music, rapping and beat-boxing has been one of my passions since I was younger," he said.
He hopes to make a career out of music or rapping in the future.
As part of that goal, he and the spectacular's cast have been rehearsing every weekend for months and spent a week of the last school holidays practising for the show.
"It's good to work with different people from around the state who all have a connection through
performing."
As for managing his time combining study, captain duties and rehearsals, he said it: "can be hard at times. I have to use my time wisely and find the time to do homework."
The Schools Spectacular will be held at Hisense Arena on Saturday, September 16 at 1pm and 6.30pm.
Tickets: or 132 849.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hisense Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Ya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schools Spectacular</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State School Spectacular</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smelley, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outkast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRANBOURNE Secondary College's Sene Smelley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian State Schools Spectacular</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
