<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423446693618433</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65464/vfacts-july-toyota-rules-as-market-heads-for-another-record</url>
  <title>VFACTS July | Toyota Rules As Market Heads For Another Record</title>
  <content>
Australia's new car sales figures are in for July and the tally points to yet another record year in the making with 92,754 new cars sold in July and a running total of 692,306 for the year, up 0.4 percent compared to 2016's record result.
Compared with June's results, sales took a dive, though with the end of financial year incentives and a big push for sales July was never going to match the previous month
Continuing its long-term trend Toyota dominated the sales charts with five vehicles appearing in the top 10, led by the HiLux ute on 3742 sales, and closely followed by the Corolla in the number two spot on 3208 sales.

Toyota also extended its lead over Ford's top selling Ranger ute, with 3072 sales for Ford's top-seller, placing it in third position. The Mazda3 landed fourth spot with 3466 sales and the Toyota Camry claimed fifth on 2385 sales - a position that's expected to evaporate once Toyota ceases local Camry production later this year.
Australia's favourite SUV was the Mazda CX-5 which took sixth place (2305 sales), topping the Toyota RAV4 (1736) and Hyundai Tucson (1719). Once again the Toyota LandCruiser poked its head into the top 10 however deceptively the sales tally includes the workhorse LandCruiser 70 Series ute and troop carrier and wagon with the scarcely related 200 Series range.

The shifting sands of Australia's new car market also saw traditionally strong-selling small car sales eroded compared to the same time last year with Hyundai's i30 losing 33.6 percent of its sales momentum, Corolla sales slowing by 5.5 percent, and Mazda3 figures taking a 5.0 percent cut - but in their place medium SUV sales continued to pick up pace.
Hyundai Tucson sales were boosted by 31.1 percent, the Toyota RAV4 climbed 8.6 percent, and Mazda CX-5 found an extra 4.8 percent. Small cars dipped by 4.1 percent and medium cars took a 6.3 percent tumble, but the medium SUV segment grew by 16.6 percent in comparison.

Once Australia's favourite car, the Holden Commodore continued its ongoing sales decline as Australian production wraps up with only 1633 units moved in July seeing a further decline of 17.4 percent year to date against 2016's results.
Brands on the way up include Mitsubishi, which built a 7.1 percent gain on the strength of its SUV and ute ranges despite an ageing fleet of vehicles while Kia continues its march up the board as it chases its sister brand Hyundai with a whopping 32.8 per cent sales growth this year.

Top 10 brands not doing as well include Holden, which dipped 11.8 percent landing the number four spot behind Toyota, Mazda and Hyundai, although Hyundai is down 7.5 percent too. Nissan sales fell by 12.3 percent and Volkswagen declined 3.1 percent compared to the state of play this time last year.
MORE News & Reviews:  |  |  |  |
Top 10 Selling Brands - July 2017
- 17,931 (up 6.0 percent YTD)
- 9528 (up 2.3 percent)
- 7501 (down 7.5 percent)
- 6467 (down 11.8 percent)
- 6270 (down 0.6 percent)
- 6020 (up 7.1 percent)
- 4266 (up 32.8 percent)
- 4265 (up 10.2 percent)
- 4094 (down 12.3 percent)
- 3803 (down 3.1 percent)
Top 10 Selling Models - July 2017
- 3742 (27,120 sales YTD)
- 3208 (22,662)
- 3076 (24,714)
- 2466 (20,518)
- 2385 (14,083)
- 2305 (15,229)
- 2123 (16,660)
- 1736 (12,547)
- 1719 (14,555)
- 1713 (12306)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota RAV4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai Tucson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Landcruiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LandCruiser 70 Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selling Models</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota RAV4 (1736</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selling Brands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Camry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai Tucson (1719</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nissan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFACTS July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Rules As Market Heads For Another Record</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YTD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2017</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Commodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda CX-5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corolla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
