<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423489643292209</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/revenue-is-sliding-at-james-packers-crown-resorts-as-vip-gamblers-fade-from-view-2017-8</url>
  <title>Revenue is sliding at James Packer's Crown Resorts as VIP gamblers fade from view</title>
  <content>
James Packer's Crown Resorts today posted a 7.5% fall in annual revenue to $3.34 billion, dragged down by fewer VIP players making big bets at Australian casinos.

Statutory net profit after tax was up 96.7% to $1.86 billion but this included  $1.55 billion in one-off gains including the sale of shares in the group's troubled Macau holdings.

Normalised profit was $343.1 million, down 15.5%.

Crown Resorts faces a number of issues, including a decline in VIP gamblers from China following a crackdown there which saw Crown staff arrested for allegedly spruiking gambling.

Packer this week  to take a more hands-on approach to his 48.2% holding in the gaming business.

Executive chairman of Crown John Alexander says the full year results reflect difficult trading conditions.

Total normalised revenue across Crown's Australian resorts fell  by 12.7%.

"This decline was due primarily to the reduction in VIP program play revenue in Australia, which was down 48.9% on the prior comparable period," he says.

"Gaming revenue also decreased by 1.4%, with Melbourne flat and softness in Perth."

Crown declared a final dividend, franked to 60%, of 30 cents a share, down from 39.5 cents the year before.

The company also plans a further on-market share buy-back of up to 29.3 million shares. Crown completed a $500 million on-market share buy-back in June.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer's Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
