<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423489643292244</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/antiabortion-protester-launches-legal-challenge-in-bid-to-fight-harassing-accusation-20170803-gxou5x.html</url>
  <title>Anti-abortion protester launches legal challenge in bid to fight harassing accusation</title>
  <content>
An anti-abortion protester accused of harassing a couple outside a clinic will argue her constitutional right to free speech means her case should be thrown out.
Kathleen Clubb​, a mother of 13, is believed to be the first person charged under new safe-zone laws that prohibit protests within 150 metres of abortion clinics.Photo: Paul Jeffers
The laws also stop pro-life protesters from making contact with people entering or leaving clinics in a way that could cause distress or anxiety.
Ms Clubb, 51, handed a pamphlet to a couple outside the Fertility Control Clinic in East Melbourne on August 4 last year, and is charged with a single count of communicating about abortions with people accessing an abortion clinic.
She doesn't dispute her actions but argues that the laws are discriminatory.
She is yet to formally enter a plea but on Thursday her lawyer challenged Victoria's constitution, in regard to the safe zones, in Melbourne Magistrates Court.

Defence counsel Christopher Brohier​ said the laws were invalid because they affected a person's freedom of political communication, and discriminatory because they were targeted at pro-life protesters, and not pro-choice supporters.
The laws also affected indiscriminate parts of Victoria, Mr Brohier said, as they made it illegal to discuss abortions in a 150-metre radius outside all the 11 major providers of abortions in the state, any other service providers and the clinics of about 100 GPs who prescribe morning-after pills.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr Brohier said the the legislation applied to indiscriminate parts of the state, "and yet the conduct is criminalised".
The laws, he said, in effect outlawed any discussion about abortion in any home, shop, restaurant or office that fell within 150 metres of a clinic, hospital or GP that provided abortion services, and the locations where women took morning-after pills.
Lawyers for the state government are resisting Ms Clubb's legal challenge.
"The state is here to uphold the validity of the law," Melinda Richards, SC, for the state government, told the court earlier on Thursday.
Ms Richards is set to respond on Friday to Mr Brohier's submissions.
Police allege Ms Clubb was directly outside the entrance of the clinic when she approached the couple in full view of officers.
"She was holding pamphlets on the topics of pregnancy and abortion, that's not disputed," prosecutor Ruth Champion told the court.
"What she said is not known.
"She tried to hand them a pamphlet or pamphlets, the couple did not take anything and entered the clinic."
The hearing continues before magistrate Luisa Bazzani​.
With AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Brohier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-abortion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melinda Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathleen Clubb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luisa Bazzani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brohier</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fertility Control Clinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Clubb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Clubb, 51</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth Champion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
