<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423528297998528</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-04/macadamia-crop-losses-this-year-masks-a-cracking-future/8773656</url>
  <title>Macadamia crop losses this year masks a cracking future</title>
  <content>
The impact of extreme weather looks like it will buck a growing trend this year, causing macadamia prices to rise as a recent forecast for Australia's crop was revised down 13 per cent.
Farmgate has valued this year's crop at around $280 million, with 47,000 tonnes in-shell at 10 per cent moisture.
Australian Macadamia Society chief executive officer Jolyon Burnett said growers had been hoping for another record harvest, but it was hit hard by drought, hail, Cyclone Debbie and record rainfall in the Northern Rivers.
"When we first forecast the 2017 crop we were hoping for about 54,000 tonnes at 10 per cent moisture," Mr Burnett said.

"That would have made it the third record crop running and four years of steady consecutive growth. We were pretty excited."

But severe weather events got in the way.
"Bundaberg, for example, was drought-declared early in the year, and then about a week or two later cyclone Debbie came through," Mr Burnett said.

Jolyon Burnett says severe weather has reduced this year's crop forecast by 13 per cent.

Jolyon Burnett says severe weather has reduced this year's crop forecast by 13 per cent.

ABC Rural: Kim Honan

"In Gympie and the Glass House Mountains we've had some of the hottest and driest weather for a decade, shortly followed by Debbie, and finally in New South Wales we had two weeks of steady rain that left a lot of the crop lying on the ground.
"Once it's washed from the orchard floor there's no way of recovering it."
The industry average price for 2016 was posted at $5.50 per kilogram, in-shell.
"We've had five years of year-on-year price growth and again I think it's a reflection of the very strong demand for macadamias, both here in Australia and in the 44 countries around the world that we export to," he said.
"I haven't been in the industry as long as many and I can remember when the price was around about $1.30.

"I think we need to keep in mind that it wasn't that long ago that the industry would have been very excited by a 47,000 tonne crop."

Macadamia nuts are sold in-shell or dehusked.

Macadamia nuts are sold in-shell or dehusked.

Supplied: Australian Macadamia Society

Flooding rains a blessing and curse

Gympie macadamia grower Nic Emery is reaping the benefits of a steady water supply.
"Our own particular farm, we actually have increased our yield from last season but that may be because we're fully irrigated and were able to keep the water up to the trees for that full time," Mr Emery said.
But the 25 growers that the Emery's contract harvest for did not fare as well, with their orchards affected by drought and a hail storm.
"Across the board we've seen roughly a 20-30 per cent yield drop from last season," Mr Emery said.
"Our last delivery usually goes into the processors in the first week of December and this season we're already looking to be complete by the end of September.
"That's the effect that (the weather) had, not only on the individual farmers and their crops but all of the aligned industries as well, all of the equipment, the contract harvesting also gets affected by it.
"But optimism's still exceptionally good. There are a lot of really exciting things happening in the industry.

"There are a number of people looking to purchase farms. There are a lot of buyers out there, not too many sellers at the moment."

Suncoast Gold Macadamias CEO Lisa Worthington inspects nut by-product, part of a suite of products.

Suncoast Gold Macadamias CEO Lisa Worthington inspects nut by-product, part of a suite of products.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Processors adapting to lower forecast

In the past year, the Emerys have increased the number of farms they contract harvest for from 15 to 25.
Their home farm now acts as a consolidation facility - storing nuts from other growers to collectively increase their bargaining power with processors.
"If you've got a whole lot of smaller growers that can accumulate all their nut together they can realise higher prices usually reserved for the larger growers," Mr Emery said.
The downturn in supply has meant processors have had to plan carefully.
"We take our product from New South Wales right through to far north Queensland, so the actual individual regions have all reacted a little bit differently," Suncoast Gold Macadamias CEO Lisa Worthington said.
"It's not too significant when you look at some agricultural crops and how they can vary. However, it is down a little on what we were hoping for.

"The main challenge is to manage your cost and also to ensure that the customers are not let down on their orders which we tend to make much earlier in the year."

Around 30 per cent of Suncoast Gold Macadamia's product is consumed domestically, with Japan and the US large customers.
The company is focused on opening markets in developing Asian areas and into Europe.
"One of the areas that we don't focus a lot on is our nut in-shell export direct to China. We are therefore able to send less under these circumstances and make sure that our processing clients, the ones that take the kernel from us, are not short on their orders," Ms Worthington said.
With South Africa suffering from severe drought, Australia is currently producing more macadamias than anywhere else in the world.
Jolyon Burnett said the nation's growers are recognised for innovation and the appetite for quality Australian macadamias continues to rise.

"The really exciting thing about the macadamia industry is that currently we make up just two per cent of the world trade in tree nuts and 80 per cent of our kernel is sold in just five markets - Australia being one of them - so the opportunity for growth in the market is just immense," she said.

"We're just beginning to develop the Chinese market. That's gone from zero to about 30 per cent of our crop in five years.
"Huge markets such as India, Indonesia, Malaysia, many parts of Asia, remain completely untapped.
"Without sort of wanting to sound too hyperbolic, the sky really is the limit."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glass House Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncoast Gold Macadamias CEO Lisa Worthington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundaberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Worthington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Burnett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Rural</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Nichols</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debbie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Rivers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Honan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Emery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolyon Burnett</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Emery</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Macadamia Society</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncoast Gold Macadamia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emery</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
