<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423532592965856</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/why-sophie-turner-is-fighting-against-hollywoods-body-standards-20170804-gxp6ns.html</url>
  <title>Why Sophie Turner is fighting against Hollywood's body standards</title>
  <content>
Since becoming an international star in  Game of Thrones, Sophie Turner has been unapologetically candid on the "f----- up" pressure for young actors to conform to the industry's body standards.
In an interview in the new , the 21-year-old, who has cemented her place as a muse for creative director of Louis Vuitton, Nicolas Ghesquiere, opened up on the balancing act between being a role model for young women and maintaining a physique which will continue to earn her roles.Photo: Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP
Joining the cast of Game of Thrones as Sansa Stark as a 13-years-old, Turner has had what she describes as "a gradual" rise to fame. Yet the role model status andcriticism that comes along with it is still something she is getting used to.
Having openly discussed her battle with body criticism in the past, the actor revealed that the stepping into the fashion world and more red carpets has made her more susceptible to self-pressure.Photo: Supplied/Porter Magazine
" I was consumed with thoughts on weight and the idea that you has to be skinny to be an actress, and that I wasn't skinny enough to get jobs," she told Porter, as the magazine's first digital cover star.
"There are times when I have done jobs and they've told me that I have to lose weight, even when it has nothing to do with the character:  It is so f----- up."

But Turner said she has taught herself to realise the "real problem" is not with influential women creating unattainable beauty ideals, but rather the industry itself which is yet to adopt diverse representation.
"It's a real problem in the industry and as much as I would like to be the champion for girls who aren't skinny minis, it is so difficult to do that and maintain a career. So now I think as long as I work out and I'm healthy that is what is important, but also to keep speaking about it."
Admitting that she still remains "vulnerable" at events like the Met Gala in which she wore a nude and white embellished Louis Vuitton gown, Turner said being part of Ghesquiere's fearless girl gang which includes her friend Alicia Vikander is an empowering experience.
"It is 100 per cent more terrifying than the Oscars or Golden Globes," the star said of the Met Gala.
" I feel exposed on the carpet, but to be an LV girl gives me some protection as Nicolas' designs have a warrior vibe; they give me an empowering strength and make me feel like a badass chic. I'm transforming myself into a role each time I put one on."

Ghesquiere and Turner pictured together in the magazine. Photo: Supplied/ Porter Magazine

Currently dating musician Joe Jonas, Turner has previously told Edit magazinethat exercise was key in helping her out of a dark place that came with worrying about her body image.
" I went through a bit of a dark place, I think for me, and for every young girl out there, body image is such a big thing," she said
"When I was forced to get into shape and eat healthily, my skin cleared up and I felt energetic all the time. It totally changed me."
Last year, she also took part in Huffington Post'ssaying that it was important for women to band together and champion diversity because we will always be "scrutinised" on social media no matter our physique.
"I just think it's really horrible that women are body shaming each other and fat shaming each other when women should be championing each other.

Sophie Turner pictured in Louis Vuitton, which she wore throughout the shoot. Photo: Supplied/Porter Magazine

The young actress, who revealed she earned a major role over an established actress because of social media following, admitted that she has been encouraged to tone down her rebuttal to criticism and political stances, not understanding how much it could implicate on her fame. 
"I was sort of eased into the whole fame thing," Turner said. " It didn't go from zero to everything like it did for someone like Jennifer Lawrence; it's quietly built up over the years."
"It was so gradual I still treated my life and social media like I wasn't in the public eye. I was a 15-year-old girl writing rash political stuff that would get a negative reaction and my team would tell me to take it down. Now I'm learning to keep the my mouth shut."
The one criticism that Turner will not remain silent over however is GOT's treatment of women being labelled "sexist", a label that she vocally rejected during the Porter interview. While her character has had a terrible time having being married twice, tortured and kidnapped, the actor said the "feminist show" importantly represents strong female characters that are forces to be reckoned with.
"The women in GOT rise above every social and political barrier put in front of them and constantly break with tradition. The women are the strongest characters, much more terrifying that the men, and that is what is amazing to me. It is a feminist show."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supplied/Porter Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas Ghesquiere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louis Vuitton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Met Gala</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alicia Vikander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ghesquiere</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JENNIFER LAWRENCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Globes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porter Magazine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huffington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Jonas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Turner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
