<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422544750471108</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832629/candle-retailer-recalls-ethanol-burners/?cs=7</url>
  <title>dusk safety recall of MoodFlame burners 2017</title>
  <content>
dusk Australia has issued a recall of its decorative alcohol fuelled products sold from December 2010 to December 2016. 
The products, titled MoodFlame(R), do not meet a newly released safety standard for ethanol burners. 
Tasmanians in posession of a MoodFlame(R) should return the product to their nearest dusk store for a full refund. 

Picture: dusk product safety recall
Federal Small Business Minister Michael McCormack said the , released on July 10, would ensure consumers' safety. 
"Decorative burners have caused more than 100 injuries and at least 36 house fires across Australia since 2010. There have also been at least three deaths that occurred overseas," he said.

As of July 15, 2017, the new standard prevented the supply of table top burners which weigh less than eight kilograms or have a footprint less than 900 square centimetres; and required freestanding and fixed devices to meet a stablity test, come with a fuel container with a flame arrester or an automatic fuel pump system and display warnings on the device about refuelling hazards. 
Cooking and heating products were exempt from the safety standard. 
A  on the devices was enforced in December 2016.  
Mr McCormack said there were tough penalties for selling products which do not comply with a safety standard.

Individuals can face a maximum fine of $220,000 and corporations facing a maximum fine of $1.1 million.

dusk Australasia PTY LTD can be contacted Monday to Friday from 9am to 5pm on 1300 387 543.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McCormack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasia PTY LTD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Small Business Minister Michael McCormack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoodFlame</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
