<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422884052893617</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Mining</source>
  <url>https://www.australianmining.com.au/news/new-mastermyne-contract-appin-boost-employment/</url>
  <title>New Mastermyne contract at Appin to boost employment - Australian Mining</title>
  <content>
Latest News

Mastermyne has been awarded a contract to supply development labour to South32's Illawarra coal operations at the Appin Colliery in New South Wales.
The scope of works will be delivered as a variation under Mastermyne's existing contract with South32.
Mastermyne's new contract scope involves the provision of mine roadway development. It is expected to employ 130 people and deliver around $20 million in revenue.
The work will be performed in parallel with Mastermyne's existing contract to provide process works and supplementary labour in the Appin mine longwall area.
Mastermyne expects the workforce for the combined contracts to average around 280 personnel, with increases during peak periods.
The initial two-year contract with South32, which includes an option for a one-year extension, was launched in November 2016.
Mastermyne chief executive Tony Caruso comented: "We are very pleased to have secured this new project and further extend our working relationship with South32's Illawarra metallurgical coal operations."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Caruso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appin Colliery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Mastermyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mastermyne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South32</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
