<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423532592965873</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/coastal-properties-were-prominent-on-the-list-of-homes-most-house-hunters-checked-out-this-week/news-story/d478e3e7a1dcc0647342cd0aa624cd2c</url>
  <title>Coastal properties were prominent on the list of homes most house hunters checked out this week - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
7 Secret Valley, Buderim

WHILE a Corinda home was Queensland's most viewed property listing this week, coastal homes also proved to be in hot demand.
According to realestate.com.au a home at was the most viewed on its site in Queensland this week.
The home described as a Palm Springs style home has six bedrooms and is scheduled for auction on August 26.

227 Dewar Tce, Corinda

The next most popular was a home at on the Sunshine Coast, which was listed for offers of more than $700,000.
The four-bedroom home is next to a neighbouring private council reserve. The home has a games area and oversized stacker doors which lead to a covered deck.
A four-bedroom at seeking offers of more than $399,000 has already been placed under contract. It came third on the list.

33 Crestridge Crescent, Oxenford

The home was described as suitable for a first homebuyer or investor.
Fourth most popular this week was .
The three-bedroom home is listed for offers of more than $795,000. It is a classic 1930s Queenslander which has been updated throughout. It has an open lounge room and dining spaces and an enclosed sunroom.

18 Susan St, Greenslopes

It was back to the coast for the fifth most popular listing this week, a four-bedroom home at .
It is listed for offers of more than $500,000.

35 Jones Rd, Buderim

The split-level home has bush views and a large rear deck with overlooks green bushland.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dewar Tce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxenford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corinda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenslopes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palm Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crestridge Crescent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
