<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422669304525220</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/green-says-simple-footy-wont-let-cowboys-survive-s/3208491/</url>
  <title>Green says simple footy won't let Cowboys survive Storm</title>
  <content>
COWBOYS coach Paul Green has ordered his team to unleash the shackles against Melbourne Storm to avoid being "choked to death" by the masters of slowing down the ruck. 
The Storm have built a reputation as the best wrestlers in the competition with skipper Cameron Smith taking advantage of the extra space to lay on four tries in last week's 40-6 thrashing of Manly. 
The Cowboys know simple football, which they've adopted since Johnathan Thurston was ruled out for the year through injury, won't be enough to break down the league's stingiest defence. 
The match is a virtual must win for fifth-placed North Queensland if they want to keep their top four hopes alive. 
A win could see them enter the top four, but a loss could place them just two points ahead of ninth spot. 
They are also looking to avoid a fifth straight loss against the Storm, their last victory coming in the 2015 preliminary final when they went on to win their maiden premiership. 
"Things like ball control and discipline, they're the masters of that so you have to be good there, but you also have to play footy," Green said.
"If you play normal one-out footy or don't play with one eye open, they'll just choke you to death. 
"You need to be prepared to play some footy." 
The Cowboys showed they're working toward unveiling a more expansive game by laying on two tries with well executed set plays against the Roosters last week. 
They squandered a 16-6 halftime lead to go down 22-16, but it has resulted in a more intense build up after Green said some players may have approached the clash against the second-placed Roosters like "just another game".
"You'd like to think when you're playing the competition leaders the boys would be up for it," Green said. 
"You need to have an awareness of their threats but they're smart enough players to be able to adjust on the run. You put too much time into one particular part they do they'll just change it."
Middle forward Shaun Fensom (rib cartilage) trained strongly on Thursday and will return to the line-up in place of youngster Braden Uele after he missed the Roosters clash. 
Tonight's match will be the first chance for Cowboys fans to watch 2018 recruit Jordan McLean in action after the Storm prop returned from five weeks out with a hamstring injury against Manly. 
"Our last four or five games to finish the season, every game is a big one," Cowboys prop Scott Bolton said. 
"There'll be a lot of tough games coming up and none of them are just like another one, we have to take them as if they are minor semi finals. 
"We'll be looking to do that this week and Melbourne is one of the bigger games we've got." 
Two Gold Coast men held hostage at Gympie camp
Man believed to be unconscious before horror highway smash
Doctors said Jazmin would be dead before she was three
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Fensom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazmin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braden Uele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
