<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423528297998454</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/edward-john-herbert-jailed-for-17-years-for-dousing-children-on-petrol-setting-daughter-alight/news-story/82b4ae4553ea5a29af6eb58d65e80c67</url>
  <title>Father jailed for 17 years for setting child on fire</title>
  <content>
A FATHER-of-three who doused two of his children in petrol and set one of them alight in her cot was jailed for 17 years for his "horrendous" crimes. 
After weeks of alcohol and cannabis abuse, Edward John Herbert poured petrol over his three-year-old's head and set the toddler on fire in his Doubleview unit in August 2015.
He then turned his attention to his seven-year-old daughter, who has significant disabilities and could not respond to the horror unfolding around her, and started dousing her in the accelerant.
The girls were rescued by off-duty police officer Stephanie Bochorsky, who ran into the house and dragged the children to safety after hearing their mother's screams for help.
Herbert claimed he could not be found guilty of criminal charges on the ground of insanity, but he was convicted of trying to kill his daughters after a judge-alone trial earlier this year.
In sentencing the 45-year-old on August 3, Supreme Court Justice Lindy Jenkins said he breached his duty to protect his children from harm in a "horrendous fashion".
Justice Jenkins told the court Herbert was experiencing psychosis and had bipolar effective disorder at the time of the attacks.
She said Herbert consumed "grossly excessive" amounts of cannabis despite the fact he knew or should have known from past experience that the drug had a terrible impact on his mental health.
Herbert was also found guilty of threatening to kill his partner, being armed with a knife in circumstances likely to cause fear and doing an act likely to endanger life with intent to harm.
After he set his daughter on fire and disfigured her face, Herbert told a neighbour he burnt the girl because she was "too beautiful".
The toddler had "serious and life-threatening" burns to 13 per cent of her body and spent about three months in hospital.
In a letter to Justice Jenkins, Herbert said not a day went by that he did not worry about his injured little girl.
"I am so sorry," he wrote. "I am in a living hell now, not because of being imprisoned but because of what I did to my daughter."
Justice Jenkins praised the actions of neighbours and police on the night, saying Const. Bochorsky acted with "extreme bravery".
"Her actions in all likelihood saved the lives of these two young girls," she said.
Outside court, the children's great uncle Trevor Hayden said no sentence would ever be long enough for what Herbert did.
Herbert was made eligible for parole and his sentence was backdated to August 2015.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Jenkins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court Justice Lindy Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Hayden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward John Herbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herbert</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bochorsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Bochorsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Const</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doubleview</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
