<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423141750935765</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/most-popular-wallet-kickstarter-v2-2016-4</url>
  <title>People are so excited about this wallet that it's become the biggest one in Kickstarter history</title>
  <content>
The  team writes about stuff we think you'll like. Business Insider has affiliate partnerships so we get a share of the revenue from your purchase.

For all their utility, most wallets are still too bulky for guys to comfortably and discreetly carry in their back pocket.

Enter the most successful wallet project in Kickstarter history and our pick for the best alternative to the traditional bifold: .

Brooklyn designer Jack Sutter got the idea for the wallet from a friend who was using a rubber band from a broccoli stem to hold his cards and cash. It was perfect, simple, and small in his pocket. Likewise, TGT wallets offer comfort, lightness, and ample pocket space; and they afford guys the ability to leave unnecessary bags at home. They're also handmade in the US by local craftsmen and artisans.

TGT wallets come in a variety of different colours; the Americana pictured here has red, white, and blue stripes and is a customer favourite. The . Have a closer look below:

TGT Tight Wallets

TGT Tight Wallets

TGT Tight Wallets

TGT Tight Wallets

TGT Tight Wallets

You can buy TGT's Americana Deluxe Wallet at

This article was originally published on 4/21/2016.

More from Insider Picks:

If you want to see more from Insider Picks, we're collecting emails for an upcoming newsletter. You'll be the first to hear about the stuff we cover.  .

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>TGT Tight Wallets</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TGT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kickstarter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TGT's Americana Deluxe Wallet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Sutter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Picks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
