<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422836808252333</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/queensland/news/police-seek-information-on-man-missing-since-february-2015/news-story/6e2dcf832e51f68e1c8f1e2502a169b8</url>
  <title>Police seek information on man missing since February 2015</title>
  <content>
Detective Inspector Damien Hansen has appealed for information over the suspicious disappearance of Sam Purcell-Price.

Share

POLICE are appealing for the public to help locate a 28-year-old Queensland man who hasn't been heard from in almost two and a half years ago.
Sam Price-Purcell was last seen in the South East Queensland area on February 16, 2015.
Appealing for assistance for the first time since Mr Price-Purcell disappeared, police say they are treating his disappearance as "suspicious".
Queensland Homicide Group Detective Inspector Damien Hansen has asked for anyone who knew Mr Price-Purcell in 2015 and may be able to help to come forward.

Sam Price hasn't been seen since February 2015.Source:Supplied
"At this stage we are treating this matter as a suspicious disappearance and we are specifically calling for anyone who has information regarding Mr Price-Purcell's movements in early 2015 or his current whereabouts to come forward," he said.
Mr Price Purcell, known as Sam Price, is described as being of caucasian appearance, about 185cm tall with a thin build, short brown hair and brown eyes.
It is the first time police have appealed for assistance in locating the young man.
Detectives are expected to reveal further information in a media conference this morning.
Anyone with information is urged to contact Policelink on 131 444 or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Purcell-Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Homicide Group Detective Inspector Damien Hansen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Policelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Price</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Price-Purcell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Damien Hansen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South East Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Price-Purcell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
