<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423352204336360</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832657/bears-beer-blog-red-hill-imperial-stout/?cs=12</url>
  <title>BEAR'S BEER BLOG - Red Hill Imperial Stout</title>
  <content>
Sometimes it's a good idea to read the label.
This imperial stout from Red Hill on Victoria's Mornington Peninsula spent a few weeks lying on its side in my fridge.

That's because - like most higher-alcohol beers (this is 8.1 per cent) - I was a bit wary.

High alcohol beers aren't really a sessionable thing, something you can have a few of without a drama.
Also, it can get a bit dicey if you have one of them on top of a few "normal" beers. That extra alcohol can have a tendency to creep up on you.
But I digress. This beer was in the fridge lying on its side. I took it out and poured it into a glass.
Then I read the label, which included the recommendation to "stand upright in the fridge".
Whoops. That would explain the streak of yeast running along the inside of the bottle from top to bottom.
Not that my error would have changed the nature of the beer that much.
Drinking it, I found it hard to believe it was an 8.1 per cent imperial stout.

There is barely a hint of that alcohol count on the palate. Instead it is a ridiculously smooth beer - and perhaps one that may be a smidge dangerous for those unaware it clocks in at over 8 per cent.
Flavourwise, it's a mix of coffee/mocha and dark chocolate characters, and the brewers have used hops they grow at the brewery for some added local flavour.
The beer wins awards each year at the Australian International Beer Awards and it's not hard to see why.

Glen Humphries is an award-winning beer writer and author of .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Humphries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian International Beer Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEER BLOG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill Imperial Stout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flavourwise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
