<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423184700609329</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/this-city-unit-block-pays-its-own-way-grossing-186000-a-year/news-story/a8868583035beb6ee4d812a41251de24</url>
  <title>This city unit block pays its own way, grossing $186,000 a year - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
AN entire inner-city unit block, which earns $186,000 a year, is set to fire up investors when it goes under the hammer this weekend.
The 12-unit, 16 bedroom, 12 car space property at , was built in the 1970s, and has come on the market for just the second time in over 45 years, according to agent Richard Mirosch of LJ Hooker Stafford.

There are 12 units in the complex. Picture: Realestate.com.au

The property is on the market for just the second time in 45 years. Picture: Realestate.com.au

The unit complex is on a 1,455sq m block zoned medium residential up to five levels.
Its quarterly costs include rates of about $2626.92, water and sewerage:$2614.25 and community power $135. Insurance costs were about $4571.59 per annum, according to the Realestate.com.au listing.
"This cash cow is to be sold in one line and has low vacancy rates, giving the buyer a strong holding income of approximately $186,000 a year gross fully tenanted," according to Mr Mirosch.

Some of the units have been updated. Picture: Realestate.com.au

There are opportunities to add value. Picture: Realestate.com.au

There are 12 living rooms in the complex. Picture: Realestate.com.au

"So much future potential to add more units with this land rich property (subject to BCC approval)".
Ten of the units are one bedders and two are three bed apartments, all with lockup garages.
Mr Mirosch believed a "developer, self managed super fund or astute investor will realise the potential of this land rich property and future landbank opportunity".
The property is open for inspection from 11.30 to noon this Saturday (August 5) and will be auctioned off at 1pm in-room at LJ Hooker Stafford (205 Stafford Rd, Stafford).
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realestate</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mirosch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooker Stafford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Mirosch of LJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stafford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ Hooker Stafford (205 Stafford Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
