<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423536887933274</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/nsw/police-reveal-two-plots-planned-by-sydney-terror-suspects-20170803-gxp3no.html</url>
  <title>Police reveal two plots planned by Sydney terror suspects </title>
  <content>
An Islamic State commander sent components to Sydney to build an improvised explosive device that was to be taken on an Etihad flight, police allege.
In what has been labelled one of the most serious plots to have ever been attempted on Australian soil, police on Friday detailed the extent of the alleged terrorism conspiracy, shaped in Sydney. 

Up Next

Lauryn Eagle charged with drug driving

00:25

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Two charged over Sydney terror plot

Police have released more details about the plot to place a bomb on a flight out of Sydney, as they charged two people with terror offences.

The plan involved two bomb plots. The first allegedly involved taking the IED on the flight out of Sydney Airport on July 15 but it was abandoned. 
A second plot allegedly related to the building of an improvised chemical dispersion device to release colourless toxic gas in a crowded space, possibly on public transport.

The alleged plotters were arrested in raids across Sydney last Saturday.
"This is one of the most sophisticated plots that has ever been attempted on Australian soil," Australian Federal Police Deputy Commissioner Michael Phelan said on Friday.

On Thursday night, the  Mahmoud Khayat, 32, and Khaled Mahmoud Khayat, 49, each with two counts of acting in preparation for or planning a terrorist act. 
The pair's case was briefly mentioned in Parramatta Local Court on Friday. There was no application for bail and the case was adjourned to November 14. The maximum penalty each could face is life imprisonment.Photo: AP
Mr Phelan said there was "conjecture" as to why the IED was not placed on the flight on July 15, but said at no stage did the device make its way into the secure section of the airport.
"At no stage did the IED breach security," he said.Photo: DEAN LEWINS
"The IED [components were] sent through international cargo. With assistance from the ISIL commander, the accused assembled the IED - so the components of the IED, into what we believe was a functioning IED to be placed on that flight."
The second plot, relating to the improvised chemical dispersion, was allegedly to be taken to a "crowded closed space".
"One of the things we will be alleging, though, that there were some, I must preface this by saying very preliminary and hypothetical, information put forward by the controller overseas to one of the people that's been charged about the types of places that you might want to put a chemical dispersion device," Mr Phelan said.
"They were talking about crowded closed spaces, you know, potentially public transport, and so on."
However, police said the plans for the chemical dispersion device was a "long way from being functional".
"This hydrogen sulphide is very difficult to make so I want to make it quite clear that, whilst it may have been a hypothetical plot for these people to put forward, we were a long way from having a functional device." 
Police would not divulge the identity of the Islamic State commander who sent the explosives to Sydney, only to say he was "not Australian" and was "not related to any of the targets".
Mr Phelan said it was a "concern" that Islamic State had been able to send the components to Australia from Turkey but said extra measures had now been put in place to screen cargo.
Justice Minister Michael Keenan said on Friday that screening of air cargo would be bolstered in light of the revelations. 
"You would appreciate it is a very big job to screen - and Australia is a very open economy, there is an enormous number of packages moving both inward and outward on any given day," he said.
"But we've taken measures to improve screening, and [Border Protection] Minister [Peter] Dutton will continue to assess what we learnt from this particular plot, and what other measures we might need to take to ensure the security of the air cargo system."
Mr Keenan said that, if it wasn't for the work of law enforcement, the outcome could have been catastrophic. 
Police will allege that the men in Sydney had been in speaking to the Islamic State commander since April. 
Timeline of the alleged plot

April - Some of the men allegedly involved in the plot start communicating with a senior Islamic State figure in Syria who instructs them on how to make a bomb. The group allegedly order military-grade explosive components in the post from Turkey. 
July 15 - Khaled Khayat, 49, allegedly escorts his unwitting brother to Sydney Airport to board an Etihad flight to Abu Dhabi with luggage containing a bomb. The bag is not checked in, possibly because it is too heavy, so Khayat takes it home with him while his brother, who was unaware of the bomb, boards his flight as planned.
July 17 - Khayat's brother-in-law, Khaled Merhi, who remains in custody, sets up a business Khaleds Powder Coating Services. The men allegedly start working on a gas dispersion device.
July 26 - US and British agencies pass on intelligence picked up from Syria about the alleged plot. Australian police start investigating immediately and put the men under surveillance.
July 27 - Security measures at Sydney Airport are enhanced on the advice of ASIO.
July 27-31 - Police create a mock IED like the one created on July 15 and test whether it would get through airport security. It doesn't.
July 29 - Four men are arrested in five raids across Sydney.
July 30 - Security is enhanced at all major Australian airports.
August 1 - Khaled Merhi's brother Abdul Merhi is released without charge.
August 3 - Charges laid against Khaled and Mahmoud Khayat.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IED</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khayat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Minister Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauryn Eagle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Khayat, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaleds Powder Coating Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat, 49</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Mahmoud Khayat, 49</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Phelan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Merhi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Lewins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police Deputy Commissioner Michael Phelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
