<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423450988585830</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:32</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/north-adelaide-electricity-blackout-caused-by-gas-workers-digging-around-power-pipes/news-story/cb1c0a8e1203892aa09be56a86366e7e</url>
  <title>Gas pipe dig blamed for North Adelaide blackout</title>
  <content>
WORKMAN digging for gas accidentally caused a blackout to North Adelaide, leaving homes, businesses and the Women's and Children's hospital without power.
Almost 300 properties were affected after a power line was believed to have been ruptured by gas workers digging around pipes along King William St at 5am on Friday.
The outage, which lasted for almost four hours before the last customer had their power restored, hit the main roads from the northern suburbs into the city.
It also caused chaos for some businesses along the usually busy O'Connell Street, causing some to lose thousands of dollars in sales.
The WCH's back-up generators "immediately kicked in" and did not affect services, a spokeswoman said. "It was business as usual," she added.
Traffic lights were hit along Main North Rd, Prospect Rd, O'Connell and Tynte streets as well as Barton, Fitzroy and Pennington terraces.
Bakery On O'Connell assistant manager James Kent, 28, said the business had lost several thousand dollars in produce, which was either thrown out or given away.
Bakers were told to come into work later while planning for this weekend's Showdown was hit.
"It has been frustrating," he said.
Crews managed to restore power to the majority of customers, and traffic lights, just after 7am while most electricity returned by 8.20am. The last customer's power was restored at 8.50am.
An SA Power Networks spokesman, Paul Roberts, said 280 customers were affected.
Initial investigations suggested that gas workers accidentally hit a power cable, during overnight works near the WCH.
Workers had, however, taken the appropriate precautions and checked with authorities about what power cables were located around their worksite.
"They did the right thing but unfortunately it appears they struck a cable," said Mr Roberts.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bakery On O'Connell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Power Networks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Workman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Connell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main North Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WCH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King William St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Connell Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tynte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pennington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
