<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423536887933253</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/deals-get-this-movie-screenwriting-tool-for-40-off/</url>
  <title>Deals: Get This Movie Screenwriting Tool For 40% Off</title>
  <content>
You shouldn't have to fuss with trivial details when you're writing the next great screenplay. That's why top writing talent like JJ Abrams, James Cameron, and Aaron Sorkin use  to turn their ideas into award-winning hits.

The industry standard for professional screenwriters and studios worldwide, Final Draft 10 takes the hassle out of formatting and paginating your scripts, so you can spend more time writing Emmy-worthy content. With Final Draft 10, your scripts are automatically paginated to industry standards, and you can use more than 100 templates to streamline your screenplays, teleplays, stage plays, and the like.

Now, you can start writing smarter with Final Draft 10 for 40 percent off its usual price.  [$149.99 USD]. And for a limited time, get an extra 15 percent off with code FINALDRAFT15.

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

All deals are carefully vetted to ensure relevance and value to Gizmodo readers. Commerce Content is independent of Allure Media editorial and advertising, and if you buy something through our posts, we may get a small share of the sale. Click  to learn more.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Final Draft 10</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Get This Movie Screenwriting Tool For 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmy-worthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gizmodo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Sorkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allure Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commerce Content</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ Abrams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FINALDRAFT15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
