<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423446693618513</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/football/matildas-v-brazil-live-stream-tournament-of-nations-kickoff-time-how-to-watch-on-tv-score/news-story/8399ec866c2fb9288ecf463d6517373c</url>
  <title>Watch: Silverware as Matildas put SIX past Brazil</title>
  <content>
THE Matildas are the inaugural winners of the Tournament of Nations thanks to a superb 6-1 win over Brazil in Los Angeles.
Having beaten USA and Japan, Alen Stajcic's side need to just draw to ensure the silverware comes with them back to Australia.
Bringing silverware back home, before squaring off again against the Brazilians in two friendlies in Australia in September, is a sign of Australia's progress and at least some revenge for the heartbreak from 2016.
After enduring a horror start, conceding a goal after 68 seconds, the Matildas' response was outstanding, particularly in an entertaining, end-to-end first-half where they blew the Brazilians, the side that conquered them in controversial circumstances at the Rio Olympics one year ago, off the park.

Football: Brazil have scored in the first 68 seconds of their match against the Matildas.

Brazil score in 68 seconds
Lisa De Vanna showed great composure to slot home a finish on the rebound after an eighth minute penalty was saved by Brazil goalkeeper Dani Neuhaus, who was kept tremendously busy by the Australians' high octane style of play.

Football: Lisa De Vanna has scored a penalty goal to equalise with Brazil in the tournament of nations event.

Matildas strike back
Then, it became the Sam Kerr show.
The superstar surged down the right, and then the left, to tee up goals for Caitlin Foord, and then De Vanna again, who became the Matildas' all time leading scorer with her 42nd strike.

.
MATCH CENTRE:

Football: Caitlin Foord has scored for the Matildas on the counter attack to give them a 2-1 lead over Brazil.

Foord scores on the counter
But the first-half party was not done yet, with Katrina Gorry showing her immense class to slot a fourth with a shot drilled across the face of goal, a chance carved by lightning feet on the edge of the box by the 24-year-old star.

Football: Lisa De Vanna and Samantha Kerr have blown apart the Brazilian defence to score in the first half of their Cup Of Nations match.

Kerr, De Vanna blitz Brazil
Australia added another two goals in the second-half; although the end-to-end action was less frenetic, the Matildas did not relent with their defensive attitude, with the Brazilians unable to force their way back into the contest.
The icing on the cake came when Tameka Butt unleashed Foord with an incisive through ball to make it five, before Kerr, the best player in the tournament - if not on the planet at the moment - got a much deserved goal, her fourth of the tournament, to round out the rout.
Australia 6, Brazil 1?
It sounds unfamiliar in football terms, and it's another display that will have the football world talking about the Matildas.

Football: Katrina Gorry has scored the fourth goal for Australia against Brazil.

Gorry gets Matildas fourth

Football: Caitlin Foord's second goal has given the Matildas a 5-1 lead and secured the win for the Australians.

Foord puts nail in the coffin

Football: Samantha Kerr has scored the Matildas sixth goal in a landslide win over Brazil.

Kerr completes AUS six-pack
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alen Stajcic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia) 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tameka Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cup Of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Vanna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Kerr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katrina Gorry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foord</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caitlin Foord</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa De Vanna</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dani Neuhaus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gorry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
