<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422445966221165</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/acid-attacker-david-phillips-has-jail-sentence-shortened/news-story/66a154ee8936915ad817cda60d97c5e8</url>
  <title>Acid attacker David Phillips has jail sentence shortened</title>
  <content>
Andreas Christopheros before the acid attack.

Emma LakeThe Sun

Share

WARNING: Graphic content
AN INNOCENT dad-of-one who lost 90 per cent of his face in a horror acid attack has called for the law to be changed as his attacker faces release after just eight years in jail.
Andreas Christopheros, 32, was attacked in his home after a thug knocked on the wrong door.
reports his attacker's sentence has now been reduced from life to 16 years, with the possibility of parole after eight.
Mr Christopheros, of Truro in England, said: "Three judges ended up concluding that life should be lifted from his sentence because he's deemed not to be a danger to society, which is probably the most baffling part of the whole story.
"It was a planned attack."
Mr Christopheros added: "I believe the UK has got its strategy towards this completely wrong.
"I strongly believe that the sentencing for anyone who carries out any form of acid attack, whether their intended victim is injured badly or not, should serve a life sentence, with a minimum term of 20 or more years."
In December 2014, Mr Christopheros, who has a four-year-old son, believed a courier bringing Christmas presents was at his door.

Andreas Christopheros after the acid attack.Source:Snapper Media

Andreas Christopheros pictured in September 2010, before the acid attack. Picture: FacebookSource:Facebook
Instead a stranger threw a beaker of sulfuric acid in his face, saying: "This is for you, mate."
His attacker believed he was targeting someone who had sexually assaulted a family member, but had knocked on the wrong door, instead inflicting a brutal assault on an innocent man.
Mr Christopheros said: "My T-shirt disintegrated from top to bottom, it just rolled away into nothing. The pain was inexplicable."
He was rushed to hospital where doctors told his wife and mother he may not live through the night. He said he was on "death watch" for weeks because of the risk of infection.
Ninety per cent of Christopheros' face has been reconstructed using skin from other parts of his body, including his scalp and neck.
He has had between 10 and 12 surgeries and will need more.
The dad has also lost his eyelids three times as scarring on his face contracts, making sleep a constant struggle.
"Not having eyelids has probably been the most torturous thing that I've been through," he said. "You can't hide from the light. You can't shut your eyes."

\Andreas Christopheros was on death watch after the acid attack.Source:Snapper Media
After pleading guilty, his attacker, David Phillips, was initially sentenced to life in prison with a minimum term of eight years, but this was reduced on appeal.
An online search reveals multiple websites selling 96 per cent sulfuric acid, which Phillips used in the attack.
One litre can be bought for less than $25.
"A litre would be enough to destroy a dozen people's lives, maybe more. Anyone can buy that," Mr Christopheros said.
He added that he is not the only one calling for changes to the law, with victim Adele Bellis slamming soft sentences after her attacker was freed after just two years.
After a recent spate of acid attacks, including one in June in which two cousins were doused with acid through a car window as they were out celebrating a birthday, Home Secretary Amber Rudd announced a review.
There have been several acid attacks in London since, from robberies to gang-related violence - including five attacks on delivery drivers in just one evening.
The Home Office has said it plans to set out guidance for prosecutors on classifying corrosive substances as dangerous weapons and to review sentencing guidelines.
"Other key actions will include a review of the Poisons Act to assess whether it should cover more acids and harmful substances and further work with retailers to agree measures to restrict the sales of acids and other corrosive substances," said Sarah Newton, minister for crime, safeguarding and vulnerability.

Andreas Christopheros was left scarred for life after a man hurled acid in his face.Source:Snapper Media
Acid attacks in London jumped in 2016 to 431 from 261 in 2015 with 282 so far this year.
Jaf Shah, executive director of London-based non-profit Acid Survivors Trust International, has called for acid to be treated like knives or guns.
He said: "There just aren't appropriate levels of controls around acid," Shah said.
"If you are caught with acid, police have to prove intent, which is very difficult."
Injuries suffered by victims of acid attacks can require hundreds of surgeries and years of recovery.
Even after extensive treatments, victims typically have scars for the rest of their lives.
"Sometimes people never recover if they have lifelong disfigurement and deformity," said Professor Peter Dziewulski, spokesman for the British Association of Plastic, Reconstructive and Aesthetic Surgeons. He has treated 20 patients in 2017.
After the rise in incidents doctors have issued guidance on how the public can help acid attack victims.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poisons Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aesthetic Surgeons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary Amber Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma LakeThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Christopheros, of Truro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopheros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele Bellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Christopheros</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FacebookSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaf Shah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapper Media</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andreas Christopheros</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andreas Christopheros, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Association of Plastic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Newton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Peter Dziewulski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Phillips</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acid Survivors Trust International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
