<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422574815242785</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/business/retail/flagship-westfield-centre-in-melbourne-hit-by-spate-of-violent-crimes/news-story/2bb40bcf4e898fbd198a95c7d6af0f43</url>
  <title>Flagship Westfield centre in Melbourne hit by spate of violent crimes</title>
  <content>
There has been a string of violent crimes at Westfield Doncaster this year. Picture: Supplied

Andrew RogersManningham Leader

Share

POLICE have been forced to step in as one of the country's top shopping centres struggles with a growing violent crime spree.
Bosses from Westfield have already removed outside seating from some parts of its Doncaster mall in Melbourne to prevent teens hanging around. A police report is expected to recommend extending security lighting and CCTV.
Westfield Doncaster is the shopping centre giant's flagship shopping centre in Melbourne.
Beleaguered centre management have been meeting regularly with local police, Manningham Council, Public Transport Victoria and Transdev after numerous reports of assaults and robberies at bus stops and carparks in the centre.
Officers from Doncaster will meet with Westfield representatives next Wednesday night with the report expected to be finalised inside a fortnight.
Victoria Police transit officers started patrolling Westfield back in May after a 21-year-old man allegedly stole a bus and drove it about 100m before a Transdev driver managed to stop the vehicle.
Accused thief Cameron Morley - known in Blackburn, Doncaster and Templestowe - last month failed to appear in Ringwood Magistrates' Court to answer charges relating to the incident. Five warrants have been issued for his arrest.
There have been a string of unrelated crimes at or near the shopping centre since February.
In May, a 14-year-old was attacked and had his phone stolen while waiting for his parents to pick him up from a car park outside the centre. The thug fled on a Templestowe-bound bus.

And in another attack, a teen was allegedly robbed of his watch, shoes and other jewellery in a brazen daylight attack at a bus stop near the centre. Three men have been charged over the incident.
Fed up authorities will now look at further crime-fighting options.
Doncaster Sergeant Jodie Vickers said the transit operations were on top of uniform and plain clothes patrolling Westfield.

Doncaster Sergeant Jodie Vickers says police meet at least once a month with Westfield Doncaster centre management.Source:News Limited
"We're in the process of putting a report together to look at ways to address issues through lighting and CCTV," she said.
"We try to meet at least once a month (with centre management) to discuss ongoing issues."
Sgt Vickers said crime at the Doncaster centre was at a similar level to other shopping centres and that management were proactive and taking their advice.
Westfield spokeswoman Julia Webb said the safety and security of customers and retailers at was management's priority.
"We don't provide commentary on our security practices and procedures, however, they are reviewed on an ongoing basis," she said.
"In the case of Doncaster we are working with groups like Victoria Police and Public Transport Victoria to adjust our processes as necessary."
PTV declined to comment.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transdev</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Templestowe-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew RogersManningham Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Morley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Transport Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flagship Westfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sgt Vickers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manningham Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doncaster</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Templestowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield Doncaster</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doncaster Sergeant Jodie Vickers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
