<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423266304989261</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/southport-spit-casino-rejection-developer-could-challenge/8774132</url>
  <title>Southport Spit casino rejection could face developer legal challenge</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Chinese consortium ASF is not ruling out a legal challenge to the Queensland Government's decision to reject its proposed $3 billion casino resort development on the Southport Spit.
ASF had planned a five-tower development on Crown land that included a casino, entertainment venues, theatres, hotels and residential apartments.
On Tuesday,  after months of community consultation, and that a new master plan would be developed instead.
This morning, ASF director Louis Chien told ABC Radio Brisbane the consortium was reviewing its next move.
"Nothing is off the table, including legal action, and we are clearly focused on what just happened and what needs to happen next," he said.
"Needless to say we're still in shock and deeply disappointed with this government and its snap decision this week."
Mr Chien said it was too early to say if ASF would resubmit a new development proposal to the State Government.

"We're reviewing all of our plans, so at the present moment we're focused on what just happened and everything else is on the backburner to be assessed," he said.
"This decision is obviously a devastating blow to investor confidence in Queensland.
"I think this decision brings in to question why would any sensible investor, who has choices of where to invest - and the world is a small place these days, you have a lot of choices in terms of where you can invest - even fathom coming in to Queensland under such an uncertain climate?
"No doubt this decision has and will continue to send shock waves throughout the business community, both onshore and offshore with the eyes of the world watching this high profile project.
"It's going to have a ripple effect, definitely."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louis Chien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport Spit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASF</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
