<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423107391196753</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4830390/truckin-on-in-the-west/?cs=2373</url>
  <title>Truckin' on in the west</title>
  <content>
SIT IN: Fries with pickled daikon, porcini, garlic and parmesan, bao buns, chicken ribs and Taiwanese soda. Picture: Max Mason-Hubers

For a couple of years people have waited patiently for their moment to taste the steamy, soft-as-a-cumulonimbus-cloud-like buns that sandwich in a whole mess of fresh, Asian inspired goodness.

Yet, a food truck is only so big, and so, inevitably, the Bao Brothers soon run out of such things, which means those who miss out are, typically, left sad and wondering.

The next chance for people to wrap their mouths around some soft and squashy baos is usually at the Newcastle City Farmer's Market, the next day. For those arriving late, however, a similar story tends to unpreventably play out as the Bao Brothers sell out of every last atom of their fantastic and formidably tasty foldable baos.

This familiar tale is told, almost every time, whenever and wherever the Baos Brothers park their food truck. The early bird gets the bao, as it were.
Not any more. The Bao Brothers have moved from the streets to the league.

NICE BUNS: Take a bao.
For the past few months, David Griffin and Nathan Martin (obviously, not really brothers), have been painting walls, plastering posters, and putting the final touches in their own space on Hunter Street, Newcastle West.

The only thing you'll be waiting for in this new joint is for your bao to arrive, alongside a number of other tasty morsels.
Between Rice's Bookshop and an op-shop, Bao Brothers makes the best of the relatively small space by dividing the dining areas into four unique places.

Up front, a bright neon sign, and a minimalist design of stacked stone, streaks of stainless steel and gold, coolly invite you in off the street and leads you through into a narrow space where hip hop's heavy hitters look down from one side of the wall (and spit loud on the speakers throughout).

This leads to a lantern-lit lane with a bamboo wall on one side and a black wall on the other that frames a length of lush green astro-turf hosting a row of multi-coloured chairs along a long, black timber bench.

Right next to this, set in a tiny alcove, is the Bao Brother's piece de resistance ... a cozy booth room plastered with movie posters drawn from many of the finest martial art movies made in the Far East and beyond. 
Of course, a dedicated restaurant means 'the brothers' can offer much more to eat (and drink) than their food trucks can, or do. For one, there's the addition of Korean rice cakes (spongy tubes of rice soaked in a morish 'hot 'n sweet' sauce with toasted sesames for texture) and the outstanding Sichuan chicken ribs (so crispy, so crunchy) served with a hypnotising pickled green chilli sauce (a beautiful balance between heat and sweet), a dollop of creamy Kewpie mayonnaise (to cool things down if things get too hot) and a few brittle leaves of not-so-ornamental basil.

You'll also find crunchy shoestring fries swathed in pickled daikon, porcini, black garlic and parmesan, a plateful of herbaceously nutty, charred broccolini, and a bowl of incredibly fresh slaw, made up of bean-shoots and chopped herbs dusted with chilli peanuts and drizzled with a delicious hot-and-sour-sauce.
Bao-wise, most of the food-truck favourites are there, right beside the welcome addition of a build-your-own-and-share-duck-bao, which you construct at your table with slices of delicately flavoured tea-smoked duck breast, slightly sweet tamarind sauce, and a zingy shallot and ginger paste.

The pleasurably textual contrast of the fried chicken bao cannot be overstated. Pillowy soft on the outside, cornflake crunchy on the inside with flavours to make your tastebuds dance and your insides smile. The same goes for the soft-shell crab topped with fermented chilli jam, pickled paw-paw and a spurt of Kewpie mayo. 

Everything is so fresh (and so clean, clean); all that's needed is a good glass of wine, or beer. In the meantime, until the brothers become licensed, wash down your bao with either a refreshing house-made ginger and kaffir lime, or, yuzu and palm sugar soda. And then, bao down in the presence of greatness.
QUICK BITE

What: Bao Brothers
Where: 701 Hunter St, Newcastle West
Owners: Nathan Martin, David Griffin
Drinks: House-made sodas and soft drinks
Hours: Wed-Sat, 11am-late
Vegetarian: Yes
Bottom Line: $70 for two, including drinks
Wheelchair Access: Yes
Do Try: Everything.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Farmer's Market</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Martin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bao Brothers</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Line: $70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baos Brothers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NICE BUNS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House-made</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Griffin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sichuan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bao-wise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rice's Bookshop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wed-Sat, 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kewpie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
