<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422428786351509</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:34</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/this-the-antitank-missile-that-the-us-sending-ukraine-2017-8</url>
  <title>This is the anti-tank missile that the US may be sending to Ukraine</title>
  <content>
Reports  on Monday that the US is planning to send defensive weapons to Ukraine in order to deter Russia, which has  and funded rebels in the Donbas. 

The plan includes sending Javelin anti-tank missile systems, and possibly anti-aircraft and other weapons systems. 

Developed by  in 1989, the FGM-148 Javelin is a large shoulder-mounted, infrared guided missile system capable of  600mm to 800mm steel armour.

The Javelin is a medium-range missile system that fires up to 1.5 miles,  about 50 pounds, and  about $US126,000 - plus $US78,000 for each missile.

Once the soldier has locked onto a target using the infrared guided system, he or she simply squeezes the trigger and then can take cover,  to the National Interest, because it's a fire-and-forget system. This means the operator doesn't have to make any adjustments to the missile flight after firing - as they do with most long-range systems. 

Ultimately, it's "one of the premier portable anti-tank missile systems in the world," the National Interest said. 

Reports have shown that Russian-backed separatists in the Donbas have Russian , , variants of , and even  tanks. 

Javelins can take out all of these, except possibly the  and . The latter two sport new  armour, which consists of an explosive layer of armour on top of another layer. They also have grenade and flare  that can divert missiles. 

Either way, the Javelin has  against Relikt armour, and therefore it's unknown if the missiles can take out the T-90s and T-72B3Ms. 

In any event, President Donald Trump still  on the plan - which could take months -  to send Ukraine the Javelin and other defensive weapons. 

There also remains speculation about the plan's intentions. "This idea doesn't flow from a policy or strategy" and could be a political move rather than military one, Michael Kofman, a Wilson Center senior fellow,  the Washington Post. 

Questions also remain about whether or not providing weapons to Kiev will inflame the conflict. While  are concerned that fighting will increase, some US officials, such as Kurt Volker, the US special representative to Ukraine, think it will decrease the fighting. 

Russia - which has  Syria to test out its new armaments - and even some US generals, however, are  to test how the east and west weapons match up against each other. 

At least 10,090 people - including 2,777 civilians - have been killed, and nearly 24,000 have been wounded, through May 15,  to the UN. More than 1.6 million people have been internally displaced.

Watch the Javelin in action: 

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Interest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Kofman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Volker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donbas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukraine</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US126,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FGM-148 Javelin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US78,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-72B3Ms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Relikt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
