<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422707959231533</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/golf/nba-superstar-stephen-curry-shoots-fourover-74-in-first-round-of-webcom-tours-ellie-may-classic/news-story/4963170b11449271ab22b309f28efbb4</url>
  <title>'Darn impressive' Curry mixes it with golf pros</title>
  <content>
NOT that we should be surprised, but Stephen Curry is really, really good at golf.
The NBA superstar made his debut appearance on golf's Web.com Tour on Friday (AEST) and more than held his own among the pros.
The Golden State Warriors sharpshooter - rated a 3000-1 winning chance by bookmakers - accepted a sponsor's invite to the event to play as an amateur.
LIVE stream the PGA Championship on FOX SPORTS. Get a free 2-week Foxtel Now trial & stream LIVE within minutes.

Golf: NBA superstar Steph Curry has tapped in for birdie playing in the Ellie May Classic golf event.

Curry's effortless birdie

He made a nervy start when his hooked opening drive landed in a golf cart cup holder, but showed plenty of talent and composure as he bagged three birdies in a four-over-par opening round of 74.
"It was an amazing experience," Curry said.
"I've been looking forward to this since I found out and to finally hit my first shot in tournament play was a really nervous moment, but it was everything that I hoped for.
"If you told me i was going to shoot 74 going into the first round, I'd take that all day, everyday.
"Happy with it, but obviously, as a competitor you always feel like you can play better so hopefully I can do that tomorrow."
The round had Curry sitting 146th in the 156-man field late on the first day's play. However his score gave him some chance of surviving the weekend cut in what would be a remarkable achievement.
"I don't know how to assess this situation, really," Curry said.
"I'll probably check the scores this afternoon and see how everyone's going. As it goes (tomorrow) hopefully I'll know what I need to shoot to give myself a chance (of making the cut)
"But I probably shouldn't have said that because I don't want the extra pressure".

Steph Curry: 74 (+4). Hit 8/18 GIR, 4/10 scrambling, 27 putts. Finished 1 shot ahead of Sam Ryder, player in his group, who won 2 weeks ago.

Steph Curry posts 74, doesn't embarrass himself and generates significant interest in a Web event. But please, keep those lame takes coming.

Steph Curry shoots 74 with 3 birdies, 5 bogeys and a double. Pretty darn impressive for a basketball player among pro golfers.

Golf has long been a passion for the Warriors guard, who plays off an impressive two handicap. He has previously spoken of an ambition to become a professional golfer after his career in basketball is over.
He came fourth in last month's American Century Championship pro-am.
- with AAP

Golf: Jordan Spieth has pulled off a miraculous shot where he admits he will have to try something stupid. It resulted in his ball landing on the green within 13 feet of the hole.

Spieth's stupid shot pays off
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GIR, 4/10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spieth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Century Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie May Classic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PGA Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Curry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph Curry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Spieth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden State Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph Curry: 74 (+4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
