<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422922707599977</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/rubiks-cube-master-feliks-zemdegs-talks-speed-cubing/8769346</url>
  <title>Rubik's cube master takes you inside the world of professional 'speed-cubers'</title>
  <content>
Welcome to the world of professional Rubik's cube solving.
It's a place where "speed-cubers" are flown around the globe for competitions, earn sponsorship deals and build social media followings that can be parlayed into big money.
And in this world, 21-year-old Melbourne man Feliks Zemdegs is officially the best.
In December he set the world record for solving the traditional 3x3 cube - doing it in just 4.73 seconds.

External Link:

Feliks Zemdegs solves Rubik's cube in 4.73 seconds
That is impressive, considering it is estimated there are 43 quintillion ways to scramble a Rubik's cube, although it's also said that all combinations can be solved in a maximum of 20 moves.
So how did Zemdegs rocket to the top?
"I went on YouTube. I decided to look up tutorials and learn how to solve it from there and got addicted," he said.

There is no great secret to solving the cube incredibly fast, he said. No particular mindset or way of thinking is required.
He is not a maths whiz - "I'm OK at maths, nothing special" - and really it all just comes down to time.
"For me I've been doing it for nearly 10 years now and I started when I was young," he said.
"I had a lot of time to practice, and you need that.
"If you start solving when you're 16-17 these days I don't think there's enough time for you to get good before you have to actually move on to other things."
The stats back this up.
Zemdegs has just returned from the World Championships in Paris where he was the oldest competitor in the finals.
He is now focusing on other things as well, like his engineering degree at university - although he is still keeping a hand in the game.
Later this year he is flying to China - paid for by his Chinese manufacturer sponsor - to appear in a game show that pits people from around the world against locals in various games.
Zemdegs also has a YouTube page with nearly 200,000 subscribers, which provides another revenue stream via the ads on the site.

External Link:

Feliks' step-by-step guide for pro cubing
Feliks' top tips for speed-cubing

Don't stick to one colour. Most beginners when they learn how to solve a cube get taught to solve it on the white side or starting with the white side. But my tip is sometimes the white side isn't always the easiest one to solve, so it's good to flexible in terms of what colour you start with.
Use all the resources available online. There's so many different videos on YouTube and websites that will teach you so many different methods to solve the cube. Anyone with a bit of patience and plenty of practice time can learn how to solve the cube.
After you learn a beginner method for solving the cube, the three main and most popular methods are the CFOP method, the Roux method and the ZZ method. So learn all of those and see which one you like the most and then use that.
Zemdeg's preferred method is the first one: CFOP.
"So the method that I and most top speed-cubers use involves building the cube from the bottom upwards," he said.
"So if you think about it in terms of layers, you've got the bottom layer, the middle layer and then the top one, so you build from the bottom up."
And don't even think about swapping some of the stickers on the cube around.
"The cube becomes unsolvable."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feliks Zemdegs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ZZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rubik</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feliks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zemdegs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFOP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
