<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422325707134000</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/top-runners-begin-bid-to-make-qld-final/3208402/</url>
  <title>Top runners begin bid to make Qld final</title>
  <content>
THE National Championships of greyhound racing are currently under way around the land.

The first state finals to be run will be at Launceston on Monday night.

Given that Tasmania has won the National Sprint Championship once in the 53 years history of the race and has never won a National Distance final, it's reasonable to suggest their runners won't be a serious threat to the other states when the grand finals are run at Albion Park in Brisbane on Friday, August 25.

Queensland's heats will be run next Thursday night.

Being the host state, we get two runners into each grand final.

There's an interesting scenario concerning the National Distance Championship.

Victoria was supposed to conduct heats at the Meadows tomorrow night.

But there were only nine final nominations so there are no heats - just one race which will serve as that state's final.

Six states compete, and with the host state getting two runners, that leaves the eighth spot to be filled in the grand final. That goes to the highest ranked greyhound in Australia which contests a state final but doesn't win.

There are two outstanding stayers in the race at the Meadows tomorrow night, Fanta Bale and Burn One Down. They are the highest ranked stayers in Australia at present.

Assuming one of them wins, the other will gain entry into the grand final as well.

If neither wins, Fanta Bale, being ranked number one, would get the spot ahead of Burn One Down.

For the Queensland heats at Albion Park this Thursday, there are 34 nominations for the sprint heats and 14 for the distance.

Those nominations closed a fortnight ago and some of the runners won't proceed for various reasons, mainly lack of form.

Our National Distance part of the series could, like the Meadows, end up as one race only with no heats.

The fields will be declared on Monday.

Ipswich hopes

THREE of the entrants for the Queensland heats of the National Distance Championship are racing at the Ipswich Showgrounds tomorrow night.

Ray Burman has Champagne Sally and Aussie Diamond running in the Stacey Electrical Stake over 630 metres. El Chad for Brad Yates is in the same race.

Realistically, they would all need to put in a good performance if they are to be a chance at the higher level next Thursday at Albion Park.

Champagne Sally is a front running type of stayer and might steal an early march on the other pair tomorrow night.

Growing pool

THE trainers' jackpot at Ipswich hasn't been won for several race meetings and is now up to $1220.

Cynthia Suttle had the jackpot dog last Tuesday. It was I'm Glad who loomed as the likely winner before finishing a close third.

Trainers are invited to pay five dollars per greyhound to be in the jackpot and when the figure gets to around where it is now, just about everybody participates.

The pool should jump to around $1400 or more today.

Consider this

NEVER worry about old flames. You should worry about new ones.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Diamond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Showgrounds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Burman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cynthia Suttle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champagne Sally</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fanta Bale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Distance Championship</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Distance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stacey Electrical Stake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burn One Down</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meadows</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Sprint Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Yates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>El Chad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
