<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423498233227037</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4830101/australias-most-unique-beach-property/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Australia's most unique beach property?</title>
  <content>
312 Teewah Beach Road, Noosa North Shore, could be the most unique beachfront property in Australia. Photo: Supplied

This could be Australia's ultimate - and most unique - beachfront estate.
Set on 77 acres of land and 34 metres above sea level with a staggering 500 metres of private and pristine beach frontage and only a few kilometres from  is so unique, it has stumped every valuer who has flown in from around Australia to put a price on it.
The problem is, says local Noosa agent  of , who is selling alongside  of , Sydney, there is nothing to compare it to.
In fact, Mr Reed says, he can't believe a property like this actually exists.
"I know that sounds a bit dramatic but honestly, for me, I just continue to go back to the fact it's hard to comprehend how something like this exists in ," Mr Reed says.

Last Christmas, a New York couple offered the owners a jaw-dropping $70,000 just to rent their property out for a mere 10 days. Photo: Supplied

"Any one of these elements that are in the property are unique in their own right - the 500-metre beach frontage, the 77 acres of land, the 34 metres of elevation, the 180-degree views, they are all incredible features - but the fact that these are all together, in one property, only minutes from the main street of Noosa...that's what makes it beyond belief."
And it would seem he's not the only one who thinks so.
Car manufacturer Mazda recently paid $5000 for the night to use the property for the launch of its CX5.
Last Christmas, a New York couple offered the owners a jaw-dropping $70,000 just to rent their property out for a mere 10 days.

What did the owners, long-time locals Liz and Peter Upton, say?
"We said no," Mr Upton shrugs. "Our kids come and stay here over Christmas and we wanted to all be together."

The views stretch from Double Island Point to all five bays of the national park. Photo: Supplied

For the Uptons, this beachfront utopia is simply their home. The site was nothing more than thick bushland and an unspoilt stretch of beach when they purchased it in 1999.
They spent two years labouring as their 750-square metre, five-bedroom two-storey home was constructed; since then, they've raised children, hosted parties and camped with friends and families under the stars while the waves crashed on the shore.
Certainly, their property has to be seen to be believed and properly understood. The sheer scale of the surroundings, like the nature reserves, national park and the uninterrupted 180-degree views from Noosa National Park and Main Beach north to Double Island Point are without rival. It's not the house that has left valuers wringing their hands - it's the position itself.

Owner Peter Upton goes surfing on his own private beach every day. Photo: Supplied

"It somehow captures and inspires everyone, whether you're a CEO, the highest of high rollers who wants to chopper into the house, or whether you're just someone who likes surfing and camping ... it has a way of connecting with and enchanting everyone who sees it," Mr Reed says.
The property is being sold by tender closing on Monday September 11 at 4pm and while it's expected someone will snap it up, the Uptons are anxious to see it go to someone who will treat it with the reverence it deserves.
"It's a pretty special place. For us it's home and we've made the most of it - we're campers and we've done a lot of that here ... I go surfing every single day. It's pretty magical," Mr Upton says.
As well as the house with its soaring ceilings, glass louvres, picture windows and multiple verandahs, the property comes with a private lock-up solar-powered beachfront shack with deck, fire pit and cubby house overlooking the surf.
Other notable features of the property include direct private vehicle access to the beachfront, easy access to the car ferry, vast level lawn (room to land a helicopter), a bountiful kitchen garden, freshwater lagoons and a creek.

domain.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Upton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Double Island Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teewah Beach Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Reed</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CX-5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Upton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday September 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa North Shore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
