<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423094506294669</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/whats-not-to-love-about-this-designer-beachside-penthouse/news-story/4dbc51ace5d5ef64d17adf1698e990b3</url>
  <title>What's not to love about this designer beachside penthouse? - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

The price of this Gold Coast penthouse has been slashed by several million dollars with hope someone will snap up the designer home.

3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

The four-bedroom, five-bathroom penthouse is at and is part of the Towers of Chevron Renaissance, crowning the main building on the 39th and 40th levels.
Kollosche Prestige Agents - Broadbeach selling agent Michael Kollosche said the property was reduced from $12,500,000 to $9,950,000.
"We had it on the market for seven months," Mr Kollosche said.
"We had an offer for $11 million but the approval didn't come through."

3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

Mr Kollosche said even with the price reduction, if the property sold, it would be the highest price for an apartment sale on the Gold Coast.
He said buyers from interstate and from Brisbane had shown a keen interest in the property.

The internal lift at 3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

Created over two years, this elegant penthouse required challenging structural changes to become a showcase for the latest design ideas from around the globe.

3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

Imagine having breakfast here at 3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

Expanses of glass in every room capture 360 degree panoramic views over the city, beaches, the blue Pacific Ocean, main river and Gold Coast hinterland.
There are no painted walls, but panels of timber veneer, smoked glass, imported marble or lustrous lacquered finishes in a caramel tone.
Living areas, featuring the finest in Italian designer furniture, look out to the nearby ocean, capturing a dazzling cityscape of lights after dark.

3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

Adjacent to the formal dining for 12 or more is a cigar and wine tasting area, flanked by integrated wine fridges behind smoky glass. The kitchen features a long breakfast bar of Diana Royal marble with a full array of top-range Miele appliances.

3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

The gym area at 3250/23 Ferny Avenue, Surfers Paradise.

A mirror-lined stairwell, illuminated by an exquisite crystal chandelier, leads up to a casual entertaining lounge with teppanyaki barbecue, billiards area, gymnasium and sauna at rooftop level.
Mr Kollosche said: "I have had the pleasure of selling some of the best prestige properties on the Gold Coast for almost 20 years and can honestly say I have never seen a penthouse that comes close to rivalling this property".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbeach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Kollosche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfers Paradise</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferny Avenue</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kollosche Prestige Agents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana Royal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renaissance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kollosche</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Towers of Chevron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
