<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422317117199096</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/soccer/la-liga-rejects-neymar-fee-over-psg-move-from-barcelona-20170803-gxozor.html</url>
  <title>Neymar settles La Liga dispute, signs five-year contract with PSG</title>
  <content>
Brazilian international Neymar has signed a five-year contract with Paris Saint-Germain (PSG)﻿ after protracted wrangling over his release clause from La Liga, according to French radio station RMC.
Lawyers representing Neymar visited La Liga in Madrid on Thursday to settle the transfer and pay the €222 million ($A330 million) break fee.

Up Next

War of words that turned cricket's pay war ugly

01:05

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Neymar leaving Barca, Spanish superclub confirms

Brazilian striker Neymar has informed Barcelona he plans to leave the club. The soccer superstar is expected to sign with Paris Saint-Germain (PSG) in a world record deal worth nearly $750 million.

Barcelona confirmed in a statement that the player's legal representatives had visited the club and made the payment to terminate his Spanish ties.
Barcelona said they would pass on details of the operation to UEFA, European football's governing body, "so that they can determine the disciplinary responsibilities that may arise from this case."

UEFA, whose financial fair play rules ban clubs from spending more than their generated revenue, could not be reached for comment.
A source from Spain's La Liga said earlier that the league had rejected the payment of the clause.Photo: AP
It was thought La Liga's refusal to accept payment could put the brakes on a transfer that mega-rich PSG believe will help them conquer the Champions League.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

PSG's president Nasser al-Khelaifi declined to comment when asked about the latest development during a visit to a children's holiday camp outside Paris, where French President Emmanuel Macron was also in attendance.
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French President Emmanuel Macron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain's La Liga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
