<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422707959231508</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/middle-east/dubai-tower-engulfed-in-flames-as-a-massive-blaze-breaks-out-in-the-worlds-tallest-residential-building/news-story/aa68c5bc1c488fe200cc2311303c7125</url>
  <title>Dubai tower engulfed in flames as a massive blaze breaks out in super tall residential building</title>
  <content>
Fire rips through Torch Tower in Dubai
0:38

A fire broke out at the Torch Tower in Dubai on August 3. Video of the tower shows fire spanning multiple floors with debris falling from the building. The same building was hit by a fire in 2015. Credit: Twitter/Mamad_ElShabazz via Storyful

August 4th 2017
42 minutes ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

A Dubai skyscraper is engulfed in flames

The Sun, staff writersNews Corp Australia Network

Share

ONE of the world's tallest residential building is engulfed in flames in Dubai.
Shocked onlookers have uploaded video to social media of the massive blaze at  in the United Arab Emirates holiday hotspot.
It marks the second fire at , in the world-famous Marina district, with an eerily similar incident in 2015.
Fire fighters are currently battling to bring the blaze under control.
#dubai#fire#marina#torch#building
Video taken at the scene shows flames spreading upwards - sending burning debris spiralling down and sparking a blaze in the streets below
Cara Spillane tweeted: "Terrifying to see Torch Tower, in the area I live in (Dubai Marina) on fire now. Hope everyone gets out OK."

A Dubai skyscraper is engulfed in flamesSource:Twitter

Still of a video shared to Twitter showing a massive blaze in a Dubai skyscraperSource:Twitter
Claire Hopkin added: "One of the skyscrapers near me is on FIRE! God! Hope everyone can get out. Scary seeing it!"
A man at the scene, John O'Nolan, said on Twitter that at least 15 floors appeared to be well alight.
Took this photo a few days ago - this is the tower which is on fire. It's huge.

Fire in Dubai marina getting bigger and spreading up building. Lot of debris. Can't tell which tower it is. Not many sirens
The cause of the fire and the current state of evacuation is not yet known.

A fire swept through the same building in February 2015 but was quickly brought under control. There were no fatalities in that blaze and seven people were treated smoke inhalation.
Dubai's glittering skyline has seen a number of similar fires in recent years.

Still of a video shared to Twitter showing a massive blaze in a Dubai skyscraperSource:Twitter

Fire engulfs Dubai residential skyscraper
0:46

A residential skyscraper in Dubai was engulfed in flames as a fire quickly spread up the outside of the building on Thursday night, August 3. It is the second fire to break out at the Torch Tower in Dubai Marina in two years. Credit: Twitter/DaliaKaki via Storyful

August 4th 2017
15 minutes ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>flamesSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter/Mamad_ElShabazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torch Tower</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Arab Emirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara Spillane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>writersNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai Marina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter/DaliaKaki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John O'Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Hopkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai skyscraperSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
