<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422321412166496</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/chadstone-shoppers-set-to-unleash-their-competitive-side-at-the-centres-luxury-arcade-precinct/news-story/8fce278ebffdcdd34bd383f301c7910d</url>
  <title>Fashion capital to host luxury bowling</title>
  <content>
CHADSTONE shoppers will get their game on with a luxury bowling alley and gold-plated skill tester to celebrate the centre's extended trading hours.
Club Royale, launching Saturday, is one of four major attractions and festivals the centre will hold during the year.
This month, the luxury in-centre arcade will feature a bowling alley flown in from the Netherlands, gold-plated skill tester and retro arcade games.
Shoppers have the chance to win more than $180,000 in prizes, including five $1000 Chadstone gift cards and vouchers from Tiffany & Co. and Anton Jewellery.
Chadstone general manager Fiona MacKenzie said she was looking forward to introducing Club Royale to shoppers.
"We are excited to offer shoppers more flexible trading hours ... and further elevate Chadstone as one of Melbourne's premier entertainment destinations," Ms MacKenzie said.
She said Club Royale was a chic destination of fun and entertainment for couples, friends and families.
"We hope that guests of Chadstone experience a wonderful sense of nostalgia and win some fabulous prizes," she said.
Ms MacKenzie said the centre was pleased to offer these festivals and attractions to shoppers.
"It is such a delight to provide our shoppers with unique experiences that are always changing and evolving here at Chadstone."
Club Royale will launch on Saturday, August 5, between 4 and 9pm.
Details: chadstone.com.au/events/113/club-royale
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadstone</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Royale</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms MacKenzie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anton Jewellery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona MacKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
