<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422317117199109</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/north-korean-missile-in-near-miss-with-air-france-flight-to-tokyo/news-story/e5198d76a8320213b27f713234bf0183</url>
  <title>North Korean missile in near miss with Air France flight to Tokyo</title>
  <content>
North Korea Missile Launch Poses Challenge for Trump
2:19

North Korea said Monday that Kim Jong Un personally guided a test launch of a ballistic missile that could be tipped with a nuclear warhead, posing the first major challenge to Donald Trump's administration from a foreign leader. Photo: AP and Reuters

February 13th 2017
6 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

North Korea sparked global shockwaves after its latest intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) test on July 28. Picture: KNCA/AFP

AP

Share

AIR France has expanded the area around North Korea ruled off-limits for its planes after the country's recent missile test.
The airline said the missile apparently fell about 100 kilometres from the trajectory taken by Air France Flight 293, travelling July 28 from Tokyo to Paris - which is just 10 minutes in flight time.
The jet was carrying more than 300 passengers at the time.
In a statement Thursday to The Associated Press, Air France said such a distance means the flight wasn't under any danger.
But it said that "as a precautionary measure, the company has decided to expand the non-flyover area around North Korea."
The airline said it routinely adjusts flight zones based on evolving threats, and already had a ban on flights over North Korea before the recent test.
It didn't specify the scope of the new no-fly area.
North Korean leader  after carrying out its latest intercontinental ballistic missile test.
Influential Republican and foreign policy expert Lindsey Graham this week told NBC's Today Show the President would rather go to war to destroy North Korea than allow it to develop a long-range nuclear-armed missile.

He also said there was a military option and it involved destroying North Korea.
Secretary of State Rex Tillerson said the US doesn't want to topple the North Korean government and told the secretive country "we are not your enemy".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>KNCA/AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air France Flight 293</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea Missile Launch Poses Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsey Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air France</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC's Today Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
