<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423528297998460</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/television/sam-frost-spills-details-about-her-upcoming-role-on-home-and-away/news-story/68621ca7f7c2e1aa2d5de0e952ccec2b</url>
  <title>Sam Frost</title>
  <content>
Sam Frost opens up on Home and Away gig

SAM Frost has revealed that her boyfriend is holding out hope for her to have an on screen lesbian kiss when she joins Home and Away.

Frost, who was  as a new cast member on the long-running soap, was tight-lipped about her upcoming role during a chat with Nova's Fitzy and Wippa this morning.

"I can't really talk about it," she told the loveable larrikins, "I'm under strict contract but it's pretty fun".

Wippa then asked Frost if there's any truth to the rumour that her , doesn't want her to kiss any male actors as part of her role.

"Oh yeah," she said, "he's like, 'if they ask why don't you ask if you could be into chicks'," Frost said.

The former Bachelorette reacted to her boyfriend by saying, "you're such a bloke! Are you kidding?"

Frost started filming her first Home and Away scenes earlier this week and she's already dreading the day she has to do a scantily-clad beach scene.

"They get everyone into bikinis so I'm really stressing out about it," she said, "but I've just got to stop eating so many carbs I think".

Frost wouldn't reveal many other details about what's in store for her on Home and Away, but that didn't stop Fitzy and Wippa from grilling her with some hard hitting questions.

"Do you hook up with Alf Stewart?" Wippa asked her.

"Definitely," Frost laughed, before Fitzy ended the chat with a zinger.

"You get half a flaming mongrel?" he asked her.

Before she makes her on screen debut in Home and Away, Frost will first be seen as a contestant on Hell's Kitchen.

The Marco Pierre White reality cooking show starts this Sunday on Channel Seven at 7pm.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frost</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alf Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wippa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nova's Fitzy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hell's Kitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
