<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423493938259601</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/happy-international-beer-day-here-are-some-classic-brew-hacks/</url>
  <title>Happy International Beer Day! Here Are Some Classic Brew Hacks</title>
  <content>
Today is  - which means you are legally entitled to clock off at noon and spend the day at the pub. [Citation needed.] To help you celebrate this sudsy occasion, we've gathered our favourite beer hacks, how tos and factoids from the Lifehacker archives.

Theme days are , but we're willing to make an exception when they involve icy cold beer. Below you'll find a selection of our favourite beer hacks - from pairing beers with specific foods to properly pouring a Guinness.

Ask for a schooner in Victoria and you'll get a blank look. Ask for a pot in Darwin and you'll probably be arrested. This is a handy guide to the different names for beer glass sizes around Australia.

Cheese and beer are a perfect marriage - but only if they have chemistry to begin with. This handy infographic pairs up nine popular beer types with the cheeses that suit them the most; from sharp cheddar (pale ale) to blue cheese (stout).

Boozy ice blocks are the ultimate in adult refreshment, but so many of them seem geared toward the wine drinkers and fruity cocktail lovers of the world. Beer seems to get the short end of the ice block stick, but no longer! These ice blocks are refreshing and easy to make and can be made without even pouring your brew from its can.

The beer-and-burger combo is beloved by pretty much everyone - which makes it blessedly easy to get your paws on while travelling abroad. This infographic lists 20 of the world's tastiest beer and burger pairings; from the Brazil's Grill Burger with Skol to South Africa's Springbok Burger with Carling Black Label. But be warned: the Australian nomination is awful.

According to a new study, drinking two beers in a row is a faster and more effective way to relieve pain than codeine or paracetamol. No, really.

Happy weekend, and welcome back to 3-Ingredient Happy Hour, the weekly drink column featuring super simple yet delicious libations. This week we're making the shandy.

If you leave a beer out, it can take on a gross, "skunked" taste. It isn't because of the temperature, though. It's because your beer is absorbing extra light. Keep it away from the sun to make sure your beer stays fresh.

Drinking in the shower is a pastime that much of the Lifehacker staff holds near and dear to their heart. The popular beverage of choice for such an activity?  Also, coffee and  Here's how you, too, can enjoy one of the greatest and most simple pleasures of your adult life.

Yesterday, US Speaker of the House Paul Ryan gave a St Patrick's Day toast with a truly sad-looking pint of Guinness, much to the horror of Irish viewers and Guinness lovers everywhere. The only way he could have made it worse is if he dropped a shot of Bailey's and Jameson in it. If you're going to pour a Guinness, here's how to do it right.

Beer is made for drinking, and I would never suggest you don't drink beer, but there's no reason you can't have a Guinness and cook with it too. Below you will find several delicious dishes designed to get the iconic stout into your stomach, all of which should be made with a cold one in hand.

Beer can bacon burgers. Beer can. Bacon. Burgers. You know you need to make these at your next backyard barbecue. Science demands it. We have the full recipe right here.

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa's Springbok Burger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bailey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingredient Happy Hour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil's Grill Burger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Patrick's Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifehacker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jameson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Speaker of the House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carling Black Label</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Beer Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guinness</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
