<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423051556620988</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/goalkeeper-jamie-signorello-is-sas-sole-representative-in-australian-under17-soccer-squad/news-story/50b205697e2ff32e7d4adba8a3823de4</url>
  <title>SA keeper has the world in his hands</title>
  <content>
JAMIE Signorello's father never wanted his son to become a goalkeeper.
But the SA youngster was glad he ignored his Dad Peter's advice after becoming the state's only representative in the Australian under-17 squad.
Signorello last week returned from Thailand, where he helped the Joeys to a third-place finish at the ASEAN championships.
It was a far cry from the Paradise teenagers' occasional stints between the posts as a kid at Campbelltown City.
"When I went in (goals) I did well and people used to say 'you should do it all the time'," Signorello, 15, said.
"But my Dad never wanted me to do it and was always against it.
"Then it came to trials for under-12s and I had to pick between being a player or a goalkeeper - I chose goalkeeper and here I am.
"Now my Dad thinks it was a pretty good decision."
Signorello saved a penalty in Australia's 7-3 triumph over Indonesia at the 12-nation tournament in Chonburi.
The Year 10 Rostrevor College student said his first taste of international football had been a learning experience under coach and Adelaide-born Socceroos great Tony Vidmar.
"It felt so good to represent my country, especially walking out and hearing the national anthem," the SA NTC player said.
"It was amazing and I'll cherish the moment forever.
"The conditions were very different, very hot and humid.
"Most of the teams we played against were really quick and played on the counter attack.
"I needed to be high off my line and sweep up anything that came behind, but I was quite happy with how I went."
The 182cm custodian credited local goalkeeper coaches Mike Harkness and Chris Higgins for overseeing his rapid rise over the past three years.
Signorello will travel to Mongolia next month to face the host nation, Vietnam and Cambodia in an Asian championships qualifying tournament.
He hoped to steer the Joeys to a berth at the 2019 under-17 World Cup and earn a youth team contract with Adelaide United.
"There's so many kids my age that want to be where I am now so I'm very grateful," said Signorello, who has modelled his game on legendary Italian keeper Gianluigi Buffon.
"I'm just going to keep working hard because this is just the start of the journey."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dad Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Vidmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gianluigi Buffon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Signorello</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JAMIE Signorello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Harkness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mongolia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Signorello, 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA NTC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chonburi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide-born Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 10 Rostrevor College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
