<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422617764916638</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/innercity-hotspots-for-dog-attacks-revealed-as-council-steps-up-patrols-20170803-gxomg5.html</url>
  <title>The inner-city hotspots for dog attacks, and dogs left off lead</title>
  <content>
Dog attacks are on the rise in inner Melbourne, leading to a push to keep our pooches in line.
"We had 10 serious dog attacks last year," Melbourne lord mayor Robert Doyle said. Photo: Joe Armao
Five people were seriously injured, four dogs were killed and another dog was seriously injured.
The attacks mainly happened in off-lead areas at council parks in Kensington and North Melbourne. The other serious attacks took place in Carlton, Parkville and the CBD. 
The previous year, there was only one dog attack reported.
One dog, a four-month-old toy poodle named Kobe, died after being attacked at a fenced-off dog park in Macaulay Road, North Melbourne, in March.

Kobe's owner, who asked to remain anonymous, said the puppy was attacked by two large dogs.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Our small, black toy poodle puppy, Kobe, was sitting at our feet when he was attacked by two large dogs which were both off leash," he said. 
"We only went to North Melbourne dog park because we heard it was the best. It was Kobe's first and last visit.
"My partner has ongoing psychological distress from the attack; she still dreams about it because she had to fight against the bigger dogs."
Although Kobe was attacked by bull terrier-type dogs, the rise in attacks is not restricted to particular breeds.
South Yarra was a hotspot for owners caught in lead-only areas with their dogs off leads.
A third of overall infringements for dogs not under effective control were handed out in Fawkner Park, which is bordered by Commercial and Toorak roads.
"We're going to step up our campaign to ensure dogs are on leash," Cr Doyle said.
"We think this is an under-reported issue, and obviously it's very distressing for victims, families and witnesses."
Council officers are ramping up their patrols to ensure dogs are not wandering the streets and that owners have their pets leashed in the correct public areas.
Melbourne council officers patrol more than 480 hectares of open space.
Dog owner and South Yarra Veterinary Centre director Dr Nicole Hoskin said off-lead areas made dogs difficult to control.
"With off-lead areas, you need to be aware of all the dogs who are there," she said.
"Dogs do need exercise, and it can be a great fun place, but individual owners need to take the responsibility to socialise their dogs."
The centre now has pet behaviour experts working to deal with increasing behavioural issues.
"Anxiety and fear are some of the main causes for the fearful aggressive attacks that are occurring. People don't understand how to behave or read the body language," she said.
Owners face fines of more than $6000 if the courts find their dog responsible for a serious attack.
In extreme cases, the courts can also order that a dog be put down.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KOBE</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fawkner Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Armao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toorak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Nicole Hoskin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Yarra Veterinary Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macaulay Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
