<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422845398187065</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/technology/mobiles-and-tablets/iphones-facebook-and-a-neverending-internet-are-sucking-our-time-and-making-us-miserable-20170803-gxom8o</url>
  <title>iPhones, Facebook and a never-ending internet are sucking our time and making us miserable </title>
  <content>
In a past life, we served on our local council. Despite the impressive size of our gross budget, our free choice in spending was remarkably limited.
By the time our road grants were spent on roads, child care funding on child care, the indoor and outdoor staff paid and the rubbish collected, funds for truly discretionary spending were tight. According to Associate Professor Alan Alter, a psychologist at New Your University, the days of our lives are just like that.
Alter tracks the rise of technology addiction, and he's particularly interested in what he describes as the "white space" in our days. It's what's left over after you deduct seven or eight hours for sleep, nine or ten for commuting and working and three or four for "survival activities" like eating and household tasks.
The few hours that remain are our discretionary time, when we might read a book, enjoy a hobby, call an old friend for a talk, play Monopoly with the family or get to the gym. According to Alter's research, our white space is increasingly consumed by computer screens and that's not making us happy.

Shutterstock.com

The professor details the science behind tech obsession in his new book "Irresistible: The Rise of Addictive Technology and the Business of Keeping Us Hooked".

, touching on the same subject, is a good introduction to the topic. Just a few minutes long, it's necessarily short on detail, but his ideas about stopping cues, or rather the lack of them in the internet age, struck a chord with us.
Once, our lives were full of stop signs. Kids' TV started at 4pm and ended at 6:30 when the nightly news marked the transition to grown up programming. There was no such thing as pleading for just one more episode of Adventure Time, because cartoons were over for the day.
You could read a newspaper from cover to cover, and it was finished. Time to fold it up and do something else. Heck, it wasn't that long ago that television stations shut down overnight.
When the last movie ended at 11pm, the station presented a goodnight message and the screen went dark, your body clock could hardly deny that it was time to get to bed and read a book.

Alter points out that online content is bottomless, seamless and endless. We can park ourselves in a chair with a smart phone or tablet, or in front of a computer or TV panel, and consume until we drop.
And many of us are sacrificing our white space doing exactly that, because the internet seldom gives us a stopping cue.
Take YouTube as a test case. We love it, who doesn't? But we can't count the times when we've promised ourselves at 9pm to be in bed by ten, only to be awake at 1am thanks to the never ending cavalcade of engaging content.
The Tube throws up more and more videos right on topic, and even auto plays the next one so we don't have to make a decision to keep going.

For others, it may be news or games, or Facebook, where you can scroll through social trivia, sorry, social media, for hours at a time.
Whatever your poison, Alter's figures suggest that we're sleeping, working and surviving for about the same aggregate time as ten years ago when the first iPhone launched. But our white space, where we can create and recreate, has been largely ceded to screen-based activities.
Worse, says the professor, the tech activities that hook us in are disproportionately ones that make us less happy. By querying test subjects engaged in various screen-based activities, Alter identifies which enhance our feelings of well being and which stir up negativity.
For instance, it turns out that as compelling as gazing at Facebook may be, it's typically associated with emotional dissatisfaction. Yet we're three times more likely to sacrifice white space to Facebook than feelgood activities like reading a good e-book.

Alter explores ideas for re-introducing stopping cues to our lives, both at work and out of hours. He's impressed by European workplaces where staff are actively prevented from pushing on past home-time, and strongly advocates the personal habit of never having a smartphone anywhere near a meal table.
But whatever the right responses may be, his insight that the internet never tells us it's time to put itself away, warrants our attention.
Peter Moon is a technology lawyer with Cooper Mills.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Us Hooked</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business of Keeping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Moon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shutterstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adventure Time</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associate Professor Alan Alter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rise of Addictive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Your University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
