<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423528297998508</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/04/11/42/us-baggage-handlers-fired-after-throwing-luggage</url>
  <title>US baggage handlers fired after throwing luggage</title>
  <content>
Three US baggage handlers have been fired after they were filmed hurling luggage off a plane.

The ground staff for Virgin Atlantic at Orlando International Airport in Florida had no idea they were being observed by mortified passengers on board a taxying plane when they began throwing luggage from a container on July 27.

Matthew Campbell told the  he couldn't believe what he was seeing.

"I saw it out of the window and I couldn't believe it. It was ridiculous. They were throwing the bags and I wouldn't be surprised if people's suitcases and belongings were broken by the way they were hurling them," he said.

"Maybe, it's because they work long hours and were tired, but either way it shouldn't be allowed to happen."

Another passenger told the publication that Richard Branson would have likely been disgusted by their behaviour.

Orlando Airport confirmed in a statement the men involved had been fired.

Related Articles

"Providing safe, secure and excellent customer service is our mission at Orlando International Airport. The incident viewed is not an example of the level of service we strive for. The employees involved have been removed from working at the airport," the statement read.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orlando Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Branson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Atlantic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orlando International Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
