<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423352204336352</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/04/11/05/three-shot-at-san-francisco-family-park</url>
  <title>Three shot at San Francisco family park</title>
  <content>
At least one gunman has opened fire at a popular San Francisco park packed with families and tourists, leaving three people wounded and sending dozens of panicked people running.
The three victims were taken to hospital, but no other details were provided.
Nearby resident Antonia Juhasz said she was sitting in Dolores Park when she heard a burst of gunshots.
"I saw a person with a gun in their hand running," she said. "I think there were a total of three shots."
Juhasz, 47, said she saw two people who had been shot. Both were bleeding as emergency workers carried them away on stretchers.
Dolores Park sits on a hill in the Mission Districts and is a popular destination for locals and tourists who come to sunbathe and take in city views. It's near a high school.
Juhasz, who has lived in the neighbourhood for more than 20 years, said the park was packed with families and tourists when the shots were fired.

Related Articles

"At first people didn't totally react because it sounded like fireworks," said Juhasz, a writer and freelance journalist. "I was yelling at people, 'It's actually a gun, it's actually a gun."'
"It was a terrifying, mostly because people weren't reacting," she added.
People began running after realising there had been gunshots, she said.
(C)  AP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonia Juhasz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dolores Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juhasz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juhasz, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
