<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422321412166492</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-now-news-in-90-seconds-for-august-4-2017-20170803-gxooid.html</url>
  <title>Canberra Now: A daylight carjacking and Cosplay in Canberra</title>
  <content>
Good morning Canberra and happy Friday.
How about all that rain last night? We ended up getting about 17 millimetres yesterday (although Tuggeranong got 25mm), but the weather bureau has forecast only a slight chance of a shower to see us through the last day of the work week - let's see how that goes. Today will see a top of 10 degrees, having got down to a low of 6 degrees overnight.
Let's take a look at what's making headlines.
$1 billion on the big four

How would you spend $1 billion? The federal government has dropped big money on consultancy firms since 2013 despite belt-tightening pledges.
Amid the axing of more than 15,000 public service jobs, outsourcing contracts with the big four consulting firms more than doubled in value from $196.4 million in 2013-14 to $420.3 million in 2015-16.

Since 2013 the big four firms donated more than $1.5 million to the Coalition and Labor, including $704,941 in 2015-16.
Doug Dingwall and Tom McIlroy have more .
Stronger pool fencing laws

River Parry drowned in a Fisher backyard pool in 2015. Photo: Supplied

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The ACT government has agreed in principle to improve its pool fencing laws after the drowning death of a toddler in 2015. 
The ACT Coroners Court last November urged the territory government to overhaul its "inadequate" and "confusing" pool fencing laws following the death of 21-month-old River Arama Parry. 
The coroner found while a lack of supervision was a key factor in the boy's drowning, the pool was unfenced, easily accessed from the house's back door and lacked child locks or self-closing mechanisms.
Katie Burgess has more .
Government introduces eftpos limit in clubs

More news from our talented reporters in the Legislative Assembly: from September, the ACT government will limit eftpos withdrawals in clubs to $200 per transaction.
There will be no limit on the number of times gamblers can return to eftpos machines, but clubs say the break from playing the pokies to get more cash will give gamblers time to reflect on whether they want to continue.
Kirsten Lawson has more .
Daylight robbery

Steve Thomas after being reunited with his red mustang after having it hijacked in Yarralumla on Thursday morning. Photo: Rohan Thomson

An "unbelievable" story from downtown Yarralumla yesterday morning - real estate agent Steve Thomas was finishing work in his car before doing a property appraisal up the road.
Suddenly, the driver's side door of his red Ford Mustang GT was flung open and a man was threatening Mr Thomas with a crowbar.
Finbar O'Mallon has , which ended with Mr Thomas getting his car back.
There's no play like cosplay

Paige Jema dressed as Lamb from video game 'League of Legends'. Photo: Rohan Thomson

Our lifestyle editor Bree Winchester has taken a deep dive into the wonderful world of cosplay - and Rohan Thomson has taken some amazing photos.
Meet a Tuggeranong couple who met at a fancy dress party and kept the fun going. Or Chisholm's Paige Jema, preparing for Gamma.Con as we speak. 
Great interviews, great photos - what are you waiting for? Read more .
Today's cartoon

David Pope.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Thomas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Thomas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GAMMA.CON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bree Winchester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finbar O'Mallon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Arama Parry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Mustang GT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legislative Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarralumla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League Of Legends</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paige Jema</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom McIlroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chisholm's Paige Jema</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Parry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirsten Lawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Coroners Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doug Dingwall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
