<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422927002567372</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/markets-live/markets-live-asx-stuck-while-wall-st-parties-20170803-gxp3al.html</url>
  <title>Markets Live: ASX stuck while Wall St parties</title>
  <content>
The Dow Jones edged up to a seventh straight record high overnight, while the S&P 500 and the Nasdaq fell, weighed down by Amazon, Apple and other top-shelf technology stocks.

Stocks lost a little ground late in the session after the  impaneled a grand jury in Washington to investigate allegations of Russia's interference in the 2016 US presidential election.

"It's more distraction for the White House and less stability," said Chris Zaccarelli, chief investment officer at Cornerstone Financial Partners. "It definitely was market moving."

The S&P 500 information technology index, which has led other sectors in 2017, dipped 0.35 per cent. Apple lost 1.0 per cent after hitting a record high the day before. It and Amazon down 0.9 per cent, weighed more than any other stocks on the S&P 500.

Silicon Valley electric carmaker Tesla jumped 6.50 per cent after reporting quarterly results above Wall Street's expectations.

Analysts, on average, expect S&P 500 earnings to have grown 11.8 per cent and they project earnings up 9.2 per cent for the September quarter.

The S&P 500 has risen 11 per cent in 2017 and is trading at 18 times expected earnings, pricey compared to its 10-year average of 14.

"Earnings are supporting this market and consumers are supporting it from a macroeconomic standpoint," said Phil Blancato, CEO of Ladenburg Thalmann Asset Management. "This is a Goldilocks economy, good enough to push the market higher, no bubbles in sight."

The Dow Jones Industrial Average edged up 0.04 per cent, or 9.86 points, to end at 22,026.1, an all-time high.

"When you hit these major milestones it's not unusual to trade sideways for a few days," Blancato said.

The S&P 500 lost 0.22 per cent to 2,472.16 and the Nasdaq Composite dropped 0.35 per cent to 6,340.34.

Wall Street has shrugged off a recent failure by a Republican-controlled Congress to overhaul healthcare legislation as well as doubts about how easily President Donald Trump will be able to fulfill promises to cut taxes and increase infrastructure spending.

Investors are watching economic data for clues on the health of the economy ahead of the keenly awaited monthly payrolls data on Friday.
Good morning and welcome to the Markets Live blog for Friday.

Your editors today are Jens Meyer and Patrick Commins.

This blog is not intended as investment advice.

Fairfax Media with wires.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thalmann Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Blancato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markets Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Ladenburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blancato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cornerstone Financial Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Commins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Zaccarelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones Industrial Average</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldilocks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican-controlled Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jens Meyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq Composite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
