<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423493938259644</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4833836/im-considering-a-drive-through-sydney-suburb-to-be-beset-by-parking-chaos/?cs=7</url>
  <title>'I'm considering a drive through': Sydney suburb to be beset by parking chaos</title>
  <content>
'I'm considering a drive through': Sydney suburb to be beset by parking chaos

SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA - AUGUST 01: Sam Campisi owner of Cake Man shop in Lave Cove next to Rosenthal carpark on AUGUST 01, 2017 in Sydney, Australia.  (Photo by Christopher Pearce/Fairfax Media

exit

Sam Campisi has been Lane Cove's resident cake man for the past seven years. But his business, and others along the suburban shopping strip, are about to meet chaos.
Work will start next month on the long-awaited Rosenthal Project - a village square in Lane Cove - but businesses and residents are dreading the estimated two-year construction which will see the halving of parking spaces, parking restrictions and changed access to streets.
"It's not only the lack of car parking spaces, but there will be barricades up blocking access to the street," said Mr Campisi, the owner of the Cake Man shop. "Hopefully the barrier will be wooden so it can be graffitied. Might make it look prettier."
Lane Cove's apartment boom - which has seen the local government area grow from 31,510 residents in 2011 to 36,051 in 2016 - has meant the need for a bigger mall and more parking.
Mr Campisi thinks he will lose 10 to 15 per cent of his business while the restrictions are in place.
"Because of the noise I will lose the customers that want to sit outside," Mr Campisi said. He hopes to get business from the construction workers, but doubts that it will make up for what he will lose. "I'm considering opening up a drive-through in order to accommodate the people that can't park," he said.
The project involves demolishing the current single level car park located on Rosenthal Avenue and transforming it into a modern community area with four levels of underground parking  - almost triple the current space.
The mayor of Lane Cove, Deborah Hutchens, is pleased the project is getting underway after years of negotiations with residents. "It will be a fantastic venue when finished," she said. "We will have an underground car park available for 500 spaces, accommodating for the parking issue common in the Lane Cove area."
Like Mr Campisi, Cr Hutchens is also concerned about traffic and parking during construction. "We have strategies for that," she said. "The widening of Coxs Lane will relieve a lot of the traffic." The village square, when completed, will feature open space, an amphitheatre, barbecues, a playground and possibly cafes. The lower floor will be home to major supermarkets.
Councillor Pam Palmer said the plans have been in development for more than 10 years because of the significant number of concerns raised by residents about traffic, noise, parking and tree preservation.
"The project has been negotiated for a very long time, so we are pleased to see it being moved forward," Cr Hutchens said.
A local resident, Sam Potts, said that the developed community area would attract more visitors, and the problem of traffic congestion would continue to be an issue.
"The council seems intent on getting more people into Lane Cove, but is not providing the suitable infrastructure for them to get out," he said. "You only have to look at the bus queues to see that."
The council determined to widen Coxs Lane by three metres to alleviate some of the traffic concerns.
The estimated cost of the development was "at best $60 million", Cr Palmer said, "and all of it fully funded". She explained that it is funded at no financial impact on ratepayers, partly by tenants in the surrounding council-owned property, as well as parking rates and development contribution accumulated in the 10 years of planning.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cake Man</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lane Cove</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Campisi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coxs Lane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deborah Hutchens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosenthal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Hutchens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Pam Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosenthal Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pearce/Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosenthal Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Potts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Campisi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 01</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lave Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
