<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422845398187074</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/our-books-are-open-for-inspection-white-spot-resea/3208567/</url>
  <title>Our books are open for inspection: White spot researchers</title>
  <content>
The declaration came after the Federal Department of Agriculture and Water Resources said it was aware of the research done by the University of the Sunshine Coast team, but to-date they had not made their methodology or data available to the department.

"The department would welcome detailed information and test data from USC researchers," a statement from the Department read.

Associate Professor Wayne Knibb, the leader of the university's Aquaculture Genetics Research Team, said their books were open and "available for anyone to inspect".

"All methods (are) open, we have signed legal lab books. They get signed every day and all lab work is recorded there," he said.

The University of the Sunshine Coast research team is ranked number one in the world for research into shrimp genetics by SciVal, the international ranking system for academics and universities.

Dim sims, spring rolls and marinara mix were among the samples tested, which included cooked food samples.

"We don't know if the detection of white spot in frozen products means the virus is infective, but this is a question that needs to be tested," Assoc Prof Knibb said earlier this week.

"In any case, it means these prawns were once infected with a living virus, and we cannot guarantee that processing will always be conducted in a way that kills the virus."

The Department of Agriculture and Water Resources said its prawn risk analysis found highly processed uncooked prawn products from retail outlets may test positive for white spot disease, but they were "considered to be unlikely to cause a WSSV (white spot syndrome virus) outbreak".

"Cooking significantly reduces WSSV levels and may completely inactivate the virus. Cooking also reduces the likelihood that prawns will be diverted to bait or aquaculture feed," the Department said.

"Cooked prawns can have fragments of viral DNA which are detected with modern testing methods but are unlikely to be infectious.

"The department considers uncooked prawns, marinated prawns, and Australian prawns processed overseas to present the highest risk of diversion to bait and aquaculture feed."

A Biosecurity Queensland spokesman said the results of the university team's testing backed up previous detections in imported seafoods made by Biosecurity Queensland and the Federal Government.

"Biosecurity Queensland is undertaking a thorough investigation into the extent of white spot disease in Queensland and the likely origin of the disease," the spokesman said.

"The research is well progressed and Biosecurity Queensland will release the findings when the work is finalised."

Assoc Prof Knibb and his team this week revealed results so far indicated the most likely source of the Logan River outbreak to be from China, having matched the DNA fingerprint of the Logan infection to one white spot strain in China.

"Biosecurity Queensland is the lead agency for the white spot response and continues to remain focussed on containing the disease and is working towards returning Queensland to a disease-free status," the spokesman said.

"To date, the Queensland Government has spent more than $15 million on white spot disease control activities and an additional $9 million is expected to be spent over the next two years.

"During the white spot disease emergency response, more than 130 full time staff were directly engaged in disease control activities including extensive surveillance and testing.

"More than 50,000 samples from prawn farms and natural waterways have been tested since white spot was detected in December 2016.

"Surveillance along the East Coast of Queensland from the Sunshine Coast to Cooktown has also been carried out.

"To date, no positive test results have been detected in wild-caught samples collected beyond the white spot restricted area in South East Queensland."

Two Gold Coast men held hostage at Gympie camp
Man believed to be unconscious before horror highway smash
Hospital loses right to train orthopaedic surgeons
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooktown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assoc Prof Knibb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SciVal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aquaculture Genetics Research Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Department of Agriculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Wayne Knibb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South East Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biosecurity Queensland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSSV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Coast of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
