<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423446693618385</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/north-east/this-golden-grove-home-may-look-impressive-from-the-front-but-wait-until-you-see-the-back/news-story/8710303baf0cab172f3cf811bab2c7b4</url>
  <title>This Golden Grove home may look impressive from the front, but wait until you see the back ... - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
3 Mockridge Street, Golden Grove

WHEN it comes to outdoor entertaining,  Golden Grove home is a cut above the rest.
Offering a flexible floorplan, the five-bedroom home at , has an extra-special alfresco entertainment space out the back that is larger than most, with spectacular views and different zones to choose from.
A true indoor/outdoor room, it features an elegant pitched-roof pergola with a ceiling fan.
It leads seamlessly off a large entertainment room. It also extends out to a private sun-drenched paved courtyard with palm trees and a resort feel.
Listing agent Craig Ricciuto from LJ Hooker Golden Grove said the property, which is listed for sale between $639,000 - $669,000, had already attracted strong interest from buyers with 29 groups attending the first open home last Saturday.
"This property is definitely different and unique and I, personally, haven't seen one like it in Golden Grove for a long time," Mr Ricciuto said.
"The alfresco area covers around 37sqm and the undercover pergola around 70sqm. So you have more than 100sqm of outdoor entertaining.
"The owners just really loved to entertain and spend a lot of time outside and the way they built it allowed them to do so all year round."
The home's interior is equally impressive, boasting a large open-plan kitchen, family and meals room at the heart of the home.
The large kitchen is a feature in itself with pendant lighting, a breakfast bar and elegant timber cabinets that contrast with the dark-toned benches and splashback.
The family room has a cosy wood fire and there is also an elegant lounge with a bay window and a more formal dining space.
The bedrooms are located in their own wing to the side and rear of the home.
The main is large and has an ensuite, walk-in robe and a bay window. The others have easy access to the main bathroom and a separate toilet.
A lower level underneath the main house, features a double garage and extensive storage area, as well as a handy powder room.
Decorated in neutral tones, the home also has ducted reverse-cycle airconditioning.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Ricciuto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ Hooker Golden Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ricciuto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mockridge Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Grove</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
