<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423438103683604</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/11/20/parliament-makes-return-from-winter-break</url>
  <title>Parliament makes return from winter break</title>
  <content>
THE WEEK AHEAD FOR FEDERAL PARLIAMENT:
* First sitting since the winter break.
* First order of business in the Senate will be referrals of senators to the High Court over their dual citizenship and eligibility to sit.
* The House of Representatives will debate laws to strengthen requirements for citizenship and deliver the remainder of the government's corporate tax cut plan.
* Liberal partyroom meeting on same-sex marriage on Monday, followed by discussion in coalition joint partyroom on Tuesday. Labor is open to bringing on debate and a vote on a bill immediately, even if the bill is proposed by a Liberal.
* Senate inquiry report on university funding reforms due on Wednesday, which will inform debate and crossbench talks on passing the bill.
* The government is expected to make progress in talks with crossbenchers about media reforms listed for debate on Wednesday.

Related Articles

* Labor is seeking a cross-party Senate inquiry into Murray Darling water rorts and the disallowance of building code changes.
* Question time will be dominated on the government side by national security, power prices and the economy. Labor will pursue inequality, tax fairness and division in government ranks.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WEEK AHEAD FOR FEDERAL PARLIAMENT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
