<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422493210862441</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/football/neymar-barcelonapsg-transfer-official-news-brazil-superstar-pays-release-clause-to-join-ligue-1/news-story/a2a680a40ca5a59ef357fd6002cacff4</url>
  <title>Official: Neymar forces $332m PSG move</title>
  <content>
NEYMAR has signed a five-year contract with Paris Saint-Germain after paying a release clause to leave Barcelona, the French club has announced.
The Brazilian winger, 25, is committed to Paris Saint-Germain until June 2022. He forced his way out of Camp Nou by paying a world record EUR222 million ($332m) release clause.
"I am extremely happy to join Paris Saint-Germain," Neymar said in a statement.
"Since I arrived in Europe, the club has always been one of the most competitive and most ambitious. And the biggest challenge, what most motivated me to join my new teammates is to help the club to conquer the titles that their fans want.
"From today, I will do everything I can to help my new teammates, to open up new horizons for my club and to bring happiness to its millions of supporters around the world."
PSG were similarly effusive after the arrival of what fans hope will be the missing piece in the hunt for an elusive Champions League crown.
"Today, with the arrival of Neymar Jr, I am convinced that we will come even closer, with the support of our faithful fans, to realising our greatest dreams," club president Nasser Al-Khelaifi said.
NEYMAR TRANSFER HEADLINES
-

-
-
-
-
-
Barcelona signed Neymar in 2013 from Santos, with the winger scoring 105 goals in 186 games, as he helped Barcelona win a Champions League, two La Liga titles and three Spanish Cups among other trophies.
He also won Olympic gold on home soil last year with Brazil in a dramatic penalty shootout win over world champions Germany.
Barcelona issued a frosty statement as Neymar's move came to fruition.
"On Thursday afternoon, Neymar Jr's legal representatives visited in person the club's offices and made the payment of EUR222 million in the player's name with regards to the unilateral termination of the contract that united both parties," Barcelona said in a statement on their website.
"As such, the club will pass on to UEFA the details of the above operation so that they can determine the disciplinary responsibilities that may arise from this case."
Earlier in the day, Neymar's lawyers were sent to La Liga headquarters in Madrid to pay the money, only to be snubbed.
"We can confirm that the player's lawyers came to the La Liga offices this morning to deposit the clause and that it has been rejected. That's all the information we are giving out at this moment," a statement from La Liga read.
But France's football body responded with incredulity and told La Liga it "demands they abide by the rules of FIFA and its responsibilities".
"The LFP is astonished and does not understand the refusal of La Liga to simply accept payment of the release clause of the player Neymar," a statement read.
"The LFP supports Paris St Germain and looks forward to the arrival of Neymar in Ligue 1.
"The legal services of the LFP are in support and available to Paris St Germain so that the contract of Neymar can be approved as soon as possible."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LFP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris St-Germain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEYMAR TRANSFER HEADLINES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasser Al-Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2022</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EUR 222</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Nou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar Jr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ligue 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
