<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422965657273938</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/shark-drum-line-debate-reignited-wa-government-not-doing-enough-to-prevent-attacks/news-story/SPP-2275843</url>
  <title>Shark drum line debate reignited</title>
  <content>
FEDERAL Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg has accused the State Government of not doing enough to prevent shark attacks ahead of summer, declaring it should use drum lines just as it "puts police on the streets".
As the detection of a tagged great white shark off Perth eight times in a week prompted authorities to warn people about going in the water, Mr Frydenberg said WA's response to the shark threat was "nothing short of pathetic".
The minister has ordered that a study by the CSIRO into the population of great white sharks be expanded to investigate if the increasing number of whales in Australian waters was leading to an increase in attacks. "The McGowan Government should wake up," Mr Frydenberg said.
"Just as they put police on the streets, they should put drum lines in the water to protect its own citizens and restore the WA way of life."
Mr Frydenberg said money and ideology should not be factors in decisions about saving lives.
"It should simply be a question of putting practical measures in place just as Queensland and NSW have done," he said.
WA Fisheries Minister Dave Kelly said the criticism was "disappointing and distasteful".
He said Mr Frydenberg was seeking to politicise the issue because Labor was in power at a State level.
Mr Frydenberg on Monday met the father of 17-year-old Laeticia Brouwer, who was killed by a great white shark while surfing near Esperance in April.
The minister's comments escalated a row between the State and Federal governments over the threat of sharks, after the Commonwealth suggested WA was not putting human life first.
Since 2000, 15 people have been killed by sharks in WA waters.
In the wake of Ms Brouwer's death, Mr Frydenberg said WA should use drum lines or nets in a bid to cull sharks, strategies rejected by the State.
Mr Kelly accused Mr Frydenberg of conducting megaphone diplomacy, claiming the minister was communicating only through the media and had ignored his requests for a meeting. He said drum lines and nets did not work.
Mr Kelly said the Government was focused on its program of subsidising personal shark deterrents, with more than 500 people taking up the offer.
"I think it's quite distasteful that the Federal Government are now taking such a political approach to this issue," Mr Kelly said.
"Under the previous State Liberal government, the Federal Government did not say a word despite there being a number of fatal shark attacks in WA."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Fisheries Minister Dave Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSIRO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Brouwer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Frydenberg</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laeticia Brouwer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
