<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422626354851361</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/shep-smith-trump-australia-fox-news-2017-8</url>
  <title>Fox News anchor says Trump 'misrepresented the truth'  --  again</title>
  <content>
Fox News anchor Shep Smith excoriated Donald Trump on Thursday, saying the president "misrepresented" the truth about his phone calls with two foreign leaders earlier this year.

of the two phone calls from January revealed unusually contentious conversations with President Enrique Pena Nieto of Mexico and Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull of Australia. At one point, Trump called the exchange with Turnbull "unpleasant" and said he preferred his conversation with Russian President Vladimir Putin.

The transcripts seemed to confirm coverage of the two phone calls at the time - coverage that Trump derided as "fake news."

"Thank you to Prime Minister of Australia for telling the truth about our very civil conversation that FAKE NEWS media lied about," Trump  on Feb. 3. "Very nice!"

On Thursday, Smith didn't let Trump off the hook.

"The media did not lie. We reported the truth," Smith said. "Then President Trump misrepresented the truth, and not for the first time. Now the White House is focusing on the leaks that let the world know the truth."

Although Fox News has been a reliable source of positive coverage of the White House, Smith hasn't shied away from critique. Last month, he  after media reports revealed that more people attended a meeting between Donald Trump Jr. and a Kremlin-linked Russian lawyer than the White House originally admitted to.

"Why is it lie after lie after lie?" Smith said on July 14.

"There are still people who are out there who believe we're making it up," Smith said. "And one day they're gonna realise we're not and look around and go, Where are we, and why are we getting told all these lies?"

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Enrique Pena Nieto of Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shep Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin-linked Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
