<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423536887933277</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/deals-a-mammoth-productivity-training-bundle-for-90-off/</url>
  <title>Deals: A Mammoth Productivity Training Bundle For 90% Off</title>
  <content>
Your time is valuable, and learning how to make the most of it is one of the simplest ways to build a better you. Of course, that's easier said than done, but you can simplify the process thanks to the .

Featuring 27 hours of productivity-boosting tips and tools used by the world's most successful people, this eight-course collection can guide you on your way to becoming a more organized and efficient person. From time management methods to speed reading techniques and even public speaking advice, this collection comes loaded with content to hone your skills in a myriad of different directions.

Now on sale for more than 90 percent off, you can take the first step towards boosting your potential with  the Ultimate Productivity Bundle  [$36 USD].

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

All deals are carefully vetted to ensure relevance and value to Lifehacker readers. Commerce Content is independent of Allure Media editorial and advertising, and if you buy something through our posts, we may get a small share of the sale. Click  to learn more.

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

WATCH MORE: Tech News & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifehacker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultimate Productivity Bundle  [$36 USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mammoth Productivity Training Bundle For 90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allure Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commerce Content</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
