<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422450261188596</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/03/31/brisbane-bus-drivers-won-t-collect-fares</url>
  <title>Brisbane bus drivers won't collect fares</title>
  <content>
Bus trips across Brisbane will be free for 24 hours, with drivers refusing to collect fares as part of their ongoing industrial stoush with the city's council.
The Rail, Tram and Bus union wants a 3.5 per cent pay increase, more security guards across the bus network and rosters aimed at reducing fatigue as part of an EBA for drivers, which has been at the centre of a seven-month long dispute.
After four work stoppages during the past three weeks, the RTBU has announced its members won't collect fares on Brisbane buses on Friday.
"Our fight will continue until our members are given a fair go, but that can't happen until the Lord Mayor starts listening to his workers," RTBU secretary Tom Brown said.
"Only then can we sit down and negotiate an agreement that's fair to both parties and finally end this dispute."
The RTBU is calling the protected industrial action "free fare Friday" but a council spokesman warned commuters they would still need to pay to travel.
"There is still a requirement by the state government for people travelling on council buses to pay a fare," the spokesman said.

Related Articles

Deputy premier Jackie Trad has urged the council and union to resolve their issues.
"Clearly, the state's view is that these matters should be resolved expeditiously," she told reporters on Thursday.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
