<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423098801262052</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829480/history-hooked-on-sygna-tales/?cs=316</url>
  <title>History | Hooked on Sygna tales</title>
  <content>
History | Hooked on Sygna tales

FISHING SPOT: "Camping on the wreck could be spooky", says Chris Simmons, author of The Sygna - My Story. Picture: Marina Neil

STERN: The former landmark on Stockton Beach. All that is left is a marker.

Sygna bow: This half of the ship was moored in Port Stephens for more than a year before being towed to Taiwan and scrapped in 1976.

exit

TODAY'S yarn could well be called a tale of two halves.
Of the same ship, that is. I'm talking about the 53,000 tonne Norwegian bulk carrier MV Sygna that ran aground north of Stockton during a cyclone on May 26, 1974.
Being Australia's largest shipwreck, it was an extraordinary sight.
Later, split in half during a salvage operation, the stern of the collier (217m or 713ft) remained a landmark on Stockton Bight beach for 42 years.
Mid last year, however, the wreck disappeared beneath the waves. Someone, however, has apparently put a marker on the beach to indicate where the Sygna stern ended her days. With that in mind, let's revisit the Sygna saga.
Wind gusting up to 165kmh and high sea had once wedged the Sygna onto the sand. The 1974 tempest has always been labelled the 'Sygna storm', while a similar storm, labelled the 'Pasha Bulker storm', occurred in 2007.
The Sygna bow was moored in Salamander Bay, at Port Stephens, for 16 months before being towed to Taiwan to be scrapped in January 1976. Weekender has much affection for the Sygna, particularly the massive bow section (maybe 100 metres long) once riding high offshore and towering over anglers in boats. Maybe that's because in April 1975 I was lucky to slip inside and explore one of the flooded cargo holds with a few friends.
It was a miserable, wet day when our speedboat cautiously motored into the jagged open maw of the Sygna to the spot where the steel had earlier ripped apart and the halves of the ship separated with a grinding shriek on Stockton Beach.
Inside the cave-like opening it was cold and gloomy. It was like being in a huge, dank, dripping vault, with the roof perhaps 13metres above us. Our hushed voices echoed eerily. We were only there briefly, but the memory of that day has lasted me decades.
Imagine if your memories of the wreck of the Sygna (both halves) extended for years, but particularly 10 years, from the early 1980s, while fishing on the stern of the rusting Sygna.
"Oh, it was wonderful," adventure fisherman Chris Simmons, of Tighes Hill, said recalling how he came to publish his memoir of the experience The Sygna - My Story last December.
"We used to paddle out by surfboard after work in the late afternoon towing a bucket and gear. We'd use a grappling hook to get onboard, then fish and come back around midnight in our wetsuits with fish slime and try not to think about any sharks hanging about," he said.
"Sometimes we'd stay overnight and some nights the phosphorescence in the water was unbelievable. You could also see the glow of the (then) steelworks. You were there in the dark with a sky full of stars, the sound of waves washing in and schools of travelling mullet about when your reel might go off.
"While once living at Fern Bay, the Sygna stern was in my backyard. But I was also very familiar with the Sygna's section up at Port Stephens. The fishing there wasn't so good because the bow section would rotate, swing around at anchor. The bow wasn't fixed to the sea floor as our stern section was," Simmons said.
"We also caught a lot of sharks from that stern. Rex Hunt the TV fisherman wanted to come out and fish with us but we said 'no'. He would have broadcast it to everyone and we wanted to keep it our little secret. Mostly it was just two of us out there fishing, then at weekends it might be four and sometimes six people. It was magic.
"The first time I was there at night lying on the rusty deck crabs crawled over me for the fish scraps on my wetsuit. And even on very calm nights I swear you could hear the wreck breathing as the tide rose and fell under you, hissing through pipes as air was compressed beneath," he said.
"It was fantastic, but camping on the wreck could be spooky. There would be a 'boom' when big waves hit the bulkhead and it vibrated. The groaning noises the wreck made sounded like a big pipe organ. I called it the Sygna symphony.
"We got good at eating cold pies. There was nothing left inside the Sygna stern, just bare metal. One of the early salvagers had lit a fire to deter vandals taking things. Another salvager later even lost a bulldozer (in the water) up there, poor bugger. But it was our good fortune as it brought more us fish."
Simmons said that at one time he and a mate got careless and one of their two surfboards floated away from the deck with the rising tide. Both men had to paddle furiously on one board to get back to the beach.
He and his mates later reluctantly left the battered, corroded wreck with its rusty red sloping deck as it was becoming very unsafe.
"I'd taken maybe 50 photos at the time. They were starting to fade. I'm nearly 60 now and I said to myself this is a part of Newcastle history. I never expected I'd be the one to write it all down.
The Sygna- My Story ($25) is available from booksellers Harry Hartog's at Kotara, Macleans at Hamilton, Dymocks at Charlestown and some newsagents
Tracking the past

HUNTER Valley historian and author Ed Tonks has been busy.
Early next week he releases not one, but three publications. One is an updated reissue of his popular book No Bar to Time, telling the history of many Newcastle hotels. As well, Ed's releasing a 128-page, hard cover, all-colour book featuring his train and rail slides. It's entitled, Tracking Back. 1970s and 1980s rail scenes of Newcastle and Lake Macquarie. Although it's a train book, it features the changing landscapes of Newcastle from Whitebridge to Wangi Wangi.
The third item published will be the Fernleigh Track Calendar 2018, the final in his series looking back to yesteryear. The launch is taking place at the Commonwealth Hotel in Cooks Hill on Tuesday, August 8, at 6pm.

mikescanlon.history@hotmail.com
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KOTARA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norwegian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wangi Wangi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sygna</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Simmons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooks Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockton Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simmons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Simmons, of Tighes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Hartog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 1975 I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fern Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV Sygna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maclean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Tonks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Story ($25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dymocks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fernleigh Track Calendar 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockton Bight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pasha Bulker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitebridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salamander Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1976</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracking Back</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
