<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422750908905129</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/donald-trump-blames-congress-for-all-time-low-in-russia-ties/8773212</url>
  <title>Donald Trump slams Congress for 'all-time, very dangerous low' Russian relations after sanctions</title>
  <content>
Washington's relationship with Russia is at an "an all-time and very dangerous low," US President Donald Trump says, blaming Congress for the situation  against Moscow.

Key points:

Senators say they deliberately drafter the sanctions so Mr Trump could not lift them
Kremlin says the US policy of sanctions is "short-sighted, unlawful, and hopeless"
Congressmen say President Vladimir Putin is the one to blame for the sanctions

"You can thank Congress, the same people that can't even give us HCare!" he added via Twitter, referring to  when his fellow Republicans failed to push healthcare legislation through the Senate.
Last week, , leaving Mr Trump with little choice but to sign the legislation, although he had long expressed a desire for better ties with Russia.
Even as he signed the bill on Wednesday, , complaining the measure - which allows Congress to stop him from easing sanctions on Russia - infringed on his presidential powers to shape foreign policy.
Russia  and an end to hopes for better ties with the Trump administration, which it described as weak.
"First, it ends hopes for improving our relations with the new US administration," Russian Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev said.
"Second, it is a declaration of a full-fledged economic war on Russia.
"Third, the Trump administration has shown its total weakness by handing over executive power to Congress in the most humiliating way."
Mr Trump's desire for better ties with Moscow has been hamstrung by the findings of US intelligence agencies that President Vladimir Putin's Government meddled in the 2016 US presidential election campaign.
Republicans and Democrats usually are strongly divided on many issues but the measure drew wide support from both parties.
Sanctions deliberately designed to hamstring Trump

Republican US Senator Tom Cotton, asked about Mr Trump's tweet in an MSNBC interview, agreed US-Russian ties were "at a very low point" but rejected the President's blame.

External Link:

Chuck Schumer tweets on Mr Trump's denouncing the sanctions
"Ultimately, the responsibility falls primarily on Vladimir Putin," Mr Cotton said, pointing to Russian actions over Ukraine, arms control treaty violations and alleged meddling in various Western nations.
"We need to confront, put pressure on Vladimir Putin at every point."
Dick Durbin, the second-ranking Democrat in the Senate, asked for his reaction to Mr Trump's tweet, told MSNBC: "I can just tell you we saw real bipartisanship on Capitol Hill when it came to these sanctions.
"Democrats and Republicans agreed we had to tell North Korea, Iran and Russia 'enough was enough.'" - the sanctions also affect North Korea and Iran.
Mr Durbin said the bill deliberately included measures to ensure Mr Trump imposed the sanctions and did not lift them.
"We put requirements in the bill which most presidents have never seen to make sure this happens."
On Thursday, the Kremlin again denounced the sanctions, calling them "short-sighted".
"Nobody should doubt that Russia will protect and defend its interests," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said at a conference call with reporters.
"We in general believe that this policy of sanctions is short-sighted, unlawful and hopeless."
Reuters

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican US Senator Tom Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Durbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick Durbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSNBC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dmitry Peskov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukraine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Vladimir Putin's Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chuck Schumer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capitol Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HCare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
