<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423103096229441</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-04/draftstars-round-20-cheat-sheet</url>
  <title>Draftstars round 20 cheat sheet</title>
  <content>
AND SO there are four rounds left. If you still haven't managed a Draftstars win throughout 2017, we're here to help with our round 20 cheat sheet. For more information visit .
Geelong v Sydney, Simonds Stadium, Friday night

As usual, we're going to start the weekend in turbo format, where Draftstars coaches need to pick one player from six different tiers based on performances so far this season.

In the first tier from this game, we're going to choose Cats midfielder Mitch Duncan (MID, $15,500). His 112-point average is too good to pass. Sydney superstar Lance Franklin (FWD, $13,450) gets the nod in tier two with his 96-point average, and emerging Swan Nic Newman (MID/DEF, $12,300) is our choice in the third tier.

Tom Hawkins' (FWD, $11,200) mammoth effort of 158 points last week against Carlton sees him become our tier four choice, even though the signs are that he won't reproduce such a score (it was his first century since round four).

Lively Swans forward Tom Papley (FWD/MID, $10,450) gets the nod in the fifth rung of players available, and he regularly hits his 80-point average. Of the final group of choices, Sydney half-back Zak Jones (MID/DEF, $9500) is the best option with his 78-point average. He can be up and down, but there aren't many other great options in there.
Greater Western Sydney v Melbourne, UNSW Canberra Oval, Saturday

What a sight for Draftstars coaches to have Stephen Coniglio (MID, $13,900) back last week. The star Giants midfielder turned one on in his return to the top level, being his side's only player to reach triple figures against Fremantle. His 104-point effort reminded people of his ability.

GWS big man Rory Lobb (FWD/RK, $10,550) was also good with 97 points. Josh Kelly (MID, $14,200) has averaged 99.7 the past three weeks but hasn't quite got back to his stunning form we saw before his minor hip injury.

Melbourne had a shining light last week against North Melbourne, and his name was Clayton Oliver (MID, $14,700). The midfielder picked up 128 points to restore his average to 102 for the season. He remains the highest-scoring Dee for the year and is a premium choice. 

Max Gawn (RK, $13,050) was also back to his best with 113 points in the loss to the Roos, while Michael Hibberd's (DEF, $14,400) form continued unabated with another 104 points (he's now averaging 93 in a career-best year). Jayden Hunt (FWD, $11,900) is coming along too; his average of 105 over the past three weeks gives him appeal. 
Essendon v Carlton, MCG, Saturday

It was the 'Joe Show' last week for the Bombers, with Joe Daniher (FWD, $12,650) kicking six goals in a best-afield display against the Bulldogs. His 127-point Draftstars total reflected that effort - it was his seventh triple-figure score this season and his third in the past four weeks.

He's one of several Bombers worth looking at. Michael Hurley (DEF, $13,850) has lifted his possession rate this year to become a key option with a 93-point average, David Zaharakis (MID, $15,100) last week scored his fourth consecutive ton, and Darcy Parish (FWD/MID, $11,800) is building in form after 96 points last week.

Last week wouldn't have been good for Draftstars coaches if you loaded up on the Blues. Of their top-liners, only Sam Docherty (DEF, $15,850) reached triple figures, and Kade Simpson (MID/DEF, $13,500) was especially low on his regular output with only 64 points. Concussion meant Matthew Kreuzer (RK, $14,000) managed only 57 points.

But in better news, Charlie Curnow (FWD, $11,000) is becoming a more consistent Draftstars option and has averaged 92.6 over the past five weeks, while Sam Kerridge (FWD/MID, $13,050) has also been more than solid with an average of 97 over the same period. They might be some cheaper Carlton choices for you to consider.
Brisbane Lions v Western Bulldogs, Gabba, Saturday

You may not have noticed, but Lewis Taylor (FWD/MID, $12,150) is having a very good year for the Lions. He's back to the zippy stuff we saw in his debut season, and last week scored 109 against the Eagles, lifting his average to 96 for the past three weeks.

Everyone knows Dayne Beams' (MID, $15,800) quality, and when he is firing like he has been of late he should be right near the top of your list of midfielders. He scored 144 last week to follow his 142-point effort the previous round (it was his fourth score in the 140s this season).

From a Bulldogs perspective, Shane Biggs (DEF, $12,300) might be one to watch. We had some doubts that his 111-point score against Gold Coast in round 18 would be a one-off, but he bettered that with 113 points against Essendon last week.

Lachie Hunter (MID, $13,750) continued his form with 106 points, Jack Macrae (MID, $14,800) just never relents and gathered 98, while Jason Johannisen (DEF, $10,800) scored 89 thanks to his four-goal haul. But the Norm Smith medallist has struggled for consistency this season. 
North Melbourne v Collingwood, Etihad Stadium, Saturday night

More midfield time is meaning more points for Luke McDonald (DEF, $11,700), who has enjoyed a strong patch of form of late. The dashing Roo has averaged 96 for the past five weeks and scored an equal team-high 105 last week in the win over the Dees.

Shaun Higgins (FWD, $12,950) delivered as he always does with another score in the hundreds (his fifth of the season) and he's averaging 96 over the past five weeks. Ben Brown (FWD, $11,250) also deserves more attention after another score in the 90s pressed his average up to 87 for the same period.

Collingwood was led brilliantly by its midfield last week, with Daniel Wells (FWD/MID, $12,800) reminded the competition of his class. The former Roo scored 143 points in the best game of his season, while Taylor Adams' (MID, $16,500) three goals pushed his score to a team-high 151 in its draw with Adelaide.

Ruckman Brodie Grundy (RK, $14,450) collected another ton, Jeremy Howe (DEF, $12,500) scored 114 points, and defender Matt Scharenberg (DEF, $11,050) had a season-high 98 points in a polished display off half-back.
Fremantle v Gold Coast, Domain Stadium, Saturday night

Fremantle drafted Luke Ryan (DEF, $12,200) in the hope he could make an immediate impact this year, and he went bang last week against GWS with 138 points in a brilliant showing in just his seventh game. His past four weeks has seen him average 93.8. 

Darcy Tucker (FWD/MID, $10,450) performed well with 107 points but his average of 63 makes it hard to choose him, while Nat Fyfe (MID, $15,250) was back to his best last week for the Dockers. His 120-point score was his best of the season and his third ton of the past four weeks.

Aaron Hall (MID, $14,650) has to be one of the most polarizing Draftstars players. His best is amazing, but in between can be some shockers, too. Last week was very good, with Hall's 152-point belter the best score by any Sun by 56 points - next best was the 96 by Pearce Hanley's (MID/DEF, $11,500).

There wasn't a lot else to love from the Suns. It's hard to trust too many of their players when you only have nine places in your 'salary' Draftstars line-up, but the return of Gary Ablett (MID, $17,450) from injury at least gives you a premium choice. 
St Kilda v West Coast, Etihad Stadium, Sunday

Nick Riewoldt (FWD, $13,250) sat out last week with injury and announced during the week this will be his last season. So we're predicting on the back of that he'll have a beauty against the Eagles on the Saints' home turf. He's still averaging 90 points in his final year.

Conditions suited Luke Dunstan (MID, $12,100) last week and he gathered 116 points against the Power, but we probably wouldn't take him under the Etihad Stadium roof where things quicken up. Seb Ross (MID, $14,000), meanwhile, is another story. It was just another 109 for Ross last week (his 13th ton of the season).

Josh Kennedy (FWD, $13,000) is making a late run for the Coleman Medal, and his six-goal haul last week catapulted him to 115 points against Brisbane - the most of any West Coast player. Former Lion Jack Redden (MID, $13,550) had 104, while Luke Shuey (MID, $14,700) was back with another 102 points in a solid display.

Dom Sheed (FWD/MID, $12,350) isn't letting us down, either. The fourth-year midfielder collected 102 points to nudge his average up to 88 for the season. His past three weeks has seen him average 98 to be among the most consistent Eagles. 
Richmond v Hawthorn, MCG, Sunday

The Tigers got the job done against Gold Coast last week but there wasn't heaps to get excited by from a Draftstars point of view. The same old faces - Trent Cotchin (MID, $14,550) and Dustin Martin (FWD/MID, $16,300) - led the way, while perennially good scorer Anthony Miles (MID, $11,750) chipped in with 95 points.

We did like the showing of Daniel Rioli (FWD, $8550), who picked up a season-high tally of 93 points against the Suns. His average has been 52 for the year so it was well above that, and it's something to keep in mind next year when we hope he's closer to being a Draftstars option for us. He's not at that point yet. 

It's all about Jarryd Roughead (FWD, $12,450) this week as he hits his 250th game, and he will do so in good form. Roughead played the best game of his season last week against the Swans with 113 points, pushing his average to nearly 90 for the past three weeks.

James Sicily (FWD/DEF, $11,700) is emerging as a quality pick in Hawthorn's defence and gathered 106 last week, while Ben McEvoy (RK, $12,350) scored 94 points as his strong season continued. And we saw something for the first time last week - Tom Mitchell (MID, $17,550) under triple figures. His 94-point score against the Swans was his lowest of the year. 
Adelaide v Port Adelaide, Adelaide Oval, Sunday

Matt Crouch (MID, $15,000) stepped up in the absence of brother last week, gathering 127 points in the Crows' comeback draw with Collingwood at the MCG. Crouch is a ball magnet and always has been, so you can grab him comfortably knowing he will deliver.

Brodie Smith (DEF, $12,000), Sam Jacobs (RK, $13,550) and Riley Knight (FWD, $9300) were all good performers for the Crows with scores in the 90s, while Paul Seedsman (MID/DEF, $12,200) scored 80 in his first senior appearance of the season. When in form he can be dangerous.

Jared Polec (MID, $11,700) was the only Power player to reach triple figures in Port's win over St Kilda last week, although the heroes of the last play - ruckman Patrick Ryder (FWD/RK, $13,650) and rover Robbie Gray (FWD/MID, $13,100) - both scored in the 90s. They should be well on your radar, and Gray has pushed his average up to 94 over the past three weeks.

It's been a disappointing Draftstars season for Hamish Hartlett (MID, $11,050), who has averaged just in 2017. Avoid despite his promise.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $9300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Hartlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hibberd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Ablett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD/RK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF, $13,850</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $14,800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RK, $12,350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF, $12,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF, $12,300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Zaharakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $12,650</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Curnow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan Nic Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD/DEF, $11,700</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF, $12,500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RK, $13,050</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNSW Canberra Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD/MID, $12,350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Shuey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayden Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $12,950</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Rioli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD/MID, $10,450</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RK, $13,550</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Parish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hurley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID/DEF</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $11,900</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $11,700</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF, $15,850</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Polec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $13,750</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Howe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Lobb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RK, $14,450</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sicily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Beams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce Hanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF, $10,800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $15,250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $14,200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $15,100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $11,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nat Fyfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Seedsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRENT COTCHIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Tucker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seb Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $15,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD/MID</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Macrae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $13,250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norm Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion Jack Redden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Dunstan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Docherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $11,250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $11,200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $14,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Scharenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Draftstars</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWD, $13,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Biggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $14,650</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $16,500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kade Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEF, $14,400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MID, $14,700</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
