<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422493210862389</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/football/neymar-psg-transfer-news-timeline-of-barcelona-move-evolution-how-it-happened/news-story/545a638916147d1cfde5c0a2445d0131</url>
  <title>The evolution of football's wildest ever transfer</title>
  <content>
TWO weeks ago, the football world was rocked by a report stating Neymar had accepted an offer to join Paris-Saint Germain.
- a journalist for Brazilian TV channel  - tweeted that PSG were ready to pay Neymar's mammoth €222 million ($329m) release clause to pry him away from Barcelona.
It sounded insane.

Neymar aceita proposta do PSG. Clube frances pagara os 222 milhoes de euros. Em instantes mais detalhes no
The Brazilian was at the top of his game, winning trophy after trophy with Barca, and playing alongside one of the all-time greats in Lionel Messi.
However, living in the Argentine's shadow was reportedly one of Neymar's main issues as he wanted to be a club's main man.
Every day new reports emerged and added to speculation that a sensational transfer could take place.

Over the past two weeks, the Rumour Mill was sent into overdrive, and followed every development.
Now you can re-live the evolution of the football's biggest transfer ever below!

Football: Barcelona confirms Neymar is seeking a future elsewhere.

Barca admits Neymar wants out
July 18:
Neymar had already been linked with a PSG transfer last year, but chose to sign a new five-year deal with Barcelona in October.
However, with various newspapers reporting PSG were preparing to bid for Neymar, Barcelona twice denied they would sell the Brazilian.
"Selling Neymar is not something the club would think about," Barcelona spokesman Josep Vives said at a press conference. "We are very calm.
"He is one of the most important players we have. We will not consider any offers we receive for him."
Barcelona sporting director Robert Fernandez added: "I don't think that's going to happen [anyone paying his release clause]."
July 19:
Barca vice-president Jordi Mestre insisted Neymar would "200 per cent" be staying at the club.
However, it was being reported that PSG had held talks with the Catalan giant about signing the 25-year-old, with Barca determined to keep Neymar.
Additionally, the French champions were reportedly hoping the signing of Brazil international Dani Alves would entice Neymar to accept a five-year deal worth at least €30m a season.
But Neymar came out and said he was looking ahead to the 2017-18 season with Barca.
"The last one was my best season in Barcelona. I am very adapted to the city, the club and I am happy here. That is reflected on the performance of an athlete," Neymar told
"It was the season where I felt more comfortable, even though we did not win the titles we would have wanted. We played great games and lived incredible moments. Now, we need to work for the 2017-18 season so it will be even more positive individually and as a group."
July 20:
Neymar told PSG players he was set to join them.
Alves, as well as fellow Brazilians Thiago Silva, Marquinhos and Lucas Moura at the French club were all reportedly drawcards for a move.
PSG were also preparing to hold discussions over a deal, with PSG's sporting director Antero Henrique set to talk with Neymar's father and agent (Neymar Senior).
A £45m signing on fee was touted as well as a wage of £596,000 a week after tax.
French outlet L'Equipe released quotes from PSG coach Unai Emery saying the club was trying to land one of the world's best players, which included Neymar.
He said: "Neymar belongs to the top five world. The president and the club have been working for years to attract the best players... Afterwards, this quest is not easy. Maybe we'll get there, maybe not."
Neymar ignored questions about a move when he was approached in an airport, while Barcelona president Josep Maria Bartomeu said: "Relaxed. We're all relaxed, we've already talked enough."
Former Barca president Joan Gaspart suggested the transfer reports were part of PSG's ploy to unsettle Barca and Neymar after the La Liga club's continued interest in Marco Verratti, while The Mail reported the Italian midfielder, Kylian Mbappe, or Alexis Sanchez could be brought in to replace Neymar.
July 21:
However, Spanish newspaper AS reported Barca "bosses have finally decided to accept they do have a problem with Neymar", while Sport added Bartomeu and Neymar held a "summit meeting" on the flight over to New York to suss out the situation.
Bartomeu also noted that PSG paying Neymar's release clause would likely infringe on Financial Fair Play rules.
Bartomeu said: "These clauses are impossible to activate, if you want to comply with the financial fair play. If someone doesn't want to comply, then, of course, it can be activated."
However, more reports said that Neymar's father was holding talks with PSG to finalise personal terms over a move, while Catalunya Radio reported there was "a high possibility to sign Neymar, a transfer is at 95%".
But Thiago Silva had no idea.
"Neymar in Paris? I don't know," he was quoted as saying in Sport. "I've heard a lot of journalists talking but at the minute there is nothing concrete although I think it is important for the PSG project. If he comes, it will be good for the group."
July 22:
Neymar then added to speculation by posting a photo on Instagram of himself in thoughtful contemplation, with PSG's Angel Di Maria, Kevin Trapp and Marco Verratti all liking the post.
French outlet Le Parisien reported that the Brazilian had told Barca teammates he intended to join PSG, while Catalan media group RAC 1 added that "certain players" at Barcelona had already tried to convince Neymar not to accept the PSG offer.

A post shared by Nj 🇧🇷 👻 neymarjr (@neymarjr) on

Sport reported that Luis Suarez attempted to persuade Neymar not to split up the MSN frontline at made up of Lionel Messi, Suarez and the Brazilian star.
Centre-back Javier Mascherano certainly didn't want to see him go.
"In the case of Ney, obviously he is young, and I hope he's here with Barcelona for many more years," Mascherano told American sports network ESPN.
"He is a really important player for the club. Because of his age, he's the future of the club, and we hope we can keep on counting on him."
July 23: Barca's last play to keep Neymar, '90 percent' exit
The Daily Mail reported that Barca would step up their bid to sign Philippe Coutinho in the slim hope it would convince Neymar to say at the Nou Camp.
That's because it was reportedly Neymar who requested Barca sign his good friend.
Barca had a £72m bid knocked back the week before, and Liverpool boss Jurgen Klopp was adamant his playmaker wasn't leaving.
"If I say he is not for selling, he is not for selling," the German told British media.
"There is nothing else to say. It's a club decision, it's my decision. That's how it is."
AS added that Neymar had "showdown" talks with Bartomeu in the US, with both parties leaving the meeting appearing unhappy.
Sky Sports sources claimed that the deal is "90 percent" done, with only a "miracle" to keep Neymar at the Catalan giants.
However, Bechler, said Neymar was now "divided" over the idea of the move after speaking to his teammates.
"Last night there was a great optimism of the PSG on how to terminate the operation and the details of the payment clause," Bechler tweeted.
"The @EsportsRAC1 information is real: Neymar is divided and Barcelona players were fundamental and put the question in his head."
July 24:
Gerard Pique seemed to confirm Neymar was not leaving Barcelona after posting a picture with the Brazilian with the caption: "He stays".
The message came hours after Neymar dazzled fans by scoring twice as Barca defeated Juventus 2-1 in a pre-season friendly in New Jersey.

Marca say Neymar will sign six-year PSG deal on £500,000 a week. Total cost £352m. £196m release clause + £156m wages
According to Sport, Suarez and Messi had convinced the Brazilian to stay at the club after a long chat.
Additionally, Catalan outlet Diario Goal said Cristiano Ronaldo advised Neymar via Whatsapp to not leave for PSG, but join Manchester United if he wanted a Barca exit.
However, Le Parisien reported that his move to PSG would be made official over the coming days in a deal that would be worth £352m in total.

Marca say Neymar will sign six-year PSG deal on £500,000 a week. Total cost £352m. £196m release clause + £156m wages
But Barca coach Ernesto Valverde wasn't concerned.
He said: "It's only rumours. There's no need to worry about something we don't know if it's going to happen or not. If it happens in the future, we'll see. But no need to worry about it now."
July 25:
AS reported that a PSG "contract is written" for Neymar, and the French club hopes he "signs it in the next few hours".
It added that Neymar originally "accepted the offer", but was now "reconsidering the offer" after talks with his teammates.
But Sport reported terms were agreed with the Barca star, but the deal was being held up over the time span that PSG would pay the £195 million fee to the Catalan giant.
Le Parisien supported Sport's report that sources close to "the player has not made his final decision".
However, the report also said there's "no evidence" the 25-year-old will be wearing a Barcelona shirt next season.
His Brazil teammate Casemiro said he would like to see him in a Real Madrid shirt next season.
The Madrid midfielder joked to GloboEsporte: "Neymar will tell you his future ... he knows what he has to do."
"Why does he not play here at Real Madrid? Here he would be welcome."
July 26:
Pique confessed his viral tweet was merely an opinion, and not inside information.
He said: "My Instagram post was a gut thing. I want Neymar to stay. [It's my] Personal opinion from conversations I've had with him. It's my intuition."
But he added: "I would understand if he went to another team if what he wants is to be a leader, since in Barcelona he has coincided with the best ever, Leo Messi."
That coincided with reports out of the UK suggesting Barcelona were ready to up their bid to £80m for Coutinho to replace Neymar.
However, French outlet Radio Monte Carlo suggested Neymar was seeking assurances that any deal done will be in line with Financial Fair Play regulations, and not open to possible UEFA sanctions.
July 27:
After scoring against Manchester United, it was reported in France that Neymar gave the 'OK' for his PSG deal to go ahead and had told certain Barca teammates he intended to leave.

Football: Barcelona have beaten Real Madrid and Manchester City have managed a convincing victory over Tottenham Hotspur.

Barca, Man City claim wins
The French club were reportedly trying to negotiate with Neymar to get the final price of the transfer down, while also looking to offload Blaise Matuidi and Angel Di Maria to comply with FFP regulations.
A judge in Sao Paulo also cleared Neymar of any criminal charges, after a long-running tax evasion case in Brazil.
July 29:
Neymar's star teammates said they begged Neymar to resist the temptation of moving to PSG after a training ground altercation with new signing Nelsen Semedo.

Footbal: Neymar has been involved in a mid-training fight causing the Brazilian superstar to storm out of training.

Neymar in Barca bust up
The unsettled 25-year-old stormed off the practice pitch in disgust.
"It's true, something did happen, but that's sometimes what happens in training," Barca midfielder Andres Iniesta said.
"All the talk about Neymar right now, everything is magnified. Things like this can happen. It's a personal decision for him, but of course we want him to stay."
Suarez added: "As soon as he clarifies the situation it's better for us and him. He will have his say when he is ready and as a teammate I will support him."
"Our relationship won't change. We want him to stay."
Neymar made an appearance at a Nike shop in Miami to celebrate the release of his new boots, but refused to talk about the PSG speculation.
Meanwhile, The Mirror reported that Eden Hazard and Dele Alli were two targets for Barca to replace Neymar.
Thiago Silva also dropped a further hint a move was on the cards.
Silva told reporters: "Now is not the right time to talk about Neymar. After the Monaco game, we can discuss it.
"After tomorrow's match, everybody will be talking about him."
July 30:
Sport reported that Coutinho was willing to take a pay cut to secure a stunning transfer to Barca from Liverpool, which could convince Neymar to stay at the Nou Camp.
But Iniesta just wanted the speculation to end.
"We consider him a fundamental piece of the team and aside from that, for the whole situation [want] all this noise to be clarified by the player himself or from the club," Iniesta said ahead of Barcelona's pre-season fixture against Real Madrid.
"We [as players] just want peace which will benefit everyone - the players, the club and everything surrounding it."
Pique said Neymar wasn't sure what to do.
"Neymar and I we are very close and I want him to stay and I know the situation," Pique told ESPN FC.
"Right now he doesn't know what to do and we are trying to help him, the ones [on the team] that are more close to him to take the right decision."
July 31:
Spain's football league chief Javier Tebas said he will file a complaint with UEFA for financial fair play (FFP) breaches against PSG over their pursuit of Neymar.
"La Liga will file this complaint because it's a problem for La Liga's competitiveness. Today it's happened to Barca, tomorrow it could happen to Real Madrid, it's happened to Atletico Madrid," Tebas, the La Liga chairman, told Mundo Deportivo.
But according to ESPN, PSG thought they could stay within FFP limits by offering Neymar a five-year deal with the option of a sixth season, which would reportedly lessen PSG's financial commitment under FFP rules.
Les Parisien still thought PSG could seal their move in the coming days, but The Times reported Neymar's father (and agent) asked to delay formal negotiations over a deal until after July 31 (UK time).
That's because Neymar's father reportedly would earn a £23.3m commission after the 25-year-old signed a new Barca contract last October.
Neymar further fuelled speculation he was about to leave after spending 15 minutes in Real Madrid's dressing room after Barca's 3-2 victory in Miami.
Neymar emerges from Real dressing room

The Brazilian emerged from Los Blancos' dressing room with Sergio Ramos and Casemiro's shirts after saying "goodbye" to his Real rivals ahead of a PSG transfer, according to Marca.
But Barca boss Valverde said: "I don't want to speculate about Neymar. I see him in the same place I have seen him recently - on the pitch with us.'"
Dani Alves was hoping the move would happen though.
He said: "I hope it will happen. I've got nothing to do with his decision, it's a very important decision for him."
"Men have to make these kind of decisions. I hope he'll join us, he's one of my best friends and I always want my friends to be close by.
"I can't interfere in his decision. It's his decision to make but we'll welcome him with open arms if he comes."
Sport also reported that Antoine Griezmann and Paulo Dybala will be lined up to replace Neymar.
August 1:
Speculation mounted that Neymar would seal a deal, with PSG "preparing his unveiling".
To finance the 25-year-old's £26m-a-year salary, PSG were considering selling the likes of £45m valued Angel di Maria, while Hatem Ben Arfa, Jese and Grzegorz Krychowiak could all be joined on the transfer list by Serge Aurier and Blaise Matuidi.
It was also reported that Neymar was sending WhatsApp messages to Coutinho telling him to join him at PSG rather than Barca.
Neymar, who has remained tight-lipped about the transfer rumours, posted a message for Chinese fans on Weibo, China's equivalent of Twitter, after arriving for a promotional visit.
"Ni Hao China! I'm Neymar Jr. and I've just arrived in China," he wrote. "I'm in Shanghai at the moment. I would like to send a huge hug to all my Chinese fans, thank you very much for your support."
August 2:
Barcelona blocked payment of a €26 million ($38.5m) bonus for Neymar as the club grew increasingly concerned about his future.
The renewal bonus was agreed on a year ago when Neymar extended his contract with Barcelona until 2021, and was due to be paid to the player after he completed a year.
But the club decided to put it on hold pending to see how the situation evolves.
Independent reported that Barca were focused on signing Paulo Dybala and Ousmane Dembele if Neymar were to leave.

Strangely similar to Neymar's case, Ousmane Dembele was restrained by teammates after clashing with Dortmund keeper Burki in training.
It came as Dembele was, like Neymar with Nelson Semedo, involved in a training ground bust up.
After fulfilling a sponsor's engagement in China, it was suggested he would fly to Doha to meet PSG's Qatari owners and pass a medical.
However, he instead landed in Barca ahead of returning to training...
August 3:
Barcelona said Neymar and his father met with club officials Wednesday to say he wanted to leave.
However, club spokesman Josep Vives said the team "referred them to the release clause in his current contract, which as of July 1 is 222 million euros, which must be paid in full."
Neymar spent 30 minutes at the club's training ground in Sant Joan Despi telling his teammates and coach Ernesto Valverde that he wanted to leave. Valverde gave him permission to go.
Neymar's teammate Lionel Messi posted a farewell message (below) on his Instagram page which read:

Football: Lionel Messi has paid tribute to departing teammate Neymar.

Messi's tribute to Neymar
"It was a huge pleasure having shared all those years with you, my friend @neymarjr," Messi wrote on Instagram next to a montage of pictures of both football stars high-fiving, embracing or laughing.
"I wish you lots of luck in this new stage in your life. See you soon tkm," he added. "Tkm" stands for "te quiero mucho" (I love you loads).
Both Bartomeu and Spanish league president Javier Tebas have said they will consider filing a complaint to UEFA if they think the PSG transfer violates financial fair play rules.
August 4:
It's done. Neymar pays his world record transfer fee ($AU332 million) and a five-year deal at PSG is announced.
Neymar declares himself "extremely happy", PSG is similarly effusive, while Barcelona issues a frosty statement confirming that the release clause transaction has been completed.
"As such, the club will pass on to UEFA the details of the above operation so that they can determine the disciplinary responsibilities that may arise from this case," Barcelona's statement read, amid furious claims of Financial Fair Play breaches.
La Liga briefly held up the transaction, snubbing Neymar's lawyers as they arrived at league headquarters in Madrid to pay the fee. They later relented.
MORE NEYMAR READING:
-
-
-
-
-
-
-

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Verratti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylian Mbappe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weibo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casemiro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tottenham Hotspur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexis Sanchez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javier Tebas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Semedo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ni Hao China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valverde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Parisien</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIAMI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cristiano Ronaldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernesto Valverde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordi Mestre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio Monte Carlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iniesta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Blancos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dele Alli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilians Thiago Silva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serge Aurier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bartomeu</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Fair Play</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andres Iniesta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coutinho</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TKM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blaise Matuidi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG's Angel Di Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEYMAR READING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergio Ramos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelsen Semedo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nou Camp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Globoesporte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equipe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>36</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dani Alves</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ousmane Dembele</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leo Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suarez</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sao Paulo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WhatsApp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antero Henrique</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marca</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mundo Deportivo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AU332</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippe Coutinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thiago Silva</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grzegorz Krychowiak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bechler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unai Emery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulo Dybala</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Parisiens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar Senior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marquinhos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurgen Klopp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucas Moura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG's Qatari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centre-back Javier Mascherano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Pique</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Suarez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catalunya Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAC1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antoine Griezmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EsportsRAC1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diario Goal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hatem Ben Arfa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sant Joan Despi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Gaspart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>29</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angel Di Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mascherano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eden Hazard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dortmund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Trapp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josep Maria Bartomeu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rumour Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>86</count>
    <score>17</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josep Vives</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atletico Madrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dembele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catalans</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tebas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Fernandez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
