<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422330002101457</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/praying-for-approaching-trough-to-lift-conditions/3208242/</url>
  <title>Praying for approaching trough to lift conditions</title>
  <content>
G'DAY surfers.
We've had another week of beautiful weather with a surprise south swell tossed in the mix.
Perhaps not so surprising if you read last week's column and follow the weather maps closely.
Sadly, it peaked Wednesday night with the biggest action being south of the border.
There's another trough approaching the coast from the west with the possibility of a low developing off NSW by midweek.
This would be the third week in a row that this same scenario has occurred. Trending? Maybe.
It's a bit early for that call just yet, so let's have a look at the weekend.
Agnes Water to Coolangatta
Saturday:
Stiff AM westerlies will keep things clean and nearly flat on the beaches. Afternoon winds will be lighter but still offshore.
Surf of less than a metre will have some north in it but don't plan on anything sizable. Half to one metre might be generous.
It will cloud up later in the day and there's a 60% chance of rain as the trough moves offshore.
The high temperature will be 25 degrees, so for anything but ultra-long boarding, it should be a fair day.
The Gold Coast will have light westerlies early too but anything up to a metre will be a surprise blessing.
Shape will be ordinary due to two days of northerly winds preceding. Afternoon winds will tend N/NE and will be light.
That's a recipe for a hot day and it won't disappoint; 25 degrees and only a small chance of a shower or two.
Sunday:
Sunday will be a light wind day, all day. That means sea conditions will be ideal but the surf will be hurting.
Left over north wind affected half metre dribble will be the best we can expect. Fun on the right equipment, so plan for that.
High temp will get to 23 degrees and around a 30% chance of a shower or two. All in all, not the best surf day, but family fun could be on the cards.
Down the Goldy, things won't differ much. Winds will be very light early, then they'll turn NE at up to 15 knots by the afternoon.
Not the best, but with barely any swell, it will make for a nice day otherwise; mostly sunny.
Top temp will be 23 degrees and almost no chance of precipitation. 
Tweed Heads to Coffs Harbour
Saturday:
Byron crew will look back wistfully at a good midweek, but they'll be facing a small, (one metre or less), north wind affected dribble.
Fresh, early westerlies will keep it clean but by afternoon the wind will tend NW-NE, not helping matters at all.
Still, on the bright side, it will be sunny and the temperature will be 21 degrees with no rain expected (5%). Get amongst it.
Coffs Harbour will have long said goodbye to the midweek swell and the leftovers will be a metre or less of north windswell.
Not so bad in some places with winds expected to be generally westerly (NW/SW) at up to 20 knots, keeping things clean.
It's going to be a sunny day as well with a high temperature of 21 degrees and no rain or showers. 
Sunday:
Light winds are predicted Sunday for Byron and if there's any swell it will be micro.
But with clean conditions and a mostly sunny day on tap, why not get out and enjoy?
Twenty-one degrees will be the high temp and zero rain is predicted.
The crew in Coffs can expect mostly sunny skies and no rain Sunday.
Winds will be from the NE later in the day but light and variable early.
Surf? Maybe a metre in a few spots, but generally smaller overall.
High temp will hit 22 degrees and no rain. Sounds like a great day to get out of the house.
Well crew, if you missed the midweek surge you can drown your sorrows in a cold water splash this weekend. And trust me, it is getting pretty cold. 
It would be wise to keep a 'weather eye' on things for a possible low down south next week. hmmmm.
Surf alert
South-east coast waters, Double Island Point to Point Danger:
Saturday: W to NW winds 10 to 15 knots early tending weaker and variable by afternoon.
Byron Coast: Cape Byron to Coffs Harbour:
Saturday: W winds 10/15 knots early tending variable 10 to 15 knots by afternoon. 
Disclaimer: This forecast is prepared the previous Thursday in order to satisfy newspaper production requirements. As conditions may change, it is always recommended that you take a good look before ever entering a surf zone.   
Man believed to be unconscious before horror highway smash
House of horrors in Queensland described to jury
EXCLUSIVE service allows parents to take time to themselves at shops
Inaugural Currie St Music Crawl was a great success
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
PRISCILLA Presley will discuss Elvis during an Australian speaking
The Presets will star at the Maroochy Music and Visual Arts Festival
The Indee is seeking young actors for a new play about Peter Pan
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agnes Water</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie St Music Crawl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Point Danger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Double Island Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-one</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolangatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visual Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Byron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tweed Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRISCILLA Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NW/SW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NW-NE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N/NE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
