<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422836808252337</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/04/08/44/pair-who-forced-frightened-south-african-man-into-coffin-face-court</url>
  <title>Pair who forced frightened South African man into coffin face court</title>
  <content>
Video of a crying South African black man being forced into a coffin by two white farmers has been played in front of an outraged courtroom.

The video is the second to emerge of the coffin assault which was originally shared on social media in November 2016.

The two accused, Theo Martins Jackson and Willem Oosthuizen, told a court they wanted to teach Victor Mlotshwa a lesson for allegedly trespassing on their farm, and did not intend to cause harm.

They pleaded not guilty during the first day of their trial at the Delmas High Court on July 31.

They face charges of kidnapping, assault, attempted murder and possession of an illegal firearm. They were granted bail last month.

The 20-second videos hows Mlotshwa cowering inside a coffin as one man pushes a lid on his head and the other threatens to put petrol and a snake inside the casket as the frightened victim wails. Mlotshwa later escaped.

"Please don't kill me," Mlotshwa is heard begging on the video.

Related Articles

"Why shouldn't we when you are killing our farm?" one of the men replies.

Almost everyone in the courtroom was brought to tears by the confronting footage.

According to Mlotshwa, he was attacked by the farmers while he was trying to hitchhike to Middelburg,  reports.

He said he was on his way to buy supplies for his mother's shop when he was set upon.

"They would beat me if I gave them answers they were not satisfied with. At that stage, I realised that because they would not stop assaulting me, I should agree with whatever they were accusing me of, thinking they may have mercy on me," he said in his testimony.

The case has caused outrage in a country where deep racial divides persist 22 years after the fall of apartheid.

The ruling African National Congress (ANC) and the official opposition party, the Democratic Alliance (DA) picketed outside the high court to raise awareness against racial prejudice in the country.
With Reuters
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Mlotshwa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willem Oosthuizen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democratic Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middelburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mlotshwa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delmas High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theo Martins Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African National Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
