<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422493210862374</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/yeah-im-guilty-killers-mum-admits-trying-to-hire-cop-to-kill-key-witness-20170803-gxolwt.html</url>
  <title>'Yeah, I'm guilty': Killer's mum admits trying to hire cop to kill key witness</title>
  <content>
A murderer's 78-year-old mother has admitted she tried to hire a hitman, who turned out to be an undercover police officer, to kill a key witness in her son's trial.
Michael Cardamone, 50, has pleaded guilty to the violent murder of Karen Chetcuti Verbunt in January 2016.Photo: Mark Jesser
He is due to face a plea hearing on August 21.
But earlier this year, he worked with his mother Maria Cardamone to arrange for a prosecution witness to be killed ahead of a possible trial before a jury.

She appeared in the Wangaratta Magistrates' Court on Thursday, via videolink from the Dame Phyllis Frost Centre.
Dressed in a bright blue jumper, Cardamone - an Italian native - appeared to struggle to understand most of what was said in the courtroom, but gave a clear answer when magistrate David Faram asked how she pleaded.

"Yeah, I'm guilty," she said.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Barrister Rob Stary said his client could understand enough English to give her instructions.
"Mrs Cardamone will enter a plea of guilty to one count of attempting to pervert the course of justice and there will be no application for bail," he said.
The charge of incitement to commit murder was withdrawn.
Maria Cardamone was arrested in May this year and was refused bail because homicide detectives feared she was a danger to other witnesses in the case.
Detective Senior Constable Steven Eppingstall told the court at the time she had become "fixated" on the man she believed had been more responsible for the death of Ms Chetcuti Verbunt than her son.
Police intercepted phone calls between Maria Cardamone and her son from jail in March, where they used code to discuss killing the witness.
The mistake was giving the job to an undercover police officer posing as a hitman, who agreed to be paid in two instalments of $12,500 before and after the job.
The case was adjourned for a plea hearing at the Wangaratta County Court circuit, starting on August 28.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Senior Constable Steven Eppingstall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Stary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cardamone, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Faram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wangaratta County Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Chetcuti Verbunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Chetcuti Verbunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Jesser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame Phyllis Frost Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Cardamone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria Cardamone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2016.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardamone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wangaratta Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
