<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423399448977365</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/football/live-matildas-close-in-on-tournament-of-nations-crown-as-they-rout-brazil/news-story/c72026acb7529710058f071cd21362c3</url>
  <title>Live: Matildas destroying Brazil</title>
  <content>
THE Matildas are well on their way to a first trophy in seven years after a first-half onslaught against Brazil at the Tournament of Nations.
Lisa De Vanna's first-half double helped the Australian women's national soccer team to a 4-1 lead at the break - and made De Vanna the all-time leading Matildas goalscorer with 42 goals.
Alen Stajcic's side need just a draw to claim the friendly competition and are on track despite conceding the first goal of the game. Caitlin Foord and Katrina Gorry were the other first half goal scorers - and the fun continued in the second.
Foord made it 5-1 and a brace to herself by collecting the ball on a breakaway, rounding the goalkeeper and tapping into an empty net.
Sam Kerr was unplayable for most of the game and after being involved in the lead-up to several goals nabbed one for herself to make it 6-1 during the 81st minute.

Football: Brazil have scored in the first 68 seconds of their match against the Matildas.

Brazil score in 68 seconds
Wins over world No. 1 USA and No. 6 Japan mean Alen Stajcic's side can claim the inaugural competition in Carson, California. It might be a friendly tournament but the uplift of claiming honours would be significant for Australia.
With two major tournaments in the next two years, a squad full of promise is desperate for proof of their progress under Stajcic.
It would also give the Matildas' world ranking a boost - which would assist in seeding for both the 2018 Asian Cup and 2019 World Cup. The Matildas last hoisted a trophy at the 2010 Asian Cup.
The Australians are wearing black armbands in respect to legendary football broadcaster Les Murray, who died on Monday.

Les, thank you for fighting for our sport, today we fight for you. Let's go ladiessss 💪🏽
Hayley Raso, who assistedKerr for the first goal in Australia's 4-2 win over Japan, said pre-game the Matildas wouldn't lack for motivation against Brazil.
The Brazilians knocked Australia out of the 2016 Olympics at the quarter-final stage. "It wasn't the best result so I think there will be a little bit of extra motivation," she said.
With a goal of consistent efforts front and centre of his mind, Stajcic said he wanted to see a third-straight performance from his team.
"If we want to win World Cups and Olympic Medals we need to put four or five games together," he said.
"Two is good. We have to be a team that string together five or six. Then we can be a contender."
Australia 6 (De Vanna 7m, 34m, Foord 32m, 68m, Gorry 41m, Kerr 81m) Brazil (Camila 2m)
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alen Stajcic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stajcic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic-medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gorry 41</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Vanna 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia) 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr 81</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camila 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Vanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Raso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katrina Gorry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caitlin Foord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa De Vanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>assistedKerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foord 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
