<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422703664264154</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:38</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/huge-fire-in-dubai-apartment-tower/news-story/972a01fe24d32aba6fb1095c755b73ac</url>
  <title>Huge fire in Dubai apartment tower</title>
  <content>
ONE of the world's tallest residential building is engulfed in flames in Dubai.
Shocked onlookers have uploaded video to social media of the massive blaze at The Torch Tower in the United Arab Emirates holiday hotspot.
It marks the second fire at the skyscraper, in the world-famous Marina district, with an eerily similar incident in 2015.
Fire fighters are currently battling to bring the blaze under control.
Video taken at the scene shows flames spreading upwards -- sending burning debris spiralling down and sparking a blaze in the streets below
Cara Spillane tweeted: "Terrifying to see Torch Tower, in the area I live in (Dubai Marina) on fire now. Hope everyone gets out OK."
Claire Hopkin added: "One of the skyscrapers near me is on FIRE! God! Hope everyone can get out. Scary seeing it!"
The cause of the fire and the current state of evacuation is not yet known.
A fire swept through the same building in February 2015 but was quickly brought under control. There were no fatalities in that blaze and seven people were treated smoke inhalation.
Dubai's glittering skyline has seen a number of similar fires in recent years.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torch Tower</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Arab Emirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara Spillane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Hopkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
