<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423098801262041</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/boost-your-productivity-with-these-cheap-tricks-2017-8</url>
  <title>Boost your productivity with these cheap tricks</title>
  <content>
Your time is valuable, and learning how to make the most of it is one of the simplest ways to build a better you. Of course, that's easier said than done, but you can simplify the process thanks to the .

Featuring 27 hours of productivity-boosting tips and tools used by the world's most successful people, this eight-course collection can guide you on your way to becoming a more organized and efficient person. From time management methods to speed reading techniques and even public speaking advice, this collection comes loaded with content to hone your skills in a myriad of different directions.

Now on sale for more than 90 percent off, you can take the first step towards boosting your potential with  the Ultimate Productivity Bundle for .

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

The Insider Picks team writes about stuff we think you'll like. We aim to highlight products and services you might find interesting, and if you buy them, we may get a small share of the revenue from the sale from our commerce partners, including Amazon. Jeff Bezos, CEO of Amazon, is an investor in Business Insider, the US partner of BI Australia's publishing company Allure Media, through his personal investment company Bezos Expeditions.
Insider Picks are independent of Allure Media's editorial and advertising teams. Click  to learn more.

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultimate Productivity Bundle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BI Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Bezos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allure Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bezos Expeditions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Picks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
