<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423609902378440</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/wilson-parking-to-tow-canberras-repeat-offenders-australias-worst-parkers-20170804-gxp9b8.html</url>
  <title>Wilson, I'm sorry! Company to tow repeat Canberra parking violators</title>
  <content>
Wilson Parking will begin towing repeat offenders from Monday in an effort to free up Canberra's limited parking space.
The ACT has the highest number of outstanding parking breaches in Australia, with over 31,000 fines outstanding for over 90 days.Photo: Karleen Minney
Wilson Parking chief executive Steve Evans said the harsh punishment was only for the ACT's serial parking violators.
"Essentially parking's a limited resource. The reality is what we want to do is free up those bays for genuine parkers and wheel clamps don't achieve that," Mr Evans said.Photo: Karleen Minney
"Over the last 12 - 19 months we've seen an increasing number of parkers that are essentially parking each day and not paying for the service."
The new policy will be rolled out at three sites in Canberra targeting vehicles with more than 10 fines remaining unpaid for over 90 days.

The three target sites are the Wilson-operated parking lots at London Circuit; the lot at the corner of Lathlain Street and Chain Street; and the lot at 48 Macquarie Street in Barton.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The ACT has the most repeat breaches out of any Australian state or territory, with 31,507 fines unpaid. It's followed by Western Australia with 31,291 then the Northern Territory with 10,799. 
One single Canberran has clocked up 327 breach notices, totaling over $21,000 in unpaid fines.
Cars with outstanding fines will only be towed after drivers have received two warning stickers and still found to be parked illegitimately.
This only applies to cars with 10 or more fines unpaid for over 90 days and there are warning signs at each of the target sites.
"There seems to be a growing minority group [...] that seem to feel that since we can no longer find out who they are that gives them license to steal our service," Mr Evans said.
"Back in 2015 we lost the right to access owner vehicle details, so because we can no longer communicate with them essentially the only way we can deal them is when they're in the car park."
Wilson Parking consulted with the ACT government and police before introducing the policy.
Before violators can reclaim their car from the towers, they will have to pay the towing company's fee and settle at least one of their outstanding fines with Wilson Parking.
The towing company is not allowed to recover the costs of the unpaid parking fines but they do set the costs of their towing fees.
"We'd rather not be towing, this is the only place in the country that we're considering this as an issue," Mr Evans said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberrans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karleen Minney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chain Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lathlain Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson-operated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Circuit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Evans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson Parking</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
