<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422579110210155</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/nsw-act/courts-law/confronting-footage-of-street-assault-of-woman-in-sydney/news-story/984379414222d3d3d93418a22eea5cda</url>
  <title>Confronting footage of street assault of woman in Sydney</title>
  <content>
Seven News: Sydney woman attacked by Ex-Iraq War guard
0:32

A Sydney woman has filmed the moment a former Iraq War security guard unleashed a racial attack on her as she walked her dog. Courtesy: Seven News

August 4th 2017
an hour ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Jing Song was left with serious facial injuries. Picture: Channel 7

Share

AN ugly confrontation on a Sydney street has emerged which shows a former Iraqi security worker unleash a series of punches on a young Asian woman.
In the footage, Jing Song, 29, can be heard telling Steven Burke, 34: "You are punching a woman".
In response Burke orders her to "get out of my face" and appears to lunge at her. Ms Song is then heard on the short video, aired on , in obvious distress as she calls desperately for help and Burke repeatedly tells her to "get out of my face".
The incident happened last October when Ms Song was walking her dog with a friend in the Sydney suburb of Mosman. It was about 1pm and the pair encountered Burke who allegedly launched into a racist attack, including telling them to "go back to China".
He denied saying that, but pleaded guilty to recklessly inflicting grievous bodily harm on Ms Song, and was jailed for nine months in May.
When she sentenced him, Downing Centre Local Court magistrate Karen Robinson referenced the "racial slur" and the injuries Ms Song suffered.

Steven Burke is appealing the severity of his sentence. Picture: Channel 7Source:Channel 7
He was released on bail however after he appealed the severity of the sentence. An appeal hearing was held on Tuesday and the case will return to court in September.
At the sentencing in May, the court heard details of the moments that police allege lead to the assault.
'He was moving his arms. He said "I'm going to punch you". He said, "f***ing Asians, go back to your country with your dogs." He said this three or four times," Ms Song's friend told police.

The Downing Centre Local Court heard Burke had worked as a security guard in Iraq and had been hospitalised for post traumatic stress disorder. In the lead-up to the assault he had struggled with his mental health.

Former Iraq security worker Steven Burke in his police interview. Picture: Channel 7Source:Channel 7
On the day of the assault he hadn't taken medication he'd been prescribed and had also abused alcohol.
When he was interviewed by police after the attack, Burke denied the assault, and said he was followed and "scratched" by an Asian man who was filming him after an altercation between their dogs, according to Fairfax.
"I remember he was filming me and then he fell over. He fell and hit the ground, the gutter, and I walked off.
"I think he tripped over some tree stumps."
Police told him the victim was a woman and she had been seriously injured.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-Iraq War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Song</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraqis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mosman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Burke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burkes</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jing Song</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing Centre Local Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jing Song, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
