<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423356499303716</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/business/sydneys-tent-city-likely-to-be-cleared-in-days/news-story/391d8e1d052632dd780f641386d315b7</url>
  <title>Sydney's tent city's days numbered</title>
  <content>
SYDNEY'S infamous homeless "tent city" located in a prime CBD location, could be swept away within days, news.com.au understands.
It comes as the State Government and City of Sydney Council continue to trade blows about who is responsibility for the camp and the people sleeping rough housed within it.
But the police, who have been trying not to be drawn into the brawl, have now gone on the offensive saying they will throw anyone who gets in the way of a possible clear up operation, "in the back of the truck".
A previous camp on Martin Place was dismantled by the City of Sydney council with the aid of the police in June after it was deemed a "public nuisance" and a fire risk.
However,
This time the camp's organisers have ensured the area is spotless with adequate access between and around the tents to give the authorities fewer reasons to evict them.
Nonetheless, it may not be enough to save the camp.
On Friday, Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore will sit down with NSW Minister for Social Housing Pru Goward and Police Commissioner Mick Fuller to discuss the growing protest.
A well-placed source close to the negotiations has told news.com.au a "solution" will be found to the tent city which should see the camp dismantled.
Despite the closed doors discussions, in public the State and local government - and now the police - remain at loggerheads.
Just two days ago the Police were taking a soft line saying while they had the power to move people on they would only do so. "based on reasonable grounds that a group is obstructing traffic/people, intimidating, harassing and/or involved in other illegal activity."
Indeed, camp leaders have told news.com.au that the police have visited the camp on regular occasions and discussions have always been cordial.
But on Thursday, NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller mirrored NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian's position by pointing the finger at the City of Sydney.
However, the state's top cop has now said the problem will persist as long as council provided facilities like mobile showers.
Mr Fuller told radio station 2GB that police were prepared to help council remove the tents and he issued a threat that if, during the camp's possible dismantling, "one person puts a step out of line, I'll throw them in the back of the truck."
"They should be gone and they should not be allowed back in the city."
However, Mr Fuller has admitted that he doesn't want "police rolling through tents and making world news".
Mayor Moore has hit back at the police and has said Council's legal powers are limited in terms of moving homeless people on and. If police want the area cleared, they already have all the power they need, she said.
"Does anyone seriously believe the NSW police need approval from the Lord Mayor to take action¬ if they think there's a -significant risk to public safety?" a council spokeswoman told .
Ms Moore has reiterated calls to find a long-term solution and urged the state government to accept a proposal for a development comprising 150 new affordable and social housing units.
Ms Goward told AAP she expects Friday morning's meeting to be "constructive".
"I don't care what it takes, we will move these people on, and of course we are looking at other options if Clover Moore is unwilling to play her part," Ms Goward said.
"No-one should have to sleep in a tent in Martin Place and yesterday Family and Community Services were there in Martin Place for the 43rd time, offering services and accommodation," she said.
She said she hoped others will join the more than 60 people formerly sleeping rough who are now in permanent housing.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fuller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Housing Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goward</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
