<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651422879757926241</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/victorian-heart-hospital-costs-increase/8773604</url>
  <title>Victorian Heart Hospital plans 'botched', Victorian Opposition says</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Australia's first standalone heart hospital could cost almost double the original estimate, but the Victorian Government denies it has bungled the project and says the facility could be bigger and better than first planned.
The Government previously predicted the Victorian Heart Hospital in Clayton, in Melbourne's south-east, would cost $350 million, but newly released tender documents say "the likely total expected investment is $450-600 million".
Health Minister Jill Hennessy said it was a "project of national significance" and ultimately the scope of the hospital would determine the cost.

Victorian Heart Hospital:

2,000 cardiac surgeries a year
20 cardiac ICU beds
22 ED cubicles
187 inpatient beds
51 same day bays/chairs
6,000+ CT scans, 4,000 MRI scans a year
48,000 clinic/tele-medicine consultations a year
60,000 consulting room consultations a year
28,300 cardiac ED patients a yearSource: EOI brief for consultancy services, DHHS

"We're looking at various scopes," she said.
"That goes to the size of the hospital, the activity, the level of medical research, the level of clinical education in it."
The Government is considering including more clinical education and medical engineering facilities, and .
No other funding has been confirmed for the hospital, which was promised during the 2014 Victorian election campaign.
Federal Health Minister Greg Hunt has ruled out a Commonwealth contribution, saying it did not fund capital works at hospitals.
The Victorian Government is trying to secure philanthropic funding for the project.
"We're now working with project partners to attract support," Ms Hennessy said.
Coalition slams Premier's 'ego' project

The Victorian Opposition blamed an unrealistically low original estimate for the increased costs.
"[Premier] Daniel Andrews has botched it at every single level," Opposition health spokeswoman Mary Wooldridge said.
"It was never realistic that this project would only cost about $300 million and could be built in a couple of years."
Before the 2014 election, the Coalition promised a specialised heart hospital at the nearby Monash Medical Centre, at a lower cost.
"Daniel Andrews' ego wanted this standalone hospital a couple of kilometres down the road, which comes with massive additional cost because you have to build all the infrastructure and duplicate many, many services," Ms Wooldridge said.
The Victorian Government argues the standalone model is best practice.
"Cardiac disease is one of our biggest killers," Ms Hennessy said.
"Co-locating the medical research, the devices, training of clinicians is a model of modern healthcare."
When built, the hospital will have capacity for 2,000 cardiac surgery operations and 28,000 cardiac emergency department presentations.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Opposition</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Medical Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Heart Hospital</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Wooldridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hennessy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Jill Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-locating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Health Minister Greg Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>yearSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EOI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wooldridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
