<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423652852052468</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/domain/domain-news/latest-news/the-key-to-megacity-survival-is-building-up-not-out-says-renowned-architect-richard-hassell-20170803-gxoos7.html</url>
  <title>'The sky is the limit': The green cities of the future</title>
  <content>
Urban planners need to rethink the way they design our largest cities if they want them to have a sustainable future. 

Redesigning cities to go up not out, and going green, are key for mega-city survival, according to internationally renowned architect Richard Hassell. 

In his keynote address at the Housing Futures 2017 Forum on Friday, the Singapore-based architect and co-founder of WOHA talked about how hyper-dense cities needed to be reimagined as garden cities with dense and vertical communities.

A public parkland atop a public housing development in  the WOHA-designed Skyville@Dawson in Singapore. Photo: WOHA

"The sky is the limit," he said. "One day we could have streets in the sky, farms on rooftops and energy farms crossing over between towers."

"But we've tied up our visionary for new districts by being too timid," Mr Hassell said. "Planners make regulations around the conservative things buildings already do, and that enshrines what we build."

With 21st-century cities facing challenges such as global warming, unprecedented population growth and limited space, Mr Hassell said it was a shame so many still relied on decades-old planning templates.

Shared green spaces and gardens, such as these at The Mailings development in Britain, can help foster a sense of community. Photo: Jill Tate

"We need to be exploring climactically appropriate designs, sky-rise greenery and holistic designs that not only focus on the environment but also build and foster communities."

While both Melbourne and Sydney's populations fall well short of the 10 million "mega city" mark,  Mr Hassell said Australian cities still need to plan better for the future.

"If we just keep doing what's done now, it will be okay for a little while, but go forward 20 years when we have much stricter outcomes for energy use and require building to be more resilient - and they'll fall short."

Richard Hassell: Singapore-based architect and co-founder of WOHA. Photo: Studio Periphery

"The high-rise developments done in Australia, are rather large consumers of energy, they have no cross ventilation and cost a lot to run," he added. 

While it sounds simple, the introduction of more greenery could change cityscapes in a big way. 

Apart from being "pretty to look at" Mr Hassell said plants and greenery throughout buildings could help absorb heat and provide shade, reducing the need for air conditioning, absorb gasses, resulting in cleaner air, and help improve mental health.

Richard Hassell said the Oasia hotel, which is completely covered in greenery, is another of his favourite projects. Photo: WOHA

He said one of WOHA's most exciting projects to date was Skyville@Dawson, an innovative public housing development in Singapore.

The site, which houses 960 apartments, has greenery throughout, community living rooms, pavilions and a rooftop public sky-park with a 400-metre jogging track.

Such shared spaces are critical for fostering a sense of community in new developments, according to fellow forum speaker, architect Cany Ash.

Skyville@Dawson has reimagined what public housing can be. Photo: Patrick Bingham-Hall

Her firm's award winning British project, The Malings in Newcastle, transformed a former scrap metal factory into a vibrant apartment development.

"There are smaller outdoor spaces for apartments, shared spaces, community gardens, shared bike storage, a composting area - places where people can interact," she said. 

She said the key to enhancing, rather than destroying existing communities through development was engaging with and co-designing with the community. 

In addition to a large rooftop park it has greenery throughout the apartment blocks. Photo: Patrick Bingham-Hall

Ms Ash also noted that to enliven our cities it was vital to do away the idea of keeping commercial and residential areas separate. 

Mr Hassell said while there was often community opposition to high-density living, when done well, it had the ability to provide equal, if not better, quality of life.​

"When cities keep stretching further and further, they're not a convenient city anymore, as people spend so much time in traffic and transport," he said. "We must densify the city, and the obvious way to do it is around public transport networks."

To improve greenery, Mr Hassell would love to see more cities embrace Singapore's  strategy, which requires developments to provide enough green space to equal to the size of the site it's on. It can take the form of one big garden, or multiple outdoor areas throughout a building.

"It may cost more to build these, but over 30 years you could save millions of millions of dollars worth of energy across developments, and really reduce our carbon footprint."

As for what a self-sufficient city of the future looks like, Mr Hassel imagines they'll be made up of four layers; a rooftop canopy, residential and workplace layer, parkland layer and transportation layer.

Mr Hassell envisions that sufficient cities of the future will have four levels. There will be a tree canopy on top, then medium-rise developments with commercial and residential properties, then a parkland layer and then a transportation layer. Photo: WOHA​

An artist's impression of a sustainable city of the future. Photo: WOHA

Quarterly house price report

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Bingham-Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WOHA-designed Skyville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WOHA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Hassell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skyville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hassell</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Futures 2017 Forum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Studio Periphery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Tate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cany Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore-based</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hassel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
