<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423609902378373</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/national/lunch-with-sam-dastyari-im-an-incredibly-insecure-person-20170801-gxmt0z</url>
  <title>Sam Dastyari's dream for 'angry centre-Left' talkback radio</title>
  <content>
Lunch with a banker fell through so I gave Sam Dastyari a try.
On an hour's notice, one of Australian politics' great self promoters agreed to meet at Fratelli Fresh on Bridge Street in central Sydney. The 34-year-old senator turned up solo 20 minutes late. Bounding in with a huge smile, he reached out for my hand.
"I'm devastated we're not doing this with kebabs," he said, and launched into a cred-establishing anecdote about being asked to open a friend's fast-food outlet around the corner. "You can put that in. You're going to ruin my reputation."
Dastyari was part way through a publicity campaign for his redemptive memoir, One Halal of a Story, which included an Australian Story episode, book-store appearances and enough interviews to make a regular author blush.

Jeremy Piper

In my mind, Dastyari personifies the light and the dark of the Labor Party: an aspirational movement that champions enlightened social advancement, its execution tarnished by cynical street politics.

Chutzpah

The son of Iranian immigrants fleeing an oppressive political regime, Dastyari raced through the NSW Labor apparatus on sheer chutzpah and superman-like energy. The right faction rewarded him with a Senate seat in 2013. Exploiting the latitude of the Senate committee system, he turned himself into one of the most visible Labor politicians in Canberra, a remarkable achievement for a rookie backbencher.
His downfall took place last year after The Australian Financial Review drew attention to a 10-month-old disclosure that he had received about $1670 from a Chinese businessman. He also asked pro-Chinese questions of Australian public servants after a Chinese donor covered a $5000 legal bill.
For a Labor activist who emerged from the NSW division of the party when it was controlled by the corrupt now-prison-dwelling Eddie Obeid ("an incredibly charming, charismatic person," Dastyari says), the behaviour was a depressing example of the venality that has undermined the party's moral authority. His excuse was honest but lame: he didn't want to pay.

Kate Geraghty

After resigning as Labor's consumer affairs spokesman rather than be sacked, Dastyari is seeking what he calls a "second look" from voters, and presumably the media. Which is why he agreed to lunch, even though I asked at his failed mea-culpa press conference last year if he was a Chinese agent and then reported he had sent me a text saying "screw you" about an earlier article.
Dastyari, who disappeared from public view, admitted seeking a doctor's diagnosis for depression. For therapy, he started writing an autobiographical Rolling Stone article that morphed into One Halal of a Story.
"I went through a very deep, dark period," he volunteered. "What I need to learn to do is slow down and think before I act, be a bit calmer, but I don't want to lose my sense of adventure."
Recognised

Wolter Peeters

The restaurant had assigned us a wall-side table where we could be seen by the whole room. We requested a larger, more discreet seating. The manager quickly obliged.
I ordered Fratelli's signature entree, soft cheese wrapped in a zucchini flower. "This is amazing," he told the Italian waitress.
Carolina had been in Australia a few months, and I asked if she recognised my guest.
"He's a senator?" she tentatively answered. "I know him."

Facebook

"You're famous!" I said.
"Politician famous - that doesn't count as famous," he replied, the self deprecation sounding rote.
"I reckon you've got a higher profile than 95 per cent of the shadow ministry," I said.
"I'm not sure that's right, and not all of that is good, let's be clear," he said.

Janie Barrett

"People say you're a show pony."
"Yeah, yeah, and also I'm controversial. I'm polarising."
Baiting

In an age where politics is fought minute-to-minute and keyboard-to-keyboard, Dastyari is a digital gladiator. A self-made video about Sydney house prices has 1 million views, a huge number for a political ad dressed up as entertainment. My favourite was a journalist-ingratiating critique of job cuts by Fairfax Media (which owns AFR Weekend), using My Little Pony figures and his two adorable daughters.
Other stunts like having his book halal certified, or shooting a video outside Friday prayers at Sydney's Lakemba mosque, and calling it the most Australian thing you could do, also drew huge interest online, much of it negative.
I asked if the abuse ever hurt. "Not really, because I bait it," he said. "I know that is going to get the Right-wing trolls to go crazy. I think that's who I am."
A curious mixture of indifference to criticism and personal insecurity, Dastyari said he was concerned by the opinions of only two people: wife Helen Dastyari and Labor leader Bill Shorten.
"Is that because Bill has the power to promote you?" I ask.

Ryan Stuart

"That's because I feel a sense of guilt about putting Bill through all that stuff last year. You know Bill - he's a working-class boy. He was so angry."
I burst out laughing. Blue-collar Bill is one of the great tropes of the MBA's life. The Labor leader's mother was a legal academic who sent him to Melbourne's most expensive Catholic school. His twin brother is an investment banker.
Helen and Sam

Dastyari's parents are known and respected within Sydney's small Iranian community for their intelligence and grace. Their only and adored son chose to marry into another community - the Labor Party - and wed the daughter of Peter Barron, a Labor fixture and press secretary to Prime Minister Bob Hawke.
I met Helen at a dinner organised by Dastyari's publisher a month earlier. Helen lit up when spoken to. At other times, she seemed to observe her husband's garrulous networking with silent resignation - at one point he was surrounded by six fascinated women - as though sitting through a slapstick performance for the umpteenth time. I asked if I was being too harsh.
"No not at all," he said. "Helen's view has always been that private Sam and public Sam are much more different people."
"Don't tell me there's a quiet Sam?" I asked. "Is there a vulnerable Sam?"
"She thinks there is a lot of bravado in the Dastyari performance," he said. "I'm an incredibly insecure person. I think a lot of people in politics are incredibly insecure - the fact that you need that level of public adulation.

"For me that insecurity always comes from that desperate need to fit in and belong."
Non-halal steak

Dastyari eats pork and drinks alcohol. For lunch, he ordered a T-bone steak with potatoes and a light beer. He polished off the meat and let me pick a few butter-smeared potatoes off his plate. He ordered a second $12 beer (the profit margins must be great), which I took as a sign he was pretending to enjoy my company. I appreciated the effort.
Both our phones kept ringing, which was a little annoying because it tripped my iPhone's recorder. Helpfully, Dastyari showed me that by switching the phone to airplane mode, calls wouldn't interrupt the recording.
(When I returned from the bathroom he was typing away on an iPad, which he put away as soon as he saw me.)
He wanted to talk about his plan to give Australia Post a banking licence, a step he believes could drive down bank fees and save failing country post offices.
Attacking the banking industry has been good for his career. Dastyari proposed a royal commission into banks a year before it become Labor Party policy. It is now supported to varying degrees by people as diverse as Small Business Ombudsman Kate Carnell and 60 Minutes reporter Ross Coulthart, and helped prepare public opinion for the Coalition government's bank tax.
"This is part of your jihad against the banks?" I ask, tabloid headlines in my eyes.

"I'm careful with the word jihad as a non-practising Muslim," he said.
(Dastyari was particularly pleased with his response to this question. I know because he rang the next day to discuss what I was going to write.)
Young people

Instead of underplaying his ethnicity to the broader community - which other MP would celebrate the word halal? - Dastyari is marketing his immigrant heritage. His own life is becoming his political message.
That message is resolutely liberal, in the classical sense of the word. By framing the Australian national character through its acceptance of immigrants like himself - a tolerance he knows is being strained by conflict between the mostly Christian West and Islamic extremists from Asia and the Middle East - Dastyari is the anti-One Nation. Perhaps he's the antidote to anti-Muslim Australian sentiment.
"While it might specifically refer to food prepared in keeping with Islamic traditions, the word 'halal' has come to mean much more than that," he writes in One Halal of a Story. "In the language of far-Right politicians and social-media trolls, 'halal' is code for 'Muslim'.
"So just as rejecting halal has become a way for bigots to 'nudge nudge wink wink' their values to each other, tucking into a halal snack pack speaks to the embrace of a more open and pluralistic Australia. That, and a raging hangover."
Being interesting

Dastyari's mission is to make politics interesting, which is why he was so open during our lunch. He knows most politics is deeply boring to all but its practitioners.
With cynicism towards mainstream politicians on the rise, competition for the swinging voter is more intense than  30 years ago. Labor's future supporters don't watch television news or buy newspapers. Dastyari is reaching out to voters that Shorten or Malcolm Turnbull struggle to communicate with.
The danger, of course, is that Dastyari won't be taken seriously by the establishment that will determine how far his political career progresses: the leaders of his own party, and others in the union movement and media who can throw up crash barriers in front of the Dastyari bus.
He may be a media tart. But Dastyari isn't stupid. His parliamentary mentor is Chris Bowen, the shadow treasurer and a likely candidate for Labor leader if Shorten fails.
Redemption

A year ago, Dastyari asked for and was given the portfolio of consumer affairs, a department that doesn't exist in the federal government. It gave him a platform to pursue injustices that had upset millions of people. He held it 46 days.
Maybe it was the alcohol, or the gravital force of his downfall, but the end-of-lunch conversation drifted back to Dastyari's self-destruction.
"This book is about that press conference, right?" I said, accusingly.

"Well, read it. The book's about a lot of things."
"Aren't you asking voters for redemption, for a second chance?"
"Redemption and second chance are very strong language. What I am asking for is a second look. What I want to do is this: we make politics boring; we make politics stale. This is an incredibly fun, interesting, exciting, business we are in, and it is also absurd and I try to capture a lot of absurdity in the book."
Talkback

I tried to tease out what job he wants in a Labor government. I got nowhere.
"You know what I really want to do in life?" he said. "Sydney talkback radio."
"What channel?" I asked.
"I want angry centre-Left radio. Dasher in the mornings - getting in to work."

When her shift finished, Carolina the waitress came over and shook hands. She seemed genuinely pleased to have served us, although maybe she was hoping for a big tip.
After I settled the tipless bill (newspapers are tight), Dastyari quipped "Do they take RMB?"
Always the joker.
MENU
Fratelli Fresh,
Bridge Street, Sydney
1 large Pellegrino water, $9.50
4 Vixen beer, $48
2 zucchini flowers, $10
1 chicken scaloppine, $29
1 Bistecca steak, $32
Total: $128.50

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR Weekend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-bone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Piper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Coulthart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Story</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dastyari</name>
    <count>25</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Barron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Right-wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Dastyari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Small Business Ombudsman Kate Carnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIXEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dashers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fratelli Fresh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastyari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Pony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pellegrino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolter Peeters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fratellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridge Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue-collar Bill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Obeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janie Barrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Geraghty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rolling Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolinas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Halal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
