<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423352204336370</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/real-estate/queensland/townsville/cottage-living-on-city-fringe/news-story/dd82e84708ef58b402829d4aa606e8de</url>
  <title>Cottage living on city fringe - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
BUYERS searching for a low maintenance home a stone's throw from the city with plenty of cottage charm will be impressed with this three-bedroom house in South Townsville.
The home is within walking distance of the new North Queensland Stadium and is also close to the boat ramp, restaurants and a hotel.
Tracey Stack and Emma Nancarrow from Smith & Elliott are selling 40 Davidson Street and are asking for offers over $365,000.
"I think the buyer could be a first homebuyer, people downsizing, or someone looking for an alternative to unit living because the house is very low maintenance," they said.
"There is no external painting required and inside it's been extensively renovated.
"The kitchen has been refurbished, there is a lovely outdoor area and it's neat as a pin."
The fringe-city suburb of South Townsville has long been popular with buyers searching for historic miners' cottages or ultra modern apartments in areas such as Palmer Street while there is also more modern builds like 40 Davison Street's masonry block cottage.
The cottage set on a 304sq m block has an open-plan living area, is fully air-conditioned, has separate laundry, undercover parking for one car, two outdoor living spaces shaded by established gardens and ceramic tiles throughout.
Ms Stack said she used to live in South Townsville herself and the area had plenty of owner occupiers which fostered a strong sense of community.
"Sometimes people overlook South Townsville because they are looking at North Ward and Belgian Gardens but I think it shouldn't be discounted because it really is right on the fringe of the city and in some cases you're closer to the city than you are in North Ward," she said.
"A lot of people do walk to work in the morning.
"There is that real sense of community in the area.
"It's industrial, commercial and residential but that makes it such an interesting suburb."
40 Davidson St will be open for inspection on Sunday from 11.30am to 12pm and Tuesday from 5.30pm to 6pm.
For more information call.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davison Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Nancarrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Stack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davidson St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davidson Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Townsville</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey Stack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Ward</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmer Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
