<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423609902378361</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/its-time-to-let-go-of-the-weather-girl-stereotype/8773722</url>
  <title>Dear viewers, it's time to let go of the 'weather girl' stereotype</title>
  <content>
Australia has long been obsessed with the weather. Think of it as a national pastime.
From droughts to floods, bushfire season or destructive cyclones, the ability to predict the future is powerful.
It's like being given a crystal ball.
And these days everyone can be an expert given the availability of apps and the popularity of the Bureau of Meteorology website. (Seriously, it rivals Google for the number of hits it gets).

But while technology has made forecasts ever more accessible, one thing that hasn't changed is the ubiquitous television weather presenter.
And this position has long attracted public comment. Love them or hate them, everyone has an opinion.
According to professor Lawrie Zion - author of the new book The Weather Obsession - this fasciation started with the dawn of television.
"While the weather girl craze abated in the United States by the early 1960s. In Australia, where television had been introduced relatively recently, it was just beginning," he .
"Decades later, the 'weather girl' tag has proved hard to shake."
For proof, you need look no further than the comments that roll in daily on social media and in gossip columns, commenting on a weather presenter's appearance/age/clothing/make-up/gender.
I've received my fair share, and it seems there's one type of presenter people are expecting to see...

External Link:

Weather girl tweet

External Link:

Weather girl tweet 2
Often these comments turn to critiques about the presenter's qualifications and ability to present the weather forecast.
Professor Zion raises this point himself and asks if a weather presenter's forecasting skill (or lack thereof) has an impact on their worthiness to fulfil the role.
I say it doesn't. And it's a point that's worth explaining.
You don't need to be a meteorologist

While meteorological training and forecasting experience definitely helps me to explain the weather on ABC News Breakfast every weekday, the actual forecast comes from the Bureau of Meteorology.
I'm not equipped with all the model data from the bureau's multi-million-dollar supercomputer and, crucially, I simply don't have the time to construct a forecast for the whole of Australia each morning.
I leave that work to the expert teams forecasting at the Regional Forecast Centres around the country.
It's more important for a weather presenter to be an effective communicator who can engage an audience and convey the importance of warnings and severe conditions.
This doesn't mean that a lack of a forecasting history means that weather presenters don't know what they're talking about - they do.
I have had many interesting conversations with other ABC weather presenters who know far more about the weather in their home states than I do, because they focus so closely on how the weather changes over a specific area.
Perhaps even more importantly, they build a relationship with the audience they serve, and an understanding of their particular needs.
The best bit is when your forecast can be both informative and entertaining.
I'll concede that for some outlets, the weather presenter is really a roving entertainment reporter who happens to read out the temperatures.
For the rest, developing a significant understanding about the weather when you look at it every day is a given.
It is on this that we should measure the value of a weather presenter. Not on their age. Not on their looks. Not on their clothes. And certainly not on their gender.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Forecast Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Zion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawrie Zion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weather Obsession</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
