<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423652852052476</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834101/sophie-turner-says-instagram-numbers-score-her-roles/?cs=2372</url>
  <title>Sophie Turner says Instagram numbers score her roles</title>
  <content>
In risk-averse Hollywood where box office bankability rules, social media followings have become the ultimate industry cheat sheet.

The higher your number, the more you'll be working - at least according to Game of Thrones star, Sophie Turner.
"A lot of what I have achieved is about timing and luck, but it is also, and I hate to say it, about a big social media following," she told Porter magazine.
Turner, 21 - who debuted as Thrones' Sansa Stark when she was just 14, her first television role - has 5.4 million followers on Instagram, and another 1.35 million on Twitter.
Those numbers are mouth-watering to Hollywood producers when it comes to casting, she says.
"I auditioned for a project and it was between me and another girl who is a far better actress than I am, far better, but I had the followers, so I got the job," Turner said.
"It's not right, but it is part of the movie industry now."
The quip may be self-deprecating modesty, as Sansa's storyline towards no-nonsense power-player has become one of the show's most lauded, but it may also explain Turner's hefty workload this year.
As well as Thrones, the actress is set to star in the sci-fi comedy Time Freak, the thriller Huntsville, and a leading part in the '90 set blockbuster X-Men: Dark Phoenix, where she reprises her role as the kinetically gifted Jean Grey.
Hollywood's latest strategy - which is also common in the worlds of publishing and music - isn't exactly an industry secret, where money-spinners look for sure bets when it comes to audience numbers.
Stars including Emma Thompson, Michael Caine and Gemma Arterton, who starred in the Bond film Quantum of Solace, have previously spoken of their frustration at the tendency and the growing pressure on aspiring actors to 'sell' themselves online.
"Actors are becoming attached in a sort of business way to their social media profiles, and I think that's a disaster," Thompson told the UK's Telegraph last May.
"If they're good, then all right, fine. But I'd say that is rare."

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK's Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gemma Arterton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thrones' Sansa Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Caine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-Men</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Freak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quantum Of Solace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Turner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
