<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423648557085065</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-04/manus-island-detention-centre-detainees-refuse-to-clear-compound-after-days-of-protests/1691236</url>
  <title>Manus Island detention centre detainees refuse to clear compound after days of protests</title>
  <content>
The standoff comes after three days of protests inside the centre, against attempts to force the asylum seekers to move out.
Detainees said a large group of local police and centre guards were being directed by Australian Federal Police and Australian Border Force Officers as to how to close the compounds and move the men inside.
Sudanese refugee Abdul Aziz Adam said it looked like authorities were preparing to use force to close down a main accommodation block.
"They are gathering in a big group of maybe 100 to 120 guys and they are ready," Mr Adam said.
"They brought the fire guys in front and the police guards were everywhere and they locked the gate and they are ready to come in and drag people out of Foxtrot."
He said the detainees were trying to keep things peaceful.
"We don't want to do anything because we know the consequence. We have hurt enough," he said.

Photo:(Supplied)
Immigration authorities have  near the main town on Manus Island, while those men whose claims for asylum were rejected must leave PNG.
They said electricity, water and cleaning services would be progressively shut off and that PNG Police would deal with any asylum seekers or refugees "illegally occupying state property".
Most of the 700 refugees on the island are refusing to move because they believe they are not safe in the PNG community.
The Australian and PNG Governments had told the refugees .
Immigration officials also warned refugees that if they continue to refuse to move, it could affect their applications to resettle in the United States.
While a number of men have been interviewed for US resettlement, the US State Department said no decisions had been made about who would be resettled.
The  and could deny entry to new refugees until the cap resets in October.
Immigration Minister Peter Dutton said on July 19 that the Manus Island centre would close by the end of October, even if the refugees cannot go to the US until the start of that month.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Border Force Officers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US State Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Aziz Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sudanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
