<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423137455968341</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/mohamed-al-daradji-turning-conflict-into-cinema-with-the-journey/8768034</url>
  <title>Filmmaker kidnapped by terrorists twice in Iraq then held by US turns ordeal into cinema</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

On December 17, 2004 award-winning filmmaker Mohamed Al-Daradji was kidnapped by Al Qaeda.
"I was shooting my first film, Ahlaam, in Baghdad," he recalls.
"It's near the famous Haifa Street - the American army called it the 'death street', [because it was] controlled by Al Qaeda at the time."
Suspected of filming propaganda material for the United States, Al-Daradji - who is an Iraqi-Dutch citizen - and three members of his crew were captured.
Their soundman was shot in the legs while trying to run away - and all were blindfolded and tortured.
"If they kidnap people, they interrogate you and after that, shoot you and throw you in the Tigris River," Al-Daradji says.
"That was famous at the time."
As feared, the group was taken to the banks of the Tigris.
Al-Daradji recalls praying to God for forgiveness and fighting the urge to collapse.
"Then after seconds, a minute - I don't know how long - my old make-up person ... said: 'They ran away, Mohamed, they ran away!'," he says.
A wail of police sirens had spooked the terrorists, heralding freedom for Al-Daradji and his crew.
Unfortunately, it didn't last long.

Hours later, as the men sat in a nearby hospital waiting for their wounded friend to be operated on, another terrorist group entered the picture.
The militias, who Al-Daradji believes controlled the hospital, were not affiliated to Al Qaeda.
Yet they took the men hostage - kidnapped, twice in one day.
"The [first] group, we knew they were Al Qaeda. We knew their language and what we needed to [say] - talk against the Americans, against the Shia, and against the government," Al-Daradji says.
But the group were unsure of how to appease the new militia.

Keeping quiet, they endured a day of torture, before being handed over to the US Army.
"I was so happy when I heard the American language by the checkpoint," Al-Daradji recalls.
"And then the Americans started to beat us, accusing us [of] working for Al Qaeda and making propaganda films against the Americans.
"It's funny - it's unbelievable."
Detained for seven days, the crew's release only came after the Dutch embassy intervened.
"If I was not Dutch, just Iraqi, I would spend two years at the prison. That's usually what happens," Al-Daradji says.
Escaping Iraq

For Al-Daradji, it was the second time the Netherlands had come to his rescue. Back in 1994, as a 17-year-old, he fled Baghdad and spent nearly a year trying to reach the Dutch border.
"The day I arrived in Holland I felt like, this is the start of my new life," he says.
"I had a very difficult time before that, and [I wanted to] study and work and develop myself here."

Growing up under the brutal reign of Saddam Hussein, and during the Iraq-Iran war, Al-Daradji's early years were tarnished by violence.
His cousin, an opponent of the regime, was one of its many victims.
"I was very close to him," Al-Daradji says.
"I was helping him, giving him fake IDs or things like that so the Iraqi Intelligence Police could not capture him.
"He [was] captured and hanged by the regime, so I ended up - with one or two friends - escaping Iraq."
Knowing little more about the Netherlands than its reputation for Friesian cows and footballer Johan Cruyff, Al-Daradji left his homelands.
But Europe offered more than just safety.
After arriving, Al-Daradji pursued his passion for filmmaking. Later, he graduated from the Northern Film School at Leeds in the United Kingdom, with a master's degree in directing and cinematography.

The study sharpened his technical skills, but Al-Daradji says storytelling was always in his nature.
Even as an eight-year-old in Baghdad, he was selected by teachers to read his tales in front of the weekly school assembly.
"The funny thing is I'd write very good stories about Saddam Hussein - [and what a] great a leader he is," Al-Daradji laughs.
"I imagined him like he was a god, so it was very good propaganda for the school to read."
Iraqi cinema during the 80s and 90s was a propaganda tool for the government.
So Al-Daradji and his friends sought out Egyptian, Indian and American films instead, like Rambo and The Godfather.
Despite these Western influences - and his education in Europe - the filmmaker's works are deeply entwined with Middle Eastern experiences.
Interpreting Islam on screen

Encouraged by family to become a religious leader, Al-Daradji says his relationship with Islam has shifted over the years.
"In the beginning it was, for me, a force. You've been forced to get this religion and I used to [practise] in a traditional way," he says.
"I used to do the call for prayer and mentally I was prepared to be an imam, you know, Sheikh Mohamed!
"But then I felt, nah, that's not for me."
Rather than turning his back on Islam, Al-Daradji forged his own interpretation of faith. He prays once a day, instead of the recommended five, and reveres stories in the Koran.

External Link:

The official trailer for Al-Daradji's award-winning film Son of Babylon
In making his 2009 film Son of Babylon, which received the prestigious Raindance Award at the British Independent Film Awards, Al-Daradji harnessed the rhythm of the Koran as a guide for his picture.
Koranic verse also plays a fascinating role in Al-Daradji's upcoming feature The Journey, which he spoke about on a recent visit to Australia for , a program supported by the Council for Australian-Arab Relations.
The film, set for festival release this year, tells the story of a young woman at a Baghdad train station about to detonate a bomb.

"My new film is based around a phrase in the Koran," he says.
"One sentence, and I make a 90 minute film about it.
"In rough translation, it's about near-death experience - the moment you sense you are about to die. God takes the veil out from your eyes and you can see the unseeable. You get see the things that [are] beyond our power as a human being.
"But the moment that you see this kind of thing, this is the moment you are about to lose your life."
The Journey, as the title suggests, is a film about stepping into another's shoes.
The would-be suicide bomber, in her last moments on Earth, meets five of the people she's about to kill.
For Al-Daradji, this story - inspired by his own near-death experience - aims to challenge extremist ideologies and emphasise the importance of shared humanity.
"Religion for me is not a way of life, but a way of understanding life," he says.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-Arab Relations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johan Cruyff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 17, 2004</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigris River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koranic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leeds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baghdad</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraqis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraqi Intelligence Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rambo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raindance Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saddam Hussein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koran</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Egyptian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al-Qaeda</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahlaam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheikh Mohamed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al-Daradji</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>16</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraqi-Dutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Son of Babylon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Independent Film Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherlands</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haifa Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Al-Daradji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq-Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Film School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
