<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423652852052465</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/one-of-melbournes-mostloved-live-music-venues-announces-its-closure-after-a-decade/news-story/10095846b429d7df3b0bf743528581e5</url>
  <title>Caravan unhitched over lease breakdown</title>
  <content>
A FAVOURED haunt for music lovers in Monash is about to be unplugged.
For almost a decade, The Caravan Music Club has played host to Australian and international artists including Ross Wilson, Don Walker, Mental as Anything, Darryl Brathwaite and Tex Perkins.
Club owner Peter Foley said he was forced to shut down the venue after being unable to come to an agreement with its terms of tenancy with the Oakleigh Carnegie RSL sub-branch.
"I'm completely devastated to be closing because we have adored every moment in the past decade in Drummond St," Mr Foley said.
He said a proposal was submitted to the sub-branch committee for a secure lease but was rejected and the club was instead offered a set of operational conditions and financial expectations.
Mr Foley said he was grateful to have brought so much joy to the community.
"The strength of this gig has been the wonderful tribe of genuine music lovers who have gathered in this lovely room week after week to celebrate music and community," he said.
"We've had some magical Don Walker and Ross Wilson gigs and three Carnival of Suburbia festivals."
He said he was overwhelmed by outpouring of support with more than 1000 Facebook messages and 500 emails by people who were devastated by the pending closure.
He said the club was on the lookout for another venue in Monash to replicate the caravan vibe.
"It's all been an amazing journey for a gig that started as a hobby in my lounge room in Oakleigh," Mr Foley said.
Australian rock legend Ross Wilson said he was devastated by the news.
"I have so many fond memories dating back to the 60s when I was part of The Pink Finks," Mr Wilson said.

Australian musician and author Brian Nankervis said the club "inspired performers to take risks because the audience is on your side".
Molly Meldrum said venues such as The Caravan Music Club were at the heart of the community.
"I hope that this venue doesn't close because they are instrumental for young musicians to get their name out there," Mr Meldrum said.
Oakleigh Carnegie RSL sub-branch president Doug Pendergast said the club's closure was due to an unsuccessful takeover bid by the venue's owners.
"The bid meant their directors would manage all event bookings for our memorial hall with the exclusion of Anzac Day and Remembrance Day commemorations," Mr Pendergast said.

He said the sub-branch offered the club an opportunity to become a subtenant and pay a commercial-based rental to remain in the hall.
"Their former license to occupy our Memorial Hall had not included any rental or outgoing costs for almost eight years of live music operations," Mr Pendergast said.
"We will continue to provide entertainment, events and support at our sub-branch."

During the speech for Samuel Johnson's Gold Logie win, Molly Meldrum gave a speech that left viewers confused as to what point he was making. Courtesy: Nine

Molly's speech rambles on
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memorial Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remembrance Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel Johnson's Gold Logie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Nankervis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly Meldrum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Wilson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drummond St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnival of Suburbia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Foley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tex Perkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caravan Music Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darryl Brathwaite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh Carnegie RSL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doug Pendergast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONASH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Meldrum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pendergast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pink Finks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
