<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423824650746633</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/flights/qantas-flight-attendant-jobs-behind-the-scenes-of-cabin-crew-training/news-story/f55fda308ce17690670f3d6e70881725</url>
  <title>Qantas flight attendant jobs: Behind the scenes of cabin crew training</title>
  <content>
Behind the scenes at Qantas cabin crew training
2:51

Behind the scenes at Qantas cabin crew training

July 18th 2017
17 days ago
/display/escape.com.au/Web/Escape.com.au - Travel/

The recruits must be prepared for all types of weather including rain.

Rowena RyanEscape

Share

"EVACUATE. Evacuate," the flight attendants shout. "Seat belts off. High heels off. Come this way."
The sense of urgency is real, the commands are well-versed, however thankfully the situation is a drill.

I'm at the Qantas cabin crew training facility in Sydney for a rare look inside the airline's intense training course for their new recruits.
"I've broken out in a stress rash, there's been a few tears. Nothing can prepare you for this training," says trainee cabin crew member Matthew Thompson, half-jokingly.
The point is, this course is intense. For those who thought cabin crew were there to serve coffee and tea, you'll be surprised at the gruelling training put in place to become a Qantas flight attendant.

Qantas cabin crew training for an emergency landing.Source:Supplied
New go through an intensive seven-week course, of which 3.5 weeks are made up of emergency training procedures.
Today we're watching trainees complete a raft evacuation into a pool to simulate an unexpected water landing.
The "wet drill" is under the supervision of George Farmakidis, who has been a Qantas aviation safety training instructor for eight years and was previously cabin crew for the airline for four years. Only once recruits pass the emergency procedures can they move on to the less taxing "service training" - food and wine.

Behind the scenes at the Qantas cabin crew training facility.Source:Supplied
"The level of instruction and assessment is so tough," says Farmakidis. Recruits must gain an 80 per cent pass mark on theory exams and 100 per cent pass on the practical examination.
"Cabin crew are not only there for the service, but they're there to save lives and make sure passengers get off if there's an evacuation procedure," he says.

The recruits must paddle away from any floating debris.Source:Supplied
We watch as the recruits perform an evacuation drill from a replica cabin into a raft that's designed to fit 70 passengers. The aim is to get passengers out of the aircraft in under 90 seconds using half the available exits. The recruits must then detach the raft and paddle away from debris and set up a canopy quickly as possible before the simulated rain showers set in. And set in they do, the raft and crew are completely drenched.
The training is ongoing. Every six months current Qantas cabin crew must do a theory exam and every year they must pass a practical test. "If they're not proficient, they can't fly," says Farmakidis.

The trainees putting a canopy over the raft to protect against the weather.Source:Supplied
Chatting with the recruits, one senses the excitement, anticipation and heightened anxiety that comes with the training course.
"We pretty much get put into a pressure cooker," says Madison Prince, 24.
"I had no idea it would be this full on," says Kate Rossiter, 35. "You're in an environment where it goes black, you hear screams, you have to remember your drills world by word and not miss a step," she says.
"I thought maybe it was going to be service-based with tea, coffee and food. There's none of that until the end, otherwise they'd put a vending machine on if that was the case. We're predominantly there to save lives if something happens," she says.

The recruits must be prepared for all types of weather including rain.Source:Supplied
Trainer Farmakidis says often the most challenging part of the course is the swim test when recruits must climb completely wet and sodden from the pool into the raft.
"It's almost militaristic training. We have instructors from the navy, army and firefighters," he says. "Some don't make it through training."
Qantas takes its safety training very seriously and has an enviable safety record. It was named the .

For more travel news and inspiration sign up to .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmakidis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madison Prince, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/Escape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Rossiter, 35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowena RyanEscape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Farmakidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
