<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423691506758804</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/the-economy/rba-sees-economy-growing-at-3-a-year-jobless-rate-to-edge-lower-20170804-gxpam6.html</url>
  <title>RBA sees economy growing at 3% a year; jobless rate to edge lower</title>
  <content>
The Australian economy is chugging along as expected and remains on track to expand at around 3 per cent a year, the central bank says.
The Reserve Bank of Australia's quarterly , contains a few positive adjustments to its earlier outlook.

Up Next

CBA accused of breaching money laundering act

03:45

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Reserve Bank holds cash rate

For the eleventh consecutive month, the RBA keeps the cash rate on hold at 1.5 per cent. Vision courtesy ABC News

"The economy is expected to grow at an annual rate of around 3 per cent over the next couple of years, which is a bit higher than estimates of potential growth," it said.
As a result, the jobless rate is expected to "edge lower" and underlying inflation to rise to around 2 per cent over the second half of 2017 and into 2018.

"The outlook continues to be supported by accommodative monetary policy and an improvement in the global economy," the RBA said.
Earlier this week, the , where it has sat for a year.

The RBA reinforced that decision on Friday, saying this was providing "appropriate support" for the economy.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The central bank also pointed to recent improvements in labour market conditions, in line with its expectation for a "gradual" recovery in wages growth.Photo: Ben Rushton
"Wage growth is then expected to pick up gradually over 2018 and 2019," it said.
But it did note the likely upward pressure on inflation from higher power prices.Photo: Nicholas Rider
"There is considerable uncertainty about when and how the range of factors that contributed to the increases in wholesale utilities prices will be resolved and how large the direct effects on retail utilities prices will be," the RBA said.
More to come
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Rider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
