<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423652852052500</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/sydney-man-guilty-of-murdering-neighbour-with-a-smashed-beer-bottle-20170804-gxpamg.html</url>
  <title>Sydney man guilty of murdering neighbour with a smashed beer bottle</title>
  <content>
A Sydney man who fatally stabbed his neighbour with a smashed beer bottle has been found guilty of murder.
Sateki Siale had admitted causing the death of Kelly Ventigadoo, but pleaded not guilty to murdering him early on October 11, 2015, at Lakemba in Sydney's south west.
However, a NSW Supreme Court jury on Friday found the 26-year-old was guilty of murder after less than three days of deliberations.
Siale previously admitted smashing a beer bottle on a brick fence then using it to stab Mr Ventigadoo in the neck causing him to fall to the ground outside his Sydney home.
Siale also admits striking him again when Mr Ventigadoo got back up, causing him to bleed to death within five minutes in front of his parents at about 12.30 am on October 11, 2015.
He pleaded not guilty to murder, instead pleading guilty to assault causing death while intoxicated - a plea which the Crown did not accept.

Clinical forensic pharmacologist John Farrar previously told the NSW Supreme Court it was estimated Siale had been drinking for more than six hours and would have had a blood alcohol content of between 0.23 and 0.36 when he attacked his victim with a smashed beer bottle.
He claimed to have no memory of the attack.
Mr Farrar said if this was correct Siale would have had to have consumed up to 17 bottles of beer and half a bottle of bourbon.
In his opening address in the NSW Supreme Court earlier this month, prosecutor Jose Crespo told the jurors the issue for them was Siale's state of mind when he caused the death of Mr Ventigadoo.
The Crown had to prove that at the time he had the intention to kill or cause really serious injury to Mr Ventigadoo or that when he did the act causing death it was done with "reckless indifference to human life", he said.
At about 12.30 am, Siale, who told police he had been consuming alcohol throughout the day, approached Mr Ventigadoo. The victim was standing in his driveway with his parents after having earlier having been to a club.
His father James is hearing impaired so "he talks loud" because he doesn't wear hearing aids, Mr Crespo said.
Siale, who had just pulled up in a car driven by his girlfriend, approached them with a bottle of beer in his hand.
Mr Crespo said he expected the jurors would hear evidence that Siale said words to the effect of: "Why are you talking so loud, this is my street".
The mother replied "OK, OK, we are going" , while her son said "mate, they are going" before he was struck with the shattered bottle.
Siale's barrister, Brad Hughes, told the jury his client had no memory of what happened, but had made various admissions agreeing "that is what must have happened".
Because of all the alcohol and illegal drugs he had consumed on October 10, "he could not form the specific intention the Crown needs to prove murder".
An expert witness had estimated his blood alcohol reading at the time was 0.32 grams.
The trial is continuing.
AAP 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sateki Siale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Crespo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ventigadoo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Farrar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Ventigadoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Crespo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siale</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 11</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Farrar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
