<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423652852052533</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/biggest-games-of-2017-2017-7</url>
  <title>The 20 biggest games coming in the second half of 2017</title>
  <content>
Do you hear it? The wave is coming. Soon, we'll be overwhelmed by dozens of blockbuster video games arriving all at once.

As usual, the back half of the year is awash with major game launches, from the highly-anticipated "Destiny 2" in September to the also highly-anticipated "Super Mario Odyssey" in October. Whether you're looking to pair up with friends online or tuck into a personal adventure, there's something great coming for you in the next few months.

Let's dive in!

Get the latest Microsoft stock price

The Fullbright Company

What it is: 'Tacoma' is the story of six crew members of a space station (named 'Tacoma'), set in the near future of 2088. You're a forensic investigator, essentially, but in space, digging through notes and audio logs and other detritus of their lives. If you played 'Gone Home,' you'll find 'Tacoma' immediately familiar.

Release date: August 2

Platforms: Xbox One, Windows 10 PC, Mac, Linux

Naughty Dog/Sony

What it is: The 'Uncharted' series, featuring Nathan Drake as he traipses around the world in third-person, is over. With 'Uncharted 4: A Thief's End,' the series was officially sunset -- until 'Uncharted: The Lost Legacy,' that is, which extends the series by following Chloe Frazer as the main character. If you liked the high-octane, Indiana Jones-esque gameplay of previous 'Uncharted' games, 'The Lost Legacy' is more of that with a new set of characters in a totally new environment.

Release date: August 22

Platforms: PlayStation 4

EA Sports

What it is: Do we need to spell out what 'Madden' is? Probably not, right? Every August, a new 'Madden' game comes out, and 2017 is no different. As usual, 'Madden NFL 18' is a football simulation sports game where you can live out your wildest NFL dreams. There's a new story mode, and this is the first time EA's made the game using its proprietary Frostbite game engine, but if you're getting 'Madden' you probably don't need to hear about any of that -- you just wanna play some football. We totally understand! This is your chance to do just that.

Release date: August 25

Platforms: Xbox One, PlayStation 4

Nintendo/Ubisoft

What it is: For the first time ever, Nintendo's Super Mario is appearing with Ubisoft's Rabbids in a game. Rather than a traditional Mario- or Rabbids-style game, 'Mario + Rabbids Kingdom Battle' is a tactical affair. You'll control a small party of Rabbids alongside characters from the world of Super Mario, tackling enemies from afar while carefully taking cover behind walls. If you're familiar with the 'XCOM' game series, you'll be right at home with 'Mario + Rabbids Kingdom Battle.'

Release date: August 29

Platforms: Nintendo Switch

Activision

What it is: From the folks who created the outrageously popular 'Halo' video game series comes 'Destiny,' a new first-person shooter series about taking down alien hordes invading Earth. The first 'Destiny' was tremendously divisive, with some fans loyally pouring hundreds of hours in while others scoffed. 'Destiny 2' is an attempt to bridge that divide, both improving the strengths of the first game and attempting to bring back in players who bounced off. An early beta showed promise, but critics and players alike are waiting for the full release before passing judgment. Whether it lives up to the hype remains to be seen.

Release date: September 6, October 24

Platforms: Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PC (launches later on PC)

Nintendo

What it is: Ever wondered what it's like to take on Pikachu? What about taking him on while he's wearing a Lucha Libre outfit? Good news: 'Pokken Tournament DX' enables exactly that. It takes the fighting system of 'Tekken' and combines it with the goofy world of Pokemon to create a surprisingly nuanced fighting game. The game already launched on the Wii U, but it's being re-launched (with prettier graphics and more fighters) on the Nintendo Switch this fall.

Release date: September 22

Platforms: Nintendo Switch

Studio MDHR

What it is: 'Cuphead' is a gorgeously hand-drawn, relentlessly difficult platform-action game. Remember 'Contra'? Or 'Rush'n Attack'? 'Cuphead' is reminiscent of those classic games, albeit drawn in an art style that's more reminiscent of Steamboat Willie than any other current video game.

Release date: September 29

Platforms: Xbox One, Windows 10 PC

Microsoft

What it is: The next iteration in the 'Forza Motorsport' series arrives this year in 'Forza Motorsport 7,' the latest edition of the long-running simulation racing franchise. As 'Gran Turismo' is to PlayStation, such is 'Forza' to Xbox -- simulation racing for hardcore gearheads, exclusively available on one game console. Also like 'Gran Turismo,' the 'Forza' series is notorious for being ridiculously pretty. 'Forza Motorsport 7' takes this to new heights due to its 4K capability. You'll need the new Xbox One X to play games in 4K, of course, as well as a 4K TV, but it will look extra pretty if you have both.

Release date: October 3

Platforms: Xbox One, Windows 10 PC

YouTube/Xbox

What it is: Whether or not your care about the 'Lord of the Rings' series is meaningless when it comes to the 'Middle-earth' series. The first game, 'Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor,' was an excellent third-person action game, combining some of the best elements of the 'Batman' series with the 'Assassin's Creed' series (as well as adding plenty of its own innovation). Most importantly, it didn't rely on any of the deep lore associated with the 'Lord of the Rings' franchise. The followup arrives this year in 'Shadow of War,' which looks like a meaty sequel to an already meaty franchise.

Release date: October 10

Platforms: Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PC

Ubisoft

What it is: Beyond the hilariously silly name, 'South Park: The Fractured But Whole' looks to be a delightful role-playing game along the lines of the most recent 'South Park' game. In it, you play as a custom character ('The New Kid') and interact with the usual cast of 'South Park' characters you'd expect to meet. Enemy interactions are handled similarly to old-school RPGs, with each party taking turns at doling out damage and healing party members. The first 'South Park' game managed to feel both fresh and retro, and 'The Fractured But Whole' seems to walk that same line.

Release date: October 17

Platforms: Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PC

Sony

What it is: If you like racing, you're probably already thinking pretty seriously about this year's entry in the long-running 'Gran Turismo' series. The franchise is known for its microbial level of detail lavished on the world of cars, racing, and gear differentials -- 'Sport' is no different in this respect, but it's planned as the first in a 'new generation' of 'Gran Turismo' games. Notably, there's an 'arcade' mode that allows players to have a bit more video game-esque fun instead of solely focusing on the simulation side of the game.

All that aside, 'Gran Turismo Sport' may be the best-looking game released this year.

Release date: October 17

Platforms: PlayStation 4

Nintendo

What it is: Just as 'The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild' was a massive evolution of the long-running, celebrated 'Legend of Zelda' franchise, 'Super Mario Odyssey' appears poised to challenge and evolve the 'Super Mario' formula.

'Super Mario Odyssey' is an open-world, nonlinear 'Super Mario' game. What that means is simple: In traditional 'Super Mario' games, your goal was to reach a flagpole that symbolized the completion of a level. In 'Super Mario Odyssey,' your goal is open-ended: collect moons, of which there are many in each area. It feels a lot like a spiritual successor to 'Super Mario 64.'

Release date: October 27

Platforms: Nintendo Switch

Ubisoft

What it is: In 'Assassin's Creed Origins' you'll explore one of history's most fascinating periods: Ptolemaic Egypt. That's the era when Egypt's millennia-spanning empire began to fall, while Rome -- led by Julius Caesar -- conquered more and more of Western civilisation. It's also, according to 'Assassin's Creed Origins,' the period when the 'Assassin's Brotherhood' was conceived. That alternative history is what you'll play when the game arrives this October -- the standard third-person action-adventure formula is returning.

Release date: October 27

Platforms: Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PC

Bethesda Softworks

What it is: In the world of 'Wolfenstein,' the Nazis won World War II. A band of resistance fighters in the US remains vigilant, and you're among their ranks as a Nazi-killing, supergun-wielding man with a plan. Beyond the foundation being solid, the style and storytelling in modern 'Wolfenstein' games is top-notch -- the first trailer for 'Wolfenstein II: The New Colossus' highlights what we're talking about.

Release date: October 27

Platforms: Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PC

Reagent Games

What it is: 'Crackdown 3' is a superhero game starring heroes you've never heard of, in a city Superman's never visited. In 'Crackdown,' you're essentially a supercop, able to leap over buildings and throw cars and -- perhaps most importantly -- collect glowing orbs that make you do all of that stuff even better. It's this loop of collection and growth that made the first 'Crackdown' such an incredible surprise. Whether 'Crackdown 3' can replicate that magic remains to be seen.

Release date: November 7

Platforms: Xbox One, Windows 10 PC

EA

What it is: The 'Star Wars: Battlefront' series is the 'Star Wars' sandbox children everywhere want. It puts all of the film series' most popular characters into a single game, outfits it with beautiful renderings of classic locales from the movies, and lets you do whatever you want. In 'Battlefront II,' a new single-player campaign also serves as a means of telling the story of the explosion of the Death Star from the side of an elite Imperial trooper.

Release date: November 17

Platforms: Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PC

Sledgehammer Games/Activision

What it is: Like taxes and 'Madden,' with each new year comes a new 'Call of Duty.' In 2017, the series is returning to its roots with a game set in World War II. No more futuristic locales, or perfectly modelled Kevin Spacey -- just the European theatre of the last 'great' war. Expect the same ultra-fast multiplayer, the same bombastic campaign mode, and the same relentless waves of Nazi zombies, albeit with a shiny new coat of paint and an all-new set of characters.

Release date: November 3

Platforms: Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PC

Guerrilla Games/Sony

What it is: If you haven't already played the incredible 'Horizon Zero Dawn,' you're in luck: It's one of the best games of 2017 (the). In 'Horizon Zero Dawn,' you play as Aloy -- a brilliant and tough lady out to discover as much as she can about her own origins, amidst a bizarro future Earth that's ruled by mechanical animals (including massive dinosaur-like machines).

In the game's first expansion, set to be released some time this fall, an entirely new area is being added to the already very large map. In this new area, there are new mysteries to uncover, new tribes to interact with, and plenty of angry machines to contend with. We only wish we knew more.

Release date: 'Fall' 2017

Platforms: PlayStation 4

Nintendo

What it is: After the outrageously successful launch of 'The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild' earlier this year, Nintendo's looking to strike gold once again with its $US20 'Season Pass.' If you purchased the pass, you've already got access to the first content -- the 'Master Trials' DLC -- and you'll get access to the second, more story-focused content later this year. In it, you'll play as Link once again, following up the story to 'Breath of the Wild.' Little is known about the story, but it looks like a variety of characters from the original game's story will return.

Release date: December 2017

Platforms: Nintendo Switch

Bluehole Studios via SideArms4Reason/YouTube

What it is: More than just a bizarre name, 'PlayerUnknown's Battlegrounds' boasts a brilliant concept: 100 people on a massive island, armed with their wits and a scattered arsenal, fighting to the death. Whoever survives at the end of the match wins -- and there can only be one.

Release date: By December 31

Platforms: PC, Xbox One

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>K TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pikachu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steamboat Willie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucha Libre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gone Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legend Of Zelda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Contras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madden</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gran Turismo Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indiana Jones-esque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assassin's Brotherhood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PlayerUnknown's Battlegrounds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gran Turismo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bethesda Softworks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thief's End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fall 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fullbright Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breath Of The Wild</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battlefront II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ubisoft</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forza Motorsport 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windows 10 PC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MDHR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forza Motorsport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tacoma</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tekken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assassin's Creed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assassin's Creed Origins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Call of Duty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Egypt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Death Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Wars</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Colossus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PlayStation 4</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUPER Mario Odyssey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RABBIDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Activision</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Park</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XCOM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Frazer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube/Xbox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Games/Sony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xbox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord of the Rings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbids Kingdom Battle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horizon Zero Dawn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pokemon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Spacey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ubisoft's Rabbids</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo Switch</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mario</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Drake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOST LEGACY</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Mario</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EA Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season Pass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolfenstein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuphead</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uncharted 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Trials' DLC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wii U</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pokken Tournament DX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sledgehammer Games/Activision</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolfenstein II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julius Caesar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shadow of Mordor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Destiny 2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 17</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 27</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naughty Dog/Sony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xbox One X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fractured But Whole</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ptolemaic Egypt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbids-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo's Super Mario</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crackdown 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi-killing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PlayStation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo/Ubisoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forza</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle-earth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RPGs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xbox One</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shadows of War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluehole Studios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Kid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SideArms4Reason/YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madden NFL 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Mario 64</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
