<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423914845060871</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/this-dad-just-claimed-a-world-record-for-views-on-twitch-after-his-little-girl-made-him-scream-2017-8</url>
  <title>This dad just claimed a world record for views on Twitch after his little girl made him scream</title>
  <content>
A UK man now holds the Guinness World Record for being the most frightened person, and he didn't even ask for it.

Tom Wheldon, who goes by the name of  when he's playing online, was engrossed in Outlast 2 and streaming it on all on Twitch.

Then, his 22-month-old daughter Jessica thought she'd bring her dad a nice cool drink, and this happened:

Wheldon explains:

"I had no clue that she had entered the room and at the exact same moment she did, a crow flew out at me in the game and I jumped.
"While taking my eyes off the screen for a split second I noticed a small figure beside me and I screamed for my life only to find out it was my daughter bringing me a cool drink."

Four days later, the clip "streamer daughter walks in on him while playing a scary game" had been viewed 2,086,451 times on the video platform.

And the folks from Guinness World Records called to let Wheldon know he's now in the book under .

"Even after the event happened I didn't expect anything much to come from it apart from I would share the footage with a few friends," he said.

"When I was contacted by the Twitch staff and Guinness World Records it really set in that my video had become number one in the world."

, and Jessica was "unfazed" by his bloodcurdling shriek, saying "bye-bye" to his audience and taking herself back off to bed.

"She has way more backbone than I have," he said.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guinness World Record</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Wheldon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outlast 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wheldon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
