<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423738751399653</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832956/title-unlikely-as-stingrays-eye-top-two/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Title 'unlikely' as Stingrays eye top-two</title>
  <content>
LAST DAY OF THE SEASON: Illawarra Stingrays Talitha Kramer will be on deck when her team take on North Shore Mariners at JJ Kelly Park this weekend. Picture: GEORGIA MATTS

Stingrays coach Brett Wallin admits Illawarra's chances of winning the league on the final day of the season are 'unlikely', but is holding out hope of a top-two finish in the NSW NPL Women's 1. 
Illawarra need both Macarthur Rams and Manly United to lose in round 18 while beating North Shore Mariners at JJ Kelly Park on Sunday for them to claim the premiership. 
As it stands, Rams (38 points) are in the box seat to become regular season champions ahead of their match against Football NSW Institute. 
Manly and Illawarra are level on 35 points heading into the weekend, but United's six goal superior differential gives them a clear advantage over the Rays.
It makes lifting the silverware on the last day of the campaign a difficult task for Wallin's side. 
"We are hoping to win it but it might be a bit unlikely," the coach said.

"We just have to focus on getting the job done on the weekend and then move forward to the finals.

"All we can do is win our game. If we win our game we should be top two but it can go anywhere."
To have any hope of winning the title, Illawarra must defeat a Mariners outfit which has been a finals contender throughout the campaign before falling just short in the final rounds. 
"They are a dangerous team," Wallin said.
"They can play football for sure. They like to knock it around and have some dangerous players but being at home, we are pretty hard to beat there.
"We have been on a bit of a roll lately.
"We have won five straight and are playing some good football so there is no reason to say that we can't continue that into the finals now."
Matildas player and gun defender Caitlin Cooper isn't likely to feature in the match as she makes the trip back from a successful Tournament of Nations campaign.
Fellow Matilda Michelle Heyman will play. 
Meanwhile, the Illawarra's first ever Matilda Julie Porter will be presented her official Australian cap at half time of the match.

Porter was the 19th Australian player to represent the national team.  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matilda Julie Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matilda Michelle Heyman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW NPL Women's 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Shore Mariners</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Matts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caitlin Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Stingrays Talitha Kramer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rams (38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Wallin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ Kelly Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAY OF THE SEASON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football NSW Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macarthur Rams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
