<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423738751399669</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/world/in-case-you-missed-it-refugees-stage-mass-protest-and-a-grumpy-seal-takes-over-south-australian-town/news-story/7ce9f22dff4c5821ac5e9caf11af4617</url>
  <title>News you might have missed: Festival Fires, Grumpy Sea Lions</title>
  <content>
Manus Island Protesters Demand Restoration of Power and Water to Compound

Protests inside Australia's offshore detention centre on Manus Island were triggered on August 1 after essential services such as power and sanitation were cut off in alleged move to coerce residents to vacate the compound. Residents of the Foxtrot compound inside the Manus Island Regional Processing Centre have faced increasing pressure from centre management to relocate before its planned closure on October 31. Refugees and activists claimed that operators switched off power and water to the facility, in a bid to hasten its departure so the compound could be demolished. As well as power and water, refugees said sanitation and cleaning services have ceased, leading to overflowing bins. A letter sent out to detainees from centre management said residents are "personally liable for any risk associated with residing or entering Foxtrox compound." Foxtrot is one of many compounds being occupied by the 800-plus refugees and asylum seekers who have been denied entry to Australia. Residents fear that if PNG Immigration and the Australian Border Force are able to successfully force residents out, then the Mike, Oscar, and Delta compounds would also be vulnerable. Although Papua New Guinea authorities have organised alternative accommodation in East Lorengau, a settlement in the Manus township, Foxtrot residents have expressed concerns for their safety - especially after three men were allegedly attacked with machetes and left seriously injured over the weekend. Credit: Anonymous via Storyful

Sanitation Services Cut Off Inside Manus Island Compound Set to be Demolished, Refugees Claim. Credit - Anonymous via Storyful
Refugees and asylum seekers on Manus Island held mass protests after essential services such as power and water were deactivated.
Residents of the Foxtrot compound inside the Manus Island Regional Processing Centre on Papua New Guinea said they face increasing pressure from centre management to vacate the premises, so it can be demolished. They said power and water have been switched off and sanitation services ceased in a bid to hasten their departure ahead of the centre's planned closure on October 31.
Foxtrot is one of many compounds being occupied by the 800-plus refugees and asylum seekers who have been permanently denied entry to Australia. Residents fear that if PNG Immigration and the Australian Border Force are able to successfully force residents out, then the Mike, Oscar and Delta compounds would also be vulnerable.
Alternative accommodation has been organised in East Lorengau, a settlement in the Manus township, but Foxtrot residents expressed fears for their safety. Over the weekend, three men were allegedly attacked with machetes by locals and left seriously injured.
On Saturday night, a Sudanese refugee had his legs slashed by a bush knife and several hours later, an Iranian man had his wrists and tendons sliced open. In an unrelated incident on Sunday morning, an Afghan refugee was attacked and robbed. Refugees on Manus told Storyful that local gangs viewed them as "badly guarded ATMs."
Tensions on the island have been exacerbated by allegations of sexual assault, towards Manus Island refugees and asylum seekers, including children. At least two people have been arrested this year - a 28-year-old Pakistani man in March for the alleged sexual assault of a 10-year-old girl in Lorengau and a 31-year-old Sri Lankan for the alleged rape of a local woman in a hotel In January.
Sea Lion Snaps That Snaps at Ranger Trying to Coach it Back Into Ocean, Goes Viral

Seal Snaps at Ranger Trying to Wrangle It Back Into the Ocean
A seal who wandered into a South Australian seaside suburb was not in the best of moods when a community ranger tried to direct the massive mammal back into the water on August 1.
The Border Watch reported the community was at a "standstill" after the seal was found at Port MacDonnell resident's doorstep from the night before. A video captured by the owners of a cafe show ranger Dale Millar using a prong to lead it back into the ocean.
The Advertiser reported about 40 people, from a town of 600, gathered to watch Millar try and coach the confused animal back into water.
The seal snaps at Millar several times and tries to lunge at him, with Millar at one point even losing grip of his stick. Despite some initial resistance, the mammal eventually returned home.
Credit: Periwinkles Cafe Port MacDonnell via Storyful

Seal Snaps at Ranger Trying to Wrangle It Back Into the Ocean
A tiny coastal town in South Australia grabbed international attention after video emerged of a confused sea lion wandered the streets of Port Macdonnell on Tuesday, August 1.
The Advertiser reported that about 40 people from the town of 600 gathered to watch ranger Dale Millar try and coach the chubby mammal back into water. Millar can be seen in the video using a prong to lead it back into the ocean, but the sea lion - evidently not in the most playful mood - snaps and lunges at Millar several times, with the ranger even losing grip of his stick at some point.
A cafe owner who recorded the video, Paul Mullen, said Millar was lightly tapping on the sea lion's flippers to coach it back into water.
Despite some initial resistance, Millar was able to encourage the animal into the ocean where it swam away.
Spanish Music Festival 'Tomorrowland' Fire Leads to Mass Evacuation

Thousands of people were forced to flee the Tomorrowland Unite Spain festival in Barcelona's Parc de Can Zam when the main stage went up in flames on Saturday evening, July 29. According to reports, more than 22,000 people had to be evacuated after the fire broke out on the left-hand side of the stage. Credit: Instagram/angel_r_ch via Storyful

Tomorrowland Stage Burns As 22,000 Evacuated From Music Festival. Credit - Instagram/angel_r_ch via Storyful
More than 22,000 people were evacuated from a music festival in Spain after a fire erupted on the main stage last Saturday evening.
No injuries were reported after the blaze broke out at the Tomorrowland Unite Spain festival in Barcelona. CNN reported the attendees were evacuated in a calm and orderly manner.
In an official statement, the festival organisers said the fire was a result of a "technical malfunction". Authorities said they were investigating the cause.
Tomorrowland in Spain is part of a larger satellite of simultaneous concerts, with the main acts taking place in Belgium. The first event was in 2005 and it remains one of Europe's most popular music festivals. In 2013, tickets reportedly sold out in one second.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wrangle It Back Into</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millar</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port MacDonnell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island Regional Processing Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Lion Snaps That Snaps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grumpy Sea Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona's Parc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lankan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Millar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Border Force</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATMs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomorrowland Unite Spain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mass Evacuation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Back Into Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Watch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Mullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG Immigration</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Lorengau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish Music Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorengau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Can Zam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomorrowland Stage Burns As 22,000 Evacuated From Music Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 31</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomorrowland' Fire Leads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ranger Trying</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Festival Fires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Periwinkles Cafe Port MacDonnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island Protesters Demand Restoration of Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Cut Off Inside Manus Island Compound Set</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomorrowland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtrox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sudanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
