<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423781701073156</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/dante-exum-has-fellow-boomer-joe-ingles-in-his-corner-as-he-aims-to-make-nba-mark-with-utah-jazz/news-story/56ef9177685a8ba46d99587173c57fb9</url>
  <title>Joe backs Exum to be on song at Jazz</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN NBA swingman Joe Ingles believes Dante Exum has a "huge opportunity" to cement his place at Utah Jazz.
Ingles, 29, plans to do everything he can to help the No.5 overall pick in the 2014 draft build on a breakout Summer League.
NBLxNBA:
INGLES:
Through three NBA Summer League games in Utah, Melbourne-born Exum averaged 20 points per game on better than 52 per cent shooting - well above his career mark of 38.5 per cent.
On top of improved shot selection, Exum, 22, showed great playmaking ability, dropping 6.3 assists a game, impressing with his ability to run an NBA offence.
The highly-regarded Boomer missed the entire 2015-16 season with a torn ACL and struggled to find his feet last season, prompting Jazz officials to question his prospects.
Exum's strong off-season, coupled with the departure of star swingman Gordon Hayward (Boston Celtics) could see the high school phenom attract more minutes.
"He's been working his ass off this off-season to be ready to go and he knows what he has to do," Ingles said.
"He's smart enough, he's a good kid and again he's a got a good opportunity this year to get out there and have a crack.
"There's no pressure. (When) you lose a guy like Gordon it changes your team, there's going to be 20 more shots open, there's going to be 35 minutes in that position, there's a lot of things that have changed now for our team."
The 1.98m combo guard, in the final year of his rookie contract, must produce at NBA level to secure a hefty pay rise.
Jazz arrivals Ricky Rubio and lottery pick Donovan Mitchell could take valuable court-time off Exum, but Ingles is confident the Boomers young gun can fill a hole.
"We've obviously brought guys in to help, but we're not going to be able to replace Gordon just overnight like that," Ingles said.
"He's (Exum) going to have a great opportunity to showcase what he's done in this off-season and ... obviously I'm going to do everything I can to help him have a really good year."
Ingles and Exum's Jazz will take on the NBL's Sydney Kings in a special exhibition match in Salt Lake City on October 3.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBLxNBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dante Exum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIAN NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exum's Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Hayward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Lake City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston Celtics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA Summer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL's Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donovan Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Rubio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-born Exum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exum</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exum, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
