<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423906255126172</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/13/01/appeal-for-information-after-oakleigh-east-burglary</url>
  <title>CCTV shows robbers kicking in door of Melbourne home</title>
  <content>
Footage has emerged of a brazen daylight break-in by three offenders in Melbourne's south-east.
Police released the CCTV footage of the break-in, which occurred in Oakleigh East on August 1.
It is believed three unknown offenders arrived at a Dublin Street address in a silver vehicle sometime between 11am and 12pm.
Investigators have been told the car was reversed into the driveway of the home, where two of the offenders, both males, exited the vehicle.
The footage shows the two men kicking and wrestling with the door before it opens.
They then forced their way through the front door of the house and took a number of items, including men's watches and clothing items.
The pair then got back into the waiting car, which drove away.

Related Articles

The car has been described as a silver Audi A5, possibly a 2010 model, and had black registration plates with white numbers/letters, the first of which was "A".
two men who they believe may be able to assist with their enquiries.
Both of the men have been described as being aged in their 20s to 30s and about 180cm tall with a medium build and short hair.
One was wearing a black jacket, black pants, and a black patterned hat with a black glove on one hand and red glove on the other.
He also wore a grey bandanna that covered his face, as well as grey plastic bags on both shoes.
The second man was wearing a red Adidas jumper with a blue drawstring pulled over his face, as well as a black beanie, black gloves and dark Nike shoes with material covering them.
Details of the third person who was driving the vehicle are unknown.
Anyone with information is urged to contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or submit a confidential crime report online at 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Audi A5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adidas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
