<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423734456432336</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/thieves-wearing-plastic-bags-on-their-shoes-force-their-way-into-a-house-in-oakleigh-east/news-story/da8c6de68ddc5074e8218422026f16e6</url>
  <title>Thieves on the run after burglary</title>
  <content>
THIEVES wearing plastic bags on their shoes are on the run after they broke into a house in Oakleigh East.
Detectives are looking for two men and an unknown driver who forced their way into a Dublin St house on August 1, between 11am and noon.
CCTV footage shows two men getting out of a silver Audi A5 and breaking through the front door of the house.
The thieves took off with several items, including watches and clothing.
Police described the car as possibly being a 2010 model, with black registration plates which had white numbers and letters, the first of which was A.
Both of the men are described as being aged in their 20s to 30s, about 180cm, with a medium build and short hair.
One was wearing a black jacket, black pants, black-patterned hat and a black glove on one hand and red glove on the other.
He also wore a grey bandana covering his face, as well as grey plastic bags on both shoes.
The second man was wearing a red Adidas jumper with a blue drawstring pulled over his face, black beanie, black gloves and dark Nike shoes with material covering them.
Details of the third person who was driving the car were unknown.
Anyone with information is urged to phone  on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Audi A5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adidas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
