<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423824650746615</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4827185/million-dollar-country-style-home-hits-illawarra-market/?cs=298</url>
  <title>Huntley property expected to sell for $1.65 million to $1.75 million</title>
  <content>
Million dollar country-style home hits Illawarra market

exit

A country-style home set on a 34-acre parcel with views of the ocean and local district will go to auction later this month.
The home is located at 586 Bong Bong Road, Huntley.
The architecturally designed home is positioned high upon its 34-acre parcel to soak up views of the ocean, local district, Lake Illawarra and escarpment surrounds.
You can explore your very own rainforest with its meandering creeks, hills and bushwalking trails, and enjoy the luxury of acreage living with metropolitan conveniences at your fingertips.
The five-bedroom, three-bathroom home will be auctioned on August 11.

FOR SALE: The five-bedroom, three-bathroom home at 586 Bong Bong Road, Huntley will be auctioned on Friday, August 11. Pictures: Supplied
Agent, Darren Kay, principal at Belle Property Wollongong said it was expected it would sell for $1.65 million to $1.75 million.
"The strengths of the property lie within the privacy and surrounds, the acreage,  within such close proximity to Wollongong CBD," he said.
"On top of that, with all the serenity surrounding it, it has absolutely stunning ocean views, which is quite rare for an acreage property."
Other features include flowing in/outdoor formal and informal living venues plus billiards room; vast undercover wraparound deck with pizza oven and six-person ozone spa; gas cooktop, top-of-the-range Miele dishwasher and walk-in pantry. 

The five-bedroom, three-bathroom home at 586 Bong Bong Road, Huntley will be auctioned on Friday, August 11. Pictures: Supplied
There's also a spacious study; sunlit full master quarters with private patio access; mixed Australian hardwood floors, two log fireplaces, large spring fed dam and remote controlled gated entry.
Mr Kay said there had been a mix of demographics displaying interest in the home. "You've got people looking to come down and relocate from Sydney, looking for privacy and seclusion," he said.
"Then you've got people locally who are looking to upgrade with their families into an acreage property."
RBA holds cash rate at record low

The Reserve Bank has kept its cash rate on hold at a record low of 1.5 per cent for the 11th consecutive month, providing little indication of when it will allow rates to rise.

Housing Industry Association senior economist Shane Garrett said the outcome of this week's RBA meeting means that the official cash rate has now been held steady for 12 consecutive months.
"The decision to hold rates steady was made in the context of fairly restrained price inflation across the economy and challenging demand conditions," he said.
"Residential building activity is now starting to contract having been a driver of growth up until recently.
"New dwelling commencements peaked in the March 2016 quarter and remain relatively high.
"Australia's economy will continue to require low interest rates in order to achieve stronger growth over the medium term.
"In terms of keeping inflation at bay, the Australian economy has performed an exceptional feat over the past number of years.

"Our exchange rate has dipped sharply and dwelling prices have escalated in key markets - but without fuelling detrimental wage or price pressures across the economy."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Kay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Industry Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belle Property Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Garrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bong Bong Road</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
