<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423700096693581</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-04/hes-not-omitted-bobs-road-less-travelled</url>
  <title>'He's not omitted': Bob's road less travelled</title>
  <content>
Robert Murphy could still be called upon to play for the Dogs on Saturday

A COMBINATION of two six-day breaks and body management were the catalyst for Western Bulldogs captain Robert Murphy being listed as a 'travelling emergency' for Saturday's clash with the Brisbane Lions, says coach Luke Beveridge.

Murphy has played the past three games for the premiers, but some lingering pain from a mid-season cleanout on his reconstrcuted knee, coupled with short turnarounds between last Sunday's win over Essendon and next Friday's clash with Greater Western Sydney, gave the club the chance to rest him. 

The 35-year-old, who joined in a light training session on Friday morning, will join the team on the flight to Brisbane later that day, and will be the player on standby if one of several sore teammates don't come up.

Speaking before training, Beveridge seemed aggrieved at the need to explain why his skipper was unlikely to face the Lions. 

"He's definitely not omitted but we've decided that we might as well give him this week off, and go into next Friday felling fresh," Beveridge said.

"As much as we want him to play this week, he hasn't quite come up as 'cherry ripe' as we'd like.

"He's got a bit of residual soreness from that knee procedure (he underwent) a little bit earlier in the year.

"So as far as taking someone up to Brisbane, there is still a chance he might play, because we've still got a couple of boys who are a little bit sore, but generally they're pretty right (to go). 

"If we need him, he'll play. 

"It's a shame we need to provide explanations these days."

More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beveridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
