<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423605607410992</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/property/law-institute-to-offload-bourke-street-office-20170804-gxp7k9.html</url>
  <title>Law Institute to offload Bourke Street office</title>
  <content>
The Law Institute of Victoria has moved to sell its Melbourne headquarters in Bourke Street, a building it has occupied for nearly 40 years.
The LIV will divest the nine-storey office tower and seek a leaseback arrangement from the buyer while it looks for a replacement space in the city, chief executive Nerida Wallace said.Photo: Arsineh Houspian
 Options around the possibility of purchasing or leasing a property in the Melbourne legal precinct in the short to medium-term were being explored by the LIV, Ms Wallace said.
The 2261-square-metre office is expected to fetch more than $30 million. The LIV purchased it for $1.5 million in 1978.
A final decision to sell would be contingent on whether the LIV can get maximum value for the property in the current strong market conditions, Ms Wallace said.
The institute was working with consultants Charter Keck Cramer but has not appointed agents.
The LIV office is opposite the flashy headquarters of the RACV club, also on Bourke.
Two weeks ago the former home of Kozminsky jewellers, down the street at 421 Bourke, changed hands for $7.6 million, snapped up by Melbourne's Giannarelli family.
Directly opposite Kozminsky's, Gross Waddell is selling the home of Auski on the corner of Bourke Street and Hardware Lane.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liv</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Giannarelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Institute of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kozminsky</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardware Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nerida Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wallace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsineh Houspian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charter Keck Cramer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gross Waddell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
