<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423871895387401</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/inside-hogewey-dementia-village-2017-7</url>
  <title>Inside the Dutch 'dementia village' that offers beer, bingo, and top-notch healthcare</title>
  <content>
Residents of , a village located in Weesp, Netherlands, lead a normal life. They go to the grocery store, complain about the weather, and enjoy a weekly game of bingo.

But there's one thing that sets the 152 residents apart from the general public: Everyone has an advanced form of dementia.

Hogeweyk is a nursing home disguised to look like the outside world. It helps people with mild to severe dementia suffer a little bit less in their remaining years, facility manager Eloy van Hal told Business Insider. He said it preserves people's sense of autonomy.

The village is comprised of 23 houses, each with six to seven residents and a caregiver who cooks, takes people to social events, helps them go grocery shopping at the village market, and watches over them to ensure their safety.

Here's what life is like inside Hogeweyk's walls.

Hogewey

'We said to each other 'What do we want for ourselves and our mums and dads?' van Hal said.

The consensus was that people wanted normalcy, at least to the extent caregivers could provide it. Gradually, Hogeweyk began folding in elements of the outside world. It started by creating 23 houses in four different 'lifestyle' categories -- cosmopolitan, nature-oriented, well-to-do, and traditional Dutch.

'You have to choose,' van Hal said. 'Which is the lifestyle according to your preferences?'

Hogewey

Hogeweyk places a great deal of importance on word choice, van Hal said. The staff members don't treat patients -- they care for residents.

'All the residents living here need medical treatment, yes. They all have medication. They all have (an) advanced stage of dementia,' van Hal said. 'But they are first a person. That's why there are people living here with dementia, and not demented people.'

Hogewey

The residents can also use real money if they want to, Hal said. Only a handful are lucid enough to do so, and typically they spend it on small items like toothpaste and candy bars.

As part of the facility's normal budgeting process, a chunk of money (not real currency) is doled out to each of the 23 houses. With some help from the caregivers, it's up to the houses to budget the money how they see fit over the course of the month.

Hogewey

As a matter of policy, Hogeweyk rejects the idea that people with dementia ought to miss out on the finer things, such as beer or wine -- even if they don't follow the social norms that most other people do.

'They have really bad manners and habits, in food and behaviour,' he said. 'We are not going to change that.'

Residents can use real money at the facility's pub. If people display signs of alcohol abuse, however, the facility will not serve them.

Hogewey

That's important for a sensitive disease like dementia, he added. There are roughly  living with dementia, which means there are an equivalent number of stages at which the disease has advanced.

It's up to the Hogeweyk staff to know which residents are more lucid than others, and to treat them accordingly if they slip up with a name or date. According to van Hal, there is no single policy for bringing residents back into 'the real world' or letting them live in their bubble.

Hogewey

Research has found that loneliness is  and twice as lethal as obesity. As seniors tend to be the age group that most often lives by themselves, Hogeweyk feels a responsibility to make sure people get as much social interaction as they require.

'You are busy, you are outside, you can complain about the weather,' he said.

Hogewey

Alzheimer's and dementia sufferers are widely  to stay physically active to keep their minds and bodies engaged.

Residents at Hogewey can stroll through the open courtyard or help caregivers tend to one of the many gardens. Even just sitting on a bench in the outdoors , research has found.

Hogewey

'If we know that you have sugar in your coffee, we will still ask you every day, 'Do you want sugar in your coffee?' so you can make that choice every day,' van Hal said. 'That you can still decide what you put in your coffee is important.'

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alzheimer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hal</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hogewey</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weesp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hogeweyk</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
