<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423820355779281</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/danish-queens-husband-refuses-to-share-her-grave/8774504</url>
  <title>Prince Henrik: Danish Queen's husband refuses to share her grave over king title snub</title>
  <content>
Denmark's Prince Henrik has announced he does not wish to be buried next to his wife Queen Margrethe, because he is unhappy he was never acknowledged as king.
Prince Henrik, 83, was given the title of Queen's Prince Consort when he married Queen Margrethe in 1967.
However, he has repeatedly stated he would have preferred to be named King Consort.
"It is no secret that the Prince for many years has been unhappy with his role and the title he has been awarded in the Danish monarchy. This discontent has grown more and more in recent years," the Royal Danish House's director of communications said.
"For the Prince, the decision not to buried beside the Queen is the natural consequence of not having been treated equally to his spouse - by not having the title and role he has desired," she added.
Prince Henrik is the father of Crown Prince Frederik, whose Australian wife is the Crown Princess Mary.
In Denmark, the wife of a male monarch traditionally becomes queen when her husband takes the throne, however, the husband of a queen can only be called a prince or 'His Highness'.
Born Henri Marie Jean Andre de Laborde de Monpezat in France in 1934, Henrik has two sons with the Queen: Crown Prince Frederik, and Prince Joachim.
He retired last year and denounced his title of Prince Consort.
Since then he has participated in very few official duties and instead spent much of his time at his private vineyard in France, although he is still married to the Queen and they officially live together.
It had been expected that the Prince would be buried in a specially-designed sarcophagus which was prepared for him and Margrethe in the Roskilde Cathedral by the sculptor Bjorn Norgaard.
His move will not change the plans for Queen Margrethe's burial.
Reuters

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Princess Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Joachim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Henrik, 83</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henrik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margrethe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roskilde Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Margrethe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark's Prince Henrik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Henrik</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prince Frederik</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Danish House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monpezat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henri Marie Jean Andre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Prince Consort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danish Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bjorn Norgaard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Consort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laborde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Consort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
