<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423953499766964</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/lifestyle/sa-weekend/kathy-lette-low-selfie-esteem-theres-a-surgical-proceedure-for-that/news-story/693a150f2883a17c00f4da36c7068b89</url>
  <title>Low selfie esteem?</title>
  <content>
GIRLS, are you going through the tunnel of love holding your own hand? New research reveals that the average age of women having cosmetic surgery has dropped below 40 for the first time - and apparently selfies are to blame. The popularity of Instagram has resulted in more female millennials going under the knife. The main reason given for the meteoric rise in younger women seeking surgery is due to photo filtering apps on smart phones. Yep. Women are so pleased with their improved appearances on doctored social media snaps that they're replicating the process in real life by signing up for cosmetic surgery.
In other words, beauty is one of the most natural and lovely things ... which money can buy.
The most popular procedure, besides breast augmentation and nose jobs, is liposuction. Liposuction involves the hoovering out of unwanted fat despite the danger of accidentally sucking out internal organs you're still using. (Surely "Fridge-o-suction" sounds an easier option - just sucking the food right out of the refrigerator, at source.) Besides, have too much lipo and your genitals could become askew - giving new meaning to a "little bit on the side".
Healthy women are subjecting themselves to this kind of unnecessary surgery despite the perils. A former Miss Argentina, Solange Magnano, died trying to make her rear end bigger with a bottom implant.
A 20-year-old model, Claudia Aderotimi, followed tragic suit shortly afterwards. Olivia Goldsmith, the author of The First Wives Club, died during a "routine" chin tuck. Joan Rivers died while having surgery on her neck. The list goes on and on ...
So, why do women take the risk? Clearly constant media scrutiny - do Madonna's lips look wrinkled? Has Beyonce lost her baby weight? - has resulted in females' collective physical confidence sinking lower than Kim Kardashian's bikini line.
Desperate to avoid all lines, (except P&O), women are having their eyes widened, necks trimmed, tummies tucked, legs lipo-ed, lips thickened and faces lifted to Bride of Wildenstein standards.
And who exactly are these cowboy clinicians wanting to splice and slice us? Obviously cosmetic surgeons don't perform unnecessary surgery - they only operate if they need the money.
Even more worryingly, there are terrifyingly few regulations involved with setting up a cosmetic surgery, which explains the huge number of lawsuits for botched operations. Bungled breast augmentations causing nipples to leak toxic yellow yoghurt, Gore-Tex fibres poking out of upper lips like bedsprings from an old mattress - the many mutilations reported in the media makes me wonder who these surgeons trained under. Was it Doctor Seuss?
It seems that most of these so-called "doctors" couldn't put a dressing on a salad. At least we know why they call what they do a practice. Most doctors wear those little green masks for hygienic reasons but cosmetic surgeons do so because when operations go wrong, they just don't want to be recognised.
So, yes, if you hadn't guessed, I'm against cosmetic surgery. My mother told me to never pick my nose - especially from a catalogue. All that's gushing out of the fountain of youth is money. The only plastic surgery a woman should experience is cutting up the credit card she was going to use to pay for all that needless butchering.
Really girls, do you honestly want to become one of those women who is approaching 40, but from the wrong direction?
There'll be bits of your body that have been operated on that don't go with the bits which haven't. Your arms will be more than four decades old and your lips, two weeks. You'll be sitting on one brand-new butt cheek while the other half of your arse is 42.
But if that still hasn't convinced you to abandon the desire to do a little shopping and tucking, I have two sobering words for you. They are "Michael" and "Jackson".
Besides, the bottom line - the lobotomised line - is this ... why would you want to attract a man who only wants you because you're silicone from tonsils to toenails? Wouldn't you prefer a bloke who likes to read between your lines?
My top tips to looking younger? Get older friends. Only be seen out with less attractive people (hey, I'm available). And get a dimmer switch - the greatest beauty aid known to womankind.
Just keep the lights low ... oh, and stop taking selfies.
Be Warned - Kathy Lette's latest novel, Best Laid Plans, will give you laughter lines
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctor Seuss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bride of Wildenstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Goldsmith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Kardashian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claudia Aderotimi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gore-Tex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solange Magnano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Wives Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Rivers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madonna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laid Plans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy Lette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Argentina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
