<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423910550093482</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/anglican-priest-arrested-at-sunshine-church-faces-court-on-child-porn-charges-20170804-gxpa3o.html</url>
  <title>Anglican priest arrested at Sunshine church faces court on child porn charges</title>
  <content>
An Anglican priest, arrested at his church in suburban Melbourne during a police raid over child pornography offences, has appeared in court.
Father Philip John Murphy, 52, faced Melbourne Magistrates Court on Friday, charged with 10 offences allegedly committed in East Burwood over five months, from September last year to February this year.Photo: Supplied
Detectives searched the Holy Apostles' Anglican Church, on Anderson Road in Sunshine West, on Thursday morning and arrested Father Murphy.
Police said the arrest was part of a 12-month investigation into online child exploitation, by the joint anti-child exploitation team.
He was charged with five counts of transmitting child pornography material using a carriage service, and another five counts of using a carriage service in a way that a "reasonable person would regard as offensive", according to court documents.
Following his arrest, Father Murphy was stood down from the church by Anglican Archbishop Phillip Freier "with immediate effect" on Thursday, an Anglican Diocese of Melbourne spokesman said.

"Archbishop Philip Freier said the church abhorred the abuse or exploitation of children and would co-operate fully with police," the spokesman said.
On Friday morning Father Murphy appeared at Melbourne Magistrates Court for a brief file hearing, where his bail was extended until his next court appearance.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The court heard Father Murphy was forbidden from using social media and online dating websites and phone apps, while on bail. 
He is also prohibited from using BitTorrent and other file sharing softwares.
Magistrate Peter Reardon approved an application to vary the bail conditions, allowing Father Murphy access to phone messaging application WhatsApp, to keep in contact with a friend.
He will appear at Melbourne Magistrates Court again on October 27.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holy Apostles' Anglican Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Burwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Archbishop Phillip Freier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip John Murphy, 52</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Peter Reardon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WhatsApp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father Murphy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BitTorrent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Diocese of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archbishop Philip Freier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anderson Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
