<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423743046367025</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834180/get-a-life-gene-simmons-slams-justin-bieber/?cs=2372</url>
  <title>'Get a life': Gene Simmons slams Justin Bieber</title>
  <content>
Legendary rocker Gene Simmons has lashed out at Justin Bieber after the Canadian pop singer cancelled the remaining dates of his Purpose world tour.
23-year-old Bieber recently posted to Instagram to confirm he is taking a "career break" to focus on leading a more "sustainable" life.

Gene Simmons, bassist with US glam-rock band Kiss, has slammed Justin Bieber for cancelling his world tour.

A paparazzo approached Simmons in Beverly Hills to ask if he has any advice in relation to the cancellation, prompting the 67-year-old to suggest Bieber needs to "get a life".
"You don't have anything to worry about, you're rich," Simmons said in a video released by TMZ.
"And in case you didn't notice, you're white. You've got white privilege ... there's nothing to complain about".

Justin Bieber has confirmed he is taking a career break because he wants his "mind, heart and soul to be sustainable".  Photo: AP

Despite the tirade, the KISS singer and bassist said he wished the young star well.
"He's young, he's got lots of fans," Simmons said, before attributing the tour cancellation to the "Beverly Hills Blues".
Bieber completed over 150 shows of the Purpose tour, and has assured fans the shows he did play were "unbelievable".
The singer completed the Australian leg of his tour in March this year with fans and critics complaining about his lacklustre performance.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Bieber</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TMZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simmons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEVERLY HILLS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beverly Hills Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bieber</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gene Simmons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
