<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423691506758808</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/logan-schools-add-to-topclass-naplan-scores/news-story/b9dd3bac640392145bc49d8fa2a96dad</url>
  <title>Southside schools boost NAPLAN</title>
  <content>
SCHOOLS in Logan made solid contributions to boosting this year's national NAPLAN results.
National results from tests in May, released on Wednesday, showed a 2.04 per cent decline in writing skills across years 3, 5, 7 and 9 since 2011 but a 3.52 per cent improvement in reading and a 2.55 per cent gain in numeracy since 2008, when the test started.
Two of the largest high schools in Logan, Springwood State High and John Paul College, both played roles boosting reading and numeracy figures with both posting their best results to date and both faring better than national averages.
Springwood State High principal Julie-Ann McCullough said her students' results improved significantly over the past year.
"The results include gains of 6 per cent in reading for year 9 students in both upper two bands and national minimum standards, and over 6 per cent in year 7 national minimum standards," she said.
"We gained a massive 10 per cent in spelling with 98 per cent of students reaching the national minimum standard in year 9. Our numeracy results also had gains of over 6 per cent in year 9, and year 7 also improved." Ms McCullough said Springwood High's active approach to improving reading paid off.
John Paul College had improvements in Year 3 results across all fields. In Years 7 and 9, the college had gains in spelling, grammar, punctuation and reading
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie-Ann McCullough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Paul College</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McCullough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springwood State High</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springwood High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
