<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423867600420044</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/cricket/cricket-australia-pay-war-erin-osborne-backs-50-million-boost-for-southern-stars-20170804-gxp6f4.html</url>
  <title>Cricket pay deal: ACT Meteor Erin Osborne backs financial boost as she chases Australian recall</title>
  <content>
ACT Meteors spinner Erin Osborne will continue juggling full-time work and her cricket ambitions despite Cricket Australia finalising a landmark pay deal for female atheltes.
Osborne has recommitted to the Meteors for the 2017-16 WNCL season but is still trying to secure a contract for the women's Big Bash League.Photo: Rohan Thomson
She is also fighting to win back a spot in the Australian side after falling out of favour with selectors earlier this year.
The Australian Southern Stars will play two women's Ashes twenty20 fixtures at Manuka Oval in November and Osborne hopes she can force her way into selection contention.

Australia's female cricketers were big winners in an ugly and drawn out contract negotiation, with total payments set to boom from $7.5 million to $55.2 million.
The base salary for international females will rise from $40,000 to $72,076 in the first year of the deal before jumping to $87,609 in the final year.

Osborne, 28, lost her international contract earlier this year but is keen to earn another cap for Australia as early as this season.
Despite losing her Australian spot, she is still classified as an international player in the WBBL player market and it has stalled her bid for a contract.
"I'd love to play for Australia again, but I'm also at the stage of my life where I'm thinking about life after cricket as well," Osborne said.
"I want to have a good season for the ACT Meteors and look to get back into that Australian squad.
"My focus at the moment is the Meteors and I think the squad is going in the right direction. If I have a good season there, I think the rest will look after itself."
Osborne, who works for ACM as a exercise physiologist, believes the new pay deal is a reflection of increased interest and success of women's cricket.
Cricket Australia and the Australian Cricketers' Association reached an agreement on Thursday to resolve a bitter pay dispute.
A revenue share model was agreed on and will make Australia's female cricketers the highest paid of any national women's team.
"Cricket Australia have been leading the way in supporting female cricketers in growth and development," Osborne said.
"We've seen that through the rise of the number of competitions available for young girls to play in. We see that in Canberra with the junior Meteors plate and Cup on Wednesday and Friday nights.
"All women's sport is going in the right direction. It's a good time to be a young girl wanting to play sport in Australia."
Tickets for the Ashes clashes in Canberra will go on sale next week, with Cricket ACT to make a donation from every ticket to the Lord's Taverners ACT charity.
Australia will play against England at Manuka Oval on November 19 and 21 as part of a series of one-day internationals and twenty20 fixtures.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord's Taverners ACT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNCL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Southern Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osborne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket ACT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Meteors</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osborne, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Meteor Erin Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
