<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423863305452745</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/beauty/face-body/dame-helen-mirren-says-moisturiser-probably-does-fk-all-despite-being-a-face-of-loreal-skincare/news-story/8482a06ba0dbbc49eaecc1774a5bdf1b</url>
  <title>Dame Helen Mirren says moisturiser 'probably does f**k all' ... despite being a face of L'Oreal skincare</title>
  <content>
Helen Mirren - who regularly finds herself on the best dressed list at showbiz events - thinks she'll be a sex symbol until the day she dies.

Fay StrangThe Sun

Share

DAME Helen Mirren says she thinks moisturiser probably does 'f*** all' despite becoming the face of L'Oreal Paris' Age Perfect range earlier this year.
The 72-year-old made the comments as she spoke about her beauty regimen at an event for the cosmetic's company in the South Of France, .

Helen Mirren attends the 23rd Annual ELLE Women In Hollywood Awards. Picture: GettySource:Getty Images
She said: "I'm an eternal optimist - I know that when I put my moisturiser on it probably does f**k all, but it just makes me feel better. I've always said to L'Oreal as well that I will only do what makes me feel better.
"I'm not setting standards for others. All I can do is be who I am. I've always loved make-up."
Helen joined forces with the brand the range earlier this year after she became a brand ambassador for the company in 2014.
The star admitted she used to be furious when she would see an advertisement promoting beauty products was fronted by a fresh-faced youngster.
She explained: "It used to drive me crazy that the ads promoting skin products were using pictures of 15- and 16-year-old girls.
"As a 30-year-old, I used to look at that and think, what the f**k are you talking about? It was ridiculous.
"P**sed me off majorly. Advertisers are only just coming out of that, and it's taken them a long time."

Meanwhile, Helen - who regularly finds herself on the best dressed list at showbiz events - thinks she'll be a sex symbol until the day she dies.
Speaking previously, she said: "I think it's probably going to follow me to my grave."
And just last month rapper 50 Cent revealed he got the chance to admire Helen's 'sexiness' first hand after cornering her on the red carpet.
After posting an Instagram picture of the movie star with the caption "I think I love her ... she know she turns me on", he decided to cut to the chase.
Explaining how he stuck it on her, smitten 50 recalled: "I said, 'You just gonna shu shu [give me the brush-off] for ever?
"'You are going to keep this going for ever, huh?'
"She didn't say much - but her husband was right there. It's her attitude, her confidence."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame Helen Mirren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oreal Paris' Age Perfect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annual ELLE Women In Hollywood Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oreal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South of France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GettySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fay StrangThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Mirren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
