<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423876190354769</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-04/frankston-back-in-vfl-after-oneyear-hiatus</url>
  <title>Frankston back in VFL after one-year hiatus</title>
  <content>
The Frankston Dolphins will return to the VFL in 2018

FRANKSTON has been readmitted into the VFL just 10 months after it was left out of the competition for debt exceeding $1 million.

That number has since decreased and with more than 1200 paid-up members, the Dolphins convinced the AFL Victoria Board and Executive representatives their hiatus should end to develop the talent pathway in south-east Victoria, with a sound long-term plan for the club also essential in the decision.

Western Bulldogs premiership player Matthew Boyd, star Melbourne defender Michael Hibberd and rising Sydney defender Nic Newman are among those to forge successful AFL careers after starting at Frankston.

AFL Victoria CEO Steven Reaper expressed his confidence in a statement the Dolphins' re-entry would be successful.

"AFL Victoria was always committed to continuing to work with key stakeholders in the region - including Frankston FC - to ensure there would be a state-league presence there into the future," Reaper said.

"The Frankston FC and all involved have shown their commitment to regain their licence in the VFL, establishing a strong strategic plan focused on governance, community engagement, sponsorship and membership that will assist the club and the region into the future."

Frankston joins the North Melbourne reverses as new teams in the competition for 2018, with Werribee to be a standalone club.

, meaning there will be 16 clubs in the competition next year.

The development league - which was the reserves competition for the VFL - will not continue in 2018.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hibberd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston FC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Dolphins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Victoria CEO Steven Reaper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reaper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Victoria Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
