<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424082348787320</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/breaking-news/qld-man-denied-bail-over-1997-murder/news-story/e303dab2750f2c3da552c491bdae850b</url>
  <title>Qld man denied bail over 1997 murder</title>
  <content>
Four uncommon bullets used to kill a Gold Coast businessman have the same chemical fingerprint as bullets found at the house of a man charged in relation to his murder, a court has heard.
Philip Carlyle, 47, was shot in the head on the morning of April 13, 1997 in a soundproof room at his Robina business.
His business partner Neil Pentland, now aged 69, was arrested for murder in June after a reignited investigation into the execution-style killing.
Mechanic John Hitchen is also charged as an accessory after the fact and is alleged to have given Pentland the gun and disposed of it after the shooting.
Pentland was denied bail on Friday after Brisbane Supreme Court Justice John Bond found there was a "substantial circumstantial case" against him.
The court heard the .32 calibre Norma bullets used to kill Mr Carlyle were not commonly sold in Australia.
Three of the fatal bullets have the same isotopic profile as a batch of bullets found at Hitchen's home, while the fourth bullet matched a second batch also found at the property.
The court heard Pentland is believed to have been the last person to see Mr Carlyle alive after meeting him at the business at 10am.
Medical evidence suggests Mr Carlyle was killed sometime between 10am and midday.
Pentland also knew the air-conditioning plant room at the premises was soundproof and went directly from the business to Hitchen's home, allegedly to arrange a car service.
The court heard Pentland is alleged to have known Mr Carlyle was prepared to move to the United States to be with a woman he was having an affair with and in doing so, would have caused Pentland significant financial difficulty.
The case will return to the Southport Magistrates Court in September.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Carlyle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Pentland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pentland</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport Magistrate Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Supreme Court Justice John Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Carlyle, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hitchens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
