<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424133888395935</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/margaret-river-pro-to-remain-on-world-championship-tour/news-story/4381625a477cfa6fd4c5e57016c837eb</url>
  <title>Margaret River Pro given lifeline</title>
  <content>
WA's premier surfing event, the Margaret River Pro, will remain on surfing's elite world tour after the McGowan Government and the sport's state administrators secured a contract extension.
Tourism Minister Paul Papalia and Surfing WA chief executive Mark Lane confirmed on Friday that the World Surf League had agreed to keep the Margaret River Pro on the World Championship Tour for at least another two years.
The multimillion-dollar deal completes a remarkable turn of fortunes for the event, after fears last year that the WSL would chop it from the top-flight of surfing contests in a bid to streamline the Australian leg of the tour.
There are currently 11 events scheduled on the men's tour and 10 on the women's, with three of those in Australia.
Given the other two Australian events are held at famed breaks on the Gold Coast and Victoria, speculation had been rife that Margaret River had been earmarked to make way.
However, Mr Papalia said that after extensive lobbying by Surfing WA and Tourism WA, the sport's world governors had agreed to maintain Margaret River's spot on the WCT until 2019, with the potential for it to be extended further.
The Minister said the breakthrough was a major boon for the South West economy, which would benefit to the tune of $5.4 million every year the event was held there.
It means the world's best surfers - including reigning men's world champion John John Florence, 11-time American world champ Kelly Slater and Australian legend Mick Fanning - will again descend on Margaret River to don their competition rashies.
"The McGowan Government stood by Surfing WA throughout negotiations to ensure we retained the exciting event on the Championship Tour," Mr Papalia said.
"High-profile international events such as Margaret River Pro inject millions of dollars into the economy, which in turn creates jobs.
"Along with the thousands of spectators, competitors and officials who head to Margaret River for the event, a massive global audience follows the world-class surfing action."
Regional Development Minister Alannah MacTiernan was similarly buoyant, saying the event was the perfect showcase for the South West's natural beauty and tourist attractions.
"This is fantastic exposure for the region's stunning coastline, natural wonders and powerful surf breaks," Ms MacTiernan said.
"The Margaret River Pro delivers $5.4 million in annual economic impact to South-West region."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms MacTiernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Papalia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John John Florence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championship Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Surf League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WCT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Championship Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South West</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret River Pro</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Fanning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfing WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Minister Paul Papalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret River</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development Minister Alannah MacTiernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
