<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424095233689505</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/04/matildas-thrash-brazil-6-1-claim-tournament-nations-cup</url>
  <title>Matildas thrash Brazil 6-1 to claim Tournament of Nations cup</title>
  <content>
Australia have claimed the Tournament of Nations after belting women's soccer heavyweights Brazil 6-1 in Carson.

51 MINS AGO  UPDATED 6 MINS AGO

The Matildas have blitzed their way to Tournament of Nations glory by defeating Brazil 6-1, claiming the competition in stunning style.

Doubles from record-breaker Lisa De Vanna and Caitlin Foord helped Australia overturn an early deficit in Carson, with Katrina Gorry also adding her name to the scoresheet.

Sam Kerr was irrepressible, winning a first-half penalty to earn an equaliser before providing two assists and icing the match with Australia's sixth goal.

The comprehensive win was the Matildas' third in a week and delivered their first piece of silverware since the 2010 Asian Cup.

While this tournament is only a friendly series, a first win over world champions USA and victories over highly-ranked Japan and Brazil make it arguably the Matildas' greatest success.

Friday morning's (AEST) win also gave Australia an element of revenge for their exit at last year's Olympics at the hands of Brazil.

Coach Alen Stajcic said his side were worthy champions.

"It's a good feeling to put together three performances like that and get better in each one," he told AAP.

"It's done so much for the confidence and belief of the group and laid a good platform for the future."

Australia are likely to move up from their world ranking of seven ahead of next year's Asian Cup and the 2019 World Cup -- now within their sights.

The triumph over Brazil came despite an early setback.

Skipper Elise Kellond-Knight conceded a free kick in the opening minute, which Tamires rolled across the box for Camila to score from.

Five minutes later, Kerr helped Australia get back on terms.

The in-form striker was hauled down in the box by Bia Zaneratto, allowing De Vanna to equalise from close range after her initial spot kick was saved.

Arnold's fine save and quick release allowed Australia to take the lead, with Foord finishing an end-to-end move just after the half hour.

Having provided Foord's assist from the right, minutes later Kerr played in De Vanna from the left and the veteran made no mistake to make the score 3-1.

De Vanna's brace moved her ahead of Kate Gill as the Matildas' all-time leading goalscorer, with 42.

Australia maintained the rage, with star midfielder Gorry beating two defenders and striking a sweet individual goal.

After the break, Foord made it five by latching onto substitute Tameka Butt's fine through ball and rounding the keeper.

Kerr then bustled her way through a bruised Brazilian defence, poking home past Dani Neuhaus with 10 minutes left.

The only negative for Australia was an ankle injury to Chloe Logarzo.

Stajcic said the 22-year-old appeared to have torn a ligament, suggesting a lengthy layoff.

The Matildas and Brazil will meet again in a two-game friendly series in New South Wales next month.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alen Stajcic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 6 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stajcic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Gill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Logarzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camila</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tameka Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Vanna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katrina Gorry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bia Zaneratto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foord</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caitlin Foord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa De Vanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elise Kellond-Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dani Neuhaus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gorry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
