<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424125298461013</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/mv-cape-don-message-in-a-bottle-found-munda-station-pilbara/8772086</url>
  <title>Message in a bottle found on a remote beach in Western Australia sparks mystery search for the author</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

It's been the subject of a film, a song, and more than likely a fantasy tale for a young child.
However it was certainly a surprise for pastoralist Michael Thompson from Mundabullangana (Munda) Station, about 100 kilometres south of Port Hedland, when he found a  washed ashore a remote beach on the property, 35 years after it was dropped into the ocean.

External Link:

Mundabullangana (Munda) Station is about 100 kilometres south of Port Hedland,
"I haven't been fishing for two years, I went for my first fishing trip last Sunday in a remote part of Munda and while driving along this beach my father got stuck in the sand.
"While we were digging him out, I looked across and saw this bottle.
"I'm normally picking up lures and bits and pieces on all these remote beaches and I looked at this bottle and thought that it looked like it had a note in it'.
"Sure enough there was a note in the bottle."
"And of course it had been floating around either for 35 years or laying on the beach of 35 years, I don't know."

The note said it was dropped over the side of MV Cape Don - a purpose-built ship which serviced navigational aids such as lighthouses off the coast of Western Australia.
However when Mr Thompson attempted to remove the note from the  old ginger wine bottle it broke into pieces, removing the writer's surname.
"The paper was that brittle I couldn't get it in my finger inside the bottle to drag it out without breaking the paper, and so I had to knock the end off the bottle and break the bottle to get the note out, and of course it broke in three."
The message read:
"This bottle was dropped over the side of the MV "Cape Don" (2000 tons) 50 miles from Port Walcott, north Western Australia on 20 November, 1982.
If found please write sending (?) Nigel Han...n (age 41), (?)7 Mawarra Street, Kingston, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia."

On the hunt for Nigel H.

In an attempt to find the man who penned the message, Mr Thompson contacted the Fremantle Ports Authority, and the MV Cape Don Society.
Treasurer of the society, John Stokes, was excited to hear of the find.
"I thought it was fantastic," he said.
"The fascination of somebody throwing the bottle into the water with a message is sort of, hope springs eternal, doesn't it.
"And luckily, somebody found it, and we'll get some details from it."
After many phone calls and emails, Mr Stokes managed to track down a member of the 1982 MV Cape Don crew, Steve Staveley, who was able to fill in the blanks.
The writer was Nigel Hanlon, who would now be 76 years old, and was last known to live in Fremantle, Western Australia.
However, no one has been able to get in touch with Mr Hanlon, to return his unique message.

Mr Stokes said it would be nice to complete the circle of the bottle's journey.
"It would be fascinating if we can find Nigel, it would finish the story after all those years, where has it been?," Mr Stokes said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stokes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mawarra Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Thompson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Hedland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV Cape Don</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Walcott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle Ports Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Han</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Staveley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mundabullangana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel H</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV Cape Don Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Don" (2000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
