<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424039399113917</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/mining/copper/bhp-billiton-plan-b-for-olympic-dam-looks-promising-20170803-gxp3dy</url>
  <title>BHP's Plan B for Olympic Dam expansion looking more promising</title>
  <content>
The boss of BHP's Olympic Dam copper mine says the company is increasingly confident about the heap leaching technology it is testing in a ramped-up pilot plant, which may eventually allow annual production to more than double to 450,000 tonnes.
Jacqui McGill, BHP's Asset President Olympic Dam, said the heap leaching project moved into "full demonstration phase" last month at a site in the Adelaide industrial suburb of Wingfield, and the signs were promising after work stepped up in the past 12 months.
She also outlined that BHP's capital spending on Olympic Dam in 2017-18 would be about $600 million, which included a $350 million smelter maintenance program announced last month. 
She said about 20 per cent of the $600 million investment program was on an underground expansion of what is known as the Southern Mine Area at Olympic Dam, which includes spending on extra fleet, bores, power and telecommunications infrastructure. About 70 per cent of the massive orebody at Olympic Dam remains untouched.

A large chunk of the $600 million would also go toward underground development in the existing northern mine area footprint. The separate heap leaching testing project is crucial in determining BHP's future plans for the mine.

BHP chose to investigate the lower-cost option of potentially using heap leach technology to expand Olympic Dam after ditching a planned US$30 billion open-cut expansion of the mine in 2012, which had been formulated during the global mining boom.
Testing on track

It was part of a sharper focus on something which has been pushing hard in the past few months as it puts pressure on the BHP board. 
"We now have the heap leach and solvent extraction pilot plants all constructed, commissioned and operating, to test and demonstrated the integrated heap leach process flow site," Ms McGill said at an American Chamber of Commerce lunch in Adelaide.

Ore was being transported from the Olympic Dam site, about 560km north of Adelaide, and being tested at the demonstration plant.
Ms McGill said the testing and trial process was on target to be finished in 2018-19. The outcome of those trials would be integral in deciding whether heap leach technology could ultimately be applied at Olympic Dam, which she said may enable BHP to expand copper production at the mine to more than 450,000 tonnes a year.
But any green light would be subject to a rigorous internal assessment of future investment returns.
"In the past 12 months we've continued testing different process conditions and now have an increased level of confidence in operating the heap leach and solvent extraction process on Olympic Dam ores at variable saline qualities," she told the lunch.

Copper at two-year high

Smelting tests conducted in Finland as part of the process had also been successful.
BHP's copper production from Olympic Dam in 2016-17 was disappointing at 166,000 tonnes, and was 18 per cent down on the record of 203,000 tonnes in 2015-16, the best result for the mine under BHP's ownership which began in 2005 after a takeover of WMC.
Copper prices are currently at their highest in two years. But Olympic Dam's output was crimped by an extended electricity outage after a , and some unplanned maintenance in refining operations.

Ms McGill said the $350 million maintenance and upgrade program of the smelter begins in earnest in late August with rolling shutdowns as 1,300 contractors converge on the site to dismantle, rebuild and upgrade the major components of the smelter. Ms McGill said it was the largest ever planned shutdown of the mine by BHP.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP's Olympic Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP's Plan B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WMC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wingfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Dam</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP's Asset President Olympic Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui McGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Mine Area</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McGill</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
