<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424039399113880</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/more-sports/kurtis-marschalls-rapid-rise-from-junior-star-to-competing-on-athletics-biggest-stage/news-story/eed3f86bd931500d19d57eba690bb6a4</url>
  <title>Marschall's plan to deliver in London</title>
  <content>
KURTIS Marschall was a high school student in Adelaide when the focus of the world was on the 2012 London Olympic Games.
Five years on and the spotlight is back on the same stadium for the world athletics championships and as Australia's No. 1 pole vaulter Marschall finds himself in the middle of it.
"I was jumping (in 2012), it was my second year jumping," Marschall said. "I think I jumped 4.50m that year. And now I am going into the world champs in the same stadium jumping 5.73m. It's pretty crazy."
What was crazy was Marschall's rapid rise last year where he went from promising junior to Rio Olympic representative in the space of a couple of months.
He thought clearing 5.70m to get into the Olympic team was a fluke. Now, he does it regularly which is why he's a completely different athlete and person going into his first world championships.
"I thought jumping 5.70 last year was a fluke to get me into the Rio team but after jumping in Adelaide once and Cairns once and Lausanne and Monaco, I am now stringing together a fair few 5.70 vaults," he said.
Marschall, 20, has started to make a name for himself on the European season, including claiming the scalp of world record holder and 2012 Olympic champion Renaud Lavillenie from France.
"That was pretty unexpected because he is the world record-holder and world-renowned for being one of the consistent guys on the circuit. It's probably not the best year he has jumped but you know anyone's scalp is there to take, I guess, and his was on that day," Marschall said.
"We will see come world champs time if he will come back up to form.
"It was huge for me though, it was a real confidence-booster knowing I am not one of the guys filling the field, not just a participant.
"I came fourth in the Lausanne Diamond League and sixth in the Monaco Diamond League and jumped higher than heaps of these guys who are so well respected, so it was pretty well up there with one of the best experiences I have had, along with Rio last year."
The obvious comparisons for Marschall are Australia's 2008 Olympic pole vault champion, Steve Hooker, although he says another former Australian champion, Paul Burgess, has been his measuring stick.
"He (Hooker) is obviously the best vaulter that's ever lived in Australia and I know he wasn't an early bloomer like me, he picked up the pole a little bit later and progressed a little bit later," Marschall said.
"But there is this other guy, Paul Burgess, who had all the national records before me, and I equalled his under 18 national record and I beat his under 20 national record so I am sort of comparing myself to him because we're on the same sort of path and he jumped six metres in the end as well.
"Obviously I would like to fulfil what Steve has accomplished in winning the Olympic Games, winning the world championships, winning world indoors, that's pretty insane. I don't think I could be any happier than doing that."
Last year's world junior championships silver medallist has spent more time in the gym since Rio and feels like he's moved on from being the "underdeveloped kid" to putting down the base for a sustained period of success.
"Coming into these championships with a 5.73m PB, that would probably get me into a final. I jumped well in Monaco, I had a few attempts at 5.77 and only one bloke cleared higher than that in that meet," Marschall explained.
"I know a few of the big names have pulled out this year which is good I guess.
"I am going in there filled with confidence knowing I have done the work and I have a strong base.
"Whatever happens, happens out there but I can be confident I have jumped 5.70m heaps of times in the past and that's what it's going to take to get into the final.
"If I do that then when it comes final time, whatever else I have in the tank, I will put that out there."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lausanne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Burgess</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's 2008 Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lausanne Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renaud Lavillenie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
