<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424047989048656</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>http://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/ask-lh-how-can-i-store-my-gaming-miniatures/</url>
  <title>Ask LH: What's The Best Way To Store Gaming Miniatures?</title>
  <content>
Dear Lifehacker, I've been collecting D&D, Reaper and Pathfinder miniatures for a few years now and have a sizeable collection. But I don't have a good system for storing and/or displaying these miniatures and keeping them dust free. Got any ideas? Thanks, Dwarf Addict

Photo:

Dear DA,

Displaying all your miniatures is supposed to be half the point! This needs to be rectified immediately to avoid a -6 hit to charisma.

In the past, we've shown how to turn old CD racks into light-up display cases which would be ideal for your collection. The beauty of this solution is that it will house each of your miniatures in their own illuminated compartments which I'm sure you'll agree is a lot cooler than just sticking 'em on a shelf. You can see how it's done .

Alternatively, you could try replicating  in your bedroom (or wherever you happen to store your miniatures.) This is achieved by sliding plumbing pipes through holes drilled in wood boards which are supported in the back with pipe clamps and strips of medium-density fibreboard. You can make the space between each shelf as narrow as you like: around 3cm should be perfect.

Want to really go all out? Here's  to building a glass display cabinet complete with LED lighting. It's a big job, but relatively easy to assemble - apart from the building materials, the only tools you need are some blue tack and a small wrench.

If you'd prefer not go down the DIY route, there are plenty of suitable display units available from IKEA and the like. This is the method favoured by Atomic editor and part-time dungeon master David Hollingworth, as he explained to us below:

IKEA do some great glass display cabinets, and you can even get lighting in them if you wants them on display. I've always wanted to get  set up for myself - it's basically how you see figures on show in stores and events.

If any 12-sided dice owners are reading, please feel free to share your own miniature display tips below!

Cheers
Lifehacker

Got your own question you want to put to Lifehacker? Send it using our .

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dear Lifehacker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IKEA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Hollingworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifehacker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reaper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dear DA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DIY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Way To Store Gaming Miniatures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwarf Addict</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pathfinder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
