<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424039399113844</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/banking-and-finance/cba-shares-slump-as-bank-vows-to-fight-the-austrac-claims-20170804-gxp9xp.html</url>
  <title>CBA shares slump as bank vows to fight the Austrac claims</title>
  <content>
Investors have dumped Commonwealth Bank shares after a government regulator took legal action for alleged breaches of anti-money laundering laws, sparking predictions a royal commission into the financial sector was now more likely.
CBA shares were down 2.9 per cent after midday on Friday as the market reacted to the government financial intelligence agency's , which the bank said it would fight. Shares in other banks were little changed.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

CBA accused of breaching money laundering act

Austrac has launched civil proceedings in the federal court alleging that CBA failed to comply with the law on more than 50,000 occasions.

News of the action emerged on Thursday afternoon, but the decline in CBA's shares escalated on Friday after the story dominated front pages of several newspapers, with predictions the bank could face massive fines.
CBA did not announce the legal action to the sharemarket via the official Australian Securities Exchange platform on Thursday.

This contrasts with how its rivals responded to news last year when they were being sued by the corporate regulator over interest rate rigging allegations  - which could also leave them facing hefty fines.
Shortly after midday, CBA noted the case via an ASX announcement that said the bank would be filing a defence in the matter.

"We will keep the market informed of any updates in compliance with our disclosure obligations," the bank said.
In its landmark case, Austrac on Thursday alleged CBA breached anti-money laundering rules more than 50,000 times,  Photo: James Elsby
Analysts said the legal action against Australia's largest bank and the risk it would trigger a royal commission into the industry was likely to weigh on CBA's shares.
"It's hard to think you won't get a royal commission. Royal commissions have a nasty habit of turning up stuff we haven't even thought of," CLSA analyst Brian Johnson said.
Mr Johnson pointed to the example of . The US lender suffered significant damage to its share price.
"Wells Fargo used to be the premium-rated US bank. A relatively small loss in the credit card mis-selling, and the stock has been smashed," he said.
He also noted that some of the money allegedly laundered through CBA's ATMs had ended up overseas.
"Historically, conduct fines in Australia have been negligible, but this goes cross border. Some of this money has gone offshore," he said.
"If anything the proceedings are a management distraction that increases the likelihood of a royal commission for the banks, which is bad for everyone," Mr Lim said.
Standard & Poor's said CBA's credit rating would not be affected by the Austrac proceedings.
David Chaikin, from University of Sydney's business school, said it was the first such legal action against an Australian bank since anti-money laundering laws were introduced in the 1980s. The current version of the anti-money laundering law was introduced last decade.
"There are thousands of pages of anti-money laundering laws and guidelines, but not enough enforcement against the big end of town," Dr Chaikin said.
He said a penalty in the hundreds of millions of dollars would not be "far fetched at all" but also pointed to a legal defence available to banks in such cases.
"If the bank can show that it took reasonable precautions and exercised due diligence to avoid the breach, that's a defence," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLSA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fargo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Chaikin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Chaikin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA ATMs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Elsby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
