<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424000744407812</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/lisa-campbell-gay-marriage-a-straight-lady-problem/news-story/6f1b1fbec7e83de63f3867183066400e</url>
  <title>Gay marriage a 'straight lady problem'</title>
  <content>
THE wife of TV host David Campbell has weighed into the rapidly escalating same-sex marriage debate, declaring the issue "a straight lady problem".
At a forum organised by the pro-gay marriage Equality Campaign on Thursday night, Lisa Campbell said if any of her three children grew up to be gay and were not allowed to marry, it would be very much her problem.
The comments come just days before the return of Parliament where the longstanding issue of marriage equality will come to a head.
On Monday, Liberal MPs will attend a special party room meeting to discuss a way forward on gay marriage which is splitting the party.
Ms Campbell shared a stage with a number of prominent women campaigning for a change to the Marriage Act including former head of the Australian Medial Association Professor Kerryn Phelps.
Asked why, as a heterosexual women, she was in favour of marriage equality, Ms Campbell said she had a personal attachment to the issue because she knew people who were legally barred from marrying.
"I may be a straight lady but it is a straight lady problem as well as a gay lady problem. This is an everybody problem," the theatre producer said at the event held at the Australian headquarters of social media company Twitter.
"I have three children, they are seven, two and two, and they may be gay.
"They deserve fairness and dignity as Australian citizens as they grow up and who they choose to be with and to have the same right I was afforded [to marry]."
Should gay people be allowed to marry, Ms Campbell said, "society will continue precisely as it is now" but to some communities it will be a huge tick of approval of the validity of their relationships.
"People will have an opportunity in front of their friends and family to make that commitment and that is vastly important for the perception of the LGBTIQ community in eyes of the wider public," Ms Campbell said.
Prof. Phelps, who is also Deputy Mayor of the City of Sydney, denied marriage equality was a fringe issue that was taking up too much of the political agenda.
"So many Australians are saying, 'hang on, this is really an issue, we're the only remaining English speaking country without marriage equality'.
"There's a small rump of politicians who are stopping this and the Australian people have had a gutful, they're angry at the political system which is stopping this from happening," said Prof. Phelps, who married her partner Jackie Stricker in New York in 2011.
With the crucial party room meeting just days away, Western Australian Liberal senator Dean Smith has said he is pressing ahead with a bill to allow same-sex marriage, labelling the government's plebiscite policy "divisive" and aimed at delaying change.
"The time is now for a parliamentary vote on same-sex marriage," he told Sky News on Friday.
The public had lost confidence in the idea of a plebiscite, describing it as a "tool for delay." Liberal colleagues have flagged the idea of a postal vote, which would not require parliament to pass a bill and would be cheaper.
Senator Smith said promoters of the postal vote such as cabinet minister Peter Dutton deserved credit for seeking to find a solution, but there were too many unknowns - including the cost, whether it would disenfranchise younger voters not currently on the electoral roll, and the "very real consideration" of a legal challenge.
He dismissed claims it was a test of Malcolm Turnbull's leadership. "This is not Malcolm Turnbull's test. This is a test of every member of the parliamentary Liberal party." Senator Smith plans to circulate his bill in the coming week, which he says will reflect the findings of a Senate inquiry.
Mr Turnbull on Thursday said he was standing by the plebiscite, as promised at the 2016 election, and any change of policy was a matter for the joint coalition party room.
Nationals members meeting in Rockhampton on Friday are expected to recommit to the plebiscite policy, which originated from a joint meeting of the parties in 2015 under Tony Abbott and is understood to be part of the coalition agreement.
One Nation leader Pauline Hanson has urged Mr Turnbull to stand firm. "Show leadership and be strong about this," she told Nine Network.
Labor leader Bill Shorten says his party would support a move to suspend business in parliament to bring on a private member's bill.
He does expect a "very small number" of Labor MPs will still vote against same- sex marriage.
- with AAP
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medial Association Professor Kerryn Phelps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof. Phelps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equality Campaign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Campbell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie Stricker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Mayor of the City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
