<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423953499767020</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/lifestyle/sa-weekend/susie-obrien-personal-trainers-stretch-image-boundaries/news-story/faa5ae28a1cc97ae6876c18cd9b740dc</url>
  <title>Personal trainers stretch image boundaries</title>
  <content>
REMEMBER when getting fit meant  with Richard Simmons or getting Physical with Olivia Newton-John?
Now it's a case of following a "fitness influencer" on social media who will persuade you to train at home, lose weight and send in photos of you in your bikini.

Take your workout to the next level with these 6 workout moves

6 moves Kayla Itsines thinks you need in your workout
Leading the  pack is Adelaide fitness trainer Kayla Itsines, who has just been called one of Time's most influential people. She's also on the BRW Young Rich list.
Not bad for someone whose job seems to involve posing in gym gear and posting photos of other people's breakfasts.
The most recent breakfast offering appeared to consist of a bowl of pink fairy floss goo topped off with spotted bird's eggs. It got 34,000 likes.
Itsines has sure come a long way from being the Greek girl who kept getting her last name mispronounced as "intestines".
However, some cracks have started appearing in the Itsines image, with recent revelations her partner Tobi Pearce, an avid bodybuilder, was picked up twice last year for speeding and was found to be in possession of what the court heard were "anti-oestrogen" pills, which reduce hormones and are "often used with steroids". He denied they were his.
Itsines has also started revealing she, too, is just as real as the rest of us.
Her recent social media snap showing the merest hint of stretch mark on her otherwise impeccably tanned hip made international headlines. Itsines' photo, captioned  received 161,000 likes and nearly 2000 adoring comments.
You would have thought she'd had passed out on the couch on a chocolate high from inhaling a family block of Cadbury washed down with a bucket of supermarket cab sav.
Now that really would merit a #thisisme! hashtag. (Well, it does sound a bit like me.)
But no. The Great Stretch Mark Reveal of 2017 came hot on the heels of Itsines also saying she has "genetically thin hair" and even sometimes wears a fake pony tail.
The fact that so many women were in raptures at the thought of Queen Kayla being even the tiniest bit imperfect speaks volumes. It's because this approach to fitness is all about appearance, not health. Itsines posts a lot of "before" and "after" images of those following her program, based on the implication that the chubbier "before" image is somehow morally and physically wrong. The "after" photos all look very much like Itsines herself: very slim with very toned abs showcased in crop tops and leggings.
But what happens if you look like the "before" shot and are happy, healthy and fit? What if the "after" shot comes at the expense of your wellbeing and mental health?
Itsines insists beauty comes from the inside, but only promotes a very narrow range of body images. She preaches self-affirmation and self-love, but these messages are totally outweighed by the sheer volume of physical perfection on offer through her social media channels.
There is also an alarming cultish mentality about it all: "I really wanna be like you," says one follower. Many post photos celebrating their "", which is a milestone with the program.
Itsines urges her followers not to compare themselves to her: "Remember your journey is YOUR journey" and yet continues to post images of her own body which create a standard for her followers to attain. It's just another way in which there is a definite disconnect between the words and images.
It's also certainly not the online love-in Itsines suggests. A few days ago, a woman showing off her new slimmer figure was soundly criticised by others for wearing shorts that were too tight and for not losing enough weight.
I'm left thinking that all fitness influencers do is influence others to feel bad about not looking like them. Maybe it's time to search for other get-fit options. Why not jump on board another latest trend and try goat yoga, crunning (running on all fours - also called crawling) or bungee dancing?
Or you could just go for a jog. Doesn't anyone do that these days?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayla Itsines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRW Young Rich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Newton-John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Itsines</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Stretch Mark Reveal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobi Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Kayla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cadbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Simmons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
