<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424039399113831</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/12/57/sateki-siale-kelly-ventigadoo-lakema-stabbing-guilty-verdict</url>
  <title>Man found guilty of beer bottle murder of neighbour</title>
  <content>
A man has been found guilty of murdering a neighbour for talking too loudly on his street in south-western Sydney.
Kelly Ventigadoo was standing in a Lakemba driveway talking to his mother and hearing impaired father at 12.30am on October 11 2015.
The crown alleged Sateki Siale approached and said "why are you talking so loud?"
The 26-year-old admits he then smashed a beer bottle on a brick fence and stabbed Mr Ventigadoo in the neck. 
Siale hit him again when he tried to get up.
Mr Ventigadoo bled to death within five minutes.
Siale turned himself in the following day and told police he did not realise he had killed someone until his mother told him.

Related Articles

"She told me I killed someone last night and I don't believe her, and then I asked 'are you serious?"
"And then she repeated the words again, that I killed someone, and then I don't know, I feel sick in the stomach."
His barrister Brad Hughes argued he did not intend to kill Mr Ventigadoo.
"He's denying he had a specific intent to kill because of the alcohol and drugs he'd consumed."
But the jury disagreed, returning a guilty verdict after two days of deliberations. 
Outside court Mr Ventigadoo's family welcomed the decision.
His sister Patricia Ventigadoo said not enough was being done to address the drug and alcohol problem.
"You can get drunk, you can take drugs and you can kill anybody and it's an excuse. It's not an excuse!"
Siale will be sentenced at a later date.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sateki Siale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ventigadoo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Ventigadoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Ventigadoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 11 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
