<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424000744407837</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/localfooty/video-is-providing-vital-evidence-in-more-local-footy-brawl-reports/news-story/ef531ec75df87d90c175a819bbab2b19</url>
  <title>Video killing the footy violence</title>
  <content>
VIDEO is becoming a powerful tool in the bid to clean up on-field violence as football leagues increasingly embrace the digital age.
When Ali Fahour clocked an unsuspecting Dale Saddington in a Northern Football League Division 1 home-and-away fixture earlier this year, widespread concern followed, with footage of the incident viewed by thousands on television screens and the web.
West Preston-Lakeside's Fahour, then the AFL's diversity manager, copped a 14-week suspension for the alleged coward punch.
He was automatically deregistered and banned for life under AFL Victoria rules after the penalty pushed him over the 16-week suspension threshold allowed under the National Deregistration Policy.

Watch the full suburban footy brawl including Ali Fahour's strike on Whittlesea's Dale Saddington (circled)

FULL ALI FAHOUR VIDEO
A marathon two-hour plus tribunal hearing in Greensborough ended with Fahour fronting the press pack and revealing he had stood down from his job at the AFL.
The Whittlesea footballer felled by Fahour has since retired on doctor's advice, had time off work and opted to take the matter further.
Victoria Police has charged Fahour on summons with recklessly causing injury, intentionally causing injury and unlawful assault in relation to the incident.
The case has undoubtedly left a trail of destruction which extends beyond the two directly involved.
But would there have been a different outcome without video evidence?
The Northern league films all of its 13 weekly senior matches, which are made available on its website.
The Essendon District league films five games on a weekend - up from one in previous years - and the Western Region league videos all five of its Division 1 fixtures.
All matches in AFL Victoria competitions - VFL, VFL Women's and TAC Cup - are also filmed.
Unlike the elite level, though, local competitions do not have the benefit of countless cameras to catch every incident.
They often rely on independent investigations, witness statements or on the chance that an eagle-eyed spectator captured vision that is crucial to the case.
Sportscast Australia, which tapes matches for the NFL, charges $400-$500 a match.
NFL chief executive Peter McDougall said: "It (video) is a great resource, not just for tribunals, but also for coaches and their opposition analysis for their own coaching and training of players. It's good for club history and archives.
"When it comes to set penalties, it certainly assists clubs to decide whether to challenge a report or not, which helps unclog our tribunal hearings and the number we have each year.
"It's definitely reduced the number of hearings.
"The number of set penalties probably have risen since filming came in, so in some ways it's been very positive.
"It also means we're in a position to recruit quality tribunal panel members because they're not going to be sitting all hours two or three times a week."
The NFL has a pool of tribunal members, with three rostered on each week.
"We only have a limited number of chairmen so we have consistency with the way that proceedings are conducted," McDougall said.
"It's important we have fair proceedings, that our procedures are applied correctly and that natural justice and procedural fairness are applied.
"Our chairmen are all trained legally so they can conduct a professional hearing."
Some on social media expressed their confusion after the Fahour verdict, questioning how he could have been given such a lengthy ban the night after Melbourne's Tom Bugg was handed a six-week sanction by the AFL tribunal for his strike on Sydney's Callum Mills.
But comparing cases, particularly in different competitions, can be difficult.
Factors such as the injury sustained by the victim, the history of the perpetrator and the circumstances involved are all considered.
"There are certain behaviours that aren't tolerated and I suppose our tribunal decided Ali's was one of those," McDougall said.
"That's as much as I can say on the Ali case. I can't speak on behalf of the panel.
"I don't sit in the hearing and I've never wanted to comment, even to clubs, about tribunal penalties because they're always subjective."
Essendon District league boss Marc Turri said video was a handy resource for local competitions.
He stopped short of declaring his league would make an extra investment to have more games filmed, saying the benefits needed to be weighed against costs attached.
"Anything that's caught on screen, there's no hearsay involved in it. You can clearly see what transpires, so it certainly makes the judicial process a lot simpler," Turri said.
"But obviously you can't just be relying on video evidence at our level because we just don't have the resources that you do at higher levels.
"But you've also got things like umpire development, player development, forward scouting - they're all benefits as well. So it's not just down to disciplinary matters that the video is used for.
"You need to weigh that against the cost involved because it's not a cheap exercise when you're doing quite a number of games over the length of the season."
Turri said it was "simplistic" to compare cases.
"Each tribunal, regardless of where you are - metropolitan Melbourne, country Victoria, state league, national league - they are all going to look at cases individually," he said.
"They don't necessarily look at another league, another state or even at the AFL themselves.
"Being independent, they look at those situations with a degree of independence so they can make the decision they think is right for that particular league."
Lengthy recent penalties in Victorian leagues include:
A Keilor player hit with a 36-game sanction - later reduced to nine on appeal - for striking an opponent.
A Hoppers Crossing player banned for two years after being found guilty of striking.
A Norwood runner given an 18-month suspension for abusing a teenage umpire.
An Eltham junior coach suspended for 12 games after he was found guilty swearing at a girl from an opposition team.
A Corio footballer handed an 18-week ban by the AFL Barwon tribunal for allegedly striking an opponent.
McDougall said there was "no link" between penalties handed down at AFL and local level.
"As far as penalties it's very hard to link and have a consistent approach. It's always going to be in the eye of the beholder," he said.
"When it comes to standards, we absolutely have a link because we should be mirroring standards at an AFL level as far as players being punched et cetera.
"That's one thing we haven't tolerated, probably for years, let alone the past six to eight weeks when the AFL's probably come up with a stronger stance.
"We've probably had a strong stance all the way through."
Western Region league chief executive Matthew Duck said behavioural incidents had steadily decreased in his competition over the past decade.
"There has been a 39 per cent reduction in tribunal cases over the past five years," he said.
"The tribunal performs an important role, but the improvement in player behaviour over the past 10 years is largely due to clubs setting clear behavioural expectations."
About 10,000 players take part in NFL matches each weekend, highlighting the need to minimise unsavoury acts.
While there will always be incidents, the video will remain the leading resource as leagues tackle violence on the ground.
Fahour is due to appear in the Heidelberg Magistrates' Court on October 11.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDougall</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoppers Crossing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Deregistration Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sportscast Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Football League Division 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon District</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Callum Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keilor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Region</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Turri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Tom Bugg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turri</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Saddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Fahour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Duck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea's Dale Saddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAC Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Preston-Lakeside's Fahour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NORWOOD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALI FAHOUR VIDEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Barwon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREENSBOROUGH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter McDougall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
