<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424138183363273</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/nitv/nitv-news/article/2017/08/04/opposition-calls-government-step-shortens-road-map-recognition</url>
  <title>Opposition calls on government to step up: Shorten's road map to recognition</title>
  <content>
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten has urged Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull to commence a Joint Parliamentary Select Committee to advise parliament on the next steps towards a successful referendum.

By

Nakari Thorpe

4 Aug 2017 - 9:29 AM  UPDATED 4 HOURS AGO

Opposition Leader Bill Shorten has urged Malcolm Turnbull to commence a Joint Parliamentary Select Committee to advise parliament on the next steps towards a successful referendum. 

In a letter addressed to the Prime Minister, Mr Shorten says the 'best chance of success for any proposal for constitutional change rests on the active engagement of Indigenous Australians in the process' in addition to strong support across the parliament.

Mr Shorten proposes a bipartisan, parliamentary process be established for working through the necessary detail so that a question for a referendum can be finalised.

To move forward, Mr Shorten says a Joint Parliamentary Select Committee is the most effective way.  

He says such a body could be set-up immediately and will advise the parliament on the necessary steps to be taken to a referendum, including a proposed timeline.

Mr Shorten says the Committee will have short lifespan with a reporting date at the end of next year to allow the Parliament to consider a proposal in the first half of next year.

The body will work with constitutional experts to develop an appropriate question that genuinely reflects the recommendations of the Referendum Council.

The former last month and recommended a constitutionally entrenched "Voice to Parliament" in the form of a national Indigenous representative body.

Mr Shorten also proposes that a small group of Indigenous leaders be confirmed at this year's Garma Festival to act as a formal advisory group to the parliamentary committee throughout the process.

He called for the other proposals that came out of the Uluru Statement, a Makarrata Commission and a truth-telling process, be clarified and advanced.

A new paper examines the ways "whiteness" reproduces racial advantages and disadvantages.

The only identified Indigenous Australian woman in WWI was actually serving for Canada.

Several people, including members of the Stolen Generation, have gathered at the Sydney Opera House to launch commemorations for the 20th anniversary of the Bringing...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makarrata Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 4 HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Parliamentary Select Committee</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stolen Generation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nakari Thorpe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 2017 - 9:29 AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
