<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424211197808605</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/television/cocreator-reveals-which-will-grace-character-wont-be-returning/news-story/6ddab90f97671c368092c95d4d72dcd9</url>
  <title>Which Will & Grace character won't be returning?</title>
  <content>
ONE of the most beloved characters from Will & Grace won't be returning for the show's new season.
Actress Shelley Morrison, who played Karen's maid Rosario Salazar, has chosen not to be a part of the rebooted show that will start airing in the US in September.
"Shelley has decided to retire," co-creator Max Mutchnick said according to .
"It was with a heavy heart that she gave us that information and that we received it, but it is the way that it goes. It is a choice that she has made.
"We really wanted Shelley to be a part of this series, so we find ourselves having to figure that out moving forward. It was not an easy decision to make, but it's one that she made."
Rosario isn't the only character who'll be missing when the show returns to our screens after its original run from 1998 to 2006.
The character of Grace's mum was played by Debbie Reynolds who died last December and therefore won't be seen in the series revival.
"That was another part of the story that we had to really spend time on addressing, all of the characters that existed in 198 episodes," Mutchnick said.
"She's obviously not coming back, but we will be speaking to it and the characters will be speaking to it."
Fans will be especially disappointed by the lack of Rosario in season nine as her love/hate relationship with Karen was one of the highlights of the show.
Here are some of their most memorable interactions:
• Rosario: Listen lady, in my county I was a schoolteacher.
Karen: Oh yeah? Well in this country, you wash my bras.
• Rosario Salazar: I'd wring her neck but I don't want to be standing in a puddle of gin.
• Rosario: Miss Karen? We have a little visitor.
Karen: Oh, for god's sake, I'm not your mother. You know where the tampons are!
Karen: It's your stepdaughter Olivia, you ghost of Christmas passed-out.
• Rosario: You know, if you're gonna leave me in the limo for five hours, the least you could do is crack a window.
Karen: What, and let you start yapping out at all the other maids so that they can come over and jump on the car? I don't think so.
Rosario: You better watch it, lady, because the next time you take a bath it'll be rub-a-dub-dub, I drop the blender in the tub.
The Will & Grace revival will be available to stream on Stan from September 29 with the show already being confirmed for a second season.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosario</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Karen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosario Salazar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mutchnick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelley Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debbie Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mutchnick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
