<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424262737417033</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/unrivalled-beachfront-estate/3208872/</url>
  <title>Unrivalled beachfront estate</title>
  <content>
AS extraordinary as any site around our coastline, it's hard to comprehend that Laguna even exists.
The ultimate alternative to an island with unparalleled private beach frontage of half a kilometre, unique along the east coast of Australia.
While the 31-hectare (77 acre) property gives the crucial element of seclusion, you are far from isolated with the beach side town of Noosa just a short drive away.
Surrounded by nature reserves and national park, amongst vast tracts of coastal heath, pockets of eucalypt and melaleuca forests, and freshwater lagoons has at its centre an uprising of basalt that soars 34m above the sea and surrounding lands. It forms a grassy knoll dotted with trees offering uninterrupted views and capturing the cooling coastal breezes; a landmark of local significance and historical value and the foundation for a home like no other.
Built on the highest point on the Noosa North Shore at 34m of elevation, the contemporary home takes advantage of mesmerising uninterrupted views from as far north as Double Island Point, across Laguna Bay to Noosa National Park and around to the vibrant Hastings Street precinct and Main Beach.
Careful consideration and design ensures that the substantial residence integrates seamlessly with its surroundings, this has been done to such a significant standard that even many long term Noosa locals are unaware it exists.
The home has been built to the highest standards offering the ultimate resistance to the coastal environment with materials that are rarely used in residential construction but often specified in coastal high-rise construction.
It is orientated to take advantage of the cooling north easterly sea breezes that prevail in the summer months, yet protected by the national park and tree canopy from the unwelcome south-easterly in winter.
With unrivalled privacy and seclusion it is actually located only 3km from the global tourism destination of Noosa, with its world class beaches, dining and boutique shopping, myriad of drawcard events, enviable climate and easy links to capital cities, you will start to appreciate just how unique this property is.
Succumb to the sound of rolling surf and soak up the views from throughout the house and decks. Laguna Bay is a sheltered haven for dolphins and a favourite resting spot for migrating humpbacks which you can watch from the house, while the lawns play host to resident kangaroos.
Surrounding bushland creates a haven for wildlife and requires little maintenance, large grassed expanses tucked behind the dunes provide ample space for hosting events of any nature and scale.
The dunes lead down to expanses of private white sandy beach where consistent breaks offer the ultimate crowd free experience to surf, kiteboard, fish, horse ride or relax on the dune-top deck, this is a backyard like no other.
NOOSA NORTH SHORE
312 Teewah Beach Rd
5 Bed, 3 Bath, 4 Car
Features: Contemporary two-level home on 31ha with highest elevation on Noosa North Shore, 470m beach frontage, mesmerising views from Double Island Point to Noosa Heads
Price: Tender closing 4pm Monday, September 11
Agent: Adrian Reed at Dowling Neylan Real Estate and Ken Jacobs, Christie's International Real Estate
Contact: 0409 446 955, 0407 190 152
Inspection: Saturday 2-3pm
PROFESSIONAL surfer Julian Wilson says he is enjoying married life
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Magistrate says break-ins frustrate community clubs
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laguna Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laguna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastings Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Double Island Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bed, 3 Bath, 4 Car</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Reed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teewah Beach Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie's International Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dowling Neylan Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa North Shore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
