<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424168248134777</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/world-travel/europe/twisted-brit-tourist-gets-tattoo-of-madeleine-mccann-as-part-of-sickening-trend/news-story/bb40d47b328a97cc216933d2641fad77</url>
  <title>Twisted Brit tourist gets tattoo of Madeleine McCann as part of sickening trend</title>
  <content>
UK police say there are still critical leads on the 10 year search for Madeleine McCann
3:29

Scotland Yard chief Mark Rowley said there are still 'critical' leads that are of 'great interest' in the investigation into Madeleine McCann's disappearance in Portugal on May 3, 2007.

April 26th 2017
3 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Twisted Brit tourist gets tattoo mocking the disappearance of Madeleine McCann as part of sickening trend. Photo: AP Photo/PA

Jon LockettThe Sun

Share

A BRITISH tourist has gotten a sickening tattoo mocking the disappearance of Madeleine McCann as a part of a disturbing new craze.
Warped tourists on boozy holidays in popular holiday spot Magaluf have been asking the notorious resort's tattoo artists to ink their skins with tasteless and offensive designs this summer in a troubling new trend.
And one twisted person clearly sees Maddie, and her well-publicised disappearance from a holiday resort 10 years ago, as fair game.
Magaluf has numerous ink parlours which stay open until 6am - so they can cash in on revellers out of their minds on drugs and booze.
They say in recent years there has been a growing trend for Brit drinkers to get the most tasteless tattoos possible.
And now a sickening photo has emerged of a man who appears to have a vile Madeleine tattoo on his leg.
The inking reads "I stole Madeleine McCann" above a heart.
Only in Maga would you find someone with an "I stole Madeleine McCann" tattoo
The Daily Star spoke to workers in parlours along the strip and many say they are willing to create any tattoo asked for.
One parlour worker said: "We get loads of crazy Brits in here asking for all sorts of tatts.

"We'll do whatever they want, even if it's offensive. Some people might say it's a bit sick but it's not going on our bodies and it's the person's decision."

The last photo taken of missing British girl Madeleine McCann, who went missing in May 2007 from her family's holiday home in Portugal at age 3. Her whereabouts remains unknown.Source:Supplied
Earlier this month, The Sun revealed how authorities in Magaluf are trying to crack down on boozed-up revellers.
In a desperate bid to rid the resort of its "Shagaluf" image, Magaluf's mayor Alfonso Rodriguez Badal says drunk Brits are "not wanted".
He has called on bar owners in areas such as Magaluf's notorious party strip, Punta Ballena, to stop offering booze at knockdown prices.
And he warned Brits that if they are looking for "debauchery" they would be "best off not coming".
Magaluf cops were called out 1,672 times between May and June - and increase from 400 last year - as the number of anti-social behaviour incidents soared.
The most common complaint related to illegal street selling with 472 complaints lodged to officials.
There were also 46 cases of drug-taking, 40 of nudism and semi-nudism and 21 cases of boozing on the street.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeleine McCann</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Rowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shagaluf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeleine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfonso Rodriguez Badal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP Photo/PA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magaluf</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punta Ballena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland Yard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon LockettThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
