<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424082348787368</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/right-to-life-hit-vic-premiers-electorate/news-story/dd9115b6095fb150fce1cf11f771e70b</url>
  <title>Right To Life hit Vic Premier's electorate</title>
  <content>
Kaitlyn OfferAustralian Associated Press

Share

A "mischievous" and "misleading" Right To Life campaign is targeting Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews' electorate in opposition to his government's proposed assisted dying laws.
Right To Life have been dropping the pamphlet throughout nine electorates, including Mr Andrews' seat of Mulgrave, as well as Bentleigh and Macedon, both held by Labor.
"That rather mischievous, almost misrepresentation of who the author of that pamphlet was, that's not particularly fair, I don't think that's right, it doesn't add to the debate," Mr Andrews told ABC Central Victoria on Friday.
"People are free to target whoever they want, but they should do so with the facts and they should be clear about who they are and they shouldn't necessarily be putting out material that looks like it's from somebody else."
Bentleigh MP Nick Staikos, who is undecided on how he will vote, has copped abuse after the flyer started circulating his electorate with his details emblazoned inside, making some readers believe he was responsible for the flyer.
He said he was disgusted with the campaign and could see why constituents were confused.
The government hopes to introduce legislation to parliament that would allow terminally ill Victorians to choose when they die, in accordance with strict guidelines including that they have less than 12 months to live.
Mr Andrews changed his mind on assisted dying after watching his father's terminal battle with cancer.
The Right To Life flyer reads "Do you believe in suicide prevention or suicide assistance from a doctor?"

It also contains MP contact information in large, bold type, with the Right To Life contact information in much smaller print on the back.
Right To Life have been contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Right To Life</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Central Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh MP Nick Staikos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaitlyn OfferAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulgrave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
