<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424168248134680</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/gas-tanker-erupts-in-flames-along-pacific-motorway-20161205-gxp37t.html</url>
  <title>Tolls waived along Logan Motorway as clean up of burnt-out chemical tanker continues</title>
  <content>
Tolls along the Logan Motorway have been waived after a chemical tanker erupted in flames at Loganholme, an incident that resulted in no injuries thanks to the quick-thinking truck driver who pulled over to the side of the road and stop traffic when he noticed a fire had broken out underneath his cab.
"Several explosions" were heard from hundreds of metres away and an emergency situation declared after a gas tanker carrying hydrochloric acid burst into flames on the Pacific Motorway.Photo: Brett Williams/Twitter
The motorway was closed near the Logan Hyperdome after a southbound Coogee Chemicals truck carrying 15,000 litres of hydrochloric acid burst into flames and billowed "large volumes of black smoke" about 8.40am on Friday.
The emergency area covered the northbound and southbound lanes and a one-kilometre radius of the crash site and was expected to remain in place for hours.Photo: Jodie Ann Riches
A witness to the explosion told 7 News he saw the truck driver leap from the cab as it erupted in flames.
"The cab was on fire and he has literally opened up the door and just bolted...it went up way too quick," the man said.

Coogee Chemicals confirmed the driver had been checked for smoke inhalation and had been released.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Queensland Ambulance Service clinical support officer Ross Hodges spoke with the truck driver and said it was very lucky nobody was injured in the explosion.Photo: Amy Mitchell-Whittington
"The truck driver did very well, he recognised the situation was quite serious early on, managed to have the foresight to pull over onto the side of the M1," he said.
"(He) managed to call the emergency services very quickly and also flag down passing motorists to get them to come to a standstill.
"(He said) the fire appeared to be coming from under his cab somewhere but he was unsure at the time of the exact cause of the fire."
Tolls were suspended from 10.45am in both directions at the eastern end of the Logan Motorway and the southern end of the Gateway Extension Motorway to provide an alternative route for motorists, according to Go Via Network's website.
Tolling was expected to resume about 6pm once the accident had been cleared and diversions removed.
Police urged nearby businesses to evacuate, people nearby to remain inside and those with breathing difficulties to have medication or breathing aids nearby.
More than 30 firefighters on scene controlled the fire just before 10am and the northbound lanes at Loganholme reopened just after 11am.
An emergency services spokesman said the smoke was blowing south towards commercial and residential areas and was "likely to affect the air" for a large part of the day.
Several explosions could be heard about 600 metres away from the incident at Andy's Auto Rentals, manager Wayne Garner said. 
"I was putting a customer out into a 12-seater bus and the next minute we heard little boom explosions in the distance and a lot of smoke," he said.
"We heard around seven explosions and the flames were quite high.
"I thought it was one of those small trucks that carries the gas bottles for barbecues, because it was repeated explosions."
In a statement, Coogee Chemicals said: "The company is relieved that no one has been injured in the incident but is concerned about disruption or distress to local residents, businesses and passersby." 
The national company, with its head office is in Western Australia, manufactures and imports agricultural, mining and industrial chemicals for both the Australian and international markets.
Police said moving the burnt tanker was going to be a "logistical challenge".
Emergency services and Coogee Chemicals officers were preparing to remove the hydrochloric acid from the damaged truck and transfer it to another tanker, estimated to take about an hour.
The damaged truck will then be removed from the site under police escort.
Scientific officers from the Queensland Fire and Emergency Services were on scene.
Meanwhile an  had been cleared, police said.
Paramedics were called to the crash near the Kessels Road on-ramp that blocked right and left lanes on the northbound lanes about 7.30am.
No one was injured and the area was cleared by 8.15am.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateway Extension Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Hyperdome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy's Auto Rentals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kessels Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coogee Chemicals</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Williams/Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Mitchell-Whittington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loganholme</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Motorway</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Motorway.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Hodges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Via Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Garner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Ann Riches</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
