<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424232672645445</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:34</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/the-prince-of-denmark-just-said-he-doesnt-want-to-be-buried-next-to-his-wife-the-queen-2017-8</url>
  <title>The prince of Denmark just said he doesn't want to be buried next to his wife, the Queen</title>
  <content>
Prince Henrik of Denmark has topped off a decades-long tantrum at not being considered his wife's "equal" by announcing he doesn't want to be buried next to her.

Henrik, 83, was born Henri Marie Jean Andre de Laborde de Monpezat in 1934 near Bordeaux. After meeting the then crown princess Margrethe of Denmark in London, the two married in 1967 and Henrik renounced his French citizenship.

By 1969, the couple had two children. One, Frederik, later went on to marry a Tasmanian, Mary Donaldson, he met in a Sydney pub.

In 1972, upon the death of her father, Margrethe became Denmark's queen. Henrik was named prince consort and remained in that role until he retired from it last year.

But for most of that time he was prince consort, Henrik insisted he should be known as king consort and treated as Margrethe's equal.

In 2002, he told a Danish tabloid he felt "pushed aside, degraded and humiliated" when he assumed he had been demoted to third in the royal hierarchy after Frederik was given some official duties ahead of his father.

"I won't be part of that game," he told BT. "I am number two. I have to be number two. You can't just change the hierarchy because it suits somebody."

The UK Telegraph reported for a while.

Then in 2015, , saying it was a form of discrimination that wives of kings are called queens, but husbands of queens must be called princes.

"It angers me that I am discriminated against," he said.

"Denmark, which is seemingly known as an avid defender of gender equality, apparently, is ready to be considered useless husbands their wives."

Today, he made it clear he would go to the grave refusing to budge on his stance.

When she dies, his wife, 77, be interred in a sarcophagus in Roskilde Cathedral. Henrik, 83, has asked to be buried somewhere else.

"For the prince, the decision not to buried beside the queen is the natural consequence of not having been treated equally to his spouse - by not having the title and role he has desired," palace communications chief Lene Balleby told BT.

While Queen Elizabeth's husband Philip has always been known as Prince Philip, Elizabeth has always publicly maintained .

He has officially been given "place, pre-eminence and precedence" in that role since the pair were married in 1947.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Donaldson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK's Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henrik</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margrethe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roskilde Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margrethe of Denmark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frederik</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monpezat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henri Marie Jean Andre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lene Balleby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Henrik of Denmark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bordeaux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laborde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henrik, 83</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
