<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423785996040537</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/boeing-tests-engines-on-its-787-dreamliner-by-drawing-a-giant-787-dreamliner-all-over-america/</url>
  <title>Boeing Tests Engines On Its 787 Dreamliner By Drawing A Giant 787 Dreamliner All Over America</title>
  <content>
A 17-hour test flight where you end up right back where you started is probably pretty boring. Any way to spice things up is probably welcome, which is likely why Boeing test pilots used their long, boring test flight to  all over America's beautiful face.

The sky-drawing was noticed by the air-traffic tracking site , who posted this tweet:

The Boeing 787-8 aircraft plotted its selfie over 22 states, and they even managed it so that the nose of the drawn plane points to the Puget Sound area where Boeing is headquartered.

Planes drawing images with their flight paths is  Usually, though, it seems like it's just , like the United States was a middle school desk.

GPS trolling is an art form spawning a movement of walkers, runners and auto enthusiasts to create map-based creations. But one enterprising pilot, with his own private plane and time to kill, took to the skies to draw the an image that fills the notebooks of 8th graders and college art majors alike - a big ol' penis.

So, in that context, this aeroplane picture is high art, literally and conceptually.

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puget Sounds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing Tests Engines On Its 787 Dreamliner By Drawing A Giant 787 Dreamliner All Over America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
