<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424129593428451</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/girlfriend-who-encouraged-teen-boyfriend-to-kill-himself-sentenced-to-jail/news-story/6edd5ecc057ae31087b6088875b90dd5</url>
  <title>Girlfriend who encouraged teen boyfriend to kill himself sentenced to jail</title>
  <content>
Michelle Carter found guilty of involuntary manslaughter of boyfriend
0:36

A judge has found Michelle Carter guilty of the involuntary manslaughter of her boyfriend Conrad Roy III after encouraging him to kill himself. Courtesy: Fox News

June 17th 2017
2 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

Michelle Carter, centre, was sentenced to two and a half years behind bars. Picture: Matt West

AFP

Share

A 20-YEAR-OLD woman has been jailed for encouraging her teenage boyfriend to make good on plans to kill himself.
On Thursday a judge sentenced Massachusetts woman Michelle Carter to two-and-a-half years, with 15 months to be served behind bars.
A tearful Carter stood with hands clasped and eyes cast down to hear her fate over the death of Conrad Roy, who killed himself in July 2014.
In an extraordinary case seen as breaking new ground in a state with no law against encouraging suicide, Carter swapped hundreds of text messages with Roy, repeatedly urging him to follow through on his plan to kill himself and conceal it from his parents.
The defence argued that Carter, who was 17 years old at the time, was racked with depressive disorders, on antidepressants and suffered from eating disorders, all of which swayed her judgment.

Michelle Carter arrives at court with her parents for her sentencing hearing. Picture: Matt WestSource:AP

Conrad Roy III died from carbon monoxide poisoning at the age of 18. Picture: SuppliedSource:Supplied
She had faced up to 20 years in prison at her sentencing in a juvenile court in Taunton, south of Boston.
But Judge Lawrence Moniz, who convicted Carter of involuntary manslaughter in June, said it was important to balance punishment and rehabilitation for her role in Roy's death in his pick-up truck in a parking lot.
Moniz said that after 15 months behind bars, the balance of her sentence would be suspended until August 1, 2022.
Roy's father, also named Conrad Roy, accused Carter of exploiting his son's battle with depression for her own self-aggrandisement.

"How could Michelle Carter behave so viciously and encourage my son to end his life? Where was her humanity?" he asked.
"I pray that his death will save lives one day."
Roy's mother said in a statement read out by the prosecution, calling for changes in the law to guard against other families enduring the same torment.
The prosecution had recommended a sentence of between seven and 12 years, accusing Carter of deliberately engineering Roy's death in a bid to seek attention and sympathy.
"Her actions killed Conrad Roy. She ended his life to better her own," the prosecutor told the court.
"She has not accepted responsibility.
"She has shown no remorse."

Judge Lawrence Moniz took into account Ms Carter's own mental health issues. Picture: Matt WestSource:AP

She received two and a half years, suspended for 15 months, and a probation order. Picture: Matt WestSource:AP
Carter's lawyer urged the judge for leniency, saying his client, dressed in red pants and a cream blouse, hoped to build a career in real estate after graduating from high school, was still in counselling and was not a danger to the public.
"This is a terrible, terrible tragedy and she very much regrets this," said Joseph Cataldo.
But the case has divided legal opinion on whether Carter's actions were even enough to secure a conviction under involuntary manslaughter.
While Roy was harming himself, he stopped and Judge Moniz said during a telephone call with Carter, she encouraged him to keep going. She also failed to sound the alarm and that was crucial to the guilty verdict.
Prosecutors said Carter stayed on the telephone listening to her boyfriend as he died.
"She called no one," Judge Moniz said in June, despite Carter knowing where Roy was and having his family's telephone numbers.
"And finally, she did not issue a simple additional instruction: 'Get out of the truck'."
He rejected a theory of involuntary intoxication raised by psychiatrist Peter Breggin, a defence witness who testified that Carter's own medication would have hindered her state of mind.
The American Civil Liberties Union criticised the prosecution's theory that she killed Roy with her words, saying in June that the conviction "exceeds the limits of our criminal laws and violates free speech protections."
But David Rossman, law professor at Boston University, said the case was so extraordinary that it was unlikely to open the door to a rash of prosecutions, such as manslaughter cases against doctors treating terminal patients.
"It's possible," he told AFP.
"But that would be a careless use of what happened in Massachusetts, because it would be ignoring what the court said."
If you or someone you know is in crisis or needs support right now, please call Lifeline on 13 11 14 or Suicide Call Back Service 1300 659 467.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suicide Call Back Service 1300 659 467</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt WestSource</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppliedSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1, 2022</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Civil Liberties Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Cataldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Breggin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YEAR-OLD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carters</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Lawrence Moniz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rossman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Moniz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conrad Roy III</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conrad Roy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taunton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Carter</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massachusetts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moniz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
