<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424254147482229</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/north-northeast/men-on-a-mission-to-save-their-rsl/news-story/c0ff4ec64da51d6f7aebee74d0e165f5</url>
  <title>Men on a mission to save their RSL</title>
  <content>
YOUNG veterans at Northfield are on a mission to give their local RSL club a more youthful image - with family-oriented activities and new services.
Warren Nelling, 40, and Tom Newton, 34, approached the Northfield sub-branch, on Grand Junction Rd, late last year to help change the organisation's bleak outlook.
"It would be sad if we lost the RSL and had to start something else," Mr Nelling said.
"It just wouldn't have the same impact because everyone knows what the RSL is.
"Generally sub-branches are oriented towards gatherings of ex-servicemen, having a beer and a chinwag, and one of the things that didn't appeal to me as a younger veteran was to do that ... we just need to reshape it."
After several months, the former committee of veterans aged in their 80s and 90s handed over the reins to a new committee led by Mr Nelling as president and Mr Newton as treasurer.
They are being guided by former committe member John Dodd, 84.
Since the new committee took over this year, the Northfield RSL membership has increased from seven to 45. Excluding Mr Dodd, Mr Nelling is the oldest at 40.
"They were happy to see some young blood, they were in their 90s and they didn't have the energy anymore to keep going".
The idea to revive the organisation came to Mr Nelling and Mr Newton when they reunited on Anzac Day last year for the first time since their Iraq tour of duty in 2003.
"I had complained about what the RSL did or didn't do ... we got talking and he suggested we get involved instead of complaining," Mr Nelling said.
"We want to be able to bring our kids and create programs that could help veterans socialise without the necessity to have a drink if they don't want to."
The committee is in communication with the Department for Correctional Services, which owns the Northfield RSL building, to create a child-friendly space.
"It's located on a main road next to the jail - it's not what everybody classifies as a prime location," Mr Nelling said.
"But we've been working fairly closely with (the department) to be able to fence off the outdoor area and put a kids playground in there."
Activities introduced at Northfield RSL include guitar and photography lessons, and there's more to come.
"Photography is a really good way to get away from the turmoil in your head some days," Mr Nelling said.
"Serving in the military is completely different to a civilian job, in that we tend to worry about ourselves in a 9-to-5 job, but in the service your job is your life ... you look after each other's backs.
"The biggest thing I found trying to reintegrate into society is I felt I could never be a civilian because of the way I was trained."
Mr Nelling did two tours of East Timor in 1999 and 2001 and one tour of Iraq.
He is calling for more veterans to get involved with their local RSL.
"A lot of the younger guys now are screaming out for help and it should be the RSL helping them," he said.
"It's just a matter of our younger veterans being involved and making it what they think it should be, so it can be passed down to the next generation."
Mr Nelling hopes to see 100 members on the membership list by the end of this year.
can be contacted on 0409 803 558.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Correctional Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Newton, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Timor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nelling</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Junction Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSL</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Newton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Dodd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northfield RSL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Nelling, 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dodds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
