<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424262737417005</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-04/eagles-to-make-big-call-on-priddis</url>
  <title>Eagles to make big call on Priddis?</title>
  <content>
Matt Priddis missed last week's win over Brisbane with a sore quad

INTRIGUE continues to surround Brownlow medallist Matt Priddis' selection for West Coast's crunch clash against St Kilda, with Eagles coach Adam Simpson refusing to reveal if the retiring champion will return for Sunday's match.

Priddis has been named on the extended interchange for the Saints game at Etihad Stadium after missing last round's win over the Brisbane Lions.

Interestingly, the veteran hasn't been listed on the Eagles website alongside the other six members of West Coast's extended bench who will play for East Perth if they miss AFL selection.

Apart from confirming Priddis is fit and available, Simpson wouldn't shed any light on the 32-year-old's chances this weekend.

"His quad (injury), he's got through that. He's trained all week, so he'll be available," Simpson said.

"I know there's been lots of questions on it, and I think we've been as open and as transparent as we can be.

"I really hope we continue to respect the man, what decision he made and enjoy and embrace the last five weeks of his career."

More to come.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
