<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424219787743330</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-prison-inmates-think-wife-killer-maged-alharazi-is-mad-court-hears-20170803-gxp4j3.html</url>
  <title>Prisoners think Canberra wife killer Maged Al-Harazi is 'mad', court hears</title>
  <content>
A Yemeni man who stabbed his wife to death in the bedroom of their Gordon home was extremely socially isolated and one of the most vulnerable detainees in Canberra's prison, a court has heard.
Inmates at the Alexander Maconochie Centre did not like killer Maged Mohommed Ahmed Al-Harazi, 36, and thought he was "mad", a forensic psychologist said on Friday.Photo: Supplied
An ACT Supreme Court jury found Al-Harazi, 36, guilty of murdering Sabah Al-Mdwali, 28, in April.
He was charged after  She had suffered 57 stab wounds.Photo: Jeffrey Chan
Al-Harazi maintained his innocence throughout his trial earlier this year, insisting Ms Al-Mdwali's father and brother were responsible for her killing.
and clashed with Ms Al-Mdwali's family members in June. 

The hearing continued in front of Justice Richard Refshauge​ on Friday, when the court heard there was a lack of consensus among staff at Canberra's jail as to whether Al-Harazi suffered a mental illness. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Forensic psychologist Ahu Kocak, who is based at the Alexander Maconochie Centre, spoke of the difficulties ACT Corrective Services staff faced in settling Al-Harazi into the jail. 
Ms Kocak had regular contact with Al-Harazi, particularly when he was initially housed in the crisis support unit, and disagreed with several psychiatrists who found he did not have a severe mental illness. 
"I believe he has a mental illness, so when you're not treated for a mental illness, that makes things very difficult."
She said the process of helping Al-Harazi to adjust to the prison environment was complex and "probably the hardest I've had to deal with in my post-graduate career".
That was mostly due to language barriers and his refusal to engage with staff and other detainees.
Ms Kocak said Al-Harazi was extremely socially isolated and had struggled to integrate, even when he was housed with Arabic-speaking inmates. 
"They would always report there was something wrong with Mr Al-Harazi, that he was crazy. They would distance themselves," she said.
He had thrown hot water over one cell mate and had been the target of violence. He also yelled though the night and talked to himself as he walked around the prison.
"He does stand out, people refer to him as odd."
He also held onto a belief he would soon be released from custody to return to Yemen with his three children.
Al-Harazi was an Arabic-speaker and did not speak English when he arrived in jail and, although his vocabulary had improved slightly, it was not at a level where he could take part in programs or education.
"Compared to other detainees, we don't have significant options in what we can offer him," she said.
Ms Kocak said he did not have family in Australia and had only had one visitor at the jail since he'd been in custody.
The hearing continues on Friday afternoon. Justice Refshauge will likely hand down his sentence next week.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Refshauge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yemen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kocak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Maconochie Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maged Mohommed Ahmed Al-Harazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arabic-speaking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maged Al-Harazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeffrey Chan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al-Harazi</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sabah Al-Mdwali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arabic-speaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yemenis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Corrective Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahu Kocak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Richard Refshauge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Al-Mdwali</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Al-Harazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
