<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424176838069665</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/steve-solomon-ready-for-gold-medalsized-challenge-at-london-world-championships/news-story/6fbf80d023a2daa25374ec861e6f44d9</url>
  <title>'I just felt this energy overwhelm me'</title>
  <content>
STEVE Solomon was in shock about what was happening on his television screen.
The 2012 London Olympic finalist in the 400m was watching the Rio final and
"I was in shock," Solomon explains.
BOLT:
RILEY'S RIDE:
FUTURE FOCUS:
"I was sitting there with my dog and I just felt this energy overwhelm me and I couldn't move.
"Just fathoming how fast 43.03 was. Watching the clock as he was coming down the home straight and thinking this was just outrageous.
"Then you see where Kirani (James) and (LaShawn) Merritt were in relation to him and how he held his composure.
"I'm young and naive and I haven't been around athletics long enough to really put a lot of weighting behind the comment that that may have been the greatest run we've ever seen but that's how it felt to me at the time."
Rather than be daunted by coming up against van Niekerk, Solomon is simply happy to be even having a conversation about it after what has been a tough five years since his London heroics.
Back then he was a nobody who came from nowhere to make the Olympic final after running a personal best 44.97 sec in the semi-finals.
It was one of the great stories for Australia to come out of the Games and Solomon then moved to the US to take up a college scholarship at Stanford University.
That's where things started to fall apart with injury after injury eventually resulting in hamstring surgery after the 2014 Commonwealth Games.
He tried to get back for Rio but missed qualifying by just four one-hundredths of a second.
In June he clocked his fastest time in five years at a meet in California, running 45.19 sec to qualify for the London world championships.
The only three times he'd ever run faster was at the 2012 London Olympics.
"I haven't been at a major championships for a while so I've missed out on the opportunities to race against the big boys," Solomon, 24, says.
"But this is where I feel confident, where I feel comfortable, where I feel hungry for success.
"I set my expectations high. I know the 400 is in a different place than it was four or five years ago when I was last in London but I think I'm a different athlete as well.
"There's no reason why I can't push for a position in the final and then going forward from that I now have a new confidence, that I probably didn't have in the London Olympic final.
"I know that I deserve to be there now and I know I can compete at that level."
He believes van Niekerk's shattering of Michael Johnson's world record, which had been set in 1999, would help others like himself raise their own expectations.
"Michael Johnson was untouchable and no-one had come marginally close to his time of 43.18 and growing up that was the time I had in my head," Solomon said.
"Then to see Wayde in one race just smoke that time like it was just amateur was just unbelievable.
"It took a few days for it to decompress in me and to realise this is where the new standard is, this is where we've got to go and this is the guy who's going to help bringing us all up in the same way that when Michael Johnson was running there were plenty of guys running 43s.
"Wayde has helped set a new benchmark in the 400m, he's inspiring things that a lot of us didn't think were possible so we're attacking the race and attacking training with new thoughts that it's possible now and it's time for other athletes, including myself, to get out there and get it done as well."
The heats of the men's 400m are on tomorrow night (Saturday AEST 7.45am) with the final on Wednesday morning (6.50am AEST).
WORLD AT THEIR FEET
SCOTT GULLAN rates the best Aussie chances in London
■
Women's 100m hurdles
Final - Sunday, August 13, 5.05am AEST
The 2012 Olympic champion is back in the mix after two years out. Seems to be peaking at the right time.
■ DANE BIRD-SMITH
Men's 20km walk
Sunday, August 13, 9.20pm AEST
Bronze medallist from Rio who has declared he's flying.
■ DANI STEVENS
Women's Discus
Final - Monday, August 14, 4.10am AEST
Former world champion who has enjoyed her most consistent season.
■ JARED TALLENT
Men's 50km walk
Sunday, August 13 4.45pm AEST
Rio silver medallist who despite interrupted preparation can never be ruled out.
■ KATHRYN MITCHELL
Women's Javelin
Wednesday, August 9, 4.20am AEST
Olympic finalist who is in the mix of an event which has some stars missing.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanford University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solomon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Niekerk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathryn Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Tallent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RILEY'S RIDE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Gullan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Olympics</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merritt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday AEST 7.45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13, 5.05</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dani Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Bird Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Johnson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WORLD AT THEIR FEET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13 4.45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaShawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solomon, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9, 4.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13, 9.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14, 4.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
