<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424340046829366</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/strong-winds-for-melbourne-blizzards-for-victorian-alps-this-weekend-20170804-gxp9z9.html</url>
  <title>Strong winds for Melbourne, blizzards for Victorian Alps this weekend</title>
  <content>
Victoria is set for more wild weather this weekend after the state recorded its coldest day in nearly 20 years on Thursday. 
Victorians are being urged to secure their properties ahead of strong winds this weekend, and blizzards in Alpine areas.Photo: Karl Gray
The Alpine region in the state's north-east will be hardest hit, with one metre of fresh snowfall, winds of between 90 and 110km/h and very poor visibility from Saturday.
Scott Williams, senior meteorologist at the Bureau of Meteorology's extreme weather desk, said Mt Hotham would probably have the strongest winds and snowfall.Photo: Supplied
"Hotham, Falls Creek, Mt Buller will all be pretty similar with snow amounts, but Hotham just tends to get the strongest winds including the road leading up to the top," he said.
The snowfall would be the biggest of the season, adding to the 75-80 centimetres already at Mt Hotham and Falls Creek.

Melbourne won't be as windy as , but the bureau is tipping gusts of between 80 and 90km/h in bayside areas and elevated parts of the city, mainly on Saturday night and Sunday.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The winds will continue until late Monday in Melbourne and coastal parts of Victoria.
David Baker, deputy chief officer operations (capability) at the State Emergency Service, said the blizzard warning was a "reminder to Victorians that winter is well and truly still with us".
Mr Baker advised people to quickly secure loose items, such as garden items, furniture and trampolines.
He also urged people in the Alpine areas to follow the advice of the mountain skin patrols and the other emergency services, stay tuned to the SES's emergency broadcasts, download the VicEmergency app and check VicRoads websites for road closure notifications.
"Blizzards can pose particularly dangers and we don't want anyone to go missing on the mountains," he said.
Melbourne had its coldest day in almost two decades on Thursday, with the temperature peaking at just 9 degrees.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Emergency Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicEmergency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hotham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Buller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alpine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Hotham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falls Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
