<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424297097155889</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834642/disgrace-australias-emissions-increase-accelerates/?cs=7</url>
  <title>'Disgrace': Australia's emissions increase accelerates</title>
  <content>
Australia's greenhouse gas emissions continue to increase, making the task of future pollution cuts to meet international commitments more difficult, the latest data for the government show.

On a seasonally adjusted quarterly basis, , the National Greenhouse Gas Inventory shows. Labor said the increase was the biggest jump in nine years.
On an annual basis, the country's emissions reached 550.4 million tonnes of carbon-dioxide equivalent, excluding land use changes such as land clearing. That tally was up 1 per cent from a year earlier.
For the March quarter alone, the 138.3 million tonnes - again excluding land use changes - was the most for any quarter since at least 2001-02.
"This is simply a disgrace and a complete failure of policy, a failure the government has no plan to fix," Mark Butler, Labor's environment spokesman, said.
Under the Coalition governments since 2013 emissions had risen 6 per cent compared with a 10 per cent drop in the pollution during the 2007-2013 Labor governments, he said.
Interestingly, the increase in emissions has not come from the electricity sector, the largest single source of pollution. That sector is down 1.9 per cent from a year earlier.
Instead, emissions rose 5.8 per cent from the stationary energy sector excluding electricity, while pollution from industrial processes rose 2.8 per cent and agriculture 2.5 per cent from a year earlier in the March quarter, the data shows.

"There is one test of a climate policy: is pollution down? Under the government's policy framework, pollution keeps going up and up," Amanda McKenzie, chief executive of the Climate Council, said.
"This data is just another alarm bell ringing that the federal government is choosing to ignore - all while Australia's pollution levels soar, driving worsening climate change."
Fairfax Media has sought comment from federal Environment And Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg.
This latest quarterly data comes about four weeks  following freedom of information queries about their overdue release.
Australia is committed to cut 2000-level emissions by 5 per cent by 2020, a target it is likely to reach because of credits earned during the Kyoto Protocol period. The Turnbull government has also signed Australia up to the Paris climate accord, pledging the country will reduce emissions 26-28 per cent by 2030 compared with 2005.
"This dramatic increase is no wonder, given this government has failed to produce any policy to reduce emissions in the transport, electricity, industrial and agriculture sectors," Mr Butler said.
The Turnbull government has deferred a decision on whether it will set up a clean energy target for the power sector - which accounts for about a third of emissions - as recommended by the Finkel review.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Climate Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Greenhouse Gas Inventory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyoto Protocol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Butler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Butler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
