<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424387291470505</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4833336/cavanough-settling-in-for-monstar-challenge/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Cavanough settling in for Monstar challenge</title>
  <content>
WET AND WILD: The Monstar, with Josh Adams aboard, winning the June Stakes (1100m) at Randwick by six lengths on a heavy track. Picture: bradleyphotos.com.au

FORMER Albury-based trainer Brett Cavanough thinks sometimes he might be better off racing his horses well away from the domination of Kris Lees' Newcastle stables.

Now four months into his time based at Scone, Cavanough is coming to grips with the Hunter racing landscape and the towering strength of Lees' and Paul Perry's Newcastle operations.

"With Kris and Paul around, it's very strong racing, especially the numbers they have," Cavanough said. "They have bloody good horses and are good trainers. Paul has historical been a very good trainer and Kris is in white-hot form.

"Sometimes I might be better off putting some more diesel in the truck and driving away from Lees and Perry, I think," he laughed.
But when it comes to The Monstar, Cavanough has little option but to take on two of Lees' best - Le Romain and Invincible Gem -  in the group 2 Missile Stakes (1200 metres) at Randwick on Saturday.

Josh Adams and Brett Cavanough after the June Stakes win. Picture: Racing NSW
"You don't have much choice when you're a 105-rater," he said. "You can't dodge them."
The Monstar won the listed June Stakes at Randwick to give Cavanough his first black-type victory since the move to Scone, where he has 46 boxes left by the departure of Greg Bennett.
The seven-year-old gelding was then a close second in the Civic Stakes and Ramornie Handicap, after which he was ordered to trial following his wayward run. He won that trial at Tamworth and will wear a one-eyed blinker on Saturday to help keep him in line.

Cavanough was hopeful the change and a wet track would put his $9.5 chance in the frame against the likes of $2.15 favourite Le Romain - a group 1 winner on heavy going at Randwick.
"It's a heavy 8 and I think it will end up a Randwick 7, it will be pretty tough," he said on Friday. "The heavier the better for me, it just takes a few out of the equation, and when you're at this level, they are all pretty good.
"He's a quirky horse but if he puts his best foot forward, he's a chance in anything and he might go to the next level.
"He's been up a while so he's got fitness on his side. But Le Romain is a genuine group 1, weight-for-age horse and one of very few from six furlongs to a mile. He's pretty tough. He must be a good horse because Kris is talking Everest and Cox Plate."
As for the move to Scone, Cavanough said it was one he has always wanted to make.
"If you want to play basketball, you go to Harlem, don't you?," he said of relocating to the thoroughbred capital of Australia.

"The Newcastle boys might leave me a few scraps and I'll hang out the back. I'll be happy to live off the scraps of the Newcastle boys. That'll do me."
The Missile Stakes is being billed as a trial for Le Romain's hopes of gaining a slot in the $10 million Everest (1200m), the world's richest turf race, in October.
Cavanough believed a wet track for the inaugural Everest could also put The Monstar in the picture.
"I haven't entertained it at all but if it's a swamp, I bet the phone will start ringing," he said.

Lees, meanwhile, told Racing NSW this week that Le Romain, a three-time group 1 winner, was ready for his first-up assignment.

"He has had two nice trials and has pleased us in everything he has done so far, so I think he is in for a good preparation. He has certainly got some improvement in him off the back of Saturday but he'll still race well," Lees said.
"He normally races on speed but there is a lot of pressure in the race so from barrier eight I'd say he'd be midfield or in the second half.
"There has been some preliminary discussions around The Everest with a couple of parties but it will come down to if they want him and then whoever is first in. Understandably, a few (slot holders) are keeping their powder dry to see how horses come up."
As for $9 chance Invincible Gem, Lees said: "I think she is in for a great preparation too. She mightn't be that well placed here at weight for age but she is ready to go and will revert back to mares company after this so it's a nice stepping stone for her.

"The Golden Pendant is her first aim this spring."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albury-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Adams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June Stakes (1100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Perry's Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harlem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Romain</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Lees' Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramornie Handicap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cavanough</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>16</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June Stakes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monstar</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Cavanough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox Plate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Pendant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Gem</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
