<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424387291470516</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/independent-senator-lucy-gichuhi-reveals-her-brother-was-forced-to-dress-as-a-girl-as-she-warns-of-unintended-consequences-from-samesex-marriage/news-story/bbe810c6b82fc459d9e7be59db53abd5</url>
  <title>Senator's bizarre gay marriage warning</title>
  <content>
INDEPENDENT Senator Lucy Gichuhi has warned of possible "unintended consequences" if Australia rushes into legalising same-sex marriage and called for a respectful discussion on the issue.
In a lengthy statement on marriage equality, the South Australian senator has revealed one of her brothers was forced to wear girl's clothes when they were growing up in rural Kenya.
Senator Gichuhi, , said she had never considered the issue of gay marriage before moving to Australia because she came from a culture where sexuality was not openly discussed.
She said one of her brothers had been dressed in hand-me-down girls' clothing as a young child because their family could not afford new clothes for him.
"As soon as he was old enough to realise what was going on - that he was a boy dressed in
girl's clothes - he became outraged and ran off to live with our cousins next door who
had more boys than girls in their family,'' Senator Gichuhi said.
"He had had enough of it! Poor boy, after him, three more sisters showed up before the next brother arrived.
"At that time, I thought nothing of it. I wonder what my brother would say if we were growing up in Australia today? How would it have played out for him now?"
Senator Gichuhi said Australian politicians should not feel pressured to follow the minority of other countries that had legislated for marriage equality.
Comparing the same-sex marriage debate to the landmark Roe v Wade Supreme Court case which legalised abortion in the United States, Senator Gichuhi said every Australian needed to have a say on the future of marriage laws.
"For those of you, who do not agree with abortion, remember, one woman introduced
abortion in the USA while many millions simply said nothing,'' she said.
"In the current debate every Australian needs to have a say because of the potential of
unforeseen and unintended consequences that could come from this change. It is about the impact on the whole of Australian society."
Federal Liberal MPs and senators will hold an emergency meeting in Canberra after some backbenchers suggested they could cross the floor to vote for marriage equality.
Senator Gichuhi said it would be "unAustralian" to attack people for their views on same-sex marriage.
"If we enter the debate with dignity and respect, I believe that both sides can work out a resolution which will benefit us now and give future generations a solid ground on which to build,'' she said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wade Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Lucy Gichuhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Gichuhi</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
