<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423790291007848</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/michael-hoopers-success-will-depend-on-what-he-does-off-the-field-20170803-gxodfl.html</url>
  <title>Michael Hooper's success will depend on what he does off the field</title>
  <content>
We never get to see the really great acts of captaincy.
They are the arm round a teammate in a hotel room on tour when he is struggling being away from family. Or the times when someone needs to speak up to address a sloppy training session or tell a few blokes who should know better to pull their heads in.

Up Next

Matildas bulldoze Brazil to win Tournament of Nations

01:30

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Plays of the Week

Nail-biting finishes, ripping yorkers and hat-trick heroes, these are the plays of the week.

Frankly, what we see on the paddock is 50 per cent of the job, probably less.
So when we are asked about the captaincy of new Wallabies leader Michael Hooper the sensible answer is: "Ask me in two years." Photo: Daniel Munoz
By then he will have had just about enough time to impose himself on the Wallabies squad.
Forget about his previous captaincy experience. That has been reward for playing well and a probably a shortage of other options.

It has never really been his team until now. If he can transmit his own high personal standards around preparation and conditioning to the rest of the squad and do it with empathy his job is half done.

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

If blokes start making good decisions even when Hooper isn't around then he has had complete success.
These are the legitimate questions to be asked around Hooper's captaincy as it unfolds over the next two years.      
What is not in doubt, however, is his position in the team, even with David Pocock due to return next year.
Where does Pocock fit in upon his return from his well-documented year away from the rigours of Test rugby?
Well, he fits in right beside Hooper in the Wallabies back row, either at No. 6 or No. 8.
And I say that as a solid advocate of a "traditional" back row unit comprising a tall, rugged, lineout-ball winning No. 6, a tall, ball-handling No. 8 and a fast No. 7 who is strong over the ball.
That is not the model that Hooper-Pocock fit. But frankly, no other No. 6/No. 8 in Australia is doing enough to split them.
There are a host of likely lads - Ned Hanigan, Lopeti Timani, Jack Dempsey, Adam Korczyk et al - but none have yet produced enough to suggest Hooper or Pocock will be put in an awkward position next year.
Besides, there is something to be said about picking your best players and fitting the system around them, not the other way round. 
The closest and most relevant model for us to look at here is the recent British and Irish Lions series against the All Blacks.
The Lions finished with a back row combination of Toby Faletau/Sean O'Brien and Sam Warburton, but they did not start the series that way.
Instead, they began the first Test with a "traditional" No. 6, Peter O'Mahony, who is a noted lineout operator.
But they ditched O'Mahony for the second Test and brought in Warburton, and the Lions proceeded to cause the All Blacks problems at ruck time. The quality of ball the All Blacks won for halfback Aaron Smith deteriorated markedly in the second Test, especially after they sacrificed blindside Jerome Kaino following Sonny Bill Williams' red card.
Hooper and Pocock are not like-for-like with O'Brien and Warburton. But the success of the Lions with those two in tandem mirrored the lift the Wallabies got in 2015 from the Hooper-Pocock partnership.
Instinctively, I would always vote for selections that conform to a certain structure - the lineout-winning No. 6 or No. 8  as mentioned earlier. But that supposes everyone in the squad is of the same quality. That is not the state of the current Wallabies.
Although Hooper has captained a poor Waratahs side this year often his personal performances were fine. As for Pocock, all evidence points to him returning from a lengthy absence and quickly regaining excellence.
That only leaves the leadership question for Hooper. He must be his own man, aligned with the coach yet distinct from him, hard on the excuse makers but approachable to the newcomers.
Those are the fine lines he must tread every day and in part explain what makes effective captaincy so difficult.
But the inescapable fact is that the growth of Michael Hooper as a leader and the recovery of the Wallabies over the next two years are but one and the same.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Faletau/Sean O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Dempsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper-Pocock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Mahony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned Hanigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Korczyk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Warburton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerome Kaino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pocock</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pocock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lopeti Timani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warburton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter O'Mahony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
