<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424348636764073</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/girl-dies-after-drinking-boiling-water-through-str/3208884/</url>
  <title>Girl dies after drinking boiling water through straw</title>
  <content>
A FLORIDA girl has died after she was injured months ago on a dare from her cousin to drink boiling water through a straw.

Ki'ari Pope, 8, suffered medical problems since March when she burned her throat and mouth upon performing the dare, the  reported.

The Boynton Beach girl, who had undergone a tracheotomy, reportedly said that she couldn't breathe Sunday night before becoming unresponsive.

She was taken to a local hospital where she was pronounced dead at 12:15 a.m. Monday.

Authorities investigated the March incident, which left Pope deaf and with chronic respiratory issues, as well as at least nine other allegations of abuse or neglect in her life.

The investigation into the dare determined that Pope had been "medically compromised," according to the Palm Beach Post.

Officials said they also plan to probe her death.

"We have opened a child death investigation to examine the circumstances surrounding her death and will deploy a Critical Incident Rapid Response Team to review all interactions this family has had with Florida's child welfare system," said Mike Carroll, secretary of Florida Department of Children and Families.

A was created to raise money for her funeral expenses.

"Due to the fact kiari had a tracheotomy the insurance refuses to pay for funeral arrangements," the GoFundMe said. "We need help assisting with Kiari's funeral and burial arrangements."

This story was originally published on the New York Post and has been reproduced here with permission.

PROFESSIONAL surfer Julian Wilson says he is enjoying married life
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Magistrate says break-ins frustrate community clubs
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOYNTON BEACH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida Department of Children</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palm Beach Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope, 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Critical Incident Rapid Response Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
