<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424382996503089</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/watch-five-great-white-sharks-swim-below-two-paddleboarders/news-story/f1cda81717f29606d87b1a6834866997</url>
  <title>Sharks get paddlers' hearts racing</title>
  <content>
THIS incredible footage shows the moment five great white sharks surrounded two paddle boarders.
The awesome video was filmed by Mark Romanov and Forrest Galante just off a beach in Southern California and shows brave duo, Kelly and Jessica, calmly paddling around the huge predators for several minutes.
Mark and Forrest used a drone to capture the extraordinary moment which was recorded as part of a documentary exploring the relationship between sharks and humans.
Incredibly Kelly and Jessica managed to keep their cool during the encounter despite being surrounded by five of the 2.4m great whites.
"It was a once-in-a-lifetime experience to be so close to Great Whites in their natural habitat," Kelly said.
"At times, the sharks got so close to my paddleboard that I could see their colour, fins, and gills in detail.
"I was so in the moment that I didn't realise how much adrenaline I had until I was out of the water."
Mark Romanov, a wildlife cameraman, said there was no time to be scared of the sharks.
"While out filming, my friend Forrest, who's a wildlife biologist, came up with the idea to ask his wife Jessica and my friend Kelly to paddleboard with the sharks so we could show that the sharks aren't the monsters they are made out to be," he said.
"I honestly didn't even have time to be scared. I've always had an intense fascination with wildlife and my natural curiosity tends to override my sense of fear.
"This experience was awe inspiring and seeing such majestic creatures in their natural state was a once in a lifetime moment. It wasn't until I finished that I noticed my hands and knees were shaking with pure adrenaline.
"We made sure to never approach or harass the sharks, only viewing them when they cruised by the paddleboards."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Romanov</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forrest Galante</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forrest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
