<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424340046829301</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/tv-shows/wet-hot-american-summer-ten-years-later-still-has-the-magic-touch/news-story/bf7977b970a2ea2cbcbf4952310c4d12</url>
  <title>Wet Hot American Summer: Ten Years Later still has the magic touch</title>
  <content>
Wet Hot American Summer: 10 years later trailer
2:58

See what happens to your favourite campers and counsellors ten years after the original Wet Hot American Summer.

August 3rd 2017
a day ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/Movies/

Could Katie and Coop finally make it?

Share

WHEN Wet Hot American Summer first came in 2001, it was slammed.
Fair enough. It was super weird and the humour wasn't exactly the witty repartee of Frasier. Then something happened. In the 16 years since its release, Wet Hot American Summer became a cult hit, loved by fans that saw the smart satire beyond the surface level of its seemingly lowbrow and juvenile humour.
It helped that the movie featured a cast of then-little known stars who went to onto to be big deals - Amy Poehler, Bradley Cooper and Elizabeth Banks among them - as their new fans discovered their back catalogue.
It became enough of a hit that Netflix commissioned a prequel series from creators Michael Showalter and David Wain, Wet Hot American Summer: First Day of Camp in 2015. Two years after that, we finally have the sequel we were promised in a scene at the end of the 2001 film.
Enter, Wet Hot American Summer: Ten Years Later.
The Camp Firewood kids are back, now in their mid- and late-twenties (of course the joke is that the actors are now in their 40s, some are pushing 50). The year is 1991 and the references to that era are copious (Slackers! Rollerblades! Laura San Giacomo!).

Welcome back, kids.Source:Supplied
All the campers are back with the exception of Bradley Cooper who has been replaced by Adam Scott as Ben (Cooper had a scheduling conflict and the series explains his changed appearance with a "nose job"). Many of the extended cast introduced in the recent prequel series, including Josh Charles, Kristen Wiig, Jason Schwartzman and Chris Pine, also return for another round of hijinks.
Fresh to this instalment is camp couple Mark (Mark Feuerstein) and Claire (Sarah Burns) who are injected into the canon as if they've been there the whole time - flashbacks to the original 2001 film with the pair obviously CGI-ed in are played for jokes.
The overall story has revolves saving the camp from nuclear destruction at the hands of a vast government conspiracy perpetuated by Ronald Reagan and George Bush snr. (Showalter's mad Reagan impression returns with a vengeance) but it's the subplots that bring the funny.

The original Wet Hot American Summer was one of the first glimpses into Amy Poehler's comedic genius.Source:Supplied
Coop's (Showalter) pining for Katie (Marguerite Moreau) may finally pay dividends, though there are, of course, complications. Andy (Paul Rudd) sparks a "King of the Camp" rivalry with cool kid Deegs (Skyler Gisando), essentially a younger version of himself while Victor may finally lose his virginity, and his perm.
Ben and McKinley (Michael Ian Black) have a new baby daughter and a new too-perfect nanny (Alyssa Milano) who McKinley suspects is a homicidal maniac. Drama queen Susie (Poehler) is now a celebrity "producing/executive producing" her own movie and brings along her co-star (Jai Courtney) to the reunion. Meanwhile, JJ is caught in a love triangle with Claire and Mark.
There's a wistful nostalgia that runs through every episode, inevitable in a series based around a reunion but it manages to do it without rampant sentimentality.
The two Netflix series never pushed it as far as the movie that kicked it off - there are no insane heroin binges - but Wet Hot American Summer: Ten Years Later has maintained its delicious weirdness. This is a world where no one bats an eyelash at a talking can of vegetables. Yep, totes norm.
Every actor looks like they're having a wildly fun time making this and that boisterous spirit carries through every scene. Each 25-minute episode passes by in a flash - that's how engrossed you are, jumping in Camp Firewood's lake headfirst, even if the last episode is a bit of a fizzer.
Wet Hot American Summer: Ten Years Later knows what it is and it embraces it wholeheartedly with every meta reference and bizarre inside joke. And that is its genius.
Wet Hot American Summer: Ten Years Later is available to stream on Netflix from 5pm AEST today.
Continue the conversation on Twitter with .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Day of Camp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poehler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Feuerstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Poehler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura San Giacomo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronald Reagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Cooper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ian Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristen Wiig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wet Hot American Summer</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showalter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Showalter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jai Courtney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King of the Camp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deegs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hot American Summer: 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Schwartzman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyssa Milano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Firewood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marguerite Moreau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hot American Summer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skyler Gisando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Years Later</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CGI-ed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Wain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Banks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frasier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
