<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424391586437943</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/7000-credit-card-fraud-was-revenge-for-domestic-vi/3208894/</url>
  <title>$7000 credit card fraud was 'revenge' for domestic violence against mum</title>
  <content>
A TEENAGER has told a court she used a credit card belonging to her mother's partner, spending almost $7000, in revenge for alleged acts of domestic violence.
The 19-year-old Maroochydore woman pleaded guilty in Maroochydore Magistrates Court yesterday to fraud.
She cannot be named to protect the identity of her mother, who has domestic violence orders against the man.
The court heard the woman used the man's credit cards a total of 212 times between May 2016 and June 2017, racking up $6997.53 in bills for goods and services including make-up, clothing, food and Uber rides.
The man cancelled his credit card three times after seeing the fraudulent transactions, but each time a new card arrived the woman took down the details.
In June, the man reported the matter to police, suspecting the teenager.
In an interview with police, the woman said the man had subjected her mother to domestic abuse.
Westpac had not compensated the man, and he sought full restitution of the money spent.
The woman had no criminal history, and the court heard she was seeking help for anxiety and depression.
The man is facing domestic violence-related charges.
Magistrate Rod Madsen told the woman she was lucky she was caught before the spending exceeded $10,000, or she could have faced a prison sentence for the "foolish" crime.
Mr Madsen said a domestic violence situation was not an excuse to break the law.
"You might have thought two wrongs make a right, but it doesn't," he said.
"Just let the police do their job... it certainly hasn't helped."
He sentenced the woman to a year on probation and ordered restitution be paid in full.
PROFESSIONAL surfer Julian Wilson says he is enjoying married life
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Magistrate says break-ins frustrate community clubs
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Madsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Rod Madsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
