<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424340046829308</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/ward-at-soontobeclosed-repatriation-hospital-in-adelaide-could-be-viable-option-to-house-remaining-oakden-patients/news-story/aa328c91737884adaaf5783a9e88968a</url>
  <title>Repat ward 'could house Oakden patients'</title>
  <content>
WARD 18 at the soon-to-be-closed Repatriation General Hospital could be a viable option to house the 12 patients left at the disgraced Oakden mental health facility, the state's chief psychiatrist told a meeting today.
Dr Aaron Groves, , told a parliamentary committee that with modifications, Ward 18, was potentially suitable for the remaining patients at the facility.
"(There are) benefits for and against Ward 18 ... and there are other facilities being considered," Dr Groves said.
While the State Government immediately closed Oakden's Makk and McLeay wards, the Clements will remain open for up to three years.
Dr Groves went on to say that it would be "bad" if Oakden was "still open and functioning as it is now" in two years time.
Earlier this year, his scathing report exposed systematic abuse and mistreatment at the state-run Oakden facility.
The meeting also heard that due to Oakden's closure, since January, there are a total of eight "Tier 7", or severe dementia patients, dispersed throughout general mental health wards in the state despite the fact these people need specialist care.
Speaking after the meeting, Opposition health spokesman Stephen Wade said the State Government was "not being aggressive enough in exploring all options" for those patients.
"It's months since Oakden closed and we still have no clear way forward for the future services for these clients," he said.
"We now know there is eight people with severe dementia who are being held in inappropriate facilities - that's not good for them and also not good for the mental health system overall."
Mr Wade urged the State Government to consider Ward 18 as an option.
"For the government to say this isn't an option that can even be considered is very inappropriate," he said.
"To keep the Clements facility (at Oakden) open for at least two to three years is extremely bad news for the people in Clements."
The Repatriation General Hospital is due to close by November.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakden</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Groves</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WARD 18</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tier 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLeay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Repatriation General Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakden's Makk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clement</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Aaron Groves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
