<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424563385132137</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/morgan-stanley-sees-the-aussie-dollar-hitting-84-cents-over-the-coming-weeks-2017-8</url>
  <title>Morgan Stanley sees the Aussie dollar hitting 84 cents 'over the coming weeks'</title>
  <content>
Having surged 10% from early May to late July, the price action in the AUD/USD has looked a little iffy recently, seeing the the pair drop back below the 80 cent level this week.

The modest pullback, seen in the daily chart below, has more than a few traders questioning whether the Aussie's rally has done its dash.

However, while some think that a more pronounced pullback or a period of , Morgan Stanley's FX strategy team thinks that there's a bit more upside to come for the Aussie, at least in the short-term.

Here's its assessment:

We remain tactically bullish on AUD, with its high carry status and continued USD weakness likely to propel AUD/USD to 0.84 over the coming weeks. The RBA highlighted the disinflationary and growth-negative impact of AUD appreciation in its statement though the market continues to look through these dovish leanings.

84 cents in just a few weeks, representing a 5.5% gain from it's current trading level of .7960 should Morgan Stanley's call be on the money.

While the bank is bullish on the Aussie near-term, it remains a staunch bear longer-term, suggesting that Australia will be vulnerable to issues relating to its housing market and its sensitivity to global funding costs.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley's FX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD/USD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
