<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423953499767001</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/property-council-says-community-must-rally-as-stem-precinct-push-heats-up/news-story/6d85803058b960dd6064ec88530307fc</url>
  <title>STEM precinct push hotting up</title>
  <content>
THE influential Property Council of Australia has thrown its weight behind a $400 million STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Maths) Centre in the Hobart CBD.
Executive director Brian Wightman said the Tasmanian division was keen to support investment and development underpinned by the education sector.
"STEM is a development of both State and national significance, which requires the support of all Tasmanians," Mr Wightman said.
"The project will not only deliver investment for Hobart, it will drive increased research and training opportunities statewide with nodes at Inveresk and West Park key elements of the University's proposed Tasmanian Innovation Network.
"Tasmania must continue to deliver positive educational investment which encourages our young people to aspire to secure the highly skilled jobs which will be required as the result of a transitioning economy."
The concept, supported by Infrastructure Australia, last week won the backing of local councils and 11 local mayors as the No. 1 project for Southern Tasmania at the Local Government of Tasmania annual conference.
Hobart City Council is expected to discuss the proposal again next week.

The State Government has shown strong interest in STEM and says it is advanced in its discussion with the Federal Government regrading a City Deal.
And key Tasmanian Federal figures, including senators Eric Abetz and Jonathon Duniam, have come out in strong support of the project, alongside the likes of Denison MP Andrew Wilkie, who say it would likely form the linchpin of a City Deal.
UTAS Vice-chancellor Peter Rathjen says STEM can proceed regardless of whether a City Deal eventuates.

Mr Wightman said from here it was vital there was a strong and cohesive approach across all levels of Government, the opposition, and industry leaders.
The community must be made aware of the transformative potential of the development and what it could mean for educational outcomes, economic growth and the overall future of the state, he said.
"... the community must remain cognisant of the many economic and social challenges which place a handbrake on growth in our State," he said.
"With the lowest weekly full-time wages in the country, health levels that historically lag the nation, and in a State with a dispersed regional population, we also have the lowest percentage of people with a bachelor's degree in the country, which is a major impediment to improving on this situation.
"When you combine these challenges, it is little wonder that Tasmania needs to receive $1.88 in GST for every $1 collected.
"A goal of continuous economic growth will only eventuate in Tasmania through investment in education."
He said he hoped the Property Council played a significant role in leading the community conversation over the Launceston City Deal, and he hoped it could plan a similar role in Hobart.
"Now is the time for all stakeholders to join with the southern councils and the Property Council in doing the same to help secure a Hobart City Deal around the STEM project," he said.
Federal Assistant Minister for Cities Angus Taylor has said the one thing holding back Hobart from a City Deal was local government support.
Given the strong backing of local councils, a spokesman for the Minister said an announcement was expected soon.

Land deals, expansions key features of education landscape

IT is early days and, at this point, little more than speculation, but it is fair to say some real estate agents would be licking their lips at the prospect of putting slabs of UTAS land on the market.

If a STEM Centre is approved - and at this point that is a reasonably big "if" - the university council would then be forced to make a decision as to whether it reinvests more than $500 million into ageing buildings at Sandy Bay, or contemplates a roots and branch shift to the city.

Any shift or sale comes amid a series of significant UTAS property deals.

Singaporean developer Fragrance Group has recently added the UTAS conservatorium of music to its expanding portfolio of prime Hobart real estate.

In June the company settled on the 1960 building, which overlooks St Davids Park, for $13.37 million.

UTAS bought the half hectare site in 1991 for $2.6 million.

The site includes the main conservatorium building on Sandy Bay Rd, a warehouse, three brick buildings on Heathfield Avenue, three heritage-listed conjoined cottages on Wilmot St and a communications tower.

UTAS will lease the conservatorium for the next three years until the $96 million Hedberg performing arts centre, near the Theatre Royal, is completed.

In 2015 UTAS paid $9.8 million for the former Goodyear site on the corner of Bathurst and Argyle St and there is market speculation that UTAS is close to buying the headquarters of the Australian Red Cross at 40-42 Melville St for $6-$8 million.

Red Cross state manager Russell Penman said: "I can tell you discussions are happening but there has been no finalisation but I would expect an announcement within a month."

LJ Hooker managing director Mark Devine said the Sandy Bay land would provide a great opportunity but may be hampered by its present zoning.

He said some of the existing buildings would offer appeal for conversion or redevelopment to alternate uses.

"The most obvious being residential and given the current demand and anticipated demand for housing stock in coming years this would provide a great opportunity for developers," he said.

"Its proximity to the Hutchins School may provide scope for Hutchins to continue with educational activities and planned growth."

He said the elevated land may be protected as public open space.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argyle St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cities Angus Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Innovation Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Federal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singaporeans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inveresk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTAS Vice-chancellor Peter Rathjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston City Deal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hedberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heathfield Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Penman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilmot St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denison MP Andrew Wilkie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Assistant Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Davids Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Bay Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodyear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTAS</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Duniam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hutchins School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melville St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infrastructure Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ Hooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart City Deal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Red Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hutchins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fragrance Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Royal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STEM Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Devine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Wightman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wightman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Deal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
