<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424511845523792</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/smh-letters/education-overhaul-in-order-but-some-restraint-needed-20170804-gxpjsf.html</url>
  <title>Education overhaul in order but some restraint needed</title>
  <content>
Greg Whitby's analysis into the value of the HSC is forthright and insightful. (" 'HSC had its day': leading educator calls for overhaul", August 4). It is paramount that questions are raised and systems restructured to challenge changing needs and opportunities for our students. The International Baccalaureate is offered as an alternative, but caution is needed.
Early this decade Britain, too, realised a need for change and rushed into an alternative English Baccalaureate to appease all concerned interest groups (students seemingly last in interest). The strength of the International version is in its breadth and depth of subject with strong international recognition. Students become engaged and look beyond to the future. The English Baccalaureate falters into rules, regulations and more testing. 
The necessity to overhaul the current system is imperative to ensure the NSW system remains respected and internationally well recognised. But rushed change or change to merely appease certain powerful interest groups wreaks havoc on an already overworked and stressed educational community. The change must be considered, directed at children's (and the wider community's) needs for the future and ensuring that staff are trained and in numbers (language and maths, for example) to accommodate. 
Mr Whitby has proposed an adequate solution, with funding, additional consultation and adequate teacher training it could happen. But let us not travel the British route and split the educational communities into rival baccalaureates. Our children are too important. 
Janice Creenaune Austinmer
 

Well done, Andrew Dostine and Pam Timms (Letters, August 4). The trouble with the current HSC paradigm that it tempts the strangulation of "competitivism" to squash creativity and character!  In real education, what can be more important than these two?
 
Rosalind Winterton  Maroubra
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosalind Winterton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Baccalaureate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Whitby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Baccalaureate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroubra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janice Creenaune Austinmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pam Timms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Dostine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
