<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424511845523856</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/lost-sponsorship-carlton-blues-hope-for-a-share-of-2-million-owed-by-careerone-20170804-gxpg34.html</url>
  <title>Lost sponsorship: Carlton Blues hope for a share of $2 million owed by CareerOne</title>
  <content>
Carlton are still hopeful they can recoup at least part of the almost $2 million they are owed from former co-major sponsor CareerOne.
As reported by Fairfax Media, administrators of collapsed education company Acquire Learning, the parent company of CareerOne, have sold its single biggest asset - the online job search site - to a media group.Photo: Josh Robenstone
Cor Cordis revealed it had sold Acquire's 90 per cent stake in CareerOne for an undisclosed sum to Octomedia. Creditors will discover the sum at the next creditors meeting in September.
It's understood CareerOne, under its former ownership, had promised to honour the $1,923,000 it owed the Blues - but that has yet to eventuate. The club will wait until the creditors meeting to get a clearer picture of where it stands.
CareerOne had been in the third year of a three-year deal with the Blues worth about $4.5 million overall.
Acquire Learning had been one of several vocational training companies that had profited from a Commonwealth-backed loan scheme that the government has since cracked down on.
The Blues were able to ease the financial strain when Carlton United Brewery, through its Mercury Hard Cider product, inked a seven-year contract to be their shorts sponsor and "official beer and cider partners".
The Blues are hunting for a new co-major sponsor but delivered encouraging news last week when car manufacturer Hyundai extended its multi-million-dollar partnership until 2022. Hyundai signed its initial six-year deal with the club in 1995 - the year the Blues enjoyed their last premiership.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercury Hard Cider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cor Cordis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Octomedia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Robenstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acquire's  90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CareerOne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acquire Learning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton United Brewery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
