<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424559090164801</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Broker</source>
  <url>http://www.brokernews.com.au/news/breaking-news/mfaa-appoints-chairman-elect-239574.aspx</url>
  <title>MFAA appoints chairman elect</title>
  <content>
The Mortgage & Finance Association of Australia () announced today that its Board has appointed director Donna Beazley to the position of Chairman-Elect, after Chairman Cynthia Grisbrook informed the Board that she would not stand for re-election this year.
Ms Beazley, who has more than 25 years' experience in the finance industry, has served as an  director since 2014. She will be officially appointed Chairman and assume this role at the 's Annual General Meeting in November 2017.
A Credit Advisor at Oxygen Home Loans, Ms Beazley has been heavily involved with the  - and as an industry leader - since becoming a mortgage broker more than 12 years ago. She served as a member of the 's NSW/ACT State Forums for seven years, including two years as President, before being elected as a  director.
Ms Beazley said she was looking forward to taking on the role as the industry continues to grow.

"The  now represents more than 13,000 brilliant, hard-working professionals. As a  member of more than ten years and a director since 2014, I believe we now have a great mix of experience and expertise on the Board, and a stable and effective executive team. I couldn't be happier with the leadership of the  in 2017," Ms Beazley said.
"Our industry is growing in both volume and share and as our industry evolves, we will need to continue to advocate strongly and raise the bar with regards to customer outcomes, professional standards and education for members.
"It's a critical time for the industry. As the finance broking industry matures, we will continue to attract the attention of regulators and other stakeholders. The  will maintain its focus on advocacy at all levels of government as we work through regulatory reviews and the formation of policy that affects our members."
Ms Grisbrook said she was proud of what the  had achieved during her time on the  Board - a period that was marked by challenges to the industry and the broking model.
"I am pleased with what we've been able to achieve in terms of advocacy for members. The Board and I have focused heavily on ensuring that the industry voice is heard during a period in which the broking model has been under intense scrutiny," Ms Grisbrook said.
"Following a period of significant change and disruption for the industry, I believe we have the right leadership in place to take the  to its next phase and so now is the time for me to step down.
"I am very confident that Donna is an excellent choice to be Chairman of the . She has proven herself extremely capable on different committees and forums and she is a passionate advocate for the industry and for our members. She has the experience and the drive to provide exceptional leadership for the Board. I wish her all the very best in her new role."

 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Grisbrook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Beazley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman-Elect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annual General Meeting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFAA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Cynthia Grisbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Association of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Advisor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Beazley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW/ACT State Forums</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxygen Home Loans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
