<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423906255126167</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/what-is-a-hydrogen-sulphide-bomb/8774240</url>
  <title>Sydney terror plot: What is hydrogen sulphide, and how could it be used in an attack?</title>
  <content>
The men accused of planning one of the most "sophisticated" terror plots attempted on Australian soil  part of their attack.
But how would the "rotten egg gas" be used in an attack - and how deadly would it be?
Professor Greg Barton, a counter-terrorism expert at Deakin University, explains what you need to know.
What is hydrogen sulphide?

It's a colourless, flammable gas - and you've almost definitely smelled it before.
Hydrogen sulphide, or H2S, is to thank for the rotten-egg odour that's produced as organic materials decay.
Our bodies create it as we digest food, and it's also a by-product of some industrial and manufacturing processes, like mining.
"At low concentration, it's nothing more than an irritant," Professor Barton says.
But being exposed to levels any higher than what our bodies naturally produce can be fatal.
What does it do to the body?

Exposure to H2S happens most often through inhalation.
While the foul odour is noticeable at first, H2S quickly deadens the sense of smell, giving the false impression the gas has dispersed.
"Rotten egg gas sounds innocent, but it can be lethal," Professor Barton says.
Just like carbon monoxide and hydrogen cyanide, H2S inhibits cellular respiration and uptake of oxygen.
Symptoms include headaches, eye and skin irritation, shortness of breath and nausea - and they get worse the higher the level of exposure.
The gas can go on to overcome the victim.
"It occurs naturally in mining operations - people have been knocked unconscious and died," Professor Barton says.
Would H2S be used to attack a plane?

"Hydrogen sulphide is one of those things you can produce yourself, and in a significant quantity it can be very dangerous," Professor Barton explains.
Airport scanners don't pick up gases, so hypothetically H2S could be smuggled on board a plane.
However, Professor Barton says it's unlikely H2S would be used to attack a plane.
"Releasing hydrogen sulphide in an aircraft cabin wouldn't render everyone unconscious," he explains.
"There simply wouldn't be enough of the gas.
"Perhaps that aspect of the plan - and we must keep in mind that the device was not built - may have been intended for release on a bus or a train, or in a public space in Sydney."
How deadly would an attack be?

Professor Barton says this is a purely speculative question.
If the gas had been released in a public space, he says the effect would be similar to "being sprayed in the face with a can of Mace".
"But perhaps used in conjunction with another means of attack, it would have created fear and panic," Professor Barton says.
The AFP says the alleged attackers had precursor chemicals and some components for the hydrogen sulphide device.
But the suspects had no concrete plans for where and when to unleash the gas, police say.
"There was no evidence this device was completed," Professor Barton says - echoing comments from the AFP boss.
Has H2S been used in terrorist attacks before?

Not often.
Professor Barton says the main obstacle to using gas in terror attacks is "how you weaponise it, and how you disperse it".
He says a high degree of planning and experimentation is needed to make such an attack a feasible threat.
"For example, the sarin gas attack on the Tokyo subway," he says, referring to a 1995 attack that killed 12 people and injured 50 others during the city's morning rush hour.
The attack is regarded as the first-ever use of a weapon of mass destruction in an act of terrorism
The cult had prepared for the attack at a remote sheep station it owned in Western Australia.
"They were killing sheep, trying to work out how the chemicals disperse," Professor Barton says.
"They were caught panicked by police closing in. They took a plastic bag, filled it with sarin, and poked holes in it to release it."
Professor Barton says there is no evidence the Sydney suspects were anywhere near an actual gas attack.
"And hydrogen is not nearly as potent as sarin," he adds.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H2S</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Greg Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Barton</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
