<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424516140491197</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/photos-co-living-startup-common-expansion-2017-7</url>
  <title>Inside the 'co-living' spaces where millennials pay over $1,765 a month for maid service and instant friends</title>
  <content>
If you've ever searched for an apartment on Craigslist,  is coming for you.

Founded in 2015, the shared-housing startup offers fully furnished apartments across New York, the Bay Area, Chicago, and Washington, DC. Common eliminates the hassle of finding an apartment and dealing with landlords.

Residents, or "members," can join these communities and instantly tap into amenities like free internet, maid service, and instant friends. But such convenience doesn't come cheap. Monthly rent at Common ranges from $A1,670 to $A3,278 depending on the location and type of room.

The market for communal living, or "co-living," spaces is quickly crowding. Companies like Open Door, , and WeLive, a subsidiary of co-working giant WeWork,  as young people continue moving to high-priced urban areas.

In the last month, Common revealed it's adding properties in Chicago, Queens, and Oakland to its growing real-estate portfolio. Take a look inside two of its new residences to see what co-living is like.

Common

The new property was announced on July 26 and opens in August.

Common

Common offers a standard 12-month lease, as well as a six-month option for more flexibility.

Common

Brad Hargreaves, founder and CEO of Common, wants the design of the company's homes to encourage spontaneous connections between members.

When the serial entrepreneur set out to build Common, he visited dozens of housing arrangements -- from hacker houses in the Bay Area to a desert commune in Arizona. He studied the pain points and cherry-picked the details he liked for Common's floor layouts.

'A lot of what we're trying to do is rethink the layout of buildings as a whole to adapt for community and to keep the benefit of living with others,' Hargreaves told Business Insider.

Common

The new home welcomed its first tenants in July. Rent starts at $A1,670 a month.

Common

Since launching in October 2015, Common hasn't been able to keep up with demand.

The startup, which currently operates more than 10 houses across four popular US cities, wants to expand from 650 bedrooms by the end of the year to 1,500 rooms in 2018. It already receives between 500 and 700 applications from eager renters each week.

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigslist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arizona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WeLive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Common</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hargreaves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay Area</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Open Doors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WeWork</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Hargreaves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
