<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423992154473085</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/business/bhps-600m-spend-on-olympic-dam-to-lay-the-foundation-for-longterm-growth/news-story/59bf77b7ad2ae7aaabc5c06d9017e8ad</url>
  <title>BHP's $600m spend on Olympic Dam</title>
  <content>
MINING giant BHP will invest $600 million at its Olympic Dam operations this financial year - the most significant outlay the company has ever made in South Australia.
The expenditure will be spread across three key areas and involve the largest ever planned shutdown at the copper, uranium and gold mine, asset president Jacqui McGill says.
"These investments - in our underground infrastructure and above-ground processing operations - will help us build the foundations for long-term, safe, stable and sustainable growth at Olympic Dam," she told attendees at an AmCham lunch in Adelaide today.
"The investment will ensure the operation is more modern, reliable and can support processing of additional tonnes in coming financial years."
About $240 million will help underpin further underground development in the existing northern mine area footprint, with a similar amount going towards a range of infrastructure projects, including a major smelter upgrade that will start in a fortnight.
Ms McGill said the smelter campaign was the single most important aspect of the Olympic Dam investment plan this year.
it will involve a rebuild of the electric slag furnace, the flash furnace and the electro static precipitator.
"Extensive preparation work for the shut has been underway for a number of months and at the peak of construction, we'll have 1300 contractors on-site working around the clock to help us dismantle, rebuild and upgrade all major components of the smelter," Ms McGill said.
"While the rolling shutdown across surface operations starts in late August, all up the maintenance campaign will run for more than 100 days and we'll be maximising this planned downtime by also undertaking important maintenance and upgrade work on our refinery.
"We are taking the time to get this right, to give Olympic Dam greater stability and capacity and reduce the frequency of future smelter maintenance shutdowns."
As a result of the upgrade, a further fall in copper production (to 150,000 tonnes) is expected this financial year. However, the resultant improved operational performance will underpin an expected increase in copper production to about 215,000 tonnes in 2019 and 280,000 tonnes in 2022.
Mr McGill said targeted mining techniques would also result in an increase in the percentage of copper in every tonne of dirt moved, and that heap leach technology might enable BHP to expand Olympic Dam production to more than 450,000 tonnes a year.
The remaining $120 million will support an underground expansion into the high-grade southern mine area - a previously untouched part of the ore body and the cornerstone of BHP's growth strategy at Olympic Dam.
To support the additional work, Ms McGill said BHP was boosting numbers in its Olympic Dam squad. Presently, more than 3000 workers are employed at the site.
"I'm proud that in the last 12 months, our recruitment of new female employees to join our team has increased by 20 per cent," she said.
Through natural attrition, as well as the support of current and future growth projects, Olympic Dam expects to continue to have a rolling requirement for about 250 roles at any one time.
Olympic Dam has 49 projects in execution this financial year - more than any other BHP operation in Australia.
In February,  because of power outages at Olympic Dam, most notably the September 28 statewide blackout.
A recent production update showed copper production at Olympic Dam during the 2017 financial year decreased by 18 per cent year-on-year to 166,000 tonnes, largely because of the outages.
"While much has been said about the impacts to Olympic Dam that were outside our control such as electricity issues, we should highlight that in FY17 we also began a program of work to invest in our infrastructure and to lay the foundations needed to support our long-term growth objectives," Ms McGill said.
luke.griffiths@news.com.au
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP's $600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AmCham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Dam</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>21</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui McGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McGill</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
