<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424511845523821</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/saturday-best-with-ray-hickson-and-mike-fraser-royal-randwick/news-story/870924a57a807c0eb71f1ef8bcd70710</url>
  <title>Saturday Best with Ray and Mike</title>
  <content>
THE Daily Telegraph's Ray Hickson and Sky Thoroughbred Central's form expert Mike Fraser analyse the nine-race card at Royal Randwick.
RACE WATCH:
HOT TIPS:
INSIDE MAIL: R1 (11.50am): WALKING2HELP.COM.AU HCP (1200m)
Fraser: Looks a very strong race. Brave Song has made strong improvement both runs this prep and was a very stylish winner at Canterbury. He's by one of the best wet-trackers we've seen and it holds him in good stead to run well. Wild Heart has made improvement all three starts and was sound in a good race last start. Addictive Nature is a bit under the odds but no knock on him. Had no peace in a line of four leaders and battled on really well. Funoon closed off strongly at Wyong and the extra 200m and bigger track suits.
Hickson: I liked the way Addictive Nature got away from them after the early pressure on debut. He should be able to control his own destiny and if he handles the ground, he'll be hard to beat. Wild Heart doesn't have to improve a lot and has the blinkers on. Solar Patch is hard to line up, didn't beat anything at Gosford but beat them easily. The Mighty Fed is proven in the wet at Randwick and has knocked off a couple of handy horses in his time.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Brave Song $4-$3.20 ($1,000 @ $4, $300 @ $4, $1,050 @ $3.60, $1,000 @ $3.20, $500 @ $3.20), Addictive Nature $2.30-$2.40 ($600 @ $2.30)R2 (12.30pm): #THERACES HCP (1800m)
Fraser: La Chica Bella has been sound all four runs this prep. The extra 200m looks well within her grasp as she'll be running first or second without any pressure. Diapason hasn't missed a place and I liked how she kept grinding last start when back to a mile. She'll have more ping in her sprint out to 1800m. Shanakee has some nice 2100m form and her sectionals last time were quite good. Long Time Ago was beaten favourite last week but is likely to get control.
Hickson: I've been on Diapason recently and I'd be upset if she won without me. I think she wants a bit of cover and she'll get it this time, and if she's not at the end of her prep she gets her chance. Labdien would like the track to improve a bit but she was never in it last week from a wide gate and this is more suitable. La Chica Bella will give a good sight and Wahng Wah is a bit of a tease, but she always runs on and could blouse them.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Diapason $4.80 unchanged ($980 @ $4.80, $200 @ $4.80)R3 (1.05pm): CINDY SULLIVAN MEMORIAL (1400m)
Fraser: Dorf Star is ready to perform, he's had three runs back and had no luck at all in any of them. He's a 1400m winner and won fourth-up last prep. Dane Thunder has been luckless in four of his six runs in Melbourne. Wet form is quite sound. King Darci was awesome first-up and might have been slightly flat last time. Significant jockey change and has the pace to lead. Francesco was a tough effort last start and a soft track is a big bonus.
Hickson: I'm a little keen on King Darci, I think it's an ideal race. He can roll forward under his own steam instead of being dug up like last time. Has to go close. Imperator Augustus is a proven wet tracker who will be on the pace and is racing very well. Francesco is close to a win and was sound behind an in-form horse last start. Sonic Swish was too bad to be true first-up and wouldn't surprise to see him improve.R4 (1.40pm): TAB HIGHWAY (1400m)
Fraser: Care To Think has been on the improve this prep and was strong through the line at Doomben. No heavy form but if he can sit three or four wide with cover he can peel into the best part of the track. Makfi Lass has improved at her last two starts and her closing sectionals were good at Scone. Super Star Bob is in the mix, he's fitter and won second-up last prep over Care To Think. Gitan is suited getting back to 1400m and has some good wet-track form.
Hickson: Gitan's two runs since a break have been excellent, he handles the wet and the form around his last run is good. He'll be on the pace and will be hard to beat. Scared of Care To Think, if the rain didn't come on Thursday I'd have him on top with confidence. The track worries me but on form he's the horse to beat. Puzzling Wonder is a bit underrated and his last Highway run was very handy. If Super Star Bob handles the wet, he's right in it as well.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Gitan $7 unchanged ($700 @ $7)R5 (2.15pm): JOHN & DENISE COBCROFT HCP (2400m)
Fraser: Sayed maps quite nicely and seems to be going really well. He's ticking over nicely with a trial since his last win and he's handled the wet OK. Life O'Brien was given no peace up on the pace last start and gets back onto a soft track, he's one of the two best wet trackers in the race. Go Benny has hit the line quite nicely at his last five starts and the conditions are to his liking. Ashlee Marie is more than likely going to lead and all her form is on soft tracks.
Hickson: With Sayed as well. He does have a heavy track win overseas and he's been racing in great form this preparation. The form around him is pretty good too and he looks the horse to beat. Get On The Grange was game in the Grafton Cup but only has to run up to his fourth behind Collateral on the heavy three starts back. Life O'Brien was huge last week and he should get a sit this time. Ashlee Marie is proven in the wet and can give a sight.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Sayed $2.80-$2.70 ($500 @ $2.80, $200 @ $2.80)R6 (2.50pm): JOCKEY CELEBRATION DAY HCP (1600m)
Fraser: Invincible Knight has been hitting the line strongly all preparation. Was forced to make a long run last start and had the race in his keeping but was bloused late. Handles the wet and is ready to peak. Admiral Jello had way too much to do first-up in the same race. Small query about the wet with him. Steyne was up in grade in that same race where he didn't have much luck so has to be in the mix. Dubaiinstyle is fitter and is an accomplished wet-tracker so could jump out of the ground.
Hickson: I loved Admiral Jello's first-up run and he finishes a length or two closer had he got out earlier. His mother won a Group 3 on a heavy 10 so there's a chance he'll handle it and if he does he'll be hard to beat. Invincible Knight is having a fantastic preparation. If he gets the last look at them he might well get the cash. Zayam will bounce back on a wet track and can be competitive. So Willie will probably be finishing in the first four somewhere again.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Invincible Knight $3.10-$3.20, Steyne $4.40-$4.60- $4.40 ($750 @ $4.60, $500 @ $4.40, $250 @ $4.40)R7 (3.30pm): MISSILE STAKES (1200m)
Fraser: Le Romain is the proven WFA performer in the race, he's had two lovely trials and won fresh last prep at the track and distance. I see him parking behind a hot speed and he looks ready to run well. The Monstar should have won the Ramornie and you only have to go back three runs where he bolted in here on a bog track. Jungle Edge is probably the best wet-tracker in the whole meeting. If they let him lead, he could be off and gone. Boss Lane is a good Randwick horse and will run his usual honest race.
Hickson: I couldn't go anywhere else but Le Romain, my only worry with him is when he's won his races he's sat second or third and he won't be able to do that. But he should get a nice sit and get to the best part of the track and class can carry him through. Invincible Gem is a query, we don't know how good she is but she came a long way last prep through to running second in the Randwick Guineas. The two wet-trackers, Jungle Edge and The Monstar, are hard to ignore.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Le Romain $2.30-$2.15- $2.20 ($1,000 @ $2.20), Jungle Edge $7-$6- $6.50, Tycoon Tara $5-$4.80R8 (4.10pm): TAB.COM.AU HCP (1000m)
Fraser: Tricky race. Tango Rain likes the wet and has the pace to cross or sit right on them. Kerrin McEvoy is a very good bias rider so he might just sit a couple of pairs back and he's the class runner. Lion Couchant had a tough run last start, his wet-track form is good and he's going quite well. Pro Consul has been excellent at his last two at this track and distance and will be launching late. Salerno keeps winning and the price keeps getting better.
Hickson: Launch Code has been well found in the betting but is one of the more promising horses. He really attacked the line at Wyong and I'm not concerned about the wet track, and it's a matter of where he gets to in the run from the gate. Sangiovese has been racing very well and got too far back behind Memes last start. Pro Consul keeps being underestimated and keeps running fantastic races. Tango Rain has to be respected but I wonder about him, maybe he'll be too good but I want to have a look at him.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Tango Rain $3.80-$2.90 ($400 @ $3.80, $625 @ $3.20)R9 (4.50pm): SCHWEPPES HCP (1200m)
Fraser: Spending To Win is fully fit now for two solid on pace runs. I don't think the horse knows he was beaten last start, it was a bob of the head, and he gets on pace favours here. One more chance. Argent D'Or has kept improving, handles the wet but is 3kg worse off. Clipper is the best wet-tracker in the race and is having a terrific preparation. Maps well and the question is the 1200m. Ghostly is also having a solid prep and his wet-track form is also good.
Hickson: Kings Of Leon faces a bit of a task but if it is down the outside by this time of day, he'll be suited. He was strong enough at the 1200m last start and he can take holding out. I have to like Last Witness as well because he got very close to Kings Of Leon last time. Spending To Win and Argent D'Or have to be respected after fighting their race out recently.
TAB MARKET MOVERS: Kings Of Leon $9 unchanged ($1,000 @ $9, $200 e/w @ $9/$3.05), Spending To Win $7-$5 ($250 x $200 e/w @ $7/$2.60, $250 @ $6, $300 @ $5, $250 @ $5)MIKE FRASER'S BEST BETS
BEST BET
Race 1, No. 2 BRAVE SONG
VALUE BET
Race 3, No. 10 DORF STAR
SATURDAY EXTRA
SHAYNE O'CASS'S BEST BETSKEMBLA
BEST BET: SMARTEDGE (Race 3, No. 5)
Was backed from $ into $1.80 to win his debut at Newcastle but was nosed out by the exciting D'Argento who has won in town since. Clearly a smart colt and will have befitted from the experience.
NEXT BEST: LUCERE (Race 1, No. 4)
Is a sister to today's Missile Stakes contender Memes and shares much of her big sisters natural pace and speed evidenced by that recent 3-lens trials win. The 1000m on debut is perfect.
VALUE: SAVETHELASTDANCE (Race 7, No. 4)
is a Team Hawkes trained mare by Redoute's Choice out of G2 winner and G1 runner-up Just Dancing. Taken a while to get her but the wait will be worth it.
JOCKEY TO FOLLOW
GRANT BUCKLEY will take some beating in the TAB Jockey Challenge with five nice rides. His best on paper is Metallic Moon for Paul Murray who won the Coffs Harbour Cup on Thursday with the tough as teak Darci's Affair.
SUGGESTED BETS
Exacta Race 3 No. 5 to beat No. 3
Exacta Race 2 No. 5 to beat No. 3
QUADDIE
Race 5: 1,2,3,5
Race 6: 1,3,7
Race 7: 4
Race 8: 5,10KEMPSEY
BEST BET: GALLANT GIRL (Race 4, No. 11)
has placed three times from her 12 starts and has a bunch of fourths and fifth on the C.V including that last start 2.5-lens fourth at Doomben.
NEXT BEST: DJERASSI (Race 6, No. 8)
has only won the one race from 29 starts but he has placed seven times as recently as July 23 when runner-up at Coffs. Won't get many better opportunities to win than today.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sayed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tango Rain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Romain $2.30-$2.15- $2.20 ($1,000 @ $2.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care To Think</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steyne $4.40-$4.60- $4.40 ($750 @ $4.60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STAKES (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hicksons</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Star Bob</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R7 (3.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R1 (11.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THERACES HCP (1800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brave Song $4-$3.20 ($1,000 @ $4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Romain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHAYNE O'CASS'S BEST BETSKEMBLA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makfi Lass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJERASSI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Witness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Ago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COM.AU HCP (1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GRANT BUCKLEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argento</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edge $7-$6- $6.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Dancing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R3 (1.05</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CELEBRATION DAY HCP (1600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labdien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LUCERE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R6 (2.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GALLANT GIRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R4 (1.40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubaiinstyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAVETHELASTDANCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gitan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doomben</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonic Swish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diapason $4.80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CINDY SULLIVAN MEMORIAL (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salerno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HELP.COM.AU HCP (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion Couchant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wahng Wah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCHWEPPES HCP (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Hawkes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Of Leon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diapason</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sayed $2.80-$2.70 ($500 @ $2.80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro Consul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARCI'S AFFAIR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SATURDAY EXTRA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wild Heart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashlee Marie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exacta Race 3 No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Thoroughbred Central</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Chica Bella</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanakee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramornie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spending To Win</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kempsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Brien</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara $5-$4.80R8 (4.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Darci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARKET MOVERS</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redoute's Choice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argent D</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tango Rain $3.80-$2.90 ($400 @ $3.80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Funoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAB Jockey Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMARTEDGE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIKE FRASER'S BEST BETS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Admiral Jello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zayam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jungle Edge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brave Song</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monstar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperator Augustus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorf Star</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clippers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G(1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph's Ray Hickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R5 (2.15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DENISE COBCROFT HCP (2400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUADDIE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick Guineas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gitan $7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Win $7-$5 ($250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIGHWAY (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francesco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exacta Race 2 No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addictive Nature</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addictive Nature $2.30-$2.40 ($600 @ $2.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Knight $3.10-$3.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R2 (12.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launch Code</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mighty Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metallic Moon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C.V</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R9 (4.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday Best</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
