<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424554795197393</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/finefixer-gives-legal-options-for-myki-speeding-citylink-fines/8774232</url>
  <title>CityLink, Myki or speeding fine? FineFixer website has the legal information you need</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Have you received one of the more than 5 million fines issued in Victoria each year?
Moonee Valley Legal Service (MVLS) has launched a website designed to help fine recipients understand their legal options.
asks users a series of questions about their fines, before presenting information about their options.
The website covers many types of fines including parking, toll roads, speeding and failure to vote.
Info in three minutes

Alexandra Lawrence was one of three RMIT University students who designed the website.
"We knew the public wanted something that would help them understand the legal system," she told 's Rafael Epstein.
"It's very complex for someone who doesn't have a legal background.
"All the information is already out there, we just realised that users were finding it difficult to get that information from a multitude of sites and pages."
She said the website simplified the information and provided a central location for users to access.
"It's not designed to give in-depth legal advice, we leave that to the experts," she said.
"It's designed so people can get information within three minutes."
Most people intend to pay

Principal lawyer at MVLS Brendan Lacota said there was $1.5 billion worth of unpaid fines in Victoria, with half of those being from toll roads Eastlink and CityLink.
He said most people with fines for unpaid road tolls who sought help from the MVLS intended to pay the toll, but left it too long.
"The toll company says, 'Sorry, we've passed your toll to Civic Compliance', and it's gone from $6 to $360," he said.
"Fines have a disproportionate impact on vulnerable people."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rafael Epstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Compliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVLS Brendan Lacota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CityLink</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVLS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Valley Legal Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
