<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423695801726157</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/retail/clothing-and-accessories/orotongroup-quits-the-gap-20170803-gxp42r</url>
  <title>'Oroton should now be more desirable without GAP'</title>
  <content>
Struggling luxury leather handbag and accessories maker OrotonGroup has quit its franchise agreement with US giant the GAP Inc, as it looks to stabilise the $44 million business and continues to look for a possible buyer.
Oroton said in a statement it was too early to say what the financial impacts would be on the company but it was limiting any future losses by cutting its relationship with the GAP. All six of the loss making GAP stores in Sydney and Melbourne are slated to close by end of January 2018.
 strategic review and the board is considering options including a sale, a capital raising or refinancing of debt facilities after receiving approaches from potential buyers.
Oroton chief executive Ross Lane said on Friday the recent amendment of the Westpac facility and today's agreement with the GAP, are important milestones in the strategic review announced on May 17. 

He said Oroton is also continuing to pursue various strategic processes aimed to maximise value for the company and its stakeholders.

Perennial Value Management fund manager Grant Oshry said exiting GAP is the right move which should make Oroton more desirable to any possible suitor.
"This will leave the business as brand Oroton only (and a 30 per cent stake in Daily Edited), which still resonates well in Australia," he said. 
"Importantly corporate costs can be significantly reduced given the reduced size of the business following GAP exit. M&A in the US with Coach acquiring Kate Spade and Michael Kors acquiring Jimmy Choo is an ongoing trend and Oroton should now be more desirable without GAP."
Oroton is 21-per cent owned by the founding Lane family and 17 per cent owned by Caledonia Funds Management chief investment officer Will Vicars. Mr Vicars is also a former Oroton director. 

Clothing distributora 7.3 per cent stake for for $3.1 million in Oroton as British-based fund manager, Highclere International exited the business.
Earlier this week, Oroton reached an agreement with its lender and Mr Vicars, securing a six-month extension on a working $35 million working capital facility.
Westpac and Mr Vicars have agreed on a put and call arrangement that extends the maturity date of the debt to October next year. Mr Vicars also has stumped up an unutilised $3 million line of credit to Oroton that expired on July 31.
Oroton at the same time reaffirmed its forecast for underlying full-year 2017 earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortisation of $2 million to $3 million.

Former managing director Mark Newman following a poor first half result. Former managing director Mr Lane, whose grandfather founded Oroton in 1938, took the reins on an interim basis after Mr Newman's departure.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Vicars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oroton</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Oshry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Choo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gap Inc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highclere International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Kors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Edited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OrotonGroup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Vicars</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Value Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caledonia Funds Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January, 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Spade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
