<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424425946176828</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/brisbane-broncos/wayne-bennett-says-brisbane-caught-on-the-hop-by-eels-as-they-prepare-for-titans-20170804-gxpcfd.html</url>
  <title>Wayne Bennett says Brisbane caught on the hop by Eels as they prepare for Titans</title>
  <content>
Wayne Bennett concedes Brisbane were caught on the hop by a highly motivated Parramatta side and must get their finals face on if they wish to climb back into the NRL top four.
Brisbane were leapfrogged by the Eels on Thursday night and find themselves sitting fifth as they head down the M1 to meet the Titans in the Saturday twilight at Robina.

Up Next

Cherry-Evans: Defence the issue for Manly

00:43

More Rugby League Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Eels notch sixth straight win

The Parramatta Eels continue their impressive form with a 20-4 win over the Canterbury Bulldogs.

But a superior for-and-against means they can reclaim the prized spot in the top four should they continue their dominance over the Gold Coast, who are out of finals contention and in the midst of negotiations to try and secure prized half Ash Taylor.
Taylor (hip) has been cleared to take on the Broncos but Kevin Proctor (hamstring) won't be suiting up for the home side, while Brisbane welcome back winger Corey Oates, who has recovered from a staph infection of his knee.

Brisbane were outplayed by the Eels last week in a 28-14 loss. It was a high-quality game and Bennett said it should act as a wake-up call for Brisbane, with virtually every team now playing a high-stakes game as the finals approach.
While the Eels took their intensity to the next level, Brisbane couldn't move through the gears. That's a mistake they are unlikely to make against the Titans, who are tricky to beat at home and have flashing lights all over them in what shapes as a potential finals trip for the Broncos.

"No doubt about that. Parramatta were on their game and played really well and we weren't that bad. The intensity they were playing at, we need to pick our intensity up a bit because the next five weeks, every one of those games is going to be important. It's just that time of the year," Bennett said.
The Eels are one of the in-form teams and anything close to what Brisbane showed last week, particularly in the early stages of the match, should see them get past the Titans. 
After that, they don't have to leave Queensland for the remainder of the season, with a series of home matches and a trip to North Queensland to face the Cowboys.
Meanwhile Bennett said they were open to an early release for prop Adam Blair, who looks likely to return to his native New Zealand to link with the Warriors.
"We've been asked about that and told him to go have a look around and come back and talk to us," Bennett said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Oates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Eels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Proctor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
