<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424567680099456</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/obituaries/les-murray-commentator-who-took-football-into-mainstream-respectability-20170804-gxpjve.html</url>
  <title>'Mr Football' put the game on the map </title>
  <content>
It is often said of migrants that, regardless of what passions they may provoke in their host country, they often bring something that changes and enriches the community that takes them in. In the case of Laszlo Urge, an 11-year-old Hungarian refugee arriving in Australia in 1957, it was a passion for football.
Urge, who was to change his name to Les Murray, was to say: "As a refugee who came here with nothing, I am very grateful to this country for the opportunities I have had. Refugees, perhaps more than other immigrants, are more likely to make a positive contribution to their new country, driven by a need to give something in return for being given a chance to start again after a terrible experience."Photo: SBS
Les James Murray was born on November 5, 1945, in Hungary, son of Jozsef and Erzsebet Urge. Growing up in a village outside Budapest, he played football and followed the fortunes of the famous Hungarian football team, the "Mighty Magyars", the "Golden Team", which reached the 1954 World Cup Final. Murray dreamed of becoming a professional footballer. But national pride was shattered by the Soviet invasion of 1956.
"My parents saw no hope for the future in their country because they knew that, more than likely, my father would be in trouble with the law for his involvement in political activities," Murray said. "The situation was quite precarious but my two brothers and I weren't fully aware of what was happening."Photo: Fairfax Media
The family was guided across the border on a cold December night by a man called Julius. After spending six months in refugee camps, they got a passage to Australia under the Hungarian Refugee Assisted Scheme. The family spent three weeks in Bonegilla migrant camp near Wodonga and then moved to Wollongong, initially sharing a house with another Hungarian family.
While his father was employed at the steelworks, Murray went to Berkeley High School. He saw that football was a minority sport, having been largely displaced by its Rugby version. He argued about its merits with schoolmates. He saw that it was followed with wild enthusiasm in migrant communities.

Murray admired Johnny Warren, very much Australian, who played for St George-Budapest from 1963, for Australia from 1965, and was captain from 1967. But with club names like St George Budapest, Sydney Hakoah and Sydney Prague, there was still a heavy ethnic bias.
The ABC's Martin Royal, acknowledged as Australia's first soccer broadcaster, did a great job but a popular retort was: "He's the only one who watches it!"Photo: Ryan Pierse
When the Urge family moved to Sydney, Murray played football in the lower grades with St George Budapest. For a time, he was lead singer for a rock group, The Rubber Band. In 1971, he joined the John Fairfax Group as a journalist on the Sydney Sun. In 1977, when he anglicised his name, he joined Ten Network as a sports commentator.
In 1980 Special Broadcasting Service (SBS) television, Channel 28, was born and the station needed someone who could provide sub-titles for Hungarian films. "It was good fortune," said a long-time colleague. "They had a sport department and Les was in the building when they said they needed someone who could talk about soccer. Even then, Les was an encyclopaedia. Then Les rang  Warren and said, 'Would you like to join me?'"
Murray and Warren were colleagues for the next 24 years in what was, his former colleague said, "one of the great long-standing double acts in Australia".
He added: "Johnny said it was not a profession but a mission. They had to evangelise. Johnny was an aficionado of Brazilian football. In Brazil they called in "O Jogo Bonito", "The Beautiful Game". Les called it "The World Game". Both of them were on a mission to take football into mainstream respectability. An event was not an event unless Les and Johnny were present."
Murray married at one stage and had two daughters. But the marriage did not last. Referred to as "Mr Football", Murray toured with the Australian team to China and Europe in 1984. That year he began presenting the program, On The Ball, the first of a series of programs which would include Toyota World Sport and The World Game.
In 1986, he was host of SBS's first broadcast of an FIFA World Cup Final. In 1996, Murray became SBS head of sport, successfully negotiated the broadcast rights for FIFA World Cups, the Tour de France and the IAAF World Athletics Championships. He became a Member of the Order of Australia (AM) for service to soccer. In 2003, Murray was inducted into the Football Federation Australia's Hall of Fame.
Warren died in 2004. Murray joined the board of the Johnny Warren Football Foundation. In July 2006, after Australia had performed with great credit in the World Cup, Murray became an editorial supervisor. In his career, he had covered Socceroos' World Cup campaigns, eight FIFA World Cups, UEFA European Championships and UEFA Champions League, FA Cup Finals and Australia's National Soccer League.
He had time to be a grandfather. "My older grandson is two years old. I have to start working on his left foot," he said.
Murray's other roles included chairmanship of the Asia-Pacific Broadcasting Union Sports Group and membership of the FIFA's Ethics Commission. In 2011, he published The World Game: The Story of How Football Went Global. In June 2014, SBS announced that Murray would retire as chief football commentator and editorial supervisor. He was retained as an expert commentator.
He died on July 31 after a long illness, survived by his partner Maria and daughters Tania, a singer-songwriter, and Natalie, a television journalist, and a grandson.
Malcolm Brown
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Story of How</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Games</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Refugee Assisted Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota World Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Hakoah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FA Cup Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George-Budapest</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laszlo Urge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Fairfax Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mighty Magyars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les James Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren Football Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wodonga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos' World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia's Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jozsef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Pierse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's National Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special Broadcasting Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Member of the Order</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O Jogo Bonito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonegilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berkeley High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIFA's Ethics Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIFA World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beautiful Game</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erzsebet Urge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rubber Band</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAAF World Athletics Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA European Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia-Pacific Broadcasting Union Sports Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Went Global</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa World Cup Finals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Martin Royal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Prague</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
