<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424181133036980</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/frankston-dolphins-football-club-regains-vfl-licence-supporters-jubilant/news-story/e37147826e1ddee76a6327cc64c0a940</url>
  <title>Dolphins back in the game for 2018</title>
  <content>
WE'RE back!
Frankston Dolphins members and supporters are jubilant after AFL Victoria today announced the club can to rejoin the VFL competition for the 2018 season.
Board member and former star player Peter Geddes said massive community support had got the Dolphins over the line.
"Once that passion started it ignited a fire across the peninsula. It was amazing," he said.
In a statement, AFL Victoria CEO Steven Reaper said the Dolphins had an important role to play in the region - with time away from the competition enabling the club to focus on its off-field structures.
RELATED:
RELATED:
"AFL Victoria was always committed to continuing to work with key stakeholders in the region, including Frankston Football Club, to ensure there would be a state-league presence there into the future," Mr Reaper said.
"Frankston Football Club and all involved have shown their commitment to regain their licence in the VFL, establishing a strong strategic plan focused on governance, community engagement, sponsorship and membership that will assist the club and the region into the future."
Weighed down by debts of more than $1.5 million, the club went into administration last August.
Soon after AFL Victoria declared Frankston's financial problems were "too hard to ignore'' and it "terminated'' the Dolphins' licence for the 2017 season.
Supporters rallied under general manager Gary Buckenara and a new board, reducing the debt to about $400,000 and boosting their membership to 1200.
Mr Buckenara said the club was now focused on building a viable list for the 2018 season.
He expects a coach to be announced between late September to early October with training to start in November.
Mr Reaper added: "With Frankston returning to the competition, another 40 players will experience training and working towards playing senior VFL football in a stand-alone club environment.
"By making this announcement now, the club can start to work on appointing a coach, building a playing list, locking away sponsors and taking the first steps in its new history," he said.
Mayor Brian Cunial praised those who had worked tirelessly to enable the club to rejoin the competition.
"It's a credit to the club and the community," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Football Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Brian Cunial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Dolphins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Buckenara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Victoria CEO Steven Reaper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Geddes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Buckenara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Reaper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
