<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424468895850348</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/palm-beach-currumbin-state-high-school-winger-bayley-desmond-scores-unbelievable-try-in-gio-schoolboy-cup/news-story/ca22eb33f6af950212cb01064506419d</url>
  <title>Is this the best try of all time?</title>
  <content>
THE GIO Schoolboy Cup has unveiled a new star: Palm Beach Currumbin State High School's Bayley Desmond.
The talented winger scored an incredible try in yesterday's knockout match against St Mary's College at Kougari Oval that has already been viewed close to 100,000 times.

Desmond produced a spectacular acrobatic effort to finish a PBC backline movement, leaping high into the air to stay infield and pluck a try from out of nowhere.
The effort stunned his coach Aaron Zimmerle.
"In 15 years of Schoolboys footy, I've never seen a try that good," he said.
Zimmerle said wingers regularly work on different techniques to find the try line.
"But nothing with a superman dive over the top of someone with a two-hand put-down in the vertical. We haven't taught that," he laughed.
It capped an outstanding game for Desmond, who scored two tries and set up another in a 36-4 win that takes PBC into a Queensland quarterfinal against Marsden.
Zimmerle revealed the young gun had only returned to his best a fortnight earlier, having had a tough run of injuries headlined by a badly broken ankle suffered in 2015.
"Last year he came back and had a couple of knocks on it and so forth so he was fighting hard last year to get his speed back," he said.
"He almost looked like he ran with a bit of a limp because he has got a pin in his ankle and that. He has come back this year and has gradually built into it.
"He scored a great try for us a fortnight ago against Coombabah ... he made a bust and he (got) caught but Bayley hit the deck, rolled and somehow bounced back up to his feet and then ran the next 20m and scored a great try.
"I said to him at the time: That's a great try. That's you back to your best a year and a half ago before you broke your leg. And then he scored that yesterday which was just phenomenal."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coombabah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palm Beach Currumbin State High School's Bayley Desmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kougari Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GIO Schoolboys Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PBC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DESMOND</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Mary's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zimmerle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Zimmerle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marsden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayleys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
