<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424430241144188</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/15/15/sculpture-at-barangaroo-impressive-display</url>
  <title>Sculpture at Barangaroo impressive display</title>
  <content>
The brains trust behind Sydney's iconic Sculpture by the Sea has unveiled its second exhibition at Barangaroo with a new curator and more artworks on display.
Curator Geoffrey Edwards has selected nine existing artworks and commissioned five brand new ones from established and emerging Australian artists for the site on the edge of the CBD.
His vision was to complement the harbourside landscape while providing a "cross generational and cross cultural representation".
"Hopefully the exhibition generates conversations and provides a catalyst for thought but chiefly something that delights the eye and adds to the pleasurable experience of visiting the reserve," Edwards told AAP.
Last year over 150,000 people visited the harbour foreshore to see the Barangaroo exhibition.
Barangaroo Delivery Authority acting chief executive Craig van der Laan is confident this year's turnout will be significantly greater.
One of the three Indigenous artists to participate in the show, Tereasa Trevor, collaborated with six Aboriginal tribes on the work 11 Ships.

Related Articles

She says the sculpture recognises the impact the 1788 arrival of the First Fleet had on First Nations peoples.
"It's a celebration of the culture that was always here and still remains."
Richard Tipping's work, Kangooroo, will be on display for a second time, having previously shown at Sculpture by the Sea at Bondi in 2016 .
His background in poetry lends itself to the artwork's play on words with "ooroo" meaning "see you later".
"When I was driving up country there was a big kangaroo sign that said next 160km and it was peppered with bullet holes," Tipping told AAP.
"(In my artwork) the roo has jumped out and escaped bouncing away leaving a potent absence."
The exhibition officially opens on Saturday.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tereasa Trevor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangooroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barangaroo Delivery Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Fleet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barangaroo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Tipping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffrey Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
