<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424597744870865</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/sydney-homeless-martin-place-clover-moore-nsw-government/8774634</url>
  <title>Stalemate over Martin Place homeless tent city as Clover slaps State Government with demands</title>
  <content>
Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore has issued the New South Wales Government with a list of demands she wants met before the council co-operates with the dismantling of a homeless tent city in Martin Place.
The camp, opposite the Reserve Bank building, has been growing for weeks and is part of a protest calling for longer-term housing options for the city's homeless.
"What I have asked for is a commitment that immediate accommodation, with a view to long-term accommodation, will be offered to everyone in Martin Place, and that the state will fund another common ground, that is a special housing facility for homeless people," Cr Moore said.
Her ultimatum came after a meeting with NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller and Social Housing Minister Pru Goward failed to reach an agreement on the homeless camp.

In her list of demands, she also called on the State Government to consider using the empty Sirius building as homeless accommodation, and for an extension to the affordable housing levy.
Following the meeting, Ms Goward attended the camp, where a spokesperson for the homeless group slammed the Minister for not properly consulting with the camp's residents:
"Maybe you need to actually ask the people who are affected rather than talking to the NGOs who are marketing their services," the spokesperson said.
"We're here to house people who aren't able to access permanent housing."
Ms Goward hit back, saying the Government had already provided permanent housing to people assessed as eligible.
"We have already housed 63 and we will continue to house people permanently," she said.
Homeless camps cleared from Martin Place before

Both levels of government have accused each other of shunting responsibility over the tent city, which is a stone's throw from State Parliament.
Ms Goward said she is considering Cr Moore's demands.
In June, police and council workers , describing the occupation as a public nuisance.
Tents, gas bottles and a barbecue were removed by council dump trucks as part of the eviction.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Housing Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goward</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
