<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424468895850337</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/television/sex-and-the-city-alum-jason-lewis-reveals-why-he-had-to-take-a-break-from-hollywood/news-story/ad1972cf3f6bcfff3f40f8f6026e4313</url>
  <title>Why this Sex and the City star left Hollywood</title>
  <content>
HE MIGHT'VE only been on the show for 18 episodes but as soon as Jason Lewis starred as Smith on Sex and the City, the world fell in love with the talented and gorgeous actor.
Lewis played the boyfriend of Kim Cattrall's character Samantha Jones and quickly established himself as one of the hunkiest actors on the small screen.
But his success from working on Sex and the City wasn't all it was cracked up to be, with the actor revealing  it made him want to leave Hollywood.
"I pulled away from the industry for a while because I think I was chasing success, and I wasn't feeling good about what I was doing," he told the publication.
The now 46-year-old actor is heading back to the small screen to star in a new supernatural series called Midnight, Texas where Lewis will play an angel.
The show comes from Charlaine Harris, the same author behind the hugely successful True Blood series.
And despite it being over ten years since Lewis has had a major role, the actor said it was always the "stories" that kept him grounded.
"It's why I like what I do,"
"I went to libraries as a kid. Stories are a great way to not only know you aren't alone but to get dialogues and wisdom from around the world," he added.
Lewis made his debut in Sex and the City for the show's sixth and final season.
He also starred in the first and second Sex and the City movies, both of which were hugely successful at the box office.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlaine Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>True Blood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Cattrall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
