<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424138183363301</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/island-paradise-for-the-price-of-a-house-in-sydney/3208747/</url>
  <title>Island paradise for the price of a house in Sydney</title>
  <content>
THE only house on an island off Mackay has gone on sale for the price of a house in Sydney.

Number 1 Victor Island is on the market for $3,500,000. It is a five-bedroom, two-bathroom lowset house on 7.7 acres of bushland, complete with freshwater dam.

Victor Island is located to the south of Mackay, less than two kilometres from the mainland. Access is from several boat ramps including Grasstree Beach, Campwin Beach, and Hay Point.

The property generates its own power using a solar electricity system with a back-up generator. There are ten rainwater tanks and a 100sqm freshwater dam for water storage.

The listing with Savills states: "There are no renovations or repairs to be done. There is no infrastructure to create or equipment and furnishings to buy. All that work has been done and virtually all the equipment on the island is still under warranty. There is also an NBN connection.

"The high-end renovation included a four-bedroom, two-bathroom home with king and queen ensembles, unique retractable blade ceiling fans in the bedrooms and air-conditioning to the master.

"There is a fully renovated self-contained caretaker's cottage, which includes a new kitchen and bathroom

"There are many walking trails that wind their way throughout the island, plus plenty of birdlife to enjoy as well."

Also included is John Deere 4WD tractor with bucket and a zero-turn lawn mower, both less than 12 months old.

The island is also being sold with a new Quintrex 610 hardtop Trident boat with a 150hp Mercury outboard, plus alloy trailer, along with a variety of tools and equipment.

Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Magistrate says break-ins frustrate community clubs
National Park mascot 'Hilaire' caught and being treated.
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
Australia's most unique house 'impossible to value'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilaire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tridents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Deere 4WD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grasstree Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quintrex 610</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campwin Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Island</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hay Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
