<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424606334805716</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/breaking-news/security-for-trumps-visit-ruffles-town/news-story/e5673bb249b20bfc43f34967250a7f3b</url>
  <title>Security for Trump's visit ruffles town</title>
  <content>
Three military helicopters hovered over Anne Choi's backyard, engaged in what appeared to be a drill ahead of President Donald Trump's visit three weeks ago to this tranquil town of farmland and horse barns in rural New Jersey.
"My sheep were terrified," Choi, 44, said on Thursday inside her two-storey barn about 1.5km east of Trump National Golf Club, as half a dozen Shetland sheep grazed outside. "It's awful. We don't have the infrastructure here. We can't support the weight of his presence."
As Bedminster prepared this week for the president's latest trip to the 240-hectare private club, a 17-day stay that is his first extended vacation in office, some of the town's 8000 residents expressed frustration at the security protocols, road closures and daily disruption that will begin with his arrival on Friday.
On Wednesday, the US Secret Service said safety measures would also include a "tethered drone", equipped with optical and infrared cameras and powered by a wire attached to a ground controller, that could impede on the privacy of nearby residences.
"It's super creepy," said Julie Henderson, an artist who lives down the road from Trump National, as two military helicopters roared overhead before circling and heading back toward the golf club.
The Secret Service said the drone would focus primarily on the outer perimeter and would not "physically intrude upon or disturb the use of private property outside the Trump National Golf Course".
Trump's movements can also lead to the closure of local roads and highways. Julie Henderson's husband, Paul Henderson, said he has twice been stuck on an Interstate on his way to work while Trump's motorcade used the highway.
Not everyone in this town about 60km west of New York City agrees Trump's visit will be a nuisance. Steve Desiderio, who owns a restaurant and catering business in Bedminster's modest downtown, said the influx of federal agents and journalists would be a welcome boost to his business.
Desiderio, a 48-year-old Trump supporter, added that complaints about the disruption were overblown and media-driven.
"It's just fake news," he said, echoing one of the president's favourite phrases. "They try to spin it like it's gridlock. So there are five more cars at the stoplight?"
Bedminster's Republican mayor, Steven Parker, also brushed off the criticism.
"It's really been a big non-event," he said.
Some residents said Trump has been a generous neighbour in past years, allowing local events to be hosted at his club. As in previous years, the township committee held its annual reorganisation meeting in 2017 at Trump National, where Parker was selected to continue as mayor.
While Trump's visit may help the town's eateries, it will shut down the local airport, where 110 private planes and 60 flight school students will be grounded from August 4 to August 20.
"Our summertime is our busiest time," said Somerset Airport President Chris Walker, as a Coast Guard helicopter landed on the runway in preparation for the weekend. "We're just rolling with the punches."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster's Republican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desiderio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump National Golf Course</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Choi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Choi, 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Desiderio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somerset Airport President Chris Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump National Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump National</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Henderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast Guard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shetland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secret Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
