<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424644989512060</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822108/ending-the-silence-one-song-at-a-time/?cs=2372</url>
  <title>Ending the silence one song at a time</title>
  <content>
Suicide. It's a word few people use but which affects the lives of so many. 

Lifeline Newcastle says eight Australians a day are lost to suicide on average. Three out of four of the lives lost are men. And, in 2015, 3027 deaths were due to suicide nationwide.

That's more than two times the national road toll. 

Newcastle singer and musician Justin Ngariki had been thinking about ways to raise awareness of suicide and mental illness for years. The death of Soundgarden frontman Chris Cornell by suicide in May was the final straw. 
Ngariki contacted Big Apachee's Marcus Wright and together they have organised Loud Love at The Cambridge on August 17. The event pays tribute to some of the late, great singers of Seattle's grunge era -Cornell, Kurt Cobain, Layne Staley and Scott Weiland - but more importantly is about raising awareness of mental illness and suicide. 

"Over the years I have had a lot of family members suffer from depression and be on the brink of suicide," Ngariki tells Weekender over coffee.

"If you have cancer your whole circle knows about it and offers to help. But cancer doesn't kill as many people in the 15 to 44 age group as suicide does. We need to talk about suicide and mental illness, to open up the dialogue - both public and personal." 

GOOD CAUSE: Left to right, Ross Flynn, Justin Ngariki, Mark Cashin, Amy Vee, Chris Hamall, Marcus Wright and Lee Rolfe. Picture: Marina Neil
Wright says it's not "making noise" just because a famous person has died.
"It's all about raising awareness. There are a lot of people out there on the edge. I know it rocked my world when Kurt Cobain died. He was my idol. I've lost friends to suicide. I had to do something positive."  
Some of Newcastle's best musicians will be at The Cambridge for Loud Love. Each has been asked to select four of their favourite songs by the Seattle artists to perform on the night. Ngariki will be joined on stage by Mark Cashin, Paul Coxon, Ross Flynn, Chris Hamall, Ken Jewell, Lee Rolfe, Kane Starkey and Amy Vee. Viagro is also playing. 
"We're not doing a greatest hits of grunge, that would be tacky," Ngairki says.

"By choosing our favourite songs we are invested in the performance and to be honest, for us to be able to play these songs, as fans, all these years later is amazing." 

Wright says the dialogue about mental illness and suicide has improved in recent years but still has a long way to go.

"Three million people live with depression in Australia. We need to talk about it more. Part of it is a macho thing. Look, I used to box and I'm tough but these days I let myself cry. Bottling your emotions up is not good for you and some of the saddest people I know have been the wealthiest. 
"And we made a point of using the word suicide in the event's title. Lifeline were happy about that. If you save just one person, that changes a lot of lives."

Ngariki agrees: "There's no nice way to broach the topic so let's just broach it.

"It's not seen as a weakness to have cancer, there are physiological factors involved. Well, it's the same with depression. We want that word front and centre. Let's talk about it."

They hope a sea of people will be wearing the official Loud Love t-shirts on the night. All money raised will go to Lifeline Newcastle & Hunter. Tickets are $15 pre-sale at bigtix.oztix.com.au or $20 at the door.

If you need someone to talk to please contact Lifeline on their 24-hour hotline: 13 11 14 or go online to their online chat service at lifeline.org.au.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cornell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ngariki</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Rolfe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Viagro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Cobain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Vee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Cornell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ngairki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Apachee's Marcus Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soundgarden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Cashin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Weiland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Starkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loud Love</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Flynn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Ngariki</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hamall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Jewell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifeline Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Coxon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Layne Staley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
