<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424640694544752</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/labor-greens-seek-delay-on-contract-rules/news-story/2de6f78c16f2ede6db273d79dbfaaad6</url>
  <title>Labor, Greens seek delay on contract rules</title>
  <content>
Labor and the Greens have called for the delay of proposed laws which would allow businesses to challenge decisions relating to government contracts.
The laws to set up the independent complaints mechanism will enable Australia to meet its obligations under the World Trade Organisation Agreement on Government Procurement (GPA).
In turn, Australian exporters will gain access to government procurement markets in other countries.
A government-dominated Senate inquiry report released on Friday called for the laws to be passed, but asked that the Finance Department consult further with the public service on the operation of the new mechanism.
However, Labor senators argued that while improving access to international markets was important, the arrangements should not be legislated before the GPA talks had concluded.
"Delaying consideration of this bill would ensure parliament has the opportunity to consider the agreement in full," Senator Jenny McAllister wrote in the report.
The Greens agreed the bill should be postponed for the same reasons.
If the bill was to be brought on, the Greens said the 10-day limit on bringing proceedings to seek an injunction should be lengthened.
The Finance Department said the 10-day period was chosen to "encourage timely efforts to resolve any concerns".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Procurement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Jenny McAllister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Department</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Trade Organisation Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
