<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424340046829333</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834522/game-on-when-sport-imitates-life/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Game On: When Illawarra and South Coast sport imitates life</title>
  <content>
Home: The hill at the St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium on July 23. Picture: Greg Ellis

Maybe it's a case of sport imitating life. 
Because plans to cut train commuting times, Wollongong council elections, the NRL and a potential A-League expansion all have one thing in common. 
Are we a region to ourselves? Or now just effectively the most southern suburb of Sydney?
On Friday, in an interview with colleague Kate McIlwain, Wollongong Lord Mayor Gordon Bradbery declared the Illawarra has lost out on millions of dollars in funding, because of a fractured definition of the region's standing.
Bradbery urged councillors to "take a stand and bat for our team in saying we are regional".
If the Illawarra's prosperity is suffering because of its identity and proximity to Sydney, sport fans - particularly rugby league and football - can relate. 
The same political pressure should be applied to ensure the Illawarra and South Coast receives a fair share of elite games. 
Hosting Wigan and Hull, the first Super League competition game to be played in Australia, is a step in the right direction. 
Perhaps the tide is coming in after all, though it still feels like small consolation to only hosting four NRL games a year and Football Federation Australia's lack of appetite for expansion.
This is without even considering the failure of the Home of Political Football development at west Dapto and the ongoing funding issues just to establish a synthetic pitch in the Illawarra.
As this column wrote some months back, at some point civic leaders need to address a burning question. 
In 10, 20, 50 years time, what sort of identity does the Illawarra want to have?

Election: Gordon Bradbery. Picture: Adam McLean

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Lord Mayor Gordon Bradbery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradbery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate McIlwain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home of Political</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Bradbery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
