<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424657874414141</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4827242/ideas-in-motion/?cs=2373</url>
  <title>Ideas in motion</title>
  <content>
IDEAS MEN: TAFE NSW pastry teacher Dean Gibson and industrial design teacher Jon Pryer with The Boneshaker. Picture: Marina Neil

Two Newcastle teachers are doing their best Willy Wonka impersonations and turning TAFE Hamilton into an innovative chocolate factory with commercial potential.

Or, perhaps, Doctor Frankenstein. TAFE teachers Dean Gibson and Jon Pryer have spent many a long night over the past year developing "The Boneshaker" - and this steampunk-inspired robotic rhinoceros is poised to revolutionise the world of chocolate sculpting. 

CLEVER: The Boneshaker is 100 per cent chocolate. Every single moving part.
Gibson is a pastry chef, teacher and chocolatier who met industrial design teacher Pryer last year while sitting his 3D computer-aided design (CAD) course. They started talking and decided to make a moving sculpture made entirely from chocolate using industrial design thinking and as much technology as possible. 

Applying industrial design to chocolate sculpting has the potential to open enterpreneurial doors in Australia. Chocolatiers could design and manufacture their own high-grade silicone chocolate moulds, rather than have them custom-made overseas at considerable cost, or 3D print chocolate bars or petit fours.

ROBOTIC: The Boneshaker is a steam punk-inspired rhinoceros.
"The global benefits for my area of design, and the chocolate and bakery field, are enormous," Pryer says. 
"Local TAFE has a real opportunity here to create an international profile. Competitive chocolate is a whole world I never knew existed. And on a pragmatic level Australian chocolate makers and bakers will benefit from the ability to produce their own moulds for their own designs for chocolate and bread here."
The Boneshaker concept was drawn and then designed in the 3D CAD modelling program and a prototype model built. Tempered Belgian chocolate slabs were made and machine-cut into mechanical parts using a CNC router (or Computer Numerical Control router). The teachers then assembled The Boneshaker. It is made entirely out of chocolate. Not even glue was used.  

"When building chocolate sculptures I would typically follow a set regime where I would draw the piece, do a bit of artwork and then build the structure out of other materials, let's say foam or waxed cardboard, to get an idea of balance and size," Gibson explains. 
"This time, I did a drawing and some artwork, Jon did a drawing and then we built a 3D moving replica out of timber. We drew the parts in CAD so they were perfect.

ACCURATE: This chocolate spring was designed on a computer.
"I haven't had to spend as much time negotiating how to balance 100 or more kilograms of chocolate on a 20-centimetre-squared base. Now I can save the details on a USB stick, give it to a colleague and they can use a water cutter or a CNC router to cut out all the pieces and make it themselves."
Working with chocolate presented some challenges. The CNC router is usually used to make parts for chairs and tables. Next time, though, it will be easier. And quicker.
"We cleaned the router and I bought a special drill bit that wouldn't fracture or destroy the chocolate. I cast massive blocks of chocolate and made 27 sheets which weighed close to 180 kilograms," Gibson says.
"Out of those sheets we formed the working parts, all 149 of them. Now we've put them together, we've got about 20 moving parts driven by one force, and that moves the other components. To my knowledge it's the first moving chocolate sculpture in the world."

The aim was, Pryer says, to get a dozen or so moving parts driven by a single crank.

"Since no one has done this before, if we got one part moving it was a first. We hope to get the number of moving parts recognised by the Guinness Book of Records as a new record category."

Assessing the properties of chocolate and determining what non-traditional processes would work with it proved interesting.

"Initially I though laser-cutting would work well but it didn't so we experimented with CNC routing which worked brilliantly," Pryer says.
"CAD is perfectly accurate and the 3D printing and CNC routing we are using is so accurate you can ignore the tolerances for most applications. Compared to traditionally sculpted chocolate it's like NASA precision versus chainsaw carving. 

"This project just scratches the surface of what can be done with that kind of  precision in the chocolate and bakery world."
TAFE NSW chocolate/pastry and industrial design students have been actively involved in the project over the past 12 months and Pryer and Gibson are working to bring an interdisciplinary approach to their courses. Industrial design students are now tasked with designing a customised chocolate mould and have already completed a chocolate-making course with Gibson. 
"I have found this to be one of the few truly collaborative projects I've worked on," Pryer says.
"Dean's at the top of his game and I could see his passion for his craft and related to that. I could also see how the skills I have could push what was happening in his industry to a new level. Following the project's progress and our collaboration means our students are going to go out into the industry and do this type of stuff as par for the course."
Gibson is a former coach and manager of Team Pastry Australia and a member of the Australian Gelato Team competing in the 2018 Gelato World Cup in Italy In February.

He grew up in Edgeworth and attended West Wallsend High School, leaving at age 14 to pursue a pastry cook apprenticeship. He was executive pastry chef at Rockpool in Sydney for many years, working under Neil Perry, and has been a guest on MasterChef twice.
"I don't think I will ever get to a point where I can say I have mastered my craft. There are always new skills and techniques to learn. As a teacher I need to push myself and be at the coal face of innovation so that I can find out what's happening next and pass that on to my students."

The Boneshaker will be unveiled at the 2017 Smooth Festival of Chocolate at The Rocks next weekend (August 12 and 13). For details go to smooth.com.au/smooth/festival-of-chocolate.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Gibson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willy Wonka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Pastry Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smooth Festival of Chocolate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy In February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockpool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guinness Book of Records</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gibson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Pryer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Gelato Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Computer Numerical Control</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D CAD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gelato World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pryer</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edgeworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctor Frankenstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wallsend High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boneshaker</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
