<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424425946176784</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/city/sa-water-to-reinstate-prospect-rd-surface-to-proper-standard-after-three-months-replacing-water-mains/news-story/54a08460904dec329c3f1585ee1f0671</url>
  <title>SA Water to fix 'bumpy' Prospect Rd</title>
  <content>
SA WATER will begin restoring Prospect Rd's permanent bitumen and brick paving surface on Sunday after criticism about the state the company had left the road in during water main replacement work.
Prospect councillors complained at a workshop on Tuesday that SA Water had dug up recently laid smooth asphalt on Prospect Rd and then relaid long strips of crumbly bitumen where pipes had been replaced.
Cr Talis Evans said the road was now bumpy and less safe, particularly for motorcycle and scooter users like him.
"It means either you've got to veer closer to the gutter or the middle of the road or have an uneven, bumpy ride," Cr Evans said.
SA Water started replacing 1.4km of mains under Prospect Rd in May, just after Prospect Council had finished digging up the road to put powerlines underground.
At the workshop, council chief executive Cate Hart said she did not know if SA Water was going to reinstate the road as it was or if the condition it was in on Tuesday was its permanent state.
Today, she said SA Water had advised the council in April that the surface would be returned to a "proper standard" after the works.
An SA Water spokeswoman said the long black strips on Prospect Rd and side streets were "temporary bitumen caps".
"Restoration of the permanent bitumen surface and reinstatement of brick paving will begin from Sunday, August 6, weather permitting, and is expected to take around two weeks to complete," she said.
"The affected surfaces of side streets will then be restored at the end of August.
"We've worked in close consultation with Prospect Council throughout this project and will continue to involve them as we conclude construction works and begin the restoration."
Mayor David O'Loughlin said he would be keen to see how SA Water would reinstate the surface where side streets meet Prospect Rd.
The road looks like pavers but is actually stencilled red bitumen.
"The street looks very ordinary now with cuts and trenches repaired each which way," Mr O'Loughlin said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor David O'Loughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Talis Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Loughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Restoration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cate Hart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prospect Rd</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Water</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prospect Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
