<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424103823624273</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/tomorrow-were-racing-a-car-vs-a-plane/</url>
  <title>Tomorrow, We're Racing A Car Against A Plane</title>
  <content>
Image:  BBC / Gizmodo
Qantas and Virgin stated that passengers need to arrive at the airport 2 hours before domestic flights due to tightened security restrictions.

This got us to thinking; is it faster to just drive to Canberra from Sydney now? Tomorrow, we intend to find out. Welcome to Mustang vs Plane.

At 8:05am tomorrow I'll be on a Virgin flight out of Sydney. Fortunately I live pretty close to the airport, but due to the new rules, that means leaving the house at 5:45am.

Worst. Saturday. Ever.

But it's okay, because I'm dragging Campbell and Rae down with me. Just as I'm getting into my Uber,  outside my house, much to the delight of my neighbours.

Taking the new check-in times into account, my journey should take just under 3 hours, which is roughly the same as the drive. Who will make it to Canberra's iconic Questacon (within the confines of the law) first?

Image: Gizmodo

You can follow all the adventure, tears and airport beers tomorrow via the ,  and on .

Sane enough to not get up ludicrously early to watch Facebook Live? That's cool, we'll save it for you, because we're nice like that.

See you tomorrow in EXCITING CANBERRA. And if anyone wants to let out the Mustang's tyres at Goulburn Maccas, I'll buy you a drink.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing A Car Against A Plane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mustang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gizmodo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Questacon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EXCITING CANBERRA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortunately I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulburn Maccas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
