<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424039399113973</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/sports-life/football-team-fires-cheerleaders-for-being-too-distracting/news-story/7e47218bbd1b91d62b5fa2f17e02ad88</url>
  <title>Football team fires cheerleaders for being too distracting</title>
  <content>
A team of cheerleaders has been sacked for being too distracting.

Rob Pattinson and Patrick GysinThe Sun

Share

A MILLIONAIRE soccer boss sacked his club's cheer-leaders because some tried to pull the players.
Semi-pro Billericay Town - part-owned by Towie star Mark Wright - had signed up the girls, known as "The Ricays", only last month. Last night the leader of the sexy dancers, Bekka Batchelor, said of their red card: "It's just a shame."
But the Essex club's owner Glenn Tamplin, 45, said: "The lads were becoming unfocused."
The soccer tycoon announced on Twitter that he had sacked the cheerleaders - suggesting they were too sexy for his players.
The millionaire tweeted: "We have had to let the cheerleaders go as the lads were becoming unfocused and some of the girls (not all) sending their numbers to them."
He feared the dancers would prove too much of an off-the-pitch distraction to his players - who include former Premier League aces Jermaine Pennant, Jamie O'Hara and Paul Konchesky.
And he was worried it could derail his dream of taking semi-pro Essex side Billericay Town into the Football League.
We have had to let the cheerleaders go as the lads were becoming unfocused and some of the girls (not all) sending there numbers to them
Auditions for the troupe - named "The Ricays" - were held at West Ham's training ground on July 17 and 18.
The chosen pom-pom girls were set to put on displays during home matches this season.

But with just a week to kick-off, club owner Glenn, 45 - who is also team manager - has shown them all the red card.
The players first met with the cheerleaders after he took the lads to watch their routines.
But one of the players and girls then got in contact via social media.
A source told The Sun: "We held auditions on the Monday night and then one of the players contacted one of the girls because one of them put the cheerleading outfit on and tweeted about it.
"He contacted her and unfortunately I think she gave her phone number to him and I think the footballer actually went and told Glenn.
"Glenn made it clear there should be no interaction between the cheerleaders and players - even though he brought the squad over to watch them.

A post shared by Bekka Batchelor (@bekkabatchelor) on

A post shared by Bekka Batchelor (@bekkabatchelor) on

We are excited to be working with  to provide the Official Cheerleaders @TheRicays 💙 Give them a follow!

"He changed his mind and said there wasn't going to have them and that's it."
Last night the dancers' leader Bekka Batchelor expressed her sadness at Tamplin's decision.
She said: "Obviously we're disappointed the cheerleading isn't going ahead but we're still great friends with Billericay Town - there's no bad feeling at all.
"It's just a shame because we've got a fantastic team already to go, but with no-one to cheer for."
The cheerleaders included Leah Torrington, Melissa Mcallister, Molly Simmonds and Jodie Hall.
Jodie is not believed to be one of the girls who texted a player.
The girls had previously told of their joy at being chosen.
Leah had tweeted: "Over the moon that I've been offered a place on @DollsAgencyUK dance/cheer squad @TheRicays. Cannot wait for training/our first event".
The players are not believed to have been sanctioned for getting friendly with the girls.
Last night a source close to devout Christian Glenn confirmed that he had caught one of the cheerleaders messaging her number to a player.
The source said: "Glenn had been having second thoughts about the cheerleaders as it didn't fit with his family club image.
"He was also wary that he runs girls and women's football teams and wanted to project the right image.
Players warming up here at
💙💙💙💙💙💙💙💙💙💙💙💙💙💙

"When he found out about the number exchange he was worried it was the shape of things to come.
"He doesn't want anything distracting his players - he is so determined to make his dream of promotion come true." Steel tycoon Tamplin - who is worth an estimated $5.9 million - took over the club last December.
His takeover has seen gates rise from 400 to nearly 2,000.
He has ploughed $2.6 million into it and Towie star and TV presenter Mark Wright owns a 20 per cent stake in the club.
Tamplin has also signed a dozen top non-league players in a bid to win promotion this season.
Billericay Town confirmed its ambition yesterday with the signature of former Liverpool winger Pennant, 34 - who set up a goal in a pre-season friendly for the side last weekend.
Billericay are currently in the 7th tier of soccer pyramid.
Tamplin set a target of three promotions in seven years - which would take his side into the English Football League.
He stunned non-league soccer last season by snapping up former England defender Konchesky, 36, and ex-Tottenham and Wolves midfielder O'Hara, 30.
But his big money backing of the Bostik Premier League club has led to green-eyed rivals dubbing the club 'Towie Town' and 'The Harlow Globetrotters'.
A spokesman for Billericay Town declined to comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn, 45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly Simmonds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Tamplin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harlow Globetrotters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jermaine Pennant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Hara, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Wright</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Konchesky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOWIE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick GysinThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bostik Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tottenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Glenn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamplin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leah Torrington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billericay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DollsAgencyUK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Semi-pro Billericay Town</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie O'Hara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Football League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Official Cheerleaders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Towie Town</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TheRicays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Pattinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa McAllister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essex</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billericay Town</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Ham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bekka Batchelor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
