<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424649284479420</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/collingwoods-daniel-wells-making-a-difference-20170804-gxpkgz.html</url>
  <title>Wells making a difference</title>
  <content>
North Melbourne have for much of this year been viewed through the prism of the club's decision to move on Brent Harvey, Drew Petrie, Nick Dal Santo and Michael Firrito. The Roos have headed into the final month of the home-and-away season third-bottom, clearly rebuilding. North coach Brad Scott said at the time of the decisions that all four were "capable of playing some really good footy in 2017". While the veterans might have made a sizeable difference had they played in the five Roos losses by under a goal earlier this season, clearly it was a long-term play.
What though of North's other departed 2016 veteran? The one they did offer a new contract. If the stats are anything to go by, North could be knocking on the door of the top eight had Wells opted to stay at Arden Street. Just ask Collingwood.

Up Next

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

03:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Collingwood and Adelaide thriller comes down to post-siren shot

2017's penchant for tight finishes threw up another dramatic match as the Crows attempted to overhaul a huge deficit at the MCG.

Without Wells this season, the Magpies are one win and eight losses. When he plays it's six wins, two losses and last weekend's draw against Adelaide. Delve deeper and the figures reinforce the reputation Wells had earned over 14 seasons at the Roos, that when fit, he is a class above, even at 32.
Of all AFL players classified by Champion Data as midfielder/forwards and who average 20 disposals a game, Wells is the leader in score assistants and score involvements, placing him ahead of players of the ilk of Chad Wingard, Travis Boak and Luke Dahlhaus. It's this impact that has drawn praise this week, but paradoxically, also led to criticism. Melbourne great Garry Lyon argued on SEN earlier this week that the fact Wells turned up unfit to his first pre-season at Collingwood could end up costing Magpies coach Nathan Buckley his job given Wells' influence in a couple of close finishes earlier in the season may have edged the Pies into the top eight. Wells' agent Liam Pickering, the man who helped secure the West Australian a three-year deal at the Holden Centre, this week defended his client.

"He [came back] exactly like he has been every year he's come back from pre-season. He wasn't fat. But he'd had a bit of extra time off because of his length of time in the game," Pickering said.
"But he's as light as he's ever been now."

Calf issues meant Wells didn't play at senior level for Collingwood until Anzac Day, by which time the club was already on the back foot at 1-3. He had another calf setback in round 11, not returning until round 17. In his absence, the Magpies didn't win a game, and were all but eliminated from finals contention.
"You can't do much about doing a calf. That can happen when you step up his loading in training," Pickering said.Photo: Fairfax Media
"It's not his fault that they had a start of the year where they struggled to get over the line. But there were games where he wasn't playing, and I guess the criticism came 'that he wasn't playing, and if he was they would have won'."
Whether you agree that Wells was at fault for not turning up in immaculate condition following an off-season trip to the Middle East, there is little doubt he remains a danger when he plays.Photo: Joe Armao
"He's proven in the games he's played that he's a class act in their footy team," Pickering said.
"It's as simple as that. They look a much better team. They look a much quicker team. Not just because of his pace but because of his decision making."
On Saturday night, Wells confronts his former for club for the first time since his defection. It's hard to imagine Scott could take the threat posed by Wells lightly. "We've got a massive amount of respect [for him]. Especially on the game he played last week," Scott said on Friday.
"We know him very very well, we know what does well. And that can be a little bit daunting at times, too."
Pickering said Wells would relish the challenge of playing against his former club, even though the North side named to face the Pies features just 12 of the players from the team that lost to Adelaide in last year's elimination final. "They'll know his strengths and weaknesses," Pickering said.
"They'll know how dangerous he can be. They'll no doubt have a plan for him. But if he's switched on, and I'm sure he will be, he's going to take some holding."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arden Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Armao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pickering</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champion Data</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Dahlhaus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Boak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Firrito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Dal Santo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Pickering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
