<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424206902841213</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/near-miss-terror-suspects-built-bomb-using-parts-sent-through-the-post-by-isis-20170804-gxp8g7</url>
  <title>'Most sophisticated plots that has ever been attempted'</title>
  <content>
Two Sydney men charged with terrorism offences used military grade explosives sent through the post by Islamic State operatives to build a fully functioning bomb before aborting an attempt to smuggle it on board an Etihad flight, police allege.
The suspects were also working on building a device to release chemical gas, possibly on public transport but AFP Deputy Commissioner Michael Phelan said  had been "completely disrupted".
"This is one of the most sophisticated plots that has ever been attempted on Australian soil," he said.
"If it hadn't been of the great work of our intelligence agencies and law enforcement over a very quick period of time, then we could well have a catastrophic event in this country."

The two charged men, Khaled Khayat, 49 of Lakemba, and Mahmoud Khayat, 32 of Punchbowl, who are reported to be brothers, were refused bail during a hearing at Parramatta Local Court, with the case adjourned to November 14.

They, along with two other men, were arrested last Saturday. Brother-in-law Khaled Merhi remains in custody under anti-terror laws while his brother Abdul Merhi, 50, was released without charge on Tuesday.
Mr Phelan said the charged duo had attempted to plant an improvised explosive device, or IED, on board an Etihad flight bound for Abu Dhabi on July 15, 11 days before Australian intelligence authorities learned of the plot following a tip-off from foreign spy agencies.
Police allege Khaled Khayat was going to use another of his brothers as an unwitting mule to carry the bomb in his luggage but the IED did not proceed past the airport check in counter. Mr Phelan said there was lots of theories on why the attack was aborted, including whether the bomb exceeded luggage weight limits or would-be terrorists lost their nerve.
Mr Phelan stressed at no time did the bomb enter the airport's "security envelope", such as X-ray scanning or metal detectors. He said in the wake of the plot, police had built a replica device and it was detected 100 per cent of the time by airport security, suggesting the real bomb would also have been picked up.

The components, including explosives, for the homemade bomb had been sent via air cargo from Turkey by an IS commander in Syria who had been instructing the men since at least April on how to build the bomb. Khalad Khayat was put in touch with the commander by a third brother who is a senior IS member in Syria.
Mr Phelan said after the airplane bomb plot was abandoned, the men started building a chemical bomb to disperse potentially deadly hydrogen sulphide gas, potentially on public transport. 
The plotters had some precursor chemicals and had conducted experiments but Mr Phelan said the cell had not identified a specific target and were a long way off completing the device.
Justice Minister Michael Keenan said air cargo screening had been stepped up after the terror group was able to send material to Australia. 

"The important thing that people should take from this is that we stopped this from occurring and at no time were our airport and security arrangements compromised," he said.
"I understand that Australians will feel very unnerved about hearing this news and the police allege that we have been the target of a very serious ISIL plot, but I do want to remind everyone that this is the 13th time, because of the excellence of our law enforcement agencies, that we have been able to stop a terrorist attack from occurring on Australian soil in the past three years."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IED</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Minister Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khalad Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP Deputy Commissioner Michael Phelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat, 49, of Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Phelan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Khayat, 32, of Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
