<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424554795197428</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/athletics/zoe-buckman-raring-to-go-ahead-of-london-world-championships-2017-20170803-gxox57.html</url>
  <title>Zoe Buckman raring to go ahead of London World Championships 2017</title>
  <content>
 The man who took Cathy Freeman to Olympic gold is gunning to make 1500m specialist Zoe Buckman the first Australian women to run under four minutes.
The Canberra export will begin her second world championships campaign in the early hours of Saturday morning on the same track she made her Olympic debut under renowned coach Nic Bideau in London 2012.
Buckman finished 10th in the London semis, before going one place better at the Rio Olympics and after an injury free preparation the 28-year-old is gunning for her second world championship final.
The dual Olympian finished seventh in the 2013 world championships final and after running a personal best 4:03.22 last year, Buckman is raring to go ahead of London.
"I've had a full year of training since Rio and feel really well prepared. We've just come out of a camp in Spain where we trained at altitude for two weeks," Buckman said.

"We had some good weather and did some fast work and I'm feeling good. We try to peak at the right time and I'm feeling nice and fresh for three rounds, not just one."
Bideau runs Melbourne Track Club and is one of the best known figures in Australian athletics for his infamous tough love approach, but also an uncanny ability to make ordinary athletes extraordinary.
"Nic does as much as he can to help you but he also gives you a certain degree of independence because ultimately that's what makes you stronger as an athlete," Buckman said.
"You can't just rely on one person to guide you every step of the way and tell you what to do, at the end of the day you've got to put your head down and get on with it yourself and he's really good at finding that balance.
"There's a lot of psychology involved and he connects with lots of people and seems to be drawing more athletes into Melbourne Track Club who bring good energy to the group.
"We all get along and don't stress, there's no drama and we all work together to focus on the bigger picture of competing against the best in the world. It's a real team environment."
Buckman has raced at the elite level for more than a decade but admits her body still fills with nerves leading into big races.
"Sometimes you feel horrible in the warm up and like you can't run a step let alone 1500m, but once I get to the line I focus on the job and the adrenalin kicks in," Buckman said.
"The energy of the crowd lifts me because I like knowing people are watching and I think about my family and friends back home in Canberra, they know how important it is to me and that my whole year shapes towards this race.
"There's a little bit of luck involved in these races and I have some doubts but that's healthy, I've just got to try and focus for those few minutes I'm out there so that I can walk away knowing I've given it my best."
Buckman will race at 3:30am on Saturday and Sunday on Foxtel channel Eurosport.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Bideau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Buckman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London World Championships 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bideau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eurosport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckman</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Track Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
