<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424683644218253</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/paolo-sebastian-fashion-goes-on-show/8775658</url>
  <title>Paolo Sebastian creator Paul Vasileff's fashion designs go on show at SA Art Gallery</title>
  <content>
As a kid, Paul Vasileff would wander through the wings of the Art Gallery of South Australia, admiring different masterpieces.
It never crossed his mind that, one day, he would be looking at his own collection.
"To think that now my work is going to be showing here and people are going to be coming to see it is a surreal and wonderful feeling," he said.
"I'm very honoured."
Mr Vasileff's renowned fashion label, Paolo Sebastian, is celebrating its 10th birthday with a special exhibition at the Art Gallery of South Australia.
The carefully crafted couture designs will feature in the Melrose Wing from October as part of the Adelaide Fashion Festival.
"My view on fashion is that it is an art form so I think that it deserves to be shown in our gallery," Mr Vasileff said.

It's been a big year for Mr Vasileff, who was named Young Australian of the Year and last night awarded an Entrepreneur of the Year prize in Adelaide.
He takes pride in knowing his gowns are made locally in Adelaide.
"I would really like people to have more of an appreciation of where their clothes are coming from and how they're manufactured and who's making their clothes," he said.
From catwalk to gallery walls

The announcement coincides with the creation of a new gallery fund, to acquire and exhibit more examples of Australian and international fashion.
It's part of a renewed push by the gallery to strengthen its relationship with the fashion industry.
"This gallery is really committed to building and developing a fashion collection," gallery director Nick Mitzevich said.
"The exhibition will demonstrate why fashion is such an important element of art and craft and design in the 21st century."
The gallery's fashion collection currently numbers about 600, with the earliest dress from 1780.
"The collection has been dormant for many years but with the great snowballing effect that's happening in Adelaide ... it's a great opportunity to draw attention to this collection," Mr Mitzevich said.
"[We want] to make sure that we make the best use of it and to make sure that we help promote Australian fashion."

Premier Jay Weatherill, who announced the Paolo Sebastian exhibition, said South Australia was proving to be a driving force in the fashion industry, with Mr Vasileff helping to put it on the map.
"Over that period he has really created some magnificent and beautiful fashions that we'll all have an opportunity to enjoy," the Premier said.
The exhibition will run from October 7 through to December 10.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Fashion Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Vasileff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Mitzevich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mitzevich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Art Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entrepreneur of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paolo Sebastian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Vasileff</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melrose Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Gallery of South</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Australian of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
