<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424610629773096</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/breaking-news/right-to-life-hit-vic-premiers-electorate/news-story/dd9115b6095fb150fce1cf11f771e70b</url>
  <title>Anti-euthanasia flyers hit Vic Prem's seat</title>
  <content>
A "mischievous" and "misleading" Right To Life campaign that's drawn the ire of Labor MPs has hit Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews' electorate.
Right To Life are dropping 270,000 pamphlets throughout nine electorates, including Mr Andrews' seat of Mulgrave and six other Labor seats.
The flyer questions the government's proposed assisted dying laws and is emblazoned with the name of each respective local MP, causing confusion about the author.
"That rather mischievous, almost misrepresentation of who the author of that pamphlet was, that's not particularly fair, I don't think that's right, it doesn't add to the debate," Mr Andrews told ABC Central Victoria on Friday.
He later went on to tell reporters the flyer was "grossly misrepresentative" of a report completed by an expert panel and the subsequent proposed assisted dying scheme.
The Right To Life flyer reads "Do you believe in suicide prevention or suicide assistance from a doctor?"
It also contains MP contact information in large, bold type, with the Right To Life contact information in much smaller print on the back.
Bentleigh MP Nick Staikos, who is undecided on how he will vote, has copped abuse after the flyer started circulating his electorate with his details inside, making some readers believe he was the author.
He said he was disgusted with the campaign and could see why constituents were confused.
The flyer has also been sent to Mordialloc, Cranbourne, Invanhoe, Carrum and Macedon - all held by Labor - as well as Shepparton, held by independent Suzanna Sheed and Ripon, where Liberal Louise Staley sits.
Right To Life President Margaret Tighe stood by the campaign, saying international assisted dying schemes are unsafe and can lead to people being killed without their consent.
"It's not mischievous," she told AAP.
"You shouldn't kill people just because they're sick or they want you to kill them."
The government hopes to introduce legislation to parliament that would allow terminally ill Victorians to choose when they die, in accordance with strict guidelines including that they have less than 12 months to live.
Mr Andrews changed his mind on assisted dying after watching his father's terminal battle with cancer.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Right To Life</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Louise Staley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzanna Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-euthanasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Central Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh MP Nick Staikos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shepparton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic Prem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulgrave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life President Margaret Tighe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mordialloc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ripon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invanhoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
