<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424683644218232</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/vic-police-recall-16m-faulty-holsters/news-story/ecebb7e84c22a63e8817fb4bc6ad6a0a</url>
  <title>Victoria Police's $1.6m gun holster bungle</title>
  <content>
Victorian taxpayers have forked out $1.6 million for thousands of faulty new police gun holsters but the force insists no one is to blame for the bungle.
Problems were identified with the custom-made holsters during training last week and Victoria Police have since announced a recall while it is determined if the 18,000 semi-automatic gun holders can be modified.
A safety alert was issued and some 350 frontline officers across the state will reshuffle their shifts until they are all equipped and trained with the previous model holsters by August 13.
"There will be no impact on our police response and operational shifts will continue to run as usual," Victoria Police said in a statement, confirming the $1.6 million price tag, but declining to name the supplier.
"No one is at fault here. The holster was designed in collaboration with Victoria Police," they say.
"We will be looking into this further to understand how the issue ... wasn't picked up during the trial."
The new holsters were designed as an improvement on the old model, to which officers will revert.
No officers have been injured or firearms accidentally discharged because of the issue.
Some 400 police staff are using the holsters as trainers or academy recruits.
"We can easily contain this group and eliminate any risks," the statement reads.
A previous five-year contract for holsters was valued at nearly $3 million when the tender was awarded in 2011.
Premier Daniel Andrews told reporters the issue was an operational matter for Victoria Police.
"But I can say there are small number of holsters where there is a minor fault with one of the safety features," he said.
"There are two safety features on each and every one of these holsters, so they are still safe."
The opposition wants to know what went wrong.
"This is a $1.6 million blunder and it occurs while Daniel Andrews is presiding over record crime wave and whilst he's falsely claiming he's giving police all the resources they need," opposition police spokesman Edward O'Donohue said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward O'Donohue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police's $1.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
