<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423996449440408</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/kaley-cuoco-and-her-boyfriend-karl-cook-have-quietly-travelled-australia-for-the-past-week/news-story/995c49094f76deca105c862a854e0754</url>
  <title>Big Bang star's secret Aussie getaway</title>
  <content>
KALEY Cuoco has been travelling our great southern land for the past week and, if it wasn't for her recent post on Instagram, no one would've had any idea.
The Big Bang Theory star has managed to fly completely under the radar during her time in Australia, somehow evading paparazzi at airports and even heading to an AFL game with 11,000 other people.
The 31-year-old actress has jetted all over Australia with her boyfriend Karl Cook and his family, clearly enjoying all the sights and activities on offer.
Cuoco appeared to fly in a week ago and, after a classic cruise around Sydney Harbour, she headed to the Greater Western Sydney AFL game on July 29.
The actress and her boyfriend seemed to be keen supporters of the Sydney team, decking themselves out in the team's merchandise.
After they polished off their quick visit to Sydney, Cuoco and the Cook family flew to Uluru, going on a hike around the monolith and heading to Bruce Munro's art installation Field of Light.
During their time in the Red Centre, the couple, who have been dating since early 2016, posed at a camel farm and even managed to do the entire hike around Uluru - a whopping 10km ring.
Cook posted a video of his girlfriend clearly struggling on the walk, captioning it "My goal was to video @normancook 's borderline crab walk down the rock face, little did I know it would end up sweet and loving. Lesson of the day; life is full of surprises."
"A beautiful, easy walk through the Australian outback," Cuoco tells the camera sarcastically.
The family also headed to the Sound of Silence dinner at Field of Light, a camel tour which costs
Their visit was full of every Aussie experience imaginable.
Cuoco posed with a joey, the family dressed up in convict outfits and appeared to go on a bushtucker walk with indigenous Australians in Uluru.
The actress clearly enjoyed her quick trip down under, posting loved-up snaps of her and Cook and captioning her Australia gallery, "We didn't have any fun at all on this trip 🇦🇺✈️✨ thank you Cook family for another trip of a lifetime ... and thank you @mrtankcook for being you".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SOUND OF SILENCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaley Cuoco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Field of Light</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bang Theory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuoco</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Munro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
