<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423867600420059</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/realestate/90-million-kingston-park-development-to-receive-28-million-in-federal-government-funding/news-story/ef302cb567ce08fe1c6047ca8976532b</url>
  <title>Federal funds secured for Kingston Park</title>
  <content>
THE redevelopment of the former Kingston High School will finally receive Federal Government funding.
Kingborough mayor Steve Wass and Liberal senator for Tasmania Eric Abetz have announced a $2.8 million grant for the project through the Building Better Regions Fund.
The council had on three previous occasions applied for Federal funding under the National Stronger Regions Fund but each time was unsuccessful.
Cr Wass said he was thrilled the project was finally successful.
"We are certainly delighted because what this Federal funding will do is bring this project forward," he said.
"Our community is out there waiting for it to happen and we can now say that it is happening and I think it will be well received in the community."
The grant is half of what is required to start construction on the $90 million project, called Kingston Park.
The development of the 11.4ha site - which is larger than Macquarie Point - is planned to include a town square, cultural and sporting spaces, meeting rooms, a cafe, occasional daycare facilities, car parking and 4ha of public open space and has been touted as the regional headquarters of southern Tasmania.
It will also create 640 jobs, helping the municipality address the 850 jobs that were lost when Vodafone moved to Hobart.
Senator Abetz the project would make Kingborough a self-contained community.
"I'm just pleased as a local ratepayer to have been involved with the local council in asking the Federal Government for the money," he said.
"These projects are funded all around Australia, we can't fund them all. We do go through a rigorous process but it is nice to see the Kingborough Council achieve this which now gives us a kickstart too."
Work is expected to begin on the development next year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingborough Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Wass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingborough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Better Regions Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Wass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Stronger Regions Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
