<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424086643754692</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/standoff-over-sydney-homeless-tent-city/news-story/1569ac1742e9fa6d9dcb9c179ae14835</url>
  <title>Standoff over Sydney homeless tent city</title>
  <content>
Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore is refusing to blink over a tent city in Martin Place, telling the government the homeless people won't be moved until she's assured there's a long-term housing solution.
Police Commissioner Mick Fuller and Social Housing Minister Pru Goward on Friday called on Ms Moore to "step up" and resolve the issue following a meeting at Sydney Town Hall.
But Ms Moore told reporters she had given a list of demands to the state government and wouldn't even consider taking action until they were met.
"The situation is they don't want to do it, they all want me to do it and I will only consider doing it if I know that accommodation for those in Martin Place and long-term solutions to homelessness and affordable housing (are in place)," the lord mayor said.
Ms Goward is surprised and disappointed by the standoff.
The minister said if the state government was to act it would first have to go to court.
"We would have to then issue warrants on vulnerable, homeless people to get them to move, I don't think anybody wants that," she told reporters.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Housing Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
