<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424730888859306</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/sa-chiropractor-accused-of-indecently-filming-women-and-teenagers-released-on-home-detention-bail/news-story/479978646ac15179bd0048ba58f25b6f</url>
  <title>Chiropractor accused of indecently filming patients</title>
  <content>
A CHIROPRACTOR accused of indecently filming women and teenagers has been granted bail - on the condition he does not return to the health and fitness industry.
The man, 50, who cannot be named due to legal restrictions, was released on Friday after his mother agreed to lodge $40,000 cash with the Adelaide Magistrates Court to guarantee his bail.
He has yet to plead to multiple counts of manufacturing and possessing child exploitation material and indecent filming.
It is alleged the man created the exploitation material, and conducted the filming, while working as a physical therapist operating out of his eastern suburbs home.
On Friday, Magistrate Alfio Grasso released the man on strict home detention bail, ordering he surrender his passport and not take up work in the health or fitness industry.
He ordered the man forfeit an additional $5000 of his own money, and his brother a further $5000, should he breach any of his conditions.
The man will face court again in October.

The cracking chiro campaign may turn you off going to the chiropractor

Hollywood chiropractor demonstrates his cracking technique
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Alfio Grasso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
