<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424773838533013</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-ideas/weird-and-wacky/pilot-draws-boeing-plane-over-us-with-flight-path/news-story/87c07db427031aa78d485f1e338d19b1</url>
  <title>Pilot draws Boeing plane over US with flight path</title>
  <content>
Boeing 787-10 Dreamliner and 737 MAX 9 fly together in dramatic display
2:04

Watch the Boeing 737 MAX 9 and 787-10 Dreamliner soar together as they show off their advanced designs, superior performance and sheer beauty. Courtesy: YouTube/Boeing

June 19th 2017
2 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Travel - News.com.au/

Pilot draws Boeing plane over US with flight path. Image: Flightradar24

Share

A CHEEKY pilot decided to have a little fun during an engine testing exercise of a Boeing 787-800 Dreamliner, drawing a picture in the sky with the flight path.
The Boeing pilot was putting the new aircraft through an endurance test to ensure it was passenger-ready when it became apparent that's not all that was happening. The pilot was also drawing a virtual plane with the flight pattern over the United States.
The self-portrait was documented by air traffic tracker Flightradar24, who published it on Twitter.
The aircraft begins to take shape
This  has been drawing a giant  for 13 hours now!
Live link:
After an 18-hour, 22-state test flight,  is back on the ground.
📼
This isn't the first time Boeing pilots have gotten creative in the air. When Boeing took one of its 737 MAX test frames for a nine-hour endurance test, it wrote a message with its flight path.
The airline manufacturer has also drawn the Boeing logo and a large '12' in support of NFL team, the Seattle Seahawks.
This isn't the first time  has used an endurance flight test to accomplish a bit of sky art.
In the past, Boeing has also drawn a 787 plus the Boeing logo and a large '12' in support of the .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle Seahawks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube/Boeing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAX 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing 737 MAX 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dreamliners</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FlightRadar24</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
