<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424425946176801</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/margaret-river-pro-set-to-return-to-world-surf-league-calender/8774758</url>
  <title>Margaret River Pro set to return to World Surf League calendar</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

The World Surf League will return to Margaret River for at least the next two years, ending speculation the future of the popular event was in doubt.
WA's minister for tourism Paul Papalia confirmed the event which is said to generate $5.4million in "economic impact" to the region-will remain on the WSL's calendar at a press conference from Surfers Point, Margaret River.
World champions Stephanie Gilmore and John John Florence were among many of the touring professionals to throw their support behind the famed south west tourist destination remaining on tour as its future hung in the balance ahead of this year's event.
"It's definitely one of the events with the most variety of waves that allows us to surf in all conditions," Florence told the ABC's  earlier this year.
"It's one of my favourite places to come to on the whole tour."
Gilmore said the location represented "authentic Australia," catering for surfers with a sense of "adventure,".
"This is a dream destination for surfers who love adventure and to me, this area really represents authentic Australia," Gilmore said.
"This event should stay."
Both men's and women's divisions will return with organisers retaining access to a surf break at nearby Gracetown as a second backup location.

This year's event was blessed with ideal conditions and created international headlines after a men's final was put on hold due to schooling fish and shark sightings.
The event is one of three for the Australian leg of the World Surf League's international tour, with stops also at Snapper Rocks and Bells Beach.
Money earner for region

Mr Papalia said the event was a huge drawcard for local tourism and a chance to showcase the region's natural beauty.
"Along with the thousands of spectators, competitors and officials who head to Margaret River for the event, a massive global audience follows the world class action," Mr Papalia said.
"This is fantastic exposure for the region's stunning coastline, natural wonder and powerful surf breaks."
Mr Papalia said the event was also a huge money-earner for the world famous region.
"The Margaret River Pro delivers $5.4 million in annual economic impact to the south-west region," Mr Papalia said.
"Retaining the event is so important for WA's professional surfers and our next generation of champions."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilmore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Papalia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gracetown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John John Florence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Papalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapper Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Surf League</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret River Pro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bells Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfers Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Gilmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret River</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
