<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424812493239345</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/accounting/remaining-old-guard-cpa-directors-to-follow-alex-malley-and-step-down-20170804-gxplk6</url>
  <title>Remaining 'old guard' CPA directors to follow Alex Malley and step down </title>
  <content>
The five remaining long-time CPA Australia directors have capitulated to the pressure of an ongoing campaign to see them all replaced and have announced they will all be gone by the end of the year.
CPA will also offer its public practice members, who will all lose their protection from multimillion-dollar malpractice lawsuits for at least six months from October, additional insurance coverage for free.
The accounting body will also expand its Nomination and Remuneration Committee to now include three external members along with chairman Jim Dickson and director Tim Youngberry.
The announcements, sent to members on Friday afternoon, comes after a Senate committee on Wednesday announced it would call them to appear and explain their actions .

A member petition has been circulating calling for an emergency meeting to spill the board while 16 past leaders have also called for the current board to resign.

Chairman Mr Dickson said the move was to allow an orderly succession to a new board.
"Over the past few months the board has focused on key initiatives to position CPA Australia for the future. We want CPA Australia to be strong, unified and forward looking. The orderly succession of Directors is another major step in achieving this objective," he said.
CPA directors Graeme Wade and Michele Dolin will both retire early from the board on 30 September. Fellow director Richard Petty and temporarily appointed director Tim Youngberry had already been planning to retire on the same day. Chairman Jim Dickson and director Sharon Portelli will also retire early, on December 31.
Mr Wade and Mr Petty have both been on the board since 2006 and were close associates of Alex Malley, the former CEO of the accounting body who was fired with a $4.9 million golden handshake in June.

The Nomination and Remuneration Committee, currently made up of CPA board members, will now include Rhonda O'Donnell, a Trustee Director at MTAA Super and member of the RMIT Council, and Leanne Rowe, a former non-executive director at Medibank and former Deputy Chancellor at Monash University, and lawyer Geoff Rees.
"The reconstituted Nomination and Remuneration Committee will shortly commence the process of working their way through over 200 applications for nine director positions," Mr Dickson said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Petty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leanne Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Petty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTAA Super</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remuneration Committees</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Youngberry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medibank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Jim Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trustee Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Malley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Portelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michele Dolin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhonda O'Donnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Mr Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Rees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
