<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424812493239357</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834843/munibung-a-new-road-to-super-hub/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Munibung a new road to 'super-hub'</title>
  <content>
MISSING LINK: Munibung Road will be joined together after a $2.2 million federal government pledge. Lake Macquarie City Council has set aside $2.9 million.

GLENDALE and Cardiff will be directly linked together following a $2.2 federal commitment to extend Munibung Road.
Independent MP Greg Piper said the road was a missing link for the region's roads, taking the burden off other areas and speeding up simple trips.
"If someone at the western end of Munibung Road at Cardiff wants to drive to Speers Point or beyond, it's an 11-minute trip," he said.

"The same trip will take only one minute when the missing link is built and that traffic can drive straight through to the new roundabout at Boolaroo."

"Furthermore, this link will take a bit of the load off Lake Road at Argenton and Glendale, and off Hillsborough Road and The Esplanade at Warners Bay and Speers Point."
Mr Piper said he would seek state funds to widen Lake Road at Argenton to four lanes to further improve the road network.
Lake Macquarie City Council invested $2.9 million in the Munibung Road connection earlier this year. They will now work with Ferrier Hodgson to begin construction. 

Lake Macquarie mayor Kay Fraser said the 700-metre stretch of new road would provide an important transport link between Glendale and Cardiff.

"This announcement demonstrates the continued high levels of confidence that both the government and businesses have in Glendale and Cardiff," Cr Fraser said. 
"This project, together with the Lake Macquarie Transport Interchange, has the potential to establish Glendale-Cardiff as a new employment super-hub and regional transport interchange, and aligns with a future expansion of the light rail network beyond the Newcastle CBD to Glendale."

Shortland MP Pat Conroy applauded the fresh commitment as "a great win for our community" but urged the government to turn its eye towards fully funding the Lake Macquarie Transport Interchange.

The money was allocated as part of the Building Better Regions funding, which will invest $219.5 million into 110 projects outside Australia's capital cities. 

In the Hunter $1.25 million was also pledged towards wine country signage in Cessnock. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Piper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Speers Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillsborough Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter $1.25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Greg Piper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrier Hodgson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardiff</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glendale-Cardiff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munibung Road</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Better Regions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shortland MP Pat Conroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boolaroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argenton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glendale</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie City Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munibung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie Transport Interchange</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
