<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424176838069669</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/broich-ready-to-embark-on-coaching-career/3208854/</url>
  <title>Broich ready to embark on coaching career</title>
  <content>
FOOTBALL: Brisbane Roar legend Thomas Broich has linked with A-League aspirants Brisbane City.
In the first step to perhaps becoming City's first A-League coach should the club gain entry into an expanded national competition, Broich will work with the NPL Queensland club's junior team, be mentored by first-team coach John Kosmina and help shape City's football department.
With the support of City, the 36-year-old two-time Johnny Warren Medallist will return to his native Germany next month to start the process of earning UEFA coaching qualifications.
Broich, who had ankle surgery on Thursday, still isn't ready to ready to announce his playing retirement after not offered a new deal by the Roar at the end of last season.
But he's happy to start his coaching career and will be content to hang up his boots if a playing offer doesn't come his way.
"This is a big opportunity that City have offered me," Broich said.
"I'm super excited about it. It has been a real thrill to engage with so many talented kids in nightly coaching sessions from Brisbane City's academy, NPL teams and joining a session alongside John Kosmina's first team.
"I am really looking forward to be able to contribute to the growth of junior skills and technical development at the club and across the wider game in Australia."
Broich said the Roar would always have a place in heart, but hoped City would eventually join his former club in the A-League.
"Brisbane deserves a second A-League and I'm really impressed with City's bid," he said.
"We've seen in Sydney and Melbourne how having a second team in the city also helps the existing club in that city, and it would be the same here."
City's A-League bid chairman Robert Cavallucci was delighted to get Roar hall-of-famer Broich on board.
"Thomas's exceptional footwork is matched by an exceptional football brain, and I am thrilled that the boys and girls of Brisbane City will experience the benefits of his extraordinary career," Cavallucci said.
"I am equally thrilled that as a club, Brisbane City is able to support Thomas as his career takes a new path."
City president David Asnicar said Broich's involvement in "nurturing" the club's players would "further cement our contribution to growing the beautiful game in Australia".
PROFESSIONAL surfer Julian Wilson says he is enjoying married life
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Magistrate says break-ins frustrate community clubs
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Roar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City's A-League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren Medallist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Cavallucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kosmina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Asnicar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Broich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cavallucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broich</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
