<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424644989512108</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829116/alt-rock-revival-at-the-cambo/?cs=2373</url>
  <title>Alt-rock revival at the Cambo</title>
  <content>
STILL SPARKLING: Everclear are touring their best-selling album So Much For The Afterglow next month.

Everclear frontman Art Alexakis is an accomplished storyteller. So good, in fact, that you can't distinguish fact from fiction in his lyrics.
An example. Fans of 1990s post-grunge alt-rock might be familiar with Everclear's album Sparkle and Fade. I saw the band tour the album at The Metro in Sydney in 1995 along with many other fans of songs like Santa Monica, Heroin Girl, Heartspark Dollarsign and You Make Me Feel Like A Whore.

Knowing that Alexakis had a tough upbringing and had almost died from a heroin overdose, I assumed the lyrics of Heroin Girl were autobiographical. Right?
Wrong. 
"Some of what I write is true but the rest I make up," Alexakis tells Weekender.

"I mean, I'm a writer. That's what I do. I get to make up shit. The job for me is to make all the songs seem like they're real. Even though they may not be true they need to be honest."
In Heroin Girl, Alexakis sings about a girl called Esther who had "two pierced nipples and a black tattoo" and who, among other things, drank Mexican beer and ate Mexican food. She dies from a drug overdose. 
"I love it when people say to me 'Oh I think I met Esther' and I think 'Well, that's funny, because Esther is a name I got out of the Bible and I made that whole song up'," Alexakis says.
"The line 'I heard the policeman say just another overdose' - that actually happened to my mum when my brother died [of a heroin overdose when Alexakis was 12]. And I overdosed many times, and people around me did, so there was truth in the story.
"Look, I did my job."
Yes, he did. And he did it very well.

"A friend of my neighbour's was a heroin dealer, she actually cooked Mexican food and we'd go over there to eat it. That's where that came from. I made this character from different elements of different names," he continues.
"Anyway, that how my mind works. It's just writing."
Sparkle and Fade was followed by Everclear's best-selling album So Much For The Afterglow. The band will play that album in its entirety - plus other fan favourites - on their upcoming Australian tour in celebration of the 20th anniversary of its release. 

Alexakis admits he is "not very critical" of the album, known for hits Everything to Everyone, I Will Buy You a New Life, Father of Mine, So Much For the Afterglow and One Hit Wonder.
"I kind of accept it as it is, warts and all. It's one of the few records where I wouldn't change a thing," he explains. 

TOUR: Art Alexakis and Everclear will be in Australia next month.
"Usually I think 'Oh I could have done this better', or in hindsight sometimes as an artist you can get the cringe factor, but I have very little cringe factor with Afterglow. It's not perfect but it couldn't have been done any other way.
"Does that make sense without sounding pretentious? It's like you have a big slobbery dog that farts a lot but you wouldn't trade it for the world."

ALT-ROCK: The original Everclear line-up in 1995.
The '90s was a melting pot of musical styles and sounds. There was a lot going on but Everclear, in the only remaining original band member's words, "carved out its own little niche". 
"People called it alternative but to me it's rock 'n' roll. I was hearing rock 'n' roll on the radio again and I loved it," Alexakis says. 
"I grew up in the '70s with bands like Zeppelin and Cheap Trick on the radio and in the '90s it kind of repeated itself.

"I hear there is something going on in Australian music right now which is good to hear because in the States it's bad. There's, like, two bands that I like on the radio - Highly Suspect and Royal Blood - and they're both on their second album and one of them is from the UK. Some of the up-and-coming bands really need to get out there, push their work on the labels."
Maybe Alexakis could help open a few doors for them?

He pauses.
"Nah, I'm too tired. And it's too much f - - - ing work."

Catch Everclear at The Cambridge on September 30. Tickets are on sale now.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Alexakis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Blood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bible</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Much For</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heroin Girl</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Make Me Feel Like A Whore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Buy You</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh I</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everclear</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Monica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheap Trick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Hit Wonder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esther</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highly Suspect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heartspark Dollarsign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexakis</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zeppelin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alt-rock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
