<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424778133500471</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/was-driver-behind-horror-bruce-hwy-fatal-driving-d/3208960/</url>
  <title>Was driver behind horror Bruce Hwy fatal driving dangerously?</title>
  <content>
A JURY has ruled the man who swerved across the Bruce Hwy into oncoming traffic in a crash that killed a Sunshine Coast man was not driving dangerously.

Paul Gerard Crimmins, 59, stood trial in the Maroochydore District Court this week, charged with dangerous driving causing death and grievous bodily harm over the Bells Creek crash on November 27, 2015.

Mr Crimmins was driving with his wife from their Lennox Head home to an 80th birthday party in Caloundra when their Nissan Patrol veered from the left northbound lane, cutting off another motorist who was forced to brake and was hit by the following car.

The Patrol continued, without any sign of braking or attempt to turn the vehicle, across the median gully and went airborne as it mounted the oncoming lanes before slamming into the driver's side of Mr Warren's Toyota Landcruiser.

Mr Warren died at the scene, and two rescue helicopters landed on the highway to transport the injured to hospital.

The crash killed Noosaville man Graeme Warren and severely injured his wife Dianne Warren, along with Mr Crimmins and his wife Gail Crimmins.

The jury returned the not-guilty verdict about 2pm yesterday, after five hours of deliberations over two days.

Mr Crimmins made written admissions to causing the crash, but the prosecution could not prove beyond reasonable doubt that Mr Crimmins was driving dangerously.

Both defence barrister Peter O'Connor and crown prosecutor Mark Whitbread told the court in their closing addresses the only reasonable explanation for Mr Crimmins' swerve was that he lost consciousness.

The prosecution's case hinged on whether Mr Crimmins had any warning before he fell asleep or fell unconscious in the moments before the crash.

Neither Mr Crimmins, Mrs Crimmins or Mrs Warren could remember the moments before the impact, and Mr O'Connor told the jury this week memory loss after a serious crash was common.

Dashcam footage from Mr Crimmins' car and testimony from witnesses including Mr Crimmins and the investigating police officer formed the main evidence base during the trial.

Mr Whitbread suggested in his closing address that dashcam footage showing Mr Crimmins making slight deviations to the left indicated he was becoming drowsy, and the radio becoming louder in the footage indicated he turned the volume up to keep himself awake.

Mr O'Connor said the suggestions were "mere speculation" at best, and said there were plenty of reasons drivers or passengers turned up the radio, if that did happen.

He said Mr Crimmins was a careful and experienced driver, and the only fine in his driving history was for a step on a vehicle that was partially covering a numberplate.

Mr Crimmins declined to comment to the media outside the Maroochydore Court House after the verdict.

Both Mr Crimmins' and Mr Warren's family have watched the trial from the public gallery since it began on Tuesday.

Coast's newest eatery opens bringing Italian to the beach
Teen spends big on mum's partner's credit card
One lane closed, traffic banking after two-vehicle smash
Coast researchers welcome govt inspection of white spot studies
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lennox Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitbread</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Gerard Crimmins, 59</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Whitbread</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Warren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Crimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Crimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nissan Patrol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Warren's Toyota Landcruiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Court House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bells Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Connor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dianne Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Crimmins</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
