<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424473190817677</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/mother-fears-queensland-woman-who-died-in-uganda-may-have-been-murdered/news-story/5a3a032e69ed86a4ea944501339847ee</url>
  <title>'I know someone was poisoning her'</title>
  <content>
A QUEENSLAND mother fears her daughter has been murdered in Uganda, with much of the information surrounding her death being withheld by authorities.
Morayfield woman Bronwyn Fielding, who is blind, died suddenly in late June.
The 37-year-old's mother, Lynn, received a phone call at 1am on June 29 informing her of the death. Since that date, authorities both in Uganda and Australia have been tight-lipped about what happened.
Bronwyn's Ugandan husband, Michael Osago, has now left the city of Mbale, where they lived.
Police are now searching for Mr Osago, Lynn said.
She said Mr Osago had told them Bronwyn had died in a nurse's care after he had carried her to hospital.
But the family was later told that Bronwyn's neighbour had actually found her body inside her home. She had died alone, Lynn said.
Her body has now been embalmed and the family fears they will never know how Bronwyn died.
The Fieldings have attempted to get information about her death but were told by the Australian Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade that information would need to be sourced from the Ugandan police.
Attempts to talk to a police officer in the East African nation have proved difficult.
"It's just terrible trying to get anything done," Lynn said.
"DFAT says we have to make direct contact with police. It's impossible. We've been trying for three and a half weeks."
Lynn's fears that Bronwyn has been murdered stem from an incident in 2011 when Bronwyn was poisoned after giving information to police that saw a criminal jailed.
Bronwyn sent messages to her mother in March, in which she said she was fearful that someone was trying to poison her again.
"I know someone was poisoning her," Lynn said.
Bronwyn left Queensland from Uganda seven years ago to join a charity that she thought assisted orphaned children.
Lynn said that Bronwyn soon found out the operation was a scam and the director was jailed after she went to police.
But despite falling severely ill, Bronwyn decided to remain in Uganda to do her own charity work and to stay with Mr Osago, who she wedded four years ago, and their children.
A DFAT spokeswoman said: "The Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade has been providing consular assistance, in accordance with the Consular Services Charter, to the family of an Australian woman who died in Uganda. For privacy reasons we won't provide further comment."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mbale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynn</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ugandan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Department of Foreign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn Fielding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Osago</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Foreign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DFAT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uganda</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn's Ugandan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consular Services Charter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Osago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
