<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424726593891956</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/what-our-politicians-asked-for-ethical-advice-on-last-year-20170802-gxnjc7.html</url>
  <title>What our politicians asked for ethical advice on last year</title>
  <content>
An ACT politician sought advice from ethics and integrity adviser Stephen Skehill on whether it was appropriate to accept an honorary appointment to a foreign entity, it can be revealed.
Another asked if it was okay to undertake travel where some or all of the cost was being covered by a foreign government.Photo: Richard Briggs
Thirteen members sought Mr Skehill's advice on 25 issues in 2016-17, according to a report recently tabled in the ACT Legislative Assembly. 
Mr Skehill has served as the ACT parliament's ethics adviser - a kind of Jiminy Cricket to the Legislative Assembly's politicians - since 2008. He was reappointed to the job until 2021 in February this year.
The matters he gives advice on are confidential but Mr Skehill outlined in general the ethical quandaries members sought clarification on. 
These include dealing with someone not on the lobbyist register; whether it was okay to use Assembly contact details or to refer to a public servant in party-political publications; and the use of government-issued publications while on the election trail.

One politician asked for advice on whether they should talk to a constituent involved in litigation against the government. 
Another asked whether it was appropriate for a member to vote on a matter in which their partner may have had an interest.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr Skehill also gave an advice to a member on whether it was appropriate to occupy a show ministerial role with responsibilities they were personally involved in.
Another piece of advice was given on how a politician's prior employment impacted on their other job. 
Mr Skehill can't release details of the advice he has given to the territory's politicians however the individual politician can. 
Since last election, the Canberra Liberals have released three rulings from Mr Skehill on their possible conflicts with the ACT parliament's code of conduct for members. 
Mark Parton was given the thumbs up to  after leader Alistair Coe sought advice on his behalf.
Mr Parton was again given the all clear after questions arose over his continuing appearance in Rolfe Honda ads he'd recorded prior to being elected. 
, as he is a committee member in the parliamentary inquiry the Land Development Agengy's Glebe Park and lakefront land deals. 
Mr Skehill told Mr Coe it was not necessary to stand aside from the inquiry, but he should disclose the relationships to the inquiry upfront.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Skehill</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Coe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legislative Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Skehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Legislative Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Land Development Agengy's Glebe Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Parton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jiminy Cricket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Parton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Coe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rolfe Honda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Briggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
