<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424816788206740</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/2017/08/04/prince-henrik-denmark-burial/</url>
  <title>Prince Henrik of Denmark refuses to be buried next to his wife</title>
  <content>
Prince Henrik of Denmark has elected not to be buried next to his wife, Queen Margrethe of Denmark, when his time comes because he's still upset that he never received the title of 'King'.
Prince Henrik, 83, married the Queen, 77, in 1967 and became the Queen's Prince Consort.
In Denmark, the wife of a male monarch can become queen but the husband of a female monarch cannot be called anything higher than prince.
The director of communications for the Danish royals confirmed in a statement to Danish publication . the Prince's decision to forego the couple's specially designed sarcophagus in Denmark's Roskilde Cathedral.
"It is true that Prince Henrik has decided that he will not be buried in Roskilde Cathedral as planned otherwise," the spokesperson said.
"It is no secret that the Prince for many years has been unhappy with his role, and the title he has been awarded in the Danish monarchy. This discontent has grown more and more in recent years.
"The Prince loves Denmark and has worked for Denmark for more than 50 years. The Prince will therefore also be buried in Denmark, but the circumstances are not in place yet."
The spokesperson said the Queen acknowledged her husband's decision and "agrees with it".
In October 2015, the Prince voiced his discontent to French newspaper Le Figaro.
"It makes me angry that I am subjected to discrimination," he said.
"Denmark, which is otherwise known as an avid defender of gender equality, is apparently willing to consider husbands as worth less than their wives."
Prince Henrik and Queen Margrethe are the parents of Crown Prince Frederik, who is married to Australian, Crown Princess Mary.
Prince Frederik is heir apparent to the throne of Denmark, and Princess Mary will become Queen when he ascends to the throne.
Prince Henrik retired from official duties last year and has spent most of his time since in France, where he was born, at his private vineyard.
As part of his retirement, Prince Henrik gave up the title of 'Prince Consort' and is now known simply as Prince Henrik.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen, 77</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Princess Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Henrik, 83</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roskilde Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Margrethe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Figaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark's Roskilde Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Henrik</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prince Frederik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Margrethe of Denmark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Prince Consort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Henrik of Denmark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Consort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Frederik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
