<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424812493239388</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/gamblers-at-dingley-international-hotel-were-biggest-pokies-spenders-in-kingston-last-year/news-story/bf36de28c503ddd4fb0dcbc278bcd9ff</url>
  <title>Punters spent $14.83m at Dingley pokies venue last year</title>
  <content>
PUNTERS spent $83.02 million at pokies machines across Kingston last year, placing the
region among the worst 10 areas in the state.
It's expenditure the council says is far too high, despite a fall of $450,000 from the
previous financial year.
"Council is concerned about the high density of electronic gaming machines in Kingston,
the large amounts of money lost and the negative impacts on the community resulting from
problem gambling," community sustainability general manager Mauro Bolin said.
"It's incredibly concerning Kingston has again been listed in the state's worst areas for
pokies losses."
Of the 16 pokies venues in Kingston, eight are hotels and eight are clubs, with Dingley
International causing the most damage in 2016-17 when punters spending $14.83 million.
The hotel has 90 pokies that drained an average $164,777 from each punter - almost
double the average loss incurred across the state's 502 venues.
Alliance for Gambling Reform director Tim Costello said real reform would only occur from
an "all hands on deck" approach and congratulated Kingston Council for joining the Alliance.
"With Kingston and Knox joining Monash and Greater Dandenong, the Alliance now has a
formidable group of councils in Melbourne's southeast, which is important because this
has been a region of great poker machine harm," Mr Costello said.
Kingston council wants to prevent new machines and venues from being located in areas of high social disadvantage, placed used by children or young people or near public housing estates, mental health clinics, and major activity hubs.
The State Government is now working on legislation that would regulate the industry over
the next 25 years.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gambling Reform</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mauro Bolin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dingley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONASH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
