<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424782428467833</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/cliches-with-originality/3208961/</url>
  <title>Cliches with originality</title>
  <content>
"I'VE always felt that it's only a cliche if you don't know why you're doing it," The Big Sick's director, Michael Showalter, muses. And with one simple sentence, a hundred rom-com screenwriters withered into nothing.
Showalter knows his romantic comedies, that's for sure. 2014's They Came Together saw him collaborate with long-time writing partner David Wain on a parody which picked the bones of the genre clean like a ravenous hyena. New York is constantly referred to as its own character, lovers come together over a shared passion for "fiction books". No cliche was left unturned.
So perhaps it's not without a hint of irony that Showalter's latest project sees him turn from wry spectator to enthusiastic participant, adapting the true-life love story of comedian Kumail Nanjiani and writer Emily V Gordon for the big screen. With Nanjiani playing himself, and Zoe Kazan as Emily, the film remains just as hilarious as any of Showalter's past work, yet it's also a film that wholeheartedly engages with the genre it's spawned out of.
At the centre of The Big Sick is a relationship fraught with obstacles, the same beating heart of every romantic comedy. Kumail and Emily are first burdened by the cultural differences brought about by the former's traditional Pakistani Muslim upbringing, then by a sudden mystery illness which strikes down the latter. However, Showalter doesn't see this as any kind of grand transition for him, even away from 2001's Wet Hot American Summer, the '80s teen movie parody that he's arguably best known for, and which recently spawned its own Netflix follow-up.
"With Wet Hot American Summer or They Came Together, to me, it's less parody and more absurd," he says. "It's absurdist, it's silly, but there's still drama. The characters do get sad. Underneath everything in The Big Sick, meanwhile, there is still an engine of comedy, of humour. Even when there's nothing funny happening, lurking somewhere deep beneath the surface is the idea that something funny could happen at any moment, because that's the kind of world they live in. It's all just different levels of the same approach, which is to make things as funny as they can be, and as serious and dramatic as they can be."
The Big Sick's emotions may be more sincere, but Showalter admits his experience with the sillier excesses of the genre has taught him much, especially when it comes to the idea of what a cliche actually is. In his eyes, rom-coms are filled with tropes that work beautifully when a writer knows why audiences have such an affection for them, disastrously when applied simply out of some notion that this is how a rom-com should be.
Thankfully, The Big Sick brings its own major subversion of the genre when Emily's mystery illness leaves her hospitalised in a coma, dropping her out of the narrative suddenly. "It would be like if, you know, in When Harry Met Sally, Meg Ryan just went into a coma 30 minutes into the movie," Showalter jokes. "The whole first part of the movie is spent meeting these two characters, having them fall in love, becoming invested in their relationship, but you don't see that what's really happening is that she's going to get sick. And then the movie kind of starts over, and becomes a new movie."
The Big Sick was a surprise hit in the States, both in its much-hyped premiere at this year's Sundance Film Festival and at the US box office.
"This is for people who've had family members be sick, this is for people who've had difficulty with their families and cultural issues, and relationship issues, who've fallen in love, who are trying to decide their careers, made the big decisions that we make as we come of age and make compromises and sacrifices," Showalter says. "We were just trying to make a big movie that could address all those themes."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Sick</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Kazan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistani Muslims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sundance Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wet Hot American Summer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Met Sally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily V. Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showalter</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Showalter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanjiani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kumail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Came Together</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kumail Nanjiani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Wain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
