<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424168248134753</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/zoe-daniel-wrap/8775208</url>
  <title>Donald Trump's week: Leaked transcripts, the White House revolving door and a looming Russia investigation</title>
  <content>
I guess it was inevitable the transcripts of 'that conversation' would emerge eventually from the leaky ship that is Donald Trump's White House.
And when you consider several Trump apparatchiks who would have been privy to what was said have been ejected over the past several weeks, the timing of the leak isn't all that surprising either.
confirm Donald Trump was seriously peeved he'd been saddled with the deal between former president Barack Obama and Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull to take refugees from Australian offshore detention.
"This deal will make me look terrible," the President said.
In truth, the timing was terrible for him politically because he had just announced travel bans on a number of Muslim majority countries on the one hand, while on the other the deal forced him to at least consider accepting about 1,250 people from those very countries.
He feared being forced to adhere to the deal would make him look weak by those who had just elected him for his strength.
However, it's what Malcolm Turnbull said that's more revealing:
"This is a big deal. It is really, really important to us that we maintain it. It does not oblige you to take one person that you do not want".
The Prime Minister's comments validate the concerns of refugee advocates and the refugees themselves that while a "good faith" assessment process was agreed to, there is no requirement for the United States to take any of the people on Manus or Nauru.
In the flurry that followed the conversation, Donald Trump announced so-called 'extreme vetting' would be applied to the group.
Homeland Security staff  but the US refugee quota for this year has already been filled. There's no news yet on whether any of those from Australian detention will get into the US when the new quota period begins.
There have been repeated denials that there was any sort of quid pro quo involved, although we know Australia agreed to consider accepting a handful of South and Central American refugees via a US-led program in Costa Rica.
The Prime Minister alludes to doing something more, but doesn't expand.
"It does not require you to take any. It requires, in return, for us to do a number of things for the United States - this is a big deal, I think we should respect deals," he says in the call.
The transcript confirms an abrupt end to the call.
"You can count on me. I will be there again and again," the Prime Minister says.
"I hope so," Donald Trump replies.
They've been , the Prime Minister displaying the support promised as the President continues to grapple with the niceties, complexities and frustrations of high office.
By the way,  is equally fascinating.
It again illuminates the fact Donald Trump is more concerned about how things look (from the perspective of his supporters), than anything else.
On the much-discussed Mexican wall, he admits Mexico won't pay for it, but asks the President not to say so:
"Because you and I are both at a point now where we are both saying we are not to pay for the wall. From a political standpoint, that is what we will say. We cannot say that anymore because if you are going to say that Mexico is not going to pay for the wall, then I do not want to meet with you guys anymore because I cannot live with that. I am willing to say that we will work it out, but that means it will come out in the wash and that is okay."
Oh brother.
Scaramooched

External Link:

@NickBryantNY: New York tabloids this morning in top form
The week was a revolving door of hirings and firings for the President:

Mooch? Out
Reince? Out
Spicy? Out
Sessions? Pending
Seriously, it's like an extreme version of Survivor:

External Link:

@CahnEmily tweet
Or, maybe even a rom-com:

External Link:

@TheSecondCity tweet: Mooch
Gained a communications director, lost a press secretary, lost a chief of staff, gained a  chief of staff, lost a communications director.

External Link:

@darth: "is this the line for nachos"
That was the whirlwind 10 days of the Anthony Scaramucci era.
He came, he saw, he conquered, he got sacked.
It was intense.
The Mooch promised big things as White House communications director.
He took two big scalps in Sean Spicer and Reince Priebus but in the end his foul-mouthed tirade to the New Yorker was too much (), even for Donald Trump, or at least for incoming Chief of Staff John F Kelly.
Four-star General Kelly, a career marine of 45 years' standing is tasked with injecting some discipline into the troops in the West Wing. The fast-talking Mooch from New York did not fit in, so he was ejected on Day 1.
General Kelly is said to be a confidant of the President. However, how the two will tolerate each other in close quarters as the General tries to bring order to the administration is something to watch.
The President sent Reince on his way with some kind words:

External Link:

@realDonaldTrump: I would like to thank Reince Priebus for his service and dedication to his country. We accomplished a lot together and I am proud of him!
However, the loss of Priebus has been marked as a major turning point for some. Conservative Washington insiders muse without Priebus, Trump is a man without a party.
And not surprisingly, there's a tweet for this occasion too:

External Link:

@realDonaldTrump: 3 Chief of Staffs in less than 3 years of being President: Part of the reason why @BarackObama can't manage to pass his agenda.
To Russia, With Love

Finally, after some delay, the President decided to sign sanctions against North Korea, Iran and Russia - yes Russia - into effect.
The President wasn't happy though.
Take a look at these two releases the White House put out - one where the President keeps his mouth shut and the other where he lashed out at Congress:

External Link:

@evanmcmurry tweet: Signing statement vs. public statement on sanctions bill. One attacks bill's constitutionality, one attacks Congress' negotiating abilities.
Interesting.
For the President, who supposedly was coming to office to mend relations with the Kremlin, it's a cruel blow to those ambitions.
The Russian response was fast and furious:

External Link:

@MedvedevRussiaE: The Trump administration has shown its total weakness by handing over executive power to Congress in the most humiliating way
On Russia, the investigation into Team Trump is heating up, with  as part of his probe into ties between Trump's Campaign and Russia.
While the investigation is a long way from completion, it's a sign Mueller continues to dig deep. , and it's latest report is comprehensive on where the probe is at, including crossing the President's "red line" by looking into financial links with Russia.
What else did you miss this week?

Tim Kaine is still America's Dad:

External Link:

@timkaine: My nephew Terence called his Dad to the kitchen: "Dad, the milk's gone bad!"  This is what he found in the fridge:
Chris Christie got his revenge on fans at the Mets this week:

External Link:

@BennyHutch: At #Cubs #Brewers game. #ChrisChristie was getting razzed by fans, so he got in the face of one of them. 5:30 on @WISN12News
A testy exchange between the White House and CNN (I was in the room for this and can confirm it was tense!):

External Link:

@DaniellaMicaele tweet: WATCH: Here's the entire exchange between Stephen Miller and @Acosta.
New fake news

Speaking of "fake news" - joining the New York Times, CNN and The Washington Post on the President's list of untrustworthy media outlets is, yep, you guessed it: Golf.com. Seriously, he tweeted it.

External Link:

@realDonaldTrump: I love the White House, one of the most beautiful buildings (homes) I have ever seen. But Fake News said I called it a dump - TOTALLY UNTRUE
Why?
Well, according to the article, which will appear in next week's Sports Illustrated magazine, the President says he .
Fortuitously  for the next couple of weeks!
Pickle and Frank's Big Adventures

The White House has continued its trend of reading out "fan mail" at the White House press briefings. This week, we heard from young Frank, who offered to mow the White House lawn free:

External Link:

@jaredrizzi: WH sends along letter from "Frank" - age 10; read at top of today's briefing by @SHSanders45
Hey, Frank, your dream could come true - last week's mailbag winner, 9-year-old "Pickle", , has been invited to tour the residence:

External Link:

Pickle to Fox and Friends: I Wrote to President Trump Because 'I Wanted Him to Be My Friend'
And indeed Frank has been invited to meet the groundsman and help mow the Rose Garden lawn.
By the numbers

4.4 million:  That's the  with Anthony Scaramucci. Not surprising!
Map of the week

So, I'm guessing by now you've heard there's a massive solar eclipse coming later this month. Well, for whatever reason, The Boston Globe put out this, um, enlightening map:

External Link:

@BostonGlobe: The path of viewing spots for this month's solar eclipse cuts overwhelmingly through places that voted for Trump.
Huh?
You've got mail

This week, a "prankster" from the UK, convinced White House personnel he was Jared Kushner and Reince Priebus.  both Homeland Security adviser Tom Bossert and, yep, you guessed it, Anthony Scaramucci in a series of emails.
The highlights?
Fake Jared Kushner inviting Tom Bossert to a "soiree" at the end of August where he promised "food of at least comparible (sic) quality to that which we ate in Iraq".
And, Fake Reince Priebus attacking the real Anthony Scaramucci about ethics:
"I can't believe you are questioning my ethics! The so called 'Mooch', who can't even manage his first week in the White House without leaving upset in his wake. I have nothing to apologize for."
Which reminds me - if you don't - follow @niceDonaldTrump on Twitter. The tweets are a nice change of pace:

External Link:

@niceDonaIdTrump: Lending a hand to the terrific landscapers on the White House South Lawn. Making the yard look great again!
Speaking of a change of pace, the President is off for a couple of weeks' vacation at his golf course in New Jersey from tomorrow.
Do you think we're in for a quiet couple of weeks?

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa Rica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TheSecondCity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Illustrated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramooched</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanted Him</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acosta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>realDonaldTrump: 3 Chief of Staffs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeland Security</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank's Big Adventures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DaniellaMicaele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump's White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NickBryantNY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BarackObama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BennyHutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CahnEmily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America's Dad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MedvedevRussiaE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brewers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Campaign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WISN12News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House South Lawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>niceDonaldTrump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John F. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOTALLY UNTRUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservative Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Bossert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BostonGlobe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>niceDonaIdTrump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Kaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHSanders45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston Globe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ChrisChristie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Christie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>realDonaldTrump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
