<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424816788206717</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/bidding-battle-scores-standout-result-for-villa-unit/news-story/b35ca8374b796328d7a1b6823ab1f170</url>
  <title>Bidding battle scores standout result for villa unit - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
sold for $1.151 million at auction on July 29.

A MARATHON auction battle spanning more than 100 bids has launched a Carnegie property hundreds of thousands of dollars beyond its price expectations.
Woodards Carnegie director and senior auctioneer Ruth Roberts said the three-bedroom unit at went under the hammer amid sizzling competition on July 29.
It eventually sold for more than $1.15 million.
"We had six bidders," Ms Roberts said.
"There were over 100 bids."
But despite the eventual bidding frenzy, the auction had a quiet start, Ms Roberts said.
"We had to start it off on a vendor bid of $830,000," she said.
But the bidding soon picked up.
"It was on the market at $880,000," she said.
"It was down in $1000 increments very early, from about $1 million."
Dozens of bids later, the home was sold for $1.151 million, a figure $271,000 after it was called on the market.
"It was a huge result," Ms Roberts said.
A downsizer won the keys to the property, while the other bidders were mostly younger buyers looking to get into the market, she said.
"The underbidder saw it for the first time that day," Ms Roberts added.
The three-bedroom, single-level villa has a streetfront position and features a private decked courtyard, a garage and a modern interior.
Ms Roberts said the fact there were more buyers in the area than there were homes was continuing to underpin the market's strength.
SEE SUBURB PROFILE:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Roberts</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodards Carnegie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURB PROFILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnegie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
