<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424125298461057</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834268/vikings-preparing-for-finals-campaign-early/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Vikings preparing for Illawarra rugby finals campaign early</title>
  <content>
Charge: Vikings forward Matthew Jones against Shamrock last month. Picture: Sylvia Liber

AS A major semi-final date with Avondale looms on the horizon, Vikings coach Sean Barrett admits he is already planning ahead.
The similarities between the Avondale and Kiama forward packs will allow him to do some fine-tuning on Saturday, when the Wollongong powerhouse collides with his former club.
With two rounds remaining, unbeaten Avondale have already secured the minor premiership, Vikings in hot pursuit, having locked down second place.
Barring a disaster, premiers University will be part of the finals series, having , who they will almost certainly meet again in an elimination final. 
Warning against complacency, Barrett is wary of Kiama derailing Vikings finals momentum, but says he'll also be developing plans to stop the Wombats when a grand final spot is on the line.
"We don't want to limp into the semi-finals, so it's important we keep working on our cohesion," he said. 
"But Kiama and Avondale both have pretty similarly good forward packs and will test us at the set piece.
"So there will be a few things we'll be able to do against Kiama that will also work in our plans for Avondale."
Avondale are on the verge of joining the all-time great teams of Illawarra rugby, needing to win games against Camden and the ever-improving Tech-Waratahs to finish with a perfect record. 
But Barrett is confident his young squad will handle the big occasions coming up, despite a lack of major finals experience. 
He declared the Blueys were destined for premiership glory, it was just a matter of when.
"They're a great group, there's a lot of young talent and they've really bought into what we're doing," he said.
"If we keep them together, there's no doubt they'll win a premiership, whether it's this year or not.
"And there's a lot of depth at the club, finals selections will be difficult.
"We'll just prepare as well as we can, which is why it's really important to play well against Kiama."
Barrett is particularly wary of flanker Michael Kauter, his former teammate at Sydney club Southern Districts.
Elsewhere, Shamrocks travel to Campbelltown on Saturday, needing to win and hope Shoalhaven can upset Uni to keep their slim finals chances alive.
The Rocks were blown away by a 34-7 first-half onslaught by Avondale last weekend, before conceding 46-28. Bowral meet Tech-Tahs, trying to bounce back after a 31-22 loss to Uni.

ILLAWARRA RUGBY
Round 17
Saturday (3pm)
BOWRAL v TECH-WARATAHS at Eridge Park, CAMDEN v AVONDALE at Camden Rugby Ground, CAMPBELLTOWN v SHAMROCKS at Campbelltown Showground, UNIVERSITY v SHOALHAVEN at University Oval, VIKINGS v KIAMA at Vikings Rugby Ground.

Ladder: AVONDALE 78, VIKINGS 69, BOWRAL 51, UNIVERSITY 48, Shamrocks 40, Shoalhaven 39, Kiama 25, Campbelltown 25, Tech-Waratahs 20, Camden 18.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camden 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech-Tahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shamrocks 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Kauter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AVONDALE 78</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eridge Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown Showground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camden Rugby Ground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Barrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avondale</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech-Waratahs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOWRAL 51</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowral</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vikings Rugby Ground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIKINGS 69</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vikings</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNIVERSITY 48</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven 39</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shamrock</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech-Waratahs 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ILLAWARRA RUGBY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blueys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
