<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424043694081275</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/cbas-board-should-consider-withholding-exec-bonuses-amid-laundering-scandal-20170804-gxparr</url>
  <title>CBA's board should consider withholding exec bonuses amid latest scandal</title>
  <content>
Commonwealth Bank of Australia's board should consider withholding the bonuses of its 13 top executives pending the outcome of the latest scandal affecting the country's largest listed company.
It would send a strong message to shareholders, customers, politicians and the public that the bank was taking the allegations seriously and was focused on its internal risk management systems. Internal controls systems are at the centre of the latest scandal.
In a bank you're always dealing with confidence and the integrity of the brand. A banks internal controls and the auditing of whether those processes are being complied with to minimise risk go to the core of protecting the integrity of a financial institution's brand.

David Rowe

It said that: "It's essential to the integrity of the Australian financial system that a major bank such as CBA has compliant and appropriate risk-based systems and controls in place to deter money laundering and terrorism financing. The effect of CommBank's conduct in this matter has exposed the Australian community to serious and ongoing financial crime."

On Thursday for allegedly failing to report 53,700 suspicious transactions that contravened the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act. The maximum fine for each contravention is $18 million.
It took until lunch time on Friday for CBA to make a statement to the Australian Securities Exchange regarding the allegations, which was thin on detail. It released a more expansive statement to the media on Thursday.
CBA chief executive Ian Narev has not commented. The bank will report its full-year profit on August 9 and this scandal will overshadow those results.
It's hard to comprehend why a CEO would have nothing to say about such serious allegations made against the bank.

David Rowe

The bank has a duty to protect shareholder funds. A statement could not only have informed shareholders of the allegations but said for now there's no basis to estimate any potential fine from the alleged breaches, until the outcome is known.
If the allegations are proven there will be fierce negotiations over what's a proportionate fine,  touted by the media.
The bank's market capitalisation is only $141 billion. 
CBA issued a statement to the media on Thursday saying it had been in discussions with AUSTRAC for an extended period and co-operated with their requests and has worked to continuously improve compliance and had kept AUSTRAC abreast of its efforts.

Critics of CBA will point to a pattern of behaviour at the bank of putting their head in the sand when problems arise. There was a slow response and ; with financial planners and even in the case of when a former CBA technology executive was jailed last year for bribery offences relating to the awarding of IT contracts.
Shareholders, customers, politicians and industry peers will be watching how the CBA board under its relatively new chair Catherine Livingstone responds or whether as they have done previously choose to just tough it out. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counter-Terrorism Financing Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommBank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
