<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423691506758767</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/chanticleer/tabcorp-ceo-management-say-dont-pay-us-bonuses-20170804-gxp8fd</url>
  <title>Tabcorp sets a precedent on lower pay for profit reporting season </title>
  <content>
Tabcorp chief executive David Attenborough is the first CEO in this profit reporting season to adhere to the idea that corporate Australia needs to show some restraint on executive remuneration.
The company's chairman Paula Dwyer revealed on Friday that Attenborough and his management team recommended to the board that they not be paid any short-term bonus for the 2017 financial year.
This will send a strong signal that remuneration structures designed to reward exceptional financial performance can also work to lower pay in the years when performance was lacklustre or ordinary.
It sets a welcome precedent for this profit reporting season at a time when community concern about executive remuneration remains elevated.

Dwyer and the chairman of Tabcorp's remuneration committee, Ziggy Switkowski, said one-off costs, including a $68 million cost of anti-money laundering breaches, had significantly depressed the reported profit results in 2017.

'Mixed results'

Tabcorp's  and final dividend payment of 12.5c a share were in line with recent profit guidance.
Dwyer and Switkowski said the "mixed results" for the year meant that the starting point for any conversation about incentive payments was "difficult".
"The CEO and his senior team recommended that no short term incentive payments be made for the year ended June 30, 2017 and this recommendation was accepted by the board in the case of the MD and CEO, chief financial officer and the chief operating officer wagering and media," Dwyer and Switkowski said.

"There was general recognition that, while much was achieved in the year which will underpin future results for the corporation, an objective assessment of, especially, financial outcomes inevitably led to this conclusion.
"Reduced awards were determined for other members of the senior executive leadership team and employees who participated in the short term performance plan (STPP) program - albeit funded from a much-reduced bonus pool."
Attenborough's total pay fell from $3.18 million to $2.8 million, CFO Damien Johnston's pay fell from $1.34 million to $1.17 million and chief operating officer Craig Nugent's pay fell from $1.25 million to $1.08 million. 
The head of the Keno and Gaming Services division, Adam Rytenskild, achieved his targets but in keeping with the bonus moderation his STI was cut to 50 per cent of target. His pay fell from $1.2 million to $1.09 million.

Tabcorp's annual report this year includes an upgraded and enhanced remuneration report in response to criticisms last year from shareholders and proxy advisers.
Tabcorp is in the final stages of a merger with Tatts Group, which has been held up by a judicial review of the Australian Competition Tribunal ruling in favour of the transaction. The deal is expected to take place in the last three months of this year.
The other gambling and wagering news on Friday was the  which beat the consensus numbers at $827.9 million.
The Crown result showed the benefits of bringing in John Alexander as CEO. He cut the corporate costs from $98.5 million to $47.1 million.

As expected, Crown announced another share buyback (about $375 million). This week James Packer and his long standing legal adviser Guy Jalland joined the Crown board.
The Crown result showed the direct negative impact of China's crackdown on high rollers. VIP program play turnover almost halved to $33.3 billion.
The Crown Resorts annual report has yet to be released so it is impossible to know if the company has shown the same restraint on executive pay as Tabcorp.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Rytenskild</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ziggy Switkowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwyer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attenborough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFO Damien Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Jalland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Switkowski</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatts Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Nugent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaming Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STPP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Attenborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paula Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
