<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424769543565567</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/kids-held-back-by-political-correctness-says-coach/news-story/f68d6172200b361bac44498825e99f30</url>
  <title>Junior team penalised for being too good</title>
  <content>
A JUNIOR football coach in Albany says kids are being held back by political correctness and has vowed to step down after his side was penalised for winning games by too much.
On July 22, two results in the Southern Districts Junior Football Association under-13s and under-15s competitions were decided by 95 and 73 points respectively.
Days later, the SDJFA recorded the results as forfeits against the winning teams, saying the margins were too one-sided and ignored the spirit of the game.
The decision was sparked by a rule introduced by the WA Football Commission in 2008 that set a strict 60-point margin cap for players between 12 and 16 years old in WA.
The coach of the under-13s Albany Eagles side, Russ Clark, said the rule was illogical and explained how often he rotated players to ensure it was fair for all players.
"At half-time we were five goals to zero, one of the kids kicked three goals so I said to him, 'Congratulations mate, well done, but you're going to full-back now so you don't kick anymore because you're too strong for them down there'," Clark told 6PR.
"I've been around football for 37 years and I coudn't care less about winning an under-13s game in Albany, it's about trying to develop kids to play footy. I keep a record of who has and hasn't been on the bench all year. They are all getting a go.
"I don't know what more I could've done."
Clark said a sporting culture of rewarding kids who didn't try and penalising successful kids was holding them back.
"If you're in a 100m race now, you can walk it and you still get a trophy at the end of it because you didn't try," he said.
"I wonder if they turn to kids [at school] and say, 'Listen mate, you keep getting 10 out 10 in maths but we need you to get three wrong next time because Johnny in the corner is getting upset.
"We don't do that at school, we give them extension maths, but in sport we take you off the ground because you're too good.
"I'm not a win-at-all-costs person and I don't need it. I'll finish this year for these kids because I owe them that, but junior footy will be looking for another coach next year.
"I said to my players last night;, 'Never apologise for doing your best' and that's the message I'm going to leave with them."
The decision to strip the team of points was commended by the WAFC.
"The message is if the game gets beyond doubt, it's the coaches' responsibility to maintain that the game is at a competitive level," WAFC Great Southern regional manager Tom Moir told the Albany Advertiser.
"In this day and age, we are losing kids to things other than sport and they are dropping out because they are getting belted and there is no enjoyment."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFC Great Southern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Football Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Moir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany Advertiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russ Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SDJFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Districts Junior Football Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
