<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424254147482172</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/west-coast-chief-executive-trevor-nisbett-confident-eagles-will-host-first-afl-game-at-perth-stadium/news-story/ddbef87dbaef26ee5616f83cbcc13f7a</url>
  <title>Eagles: 'We'll be opening the stadium'</title>
  <content>
WEST Coast expect to be hosting the first AFL match to open Perth Stadium next season.
Eagles chief executive Trevor Nisbett said the Eagles were bidding to host the only game to be played at the new $1.4 billion venue in round one next year.
The possibility of both West Coast and Fremantle hosting home matches at the Burswood ground on the season's opening weekend had been flagged by AFL chief Gillon McLachlan.
But Nisbett said his club wanted the season-opening hosting rights to themselves.
Both WA clubs have traditionally alternated the first home game of the year at Domain Stadium, with Fremantle playing Geelong in round one this year.
"It's our turn, so we'll be opening the stadium," Nisbett said.
Turf laid at Perth Stadium

"I don't think so (that it'll be two games). I think it'll be one game and then we'll move forward into the new season.
"I don't think so (it'll be a derby). I think it'll be a West Coast home game.
"I just don't think it makes sense to have a derby when you can have a big game to open the season. If the Dockers play the next week, it'll be a big game for them to open the season.
"The derby will be another big game during the season.
"The whole idea is to maximise the capacity of the ground and make sure we fill it."
Nisbett and Eagles coach Adam Simpson launched a 10-year partnership with Edith Cowan University this morning.
Under the agreement, ECU have been granted naming rights to the media and broadcast facility, as well as the high performance centre, to be built at West Coast's future base at Lathlain Park.
ECU students will also be given experience creating media content for West Coast under the deal, with one person to receive a scholarship with the Eagles each year.
Nisbett said a final agreement surrounding the Perth Stadium needed to be signed off within the next month to avoid threatening the transition of resources in time.
He said West Coast were aiming to have a builder in place for their new $68 million facility at Lathlain Park by the end of this month.
Construction is due to start on the headquarters in September, with an eye to finishing the project by December next year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillon McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Nisbett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nisbett</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lathlain Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edith Cowan University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Stadium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burswood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
