<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424511845523837</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834621/northstars-face-more-setbacks/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Northstars face more setbacks</title>
  <content>
Andrew Petrie addresses the troops earlier in the season. Picture: Peter Podlala

Northstars coach Andrew Petrie has praised his decimated squad's resilience as they face a do-or-die double-header against the Australian Ice Hockey League leaders in Melbourne this weekend.

Newcastle will be missing three of their five imports and possibly their captain when they face the Melbourne Ice to keep their finals hopes alive.

Canadian scoring machines Felix-Antoine Poulin and Kale Kerbashian have left the club in the past two weeks and countryman Matt Marantz is out injured.

Skipper Bert Malloy is also in doubt with an injury, but Petrie has not given up hope as his side have won four of their past five games to sit four points behind fourth-placed Melbourne Mustangs with six games to play.

"It makes me fall a little more in love with the crop of guys we've got, that they keep finding ways to be resilient and ignore everything that's coming at them and still find ways to put the puck in the net and win games," Petrie said.

The Northstars stormed home with four goals in the final term to beat the Sydney Bears last week without Poulin, who is a defenceman but was leading the league in scoring before earning a contract in Slovakia.
Petrie said losing Poulin could free up his forwards to be more incisive, as happened last weekend.  

"It puts more responsibility on them, and sometimes that's what they want."
The Mustangs are inactive this weekend, giving Newcastle a chance to jump into fourth place before hosting the Melbourne club the following week.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Bears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mustang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poulin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Mustangs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bert Malloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slovakia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Marantz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northstars</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Podlala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Ice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felix-Antoine Poulin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ice Hockey League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kale Kerbashian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Petrie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
