<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423820355779273</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/celebrity-kids/nine-reporter-sam-squiers-finally-takes-premature-baby-girl-home-i-cried-when-i-got-in-the-car/news-story/dd9b55f0511ee34ca224976539c0cc5b</url>
  <title>Nine reporter Sam Squiers finally takes premature baby girl home: 'I cried when I got in the car'</title>
  <content>
Channel 9 sports presenter Sam Squiers with daughter Imogen Grace

Share

CHANNEL 9 sport reporter Sam Squiers has finally returned home after 44 days in hospital with her five-week premature baby girl.
In a heartbreaking message on social media the 35-year-old mother, who suffered a placental abruption, said she "cried as soon as I got in the car."
The condition is a serious pregnancy complication in which the placenta detaches from the uterus.

on

Squiers gave birth to Imogen Grace, who weighed just 1.3 kilograms in June, and has spent her first few weeks of her life in ICU.
"For the past 44 days Ben & I have watched other parents walk out of level 5 of the @matermothers with their babies in their arms as we walked in to see ours on level 6...and finally we got to walk that walk ourselves," she wrote on Instagram.

on

"Immi felt the warmth of the sun for the first time, the breeze on her face and the sloppiness of Broby's welcome home lick.
"We're forever grateful to the wonderful staff here in the NCCU for looking after Immi and us, the amazing ICU staff during those frightening first days I was there after suffering severe pre-eclampsia, my obstetrician Dr Megan Castner & our paediatrician Dr Aaron Easterbrook.

on

"I cried as soon as I got in the car and instantly felt relieved when we got home...it doesn't matter how many times I have to wake in the night or how little sleep I get, there's nothing quite like finally being at home with Imogen.
"A few more hospital stays in the coming weeks and months but our life can finally begin."

Squiers returned home with oxygen tanks, which will support Imogen's breathing.
She wrote of the first time she was able to bath Imogen just last month.

on

"We've had plenty of moments feeling helpless in here & when people say 'you're a mum' it felt really surreal when you had to ask to hold your baby & could only do that once a day," she wrote at the time.
"So a simple thing like bathing Immi for the first time made Ben & I feel like real parents and did so much for us emotionally.

Channel 9 sports presenter Sam SquiersSource:Supplied

Sam Squiers and baby ImogenSource:Supplied
"Little things like changing a nappy were so important, we would get disappointed when it was changed before we arrived for the day as it made us feel like we were being useful and somehow taking care of our baby.
"We're so close now and should be going home this week but I don't want to forget how little things like this mattered to us in such a big way.
"This experience has given us a new perspective on everything."

on

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Squiers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Aaron Easterbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Megan Castner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam SquiersSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imogen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Squiers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCCU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ImogenSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imogen Grace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
