<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424258442449648</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/horseracing/former-godolphin-australia-boss-henry-plumptre-serious-bullying-clouded-strangles-mistake-20170803-gxp4kt.html</url>
  <title>Plumptre admits 'serious bullying issue' clouded strangles call</title>
  <content>
A contrite Henry Plumptre admitted a "serious bullying issue" he was investigating within Godolphin the same week Polemic was showing symptoms of strangles clouded his judgement in the non-reporting of the condition as the fallout continues.
Godolphin's former head Australian trainer John O'Shea will fight two charges levelled against him in the controversial strangles probe - including one of giving false or misleading evidence - as the world's most recognisable racing brand was dragged before stewards again on Friday.Photo: Anthony Johnson
An otherwise stony-faced Plumptre read from a statement admitting he had erred in withholding Polemic's condition from stipes, an offence under the Australian rules of racing.
The ex-Godolphin Australia boss pleaded guilty to the charge levelled against him on Wednesday, as revealed by Fairfax Media.

His legal counsel Peter Braham conceded Plumptre "went to war with [O'Shea] on a number of issues [in regards to workplace practices] which was a long, tiring [and] drawn out process" as the blame game about who knew when of Polemic's condition continued.
But it was his role in probing a bullying complaint at Osborne Park which surfaced on Friday.

Plumptre said he said he was satisfied Polemic's case would not affect Godolphin's horse population or that of the wider Sydney basin after the colt was quarantined last August.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It occurred during the week I was investigating a serious bullying issue at Osborne Park," Plumptre said. "I considered the [Polemic issue] and noticed there was a strong reluctance from the training team to report it and I agreed to monitor the colt.
"At the time did I consider the bullying issue to be of more importance? The answer would be yes and I acknowledge that would be wrong. It's of great disappointment to me that I failed in this instance."
Plumptre conceded he did not seek to "deny, deflect or minimise" the charge - a result of a "bad mistake" - but argued an exclusion from the industry would be unfair punishment on top of his resignation from a 16-year role with Sheik Mohammed's operation.
His submission on penalty included references from Melbourne Cup fanatic Lloyd Williams, Australia's leading trainer Chris Waller and Hong Kong Jockey Club boss Winfried Engelbrecht-Bresges.
He apologised to Racing NSW and the wider Australian racing public, claiming he plans to return to the industry as a bloodstock agent after resigning from his job last week.
Earlier, O'Shea said he would fight the two charges levelled against him on Wednesday for being a party to Plumptre's call to cover up Polemic's condition from stewards and tendering false evidence to a previous inquiry. He pleaded not guilty to both.
"I'm extremely disappointed to be even considered to give false evidence," O'Shea said. "I emphatically deny that. It's not in my nature to make false or misleading statements."
O'Shea is on the brink of resuming his training career as a public conditioner at Randwick after his messy split from Godolphin, which was revealed in late April and confirmed shortly afterwards.
It caps months of upheaval worldwide at Godolphin with Sheikh Mohammed's right-hand man John Ferguson also leaving his post after a savage spray from the organisation's most recognisable trainer, Saeed bin Suroor.
O'Shea's successor James Cummings has hit the ground running in his new role and prepared the first two winners of the new metropolitan season, but bigger tests await in the stallion-making spring races in coming months.
The inquiry is continuing.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Shea</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suroor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheik Mohammed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Braham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plumptre</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Waller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Plumptre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheikh Mohammed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godolphin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osborne Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong Jockey Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godolphin Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John O'Shea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winfried Engelbrecht-Bresges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saeed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
