<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424301392123256</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/04/13/59/canadian-reporter-lost-for-words-in-live-tv-slip-up</url>
  <title>Canadian reporter lost for words in live TV slip-up</title>
  <content>
A reporter has made a valiant attempt at a recovery after sheepishly forgetting her lines during a broadcast in Canada.
CBS News journalist Avneet Dhillon was reporting on a skateboarding stunt-gone-wrong yesterday when she made the slip-up.  
The cross began smoothly as Dhillon reported a 17-year-old girl had been injured after falling off a skateboard while also holding onto a Jeep.
"Things took a turn when the jeep hit one of these speedbumps. The girl then fell and the jeep ran over her leg and pelvic area," she said.
One minute into the segment, things took a turn for the worse as she began to reiterate a statement from local police.
"In the meantime, the RNC has issued a statement saying that ... uh ... the driver of the vehicle was also a 17-year-old girl," Ms Dhillon said, as the realisation hit.
"The RNC says calls like this are not common ... uh ...," she continued, before swearing under her breath.

Related Articles

Beginning to pace, Dhillon attempted the line again before sighing and returning her gaze to the camera.
"Calls like this are not common ...," she said for a third time as she desperately searched for words.
Cutting off Dhillon's cross, the segment returned to the presenter who assured viewers they would "keep an eye" on the story.
The video has since clocked up more than 15,000 views on YouTube.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dhillon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeep</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RNC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Dhillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avneet Dhillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
