<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423777406105765</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/green-funding-for-adelaide-student-digs-20170804-gxp6kr</url>
  <title>Blue Sky and green money: funding for Adelaide students digs</title>
  <content>
Blue Sky Private Real Estate and its joint venture partner Goldman Sachs have won $32 million in green funding from the Clean Energy Finance Corporation to build student accommodation in Adelaide.
The federal government's green funding agency is contributing the debt finance for the 428-bed student digs project on Waymouth Street.
It will be run by Atira Student Living, the joint venture set up between Brisbane-based Blue Sky Private Real Estate and Goldman Sachs.
The CEFC's first investment into the Adelaide real estate sector comes as the agency directs increasing amounts of funding into the commercial property sector.

"This project will lift the benchmark for building standards in student accommodation, representing an important step toward achieving net zero carbon buildings," said chief executive Ian Learmonth said.

"The CEFC has a clear focus on investing in clean energy in industry sectors with the strongest potential for decarbonisation.
"We have already committed more than $600 million to the property sector in support of market-leading projects such as this one."
In June last year, the federal government's green funder for the new WorkSafe headquarters in Geelong being developed by Quintessential Equity.
Last December, the agency invested to boost energy efficiency.
With the green funding on board, the Waymouth Street project is aiming to achieving a minimum 25 per cent improvement on energy efficiency compared with a business as usual development.

"We also expect to create benefits through reduced operating costs by integrating technologies that significantly lower base building energy usage," said Nick Singleton, Blue Sky Private Real Estate investment director.
The development will include energy efficient heating, ventilation and air conditioning, energy efficient equipment, LED lighting, centralised gas water heating, water efficient taps and a 25kW rooftop solar photovoltaic system.
The Blue Sky joint venture has ben busy building its student accommodation portfolio after it  in Melbourne and Adelaide last year.
The partnership's pipeline has swelled to more than 3000 purpose-built beds nationally.

a 540-bed Brisbane development at Toowong, close to the University of Queensland, to the portfolio along with a site for a 576-bed facility on Peel Street in North Melbourne, near the University of Melbourne.
The student accommodation sector is booming, with adriving a wave of developments worth billion of dollars in the state capitals.
Institutional investment has rushed in the fill the gap, with players such as Scape Student Living, .
Other major providers include GSA, which has  and South Africa's Redefine Properties, which also has two Melbourne locations,

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Sky</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clean Energy Finance Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peel Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Sky Private Real Estate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atira Student Living</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quintessential Equity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scape Student Living</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WorkSafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane-based Blue Sky Private Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Singleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Learmonth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waymouth Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GSA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEFC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa's Redefine Properties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
