<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424516140491160</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/keysborough-hotel-gamblers-feed-more-than-twice-state-average-into-each-pokie/news-story/d7aea1008783a83695158d55b267f079</url>
  <title>Pokies working overtime</title>
  <content>
THE pokies at Greater Dandenong's most notorious gambling hot spot suck more than twice the cash from punters than Victoria's -average gaming machine.
The latest statistics from the Victorian Commission for Gambling and Liquor Regulation show the 89 pokies at the Keysborough Hotel drained an average of $212,472 each from players in 2016-17. The state expenditure average was $95,000.
Alliance for Gambling Reform director and spokesman Tim Costello said the hotel was the third worst poker machine venue in the state in terms of cash poured in and criticised the hotel's 9am to 5am operating hours.
"The Woolworths--controlled Keysborough Hotel is doing the most damage in Greater Dandenong with annual losses jumping from $18.13 million to $18.91 million, making it the second most lucrative of the 81 pokies venues Woolworths operates in Victoria," Mr Costello said.
"Pokies venues on main roads, near shopping strips and accessible by public transport tend to inflict the most harm and if they were responsible the Keysborough Hotel would not be open for 20 hours every day."
Players spent $118.19 million at 15 venues last financial year in Greater Dandenong.
Highways Sandown was the municipality's second worst venue for pokie expenditure with over $16 million fed through machines.
Mayor Jim Memeti said the council was lobbying the Government "to actually reduce" the amount of poker machines in the city.
Mr Costello called on -Woolworths to "exit the poker machine business or at the very least cut back the losses by embracing long overdue reforms such as the $1 maximum bet".
Woolworths did not respond to Leader's questions.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liquor Regulation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gambling Reform</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keysborough Hotel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Costello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highways Sandown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Jim Memeti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Dandenong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
