<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424039399113928</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/jarryd-roughead-250-former-hawthorn-teammate-xavier-ellis-spills-on-the-loveable-larrikin/news-story/64ccef2bf45ffeeddff9f2a28475e368</url>
  <title>Roughy 250: Teammate spills on beers, bobcats</title>
  <content>
JARRYD Roughead is the ultimate professional.
A footballer capable of playing in virtually any position on the field, a four-time premiership star who always has his say on grand final day and the captain of an imposing Hawthorn team.
Yet deep down, to those who know him best, Roughead is still the happy-go-lucky larrikin from Leongatha that grew up playing practical jokes on his teammates as a teenager.
And no one knows about such hijinks more than his former Hawthorn teammate Xavier Ellis.
Having played basketball against each other since the age of 10, Ellis and Roughead always knew of one another. But it wasn't until they were paired together in representative football around the age of 13 that they began to develop a strong bond.
Both talented junior prospects who caught the eye of AFL recruiters from a young age, the two Gippsland Power products because great mates throughout the draft process.
A year apart in age, Roughead acted as Ellis' guide - both at Gippsland and even after 'Roughy' had been recruited to Hawthorn with Pick 2 in the 2004 national draft.
Roughead became someone Ellis idolised. And someone who he lent advice to throughout a challenging couple of years for young AFL hopefuls.
So when Ellis made his TAC Cup debut as a bottom-age prospect, he would once again look to Roughead - his teammate at the time - for a helping hand. Just not this sort of helping hand.
"What stands out most about Rough as a teammate was during my very first game with the Gippsland Power," Ellis tells foxfooty.com.au.
"I was playing as a 16 year-old in the under 18s and I was obviously very nervous.
"The coach was eyeballing me at quarter time in the huddle and then, all of a sudden, I felt this creepy crawly hand going up my leg.
"Poor old me, Roughy had thought it was appropriate when I was getting a pump-up to wander his hands up my shorts and have a little fiddle around as I was copping a speech.
"He's always been a bit of a lad. He's really friendly and he loves his footy. He takes it seriously, but he's got a really good balance. He's just a big kid."

Twelve months after Roughead was drafted to Hawthorn, Ellis followed suit.
Recruited to the Hawks with Pick 3 in the very next draft, the pair were reunited once more.
And so the mischief continued.
While you could take the kids out of the country, you couldn't take the country out of the kids.
"I remember one time we had the week off during the finals in 2008," Ellis says.
"We were all quite young - Rough was 21 and I was about 19 or 20 - and we were told to stay away from the beers on the weekend off.
"We had a preliminary final the weekend after, but Roughy thought it was a good idea to head around to his place and watch the other games.
"Our usual ritual was that if we had the right amount of days off, we'd enjoy a few beers. But before you knew it, a couple of beers that we weren't meant to have turned into people driving bobcats down the street.
"All sorts of misbehaviour caused us to have a few stories of waking up on the Sunday feeling sorry for ourselves."
Ahead of his 250th game this weekend, Roughead is perhaps beyond his cheeky formative years with both Gippsland and Hawthorn.
But what makes the 30-year-old such a special footballer and person, both for Ellis and many others who know him well enough, is how Roughead has never lost the balance in his life.
He remains a fearless leader and a feared opponent, but also someone who doesn't take himself too seriously. According to Ellis, that's what makes him such a respected figure in the game.
But it's not something Roughead has developed over time. Rather, his personable attitude, maturity and care for others has always been present - even as that young, mischievous kid.
"I was really fortunate (to get drafted to Hawthorn)," Ellis says.
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
"I remember playing TAC Cup while Roughy was playing with Hawthorn. He always showed a vested interest in me, which was great.
"We obviously couldn't predict I was going to go with Hawthorn, but he still called and checked in and offered advice. He gave me a friendly chat and told me about the process I was going to face.
"I was really lucky that two Gippsland boys followed each other to Hawthorn, because I was just in awe of him."
Another chapter of Roughead's incredible football story was written midway through the 2015 season, when the Hawk had a melanoma cut from his lip.
He would return to the field later that year, helping Hawthorn to its fourth premiership in eight seasons, only for scans to soon reveal that the cancer had returned in secondary locations.
Roughead would miss the entirety of Hawthorn's 2016 campaign to undergo successful immunotherapy treatment, revealing the news everyone had been praying to hear in December last year. He was now "cancer free".
To complete his remarkable return, Roughead was named captain of Hawthorn for the 2017 season and beyond just over a month later.
"You always hope for the best, but to say I expected he'd come back and be a captain of the side ... it's not just a calf or a broken arm," Ellis says.
"When you're dealing with cancer it's such an unknown. None of us are really too well educated in that field.
"For him to come back and take the leap he has this year as a captain, I sort of expected it a little bit in the way that it was just Roughy. In my eyes, he's bullet proof.
"He's such a loveable country kid who loves footy and having fun, I just expected he'd bounce back."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xavier Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn's 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gippsland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gippsland Power</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pick 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pick 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughy 250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAC Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellis</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leongatha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
