<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424039399113961</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/13/31/failed-sydney-terror-plot-may-have-galvanised-isis-extremists</url>
  <title>Failed Sydney terror plot may have galvanised ISIS extremists</title>
  <content>
A failed plot to blow up a flight at Sydney Airport may have succeeded in motivating ISIS extremists to plan similar attacks.

While the Australian Federal Police may have thwarted  on Australian soil, US counter-terror analyst Michael S. Smith II told nine.com.au the plot alone is enough to inspire other extremists.

"As their contacts in Islamic State were almost certainly aware, even if the would-be terrorists failed to execute these attacks, the plot concepts alone will clearly win Islamic State yet more headlines in the West," Mr Smith said.

"This all factors importantly in the group's efforts to terrorise Westerners. That, in turn, factors importantly in the group's efforts to both re-train members while generating yet more defections from competing Salafi-Jihadist groups like al-Qa'ida."

Mr Smith said it is likely Australia and other western countries will see more elaborate terrorist attempts in the near future.

"Even with failed plots like this, Islamic State is demonstrating to the seasoned jihadis whom it needs to move into its ranks that it is more dedicated to the cause of terrorizing the so-called 'enemies of Islam' here in the West than al-Qa'ida. It's very likely we will see more of this during the next year," he said.

"While Islamic State has been calling for simple attacks in Australia, the US, Europe and Canada using such basic weaponry as knives and cars since 2014, even though these attacks failed to materialize, these plot concepts serve to enhance awareness among Islamic State supporters that mass-casualty attacks are the ultimate goal."

Related Articles

AFP deputy commissioner Michael Phelan said today that an IED concealed in a meat grinder found during a Sydney raid was allegedly designed to blow up an Etihad flight out of Sydney on July 15, but did not breach airport security.

The parts for the IED came from Turkey and were sent by a leading ISIS figure, police say.

Lakemba man Khaled Mahmoud Khayat, 49, and Punchbowl man Mahmoud Khayat, 32, have been charged with two counts of preparing and planning a terrorist act.

They did not appear in court today and no application for bail was made.

Police will allege the 49-year-old carried the device to Sydney's international airport in the hope of putting it on the plane in "checked luggage", using the unwitting brother of one of the men to carry the bomb.

"One of the two gentlemen charged, the brother we're alleging is a senior member of ISIL in Syria and he indeed introduced another person, who we call the controller, to one of the people that has been charged," Mr Phelan said.

The AFP also averted an alleged plot involving plans to build an improvised chemical dispersion device to release highly toxic hydrogen sulphide.

However, police said the chemical weapon was "a long way" from being functional.

The US counter-terror analyst warned the chemical plot was the most nefarious of the two planned attacks because it showed the deadly lengths extremists will go do to incite primal fear.

"The plot entailing construction and deployment of an improvised chemical dispersal device can help stimulate thinking among Islamic State supporters in the West about ways to increase the fear factor with simple attacks by producing innovative, albeit unsophisticated weaponry," he said.

"When was the last time al-Qa'ida supporters executed a chemical weapon attack in the West?"

The maximum penalty for the charges is life imprisonment.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Phelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IED</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salafi-Jihadist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael S. Smith II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Mahmoud Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westerners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Phelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
