<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424644989512120</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/business/government-program-providing-incentives-to-companies-that-hire-indigenous-workers-suspended-over-allegations-of-fraud/news-story/a68bb590c1881372b4d45f9b45429741</url>
  <title>Govt program halted over fraud allegations</title>
  <content>
A GOVERNMENT program aimed at providing incentives to companies that hire indigenous workers has been suspended over allegations of fraud.
The full extent of the fraud is unknown at this time, but is suspected to involve tens of thousands of dollars, but most likely more.
Infrastructure Minister Nicole Manison suspended the Indigenous Employment Provision Sum program Friday afternoon after being informed of "potential widespread fraud" by the Department of Infrastructure, Planning and Logistics following an audit.
Ms Manison said six companies have been referred to NT Police for investigation. More could be referred later.
"The program was well intentioned, well meaning and was all about ensuring we had more indigenous Territorians in jobs," she said.
"However, there have been cases brought forward that the Department has now had to refer to police.
"In the meantime, we are working to look at what can replace this program.
"We're still targeting making sure we are enhancing employment opportunities for indigenous Territorians."
It is alleged companies were improperly claiming indigenous employees who weren't indigenous in order to qualify for construction contract tenders.
Ms Manison said there was no independent oversight of the program to check on the individual companies' employment claims.
"However some questions have been raised around that," she said.
"We had industry raising concerns about the program for a range of reasons."
One case of suspected fraud was identified in March and was referred to NT Police and the Auditor General.
It was unclear on Friday why that case was not made public at the time.
A statement from the Department said: "Since that time, there have been multiple alleged misuses discovered which has led to (Friday's) announcement (that the program) has been suspended on all new tenders and contracts issued after (Friday)."
The IEPS scheme was established in October 2014 by the previous CLP Government.
More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Manison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Employment Provision Sum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLP Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Infrastructure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IEPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Nicole Manison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auditor-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
