<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423996449440397</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/sa-sport-gurus-state-league-soccer-upsets-basketball-playoffs-adelaide-superfish-at-marion-at-afl-sledges/news-story/d8403fac62ac699cec306763aeeece06</url>
  <title>SA Sport Gurus: Upsets, retirements, superfish, AFL sledges</title>
  <content>
WE CAN almost smell finals footy in the air.
The temperature gets a bit warmer - we're still waiting for that - and all of sudden 50 players rock up to footy training at local grounds hoping to get a gig.
The same feeling is in gyms across the city with basketball finals in full swing (catch-up on that below) and in the dressing sheds at soccer grounds with a only a few games to go until the serious stuff.
It's the best time of the year to be a sports reporter or player, if you're lucky enough to be involved.
While we go clear our calendars for all the sporting action over the next two months, here's our best picks from across the suburbs to keep you going.
Pirates plunder points

IT WAS an 'ol fashioned ye upset at Adelaide Shores last Saturday when lowly Port Pirates upset Sturt Lions, 4-1 in their State League soccer clash.
The win may lead to more treasure for Pirates - just a few weeks ago, Mauro DeMarco's men were flirting with the drop zone and could have quickly found themselves in Davy Jones' locker.
But the Pirates secured their fourth consecutive victory with a win over Sturt, which lifted them to equal sixth on the table and a sneaky chance of a finals qualification.
Name game

LAST week we brought you an extensive list of athletes whose last name is either the spelling of an animal, or sounded like an animal, e.g Garry Lyon.
Thank you to the readers who submitted the following names we missed.
- Jed Lamb (AFL player)
- Harry Dear (AFL player)
- Greg Dear (AFL player)
- Paul Dear (AFL player)
- Hamish Peacock (Australian javelin thrower)
- Mike Trout (US baseballer)
Keep an eye out in this column for our name game lists, we plan to do many more.
Bloody Merv-ellous

RECEIVING "constructive criticism" from Merv "Granma" Mules is almost a tradition at Morphett Vale Football Club, we're told.
Mules, 80, has been handing it out over more than four decades at the Emus while serving in various roles including timekeeper, runner, goal umpire, team manager, secretary and treasurer.
Usually, he voices his opinion wearing his trademark red, woollen op-shop jumper with a patched on Morphett Vale logo and tends to direct it at coaches.
So it was somewhat ironic that this month the Emus named their coaches box after the passionate club legend.
"Of course I'm a pain in the bum to a lot of people," says Mules, the club's present timekeeper, with a chuckle.
"I accept that - I would drive some people up a wall, but that's me.
Read the full article on Merv,
Heroes

ADELAIDE swimmers Lillee Hamilton and Adam Holland get the nod this week.
The pair, both 12, won a combined 47 medals at the recent the State Shortcourse Swimming Championships at Marion.
Lillee snared 12 golds and five silver while Holland grabbed 30 gold.
GOT A GREAT LOCAL SPORT STORY? Let us know by emailling duane.schultz@news.com.au

Villains

THE Southern Footy League gets branded villains this week for their discussion paper of splitting the competition in two. Not because of starting the discussion, which we Gurus think is a great move, but for waiting more than five years to do it. Granted the clubs have a lot to answer to here but the league's decision to release the discussion paper on Facebook, before the all-in meeting with the club presidents was a weird one. None the less, keep your eyes on this column and your Southern Times Messenger for updates to this story.
Sabres bow out

STURT was bundled out of both the men's and women's Premier League basketball play-offs on the weekend after both sides suffered disappointing losses in their respective elimination finals.
The Sabres' men, without an import and two of their gun juniors - Jacob Rigoni and Isaac White are in the US - went down to West Adelaide at Port Adelaide on Saturday, 77-68.
The women lost a nailbiter to Norwood at Campbelltown, 69-65.
It sets up an intriguing week two of the playoffs - In the men's North Adelaide faces Southern Tigers (the top two sides from the minor round), while West Adelaide faces Norwood at Mars - note it is not at Campbelltown as the centre was already booked for another function. In the women's, the Tigers take on the Rockets, while Eastern Mavericks take on the Flames.
Staying on hoops ...

WE SA Sport Gurus thought the SA Premier League was following the NBL and trying to capture a US audience when the fixtures for this week's finals came out. With a tip-off time of 1am, we presumed it was to capture the lunch crowd in New York but alas, it was a typo. Check  for the updated times of basketball fixtures.
Banter at Largs

OUR photographers caught the moment former Magpie and Magarey Medallist, now Port District coach, Jeremy Clayton shared in some banter with former Sturt, Gold Coast Sun now Rostrevor Old Collegians forward Michael Coad.
It may have gone something like this:
Clayton: "You won't kick this, Michael, you're old, you can't possibly make the distance ..."
Coad: "I beg the differ Jeremy, ride it home with me like Sturt's grand final win last year, when was the Magpies' last flag?"
Clayton: "C'mon mate, you're no chance, you're a defender aren't you? Stop soaking the clock and kick it, the photographer's already taken your picture. Come and have a chat to me after the game about footy, I'll show you my Magarey Medal ..."
Coad: " ..."
For the record, Coad missed that shot, we're told, but it was great to see the old fashioned sideline banter even if the exchange was slightly different to the above record.
*Note the SA Sport Gurus took creative license with the above exchange.
Catanzaro gets one back

LAST month we brought you the story of SA soccer Hall of Fame inductees Jason Trimboli and Simon Catanzaro playing against each other in Sunday's division one amateur soccer league.
Catanzaro, the coach of Salisbury United in the State League (played on Saturdays), was beaten by Trimboli, the coach of Modbury Jets (played on Saturdays), when the former teammates coached against each other last month.
However, Catanzaro got one back on the pitch last Sunday when his Parafield Gardens beat Trimboli's Salisbury Florina, 3-2 at Underdown Park.
Chidiac on the world stage

WELL done to Windsor Gardens' own Alex Chidiac making the Matildas squad.
After scoring for the Young Matildas in a friendly series in Canberra last month, the Adelaide City striker was selected for the Matildas squad, which stunned Brazil, 6-1, to win the Tournament of Nations in California.
Chidiac did not get any game time during the clash with Brazil but played cameos in matches throughout the tournament, a big achievement for an 18 year old.
Pay deal done

FINALLY cricket fans across Adelaide can be rest assured the Ashes will go ahead in November following the end to the cricket players' pay war with Cricket Australia.
While the cricketers get to share in the spoils of the $500 million peace plan, which gives the athletes a share of the revenue generated by the game, we Gurus' dreams of slotting in to a third-string Australian team have been dashed.
Anyone out there need some never-been-worn cricket whites for summer? If so, email us at duane.schultz@news.com.au
Johnson, the goal kicker?

STAYING on cricket, we got a bit excited when we saw the great Mitchell Johnson named in the best for Flagstaff Hill in their Southern Football League loss to Noarlunga.
The Falcons lost 9.9 (63) to 7.13 (55) despite Johnson snagging three goals.
However, the great former Test quick wasn't in town checking out the place in readiness for an Adelaide Strikers contract later in the year, no. It was another case of different athletes with the same name, following on from last month's column featuring Mitcham Hawks' Brett Aitken, not the cyclist, getting in the best.
Milestone men

Well done to the players which chalked up milestone matches across the Adelaide Footy League last week.
350 games: Trent Kolbig (North Haven)
300: Jordan Pepper (Hope Valley)
200: Josh Pike (Athelstone), Matt Mitchell (Pulteney), Stephen Hansen (Flinders Park)
100: Seb Paynter (Adel Uni), Nathan Wells (Salisbury), Kyle Slattery (Edwardstown)
Looking forward ...

SOUTHERN suburbs youngster Kurtis Marschall, 20, is competing in the pole vault in London on Sunday at the World Athletics Championships. We're keen for young Kurtis to do well and will be tuning in Sunday, 7.10pm Adelaide time.
We're also keen to see how Adelaide boy Jack Graham goes in his AFL debut with Richmond in its clash against Hawthorn on Sunday.
The Tea Tree Gully product, 19, has had to be patient after being drafted from North Adelaide at pick No. 53 in last year's National Draft. He showed promising signs before fracturing his ankle in the pre-season.
Shout out to Guru Matt Turner, who is on annual leave. Hope you're having fun on your travels.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Largs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Shortcourse Swimming Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coad</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADAM Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adel Uni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magarey Medallist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Coad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athelstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Footy League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Times Messenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Trout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parafield Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hope Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Kolbig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mauro DeMarco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merv</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Sport Gurus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sturt Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Footy League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphett Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitcham Hawks' Brett Aitken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trimboli's Salisbury Florina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Haven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Shores</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Hansen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Rigoni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lillee Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flagstaff Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Slattery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Football League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphett Vale Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sabres</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modbury Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pulteney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lillee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salisbury United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salisbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Strikers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Peacock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Catanzaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Pike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sturt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guru Matt Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Pepper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Mavericks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davy Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catanzaro</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Athletic Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merv-ellous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trimboli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pirates</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Underdown Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Trimboli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jed Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tea Tree Gully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Pirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seb Paynter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chidiac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mules, 80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NORWOOD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magarey Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noarlunga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwardstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Dear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREAT LOCAL SPORT STORY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Chidiac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Dear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Clayton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Dear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rostrevor Old Collegians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
