<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424215492775961</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/sophisticated-traveller/living-the-dream--how-to-almost-get-an-upgrade-20170804-gxp8cr</url>
  <title>Living the dream - how to (almost) get an upgrade to the Pointy End. Guaranteed.</title>
  <content>
"No thanks, I don't want an upgrade, give it to someone else - I'm fine in Economy," said no-one ever.
What is it about the Pointy End that keeps us ever hopeful of an unlikely last minute bump to the left as we wheel our little cabin spinner towards that harshly lit departure gate, ready to be swallowed whole into the underbelly of cattle class.
Is it the bottomless champagne up front? The amenity kits with their hydration lotions and lip potions to play with all the way to Dubai? The flat bed and duvet, organic cotton eye mask, celebrity chef menu, way-too-big PJs, and on it goes.
Curiously, it's more even than the bells and whistles. In a world that's overpopulated and overshared, Business and First remain, if only in our imagination, among the last bastions of exclusivity. A Shangri-la in the clouds; an Aladdin's Cave of airborne treasure to which many are called, but few are chosen.

Shutterstock

And therein lies the rub.

If only there were a set of simple rules to guarantee an upgrade. Sadly, despite so much click bait, it simply isn't so. Mark Trim, Managing Director of  pours yet more cold water on the dream. "Really, these stories should be called 'why you'll never get an upgrade at the airport','" he says bluntly. "The days of donning your tweed sports coat and asking politely are long gone. Ditto, no-one's interested if it's your honeymoon or a bereavement flight. Airlines don't factor that stuff in anymore."
Part of the problem is the Pointy End has never been so, well, pointy. Business Class, along with the airline lounges behind those frosted sliding doors, plus loyalty programs and the associated complex algorithms are serious revenue drivers, not least given the premium end of aircraft interiors now have to be refreshed every five to seven years.
"Look at Qantas," says Trim. "Their Frequent Flyer program is one of the most profitable arms of the business."
Luckily, not all hope is lost.

Supplied

The sweet spot now is in value-based Business Class deals. Airlines trying to establish a new route or product usually provide outstanding value while phasing in new services. Most notably, Skytrax 2017 airline of the year, Qatar Airways, in the Australian market. Qatar began flying out of Adelaide this year, and will add Canberra services in 2018, offering Business Class prices that are often thousands of dollars less than their comparable competitors. In July, Flat Beds was selling return Business Class flights from Sydney or Melbourne to Prague or Nice, via Doha, from $3984 in low season aboard Qatar Airways. 
Finnair too is strong value, as long as you don't mind flying from Australia via Bangkok and Helsinki to Europe. For $5148 return, you can do just that. The Australia-Bangkok leg is aboard Finnair's oneworld partner Qantas. "You're effectively getting Qantas Business Class half way to Europe at an unbelievable price," says Trim.
"It's a 'time and money equation'," he adds. "If you can be flexible and take a bit longer to get there, you can benefit from sharp pricing to fly fully flat."
The other upgrade option is the bidding system, by which airlines auction their remaining premium seats. Marketed under various names, like UpgradeMe with Virgin Australia, airlines promote these programs via their websites within about a week of departure. "Malaysia Airlines and Etihad are among the most active," says Trim. As of July 17, Cathay Pacific joined the fray with its Upgrade Bid. "The customer places a bid from a sliding scale of recommended prices to upgrade an existing Economy ticket to a premium cabin class," Trim explains. "If the bid is accepted, the airline debits your credit card and confirms the seat. Some airlines allow you to use points instead." To increase your chances, bid between 10 to 25 per cent higher than the base figure - and use an odd not a rounded off figure, such as $507, Trim recommends.

On Qantas, cash and points combinations can be used for their Bid Now Upgrades, where a minimum of 3000 points is required for a domestic upgrade, rising to 5000 for international.
Since it was introduced in 2015, the system has been so popular, more than 800,000 Qantas Frequent Flyers used their points to secure better seats last year, with New Zealand, Los Angeles, Honolulu and Bali among the most popular reward seat destinations. A final tip: Tuesday and Wednesday tend to be the quietest days of the week to fly.
With that, good luck and bon voyage. May the best bidder win - and may you never disembark from Economy at Heathrow at 5am ever again.
Fiona Carruthers edits the quarterly Sophisticated Traveller magazine, out in today's AFR Weekend.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Managing Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR Weekend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar Airways</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ditto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UpgradeMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finnair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shutterstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pointy End</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flat Beds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heathrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas Frequent Flyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PJs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Class</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HONOLULU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Trim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangkok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upgrade Bid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skytrax 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophisticated Traveller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia-Bangkok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frequent Flyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Carruthers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bid Now Upgrades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas Business Class</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prague</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shangri-La</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aladdin's Cave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helsinki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathay Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
