<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424211197808628</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/cats-will-face-a-dangerous-test-on-friday-night-footy-20170804-gxp9fi.html</url>
  <title>Cats will face a 'Dangerous' test on Friday night footy</title>
  <content>
Can the Cats pass the Danger test?
What better way to start the weekend than with a clash between two of the competition's most in-form sides? All eyes will be on Simonds Stadium on Friday night when Geelong and Sydney do battle in a top-eight blockbuster. The Cats head into the game without Patrick Dangerfield for the first time since he joined them at the end of 2015, so there is an element of "going into the unknown" for them. The Swans will also be missing their midfield maestro Josh Kennedy (hamstring) but have welcomed back a quartet of experienced players in  Jake Lloyd, Kurt Tippett, Sam Reid and Gary Rohan. Geelong's home ground has been a graveyard for most teams recently, but it holds no fears for Sydney. The Cats have won 15 of their past 16 matches there, with their only loss in that period coming at the hands of the Swans in round 16 last year.

Up Next

Sam Mitchell retires

02:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

Sam McClure previews all the footy action ahead of round 20 in the AFL.

Blues aiming to crash old foe's finals party
A meeting between two of the competition's oldest and fiercest rivals will have a lot more riding on it than usual on Saturday when Essendon clash with Carlton at the MCG for the 246th time. The Bombers are 9-9 in 10th spot with their finals hopes on a knife's edge and must do something they haven't done since 2013 to make a certainty of September action - win four games in a row. That task begins this weekend with what seems like a relatively easy assignment against the 17th-placed Blues who have only won five games this year and lost their past six in a row. However, one of those victories came against Essendon in round three as they totally outplayed their more-fancied opponents in wet conditions. It appears as though both sides will be greeted by rain again on Saturday, which helps Carlton's chances. The underdog has had an uncanny ability of winning this fixture in the past two decades and nothing would give Carlton more joy than to ruin the Bombers' finals dream.Photo: AAP
250 for big Rough
Hawthorn captain Jarryd Roughead runs out for his 250th match on Sunday when his rejuvenated Hawks face Richmond at the MCG in one of the round's most highly anticipated contests. Roughead's milestone seemed a long way off 12 months ago when he was battling to overcome a recurrence of melanoma, which had spread to his lungs. But a year on, the four-time premiership star is fighting fit and is spearheading his young team's unlikely bid for a finals spot. Having Hawthorn in the finals mix seemed fanciful after they lost their first four games by an average of 55 points, but their performances against premiership contenders in the past two months have been extraordinary with wins against Adelaide and Sydney (twice), a draw with GWS and a three-point loss to Geelong. Richmond head into a match with Hawthorn placed higher on the ladder than them for the first time since 2006.

A Showdown for the ages in the offing

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The traditional Showdown between arch enemies Adelaide and Port Adelaide is one of the biggest occasions on the football calendar and with both sides in the top five, the 43rd edition at Adelaide Oval on Sunday promises to be one of the more memorable ones. A win for the Power would not only have the potential to put the Crows' hopes of a home final in the first week at risk, but also prove that they can mix it with the best given they have only beaten two top-eight sides from eight attempts. A victory would also keep Port Adelaide's top-four hopes on track. But if the Crows make it five Showdown wins in a row for the first time ever, Port Adelaide could finish the round locked on 11 wins with four other teams. The big guns are back for the Crows with Eddie Betts, Brad Crouch and Jake Lever all named.
Deledio returns for critical meeting with Melbourne
A mere 15 hours after the Cats face the Swans, we will be treated to another match that has a huge bearing on the finals make-up. GWS host Melbourne at Manuka Oval on Saturday in what looms as a critical encounter for both the Giants' top-four aspirations and the Demons' top-eight hopes. Overshadowing the enormity of the occasion to a large extent, though, is the long-awaited return of Brett Deledio who has overcome a series of frustrating calf injuries to finally be selected for his first game with Greater Western Sydney. The former Richmond champ hasn't played a senior game since round 17 last year and if he can recapture his spark, he could ultimately prove to be the difference in the Giants' pursuit of their maiden premiership.
Bulldogs return to their 'Gabbatoir'
Is the Western Bulldogs' premiership defence officially back on? We will get a good indication on Saturday evening when they face the Brisbane Lions at the Gabba. The Dogs seemed to finally click into gear last week as they produced arguably their best performance of the year in a crucial "eight-pointer" against Essendon. They now sit in ninth spot and within touching distance of the top eight. And as they showed last year, all they have to do is make the eight to be a premiership chance. However, the Bulldogs haven't beaten the Lions at the Gabba since 2009 and with some important players like Dayne Zorko, Eric Hipwood and Daniel McStay returning to Brisbane's line-up, it's unlikely that Dogs fans will rest easy until the final siren sounds.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Tippett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam McClure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel McStay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Hipwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Zorko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabbatoir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
