<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423781701073164</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/life/loreal-brand-ambassador-helen-mirren-admits-moisturiser-does-f-all/news-story/af8024d6d612667acc52990387be390d</url>
  <title>'My moisturiser? It doesn't work'</title>
  <content>
Helen Mirren may have single-handedly destroyed the mystique - not to say the share price - of the make up brand she represents, after publicly confiding that using moisturiser "probably does f*** all."
The 72-year-old actress, whose flawless complexion helped get her the job as brand ambassador of the French product range L'Oreal, made the remark while sitting on a L'Oreal panel in the South of France.
"I'm not setting standards for others. All I can do is be who I am. I've always loved make-up," she said.
"I'm an eternal optimist - I know that when I put my moisturiser on it probably does f--- all, but it just makes me feel better. I've always said to L'Oreal as well that I will only do what makes me feel better."
Her comments have drawn comparison with those of British jeweller Gerald Ratner, whose empire very nearly collapsed in 1991 after he described his products as "total crap", knocking nearly $1bn off the firm's value with those few words.
Ms Mirren is the face of L'Oreal's 'Age Perfect' moisturiser range. She was signed in 2014 after consumer research showed she was regarded as "genuine, intelligent and glamorous, with looks that seem only to improve with the passing of time".
She has always insisted that the advertisements in which she features aren't digitally retouched to erase wrinkles.
Speaking at the event n Cannes, the Oscar winning actress also described her frustration with the advertising world's long term fixation on extreme youth.
"It used to drive me crazy that the ads promoting skin products were using pictures of 15 and 16-year-old girls," she said..
"As a 30-year-old, I used to look at that and think, what the f--- are you talking about? It was ridiculous. P----- me off majorly. Advertisers are only just coming out of that, and it's taken them a long time."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cannes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Age-Perfect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mirren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oreal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South of France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerald Ratner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Mirren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
