<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423747341334377</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-04/dangerfield-no-certainty-to-present-brownlow-medal-says-mclachlan</url>
  <title>Danger no certainty to present Brownlow, says McLachlan</title>
  <content>
Will Patrick Dangerfield present this year's Brownlow Medal?

IT'S NOT a fait accompli reigning Brownlow medallist Patrick Dangerfield will present the award to this year's winner, with AFL CEO Gillon McLachlan saying the superstar's thoughts on the issue will be paramount.

Dangerfield was rubbed out of Brownlow contention when he accepted a one-match ban offered by the Match Review Panel for a tackle on Carlton ruckman Matthew Kreuzer that left the big Blue concussed.

Powerful Richmond midfielder Dustin Martin looms as the unassailable favourite to take 'Charlie' home according to the AFL.com.au , but Dangerfield would not necessarily be the one to hand the medal over, as per tradition.

"At the right time, we'll have a discussion with Patty. We certainly don't want to make him feel uncomfortable," McLachlan told Melbourne radio station 3AW on Friday morning.

"I don't know where his mindset will be on that going forward. I just reckon we would be sensible about that.

"I haven't had discussions about that internally but I'm aware of the issue and if Patty said to me 'I just don't want to be there. I'd feel bad' or for whatever reason, I think we'd feel sensible.

"On the flipside, in a few weeks' time when he's reflected, he is the reigning Bronwlow medallist. He should be incredibly proud and he may well go 'Of course I want to be there'."

Dangerfield told KIIS FM he thought it was unlikely he would poll more votes than Martin and then awkwardly have to put the medal around the Tiger's neck.

"It could potentially happen, but I don't think it's going to be a reality," Dangerfield said.

"I think Dusty is going to win quite convincingly, but you never know, stranger things have happened."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL CEO Gillon McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S NOT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLachlan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KIIS FM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
