<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423695801726218</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/no-jail-for-perth-driver-oscar-graetz-over-car-crash-that-killed-nz-teenager-logan-cant/news-story/a40463d2daf0335e3d0fafedfc415dd8</url>
  <title>No jail over crash that killed NZ teen</title>
  <content>
A YOUNG man who drifted onto the wrong side of the road and smashed head-on into a teenage motorcyclist has escaped jail by the "barest of margins" over the fatal crash. 
Oscar Walter Erich Graetz, 21, was driving his little brother home in his dad's utility in April 2015 when he smashed head-on into a motorcycle in Hopeland.
The victim, 17-year-old Logan Cant, was thrown from his Kawasaki motorbike and died on the side of Karnup Road.
Graetz pleaded not guilty to dangerous driving causing death but was convicted of the charge after a trial.
District Court Judge Julie Wager jailed Graetz for two years today but suspended the term for two years.
He was disqualified from driving for 2.5 years.
After the crash, Graetz told police he hear a bang at the point of impact but did not see Mr Cant before the collision on the 100km/h road.
Graetz spoke to his mother on the phone for a few minutes using a hands-free device but hung up just before the crash on the rural road.
He had the car's cruise control set to 100km/h at the time.
Prosecutor David Jubb argued there must have been a prolonged period of "highly dangerous" inattention before Graetz slammed into the motorcyclist.
"We don't know what gave rise to that lapse of attention," he said.
"But the end result was that this offender drove on the wrong side of the road for a significant period of time."
The court was told Graetz had been caught speeding three times after the fatal crash.
"One might question whether this was a life changing incident given these three breaches of speeding that followed it," Mr Jubb said.
Defence lawyer John Prior described the case as unique and said no sentence would bring back Mr Cant.
He said his client drove past the accident scene "every single day".
"This is a unique case, a tragic case because it involves two very young men, the deceased and Me Graetz," Mr Prior said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Ca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karnup Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Prior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jubb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hopeland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar Walter Erich Graetz, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jubb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graetz</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-17</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court Judge Julie Wager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawasakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ca</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Prior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
