<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424211197808540</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/carlton-unsure-on-young-gun-harry-mckays-return-20170804-gxpbpa.html</url>
  <title>Carlton unsure on young gun Harry McKay's return</title>
  <content>
Carlton are hoping exciting tall forward Harry McKay's AFL season isn't over after he was sidelined by a toe injury.
The 19-year-old will miss Saturday's clash with Essendon at the MCG after making his highly-anticipated debut a fortnight ago.

Up Next

Sam Mitchell retires

02:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

Sam McClure previews all the footy action ahead of round 20 in the AFL.

McKay is one of several forced omissions along with Simon White (knee), David Cuningham (ankle) and Tom Williamson (illness).
The 17th-placed Blues have dropped their past six games and face a tough run home with the Bombers, West Coast, Hawthorn and Sydney to come.Photo: AAP/Dan Peled
With coach Brendon Bolton eager to give his young charges as much experience as possible, McKay will be given every opportunity to return this season.
"We're hoping to get some games into him before the end of the year but we'll just have to see how that toe comes up," Bolton said on Friday.

"Hopefully it's a week or two but that's the unknown."

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Saturday's clash looms as a must-win for 10th-placed Essendon's chances of making the finals.
The Blues claimed an upset victory at a drenched MCG when the two sides met in round three, but Bolton acknowledged the free-wheeling Bombers had only improved since then.
While Bolton signalled Carlton would look to add midfield depth and outside run during the off-season, the Blues have already placed focus on rotating young players through new positions.
"We've had Charlie Curnow able to play in the ruck and some more midfield - that's great learning for him," Bolton said.
"A fortnight ago, Jack Silvagni played at half-back. We got the opportunity for [Caleb] Marchbank to play a little bit of wing last week and not just in defence.
"They're all signs of growth for us. They might be little from the outside but they're going to pay us back."
Carlton have recalled Dennis Armfield, Billie Smedts, Blaine Boekhorst and Jarrod Pickett for Saturday's game at the MCG.
The 30-year-old Armfield has only managed two games this season but Bolton was yet to speak with the veteran about his future.
"He's been a terrific leader for us," Bolton said.
"He's been investing in our kids and he's driven really good standards in the VFL. He's a great character and I'm sure he's going to be playing with some determination this week."
AAP 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marchbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Armfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry McKay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam McClure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Silvagni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry McKay's AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Curnow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blaine Boekhorst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billie Smedts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Dan Peled</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Pickett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Williamson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cuningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caleb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
