<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424211197808636</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/tolls-waived-on-logan-motorway-until-6pm-today-to-help-ease-traffic-congestion/news-story/3c292961e2eccf5e1d7e7a8cfdf0547d</url>
  <title>Tolls waived on motorway</title>
  <content>
TOLLS will be waived in both directions on the Logan Motorway from the M1 to the Gateway merge until 6pm today in a bid to alleviate traffic congestion caused by a truck fire.
when travelling southbound on the M1 at Loganholme about 8.40 this morning.
The driver was assessed by paramedics but escaped unhurt.
Both directions of the highway were closed as police set up an exclusion zone, with the southbound lanes still closed near the scene.
Acting Main Roads and Road Safety Minister Steven Miles said waiving the tolls on the Logan Motorway between the M1 merge (Loganlea toll point) and Gateway merge (Kuraby toll point) would help keep motorists moving while emergency services continue recovery efforts at the accident site.
"We understand the frustrations of being caught in traffic and we thank those motorists who were affected this morning for their patience," Mr Miles said.
"While the northbound lanes of the M1 have reopened this morning, police advise traffic will be disrupted for much of the afternoon and the southbound lanes will remain closed for some time.
"To help get the network moving again we've waived tolls on the Logan Motorway from the M1 to the Gateway merge until 6pm.
"Anyone thinking of travelling between the Gold Coast, Brisbane and Logan this afternoon is advised to take these travel disruptions into account and plan accordingly.
"Toll tags will still beep when travelling underneath a tolling point, however tolls will not be charged between 10.45am today and 6pm tonight."
Mr Miles said once the truck was empty, it would be loaded on to a recovery vehicle and taken away under police escort.
"Once cleared by emergency services to do so, our crews will assist with the clean-up and assess any damage to the road," Mr Miles said.
"I would like to thank the Queensland Police Service and Queensland Fire and Emergency Services for their efforts and motorists for their patience."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuraby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loganholme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Motorway</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Road Safety Minister Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Miles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loganlea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
