<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424000744407825</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/food/eat/brisbane-woman-claims-shes-found-a-bullet-in-her-kangaroo-steak/news-story/8303382e59fcadf9a697f2c0443c66e9</url>
  <title>Brisbane woman claims she's found a bullet in her Kangaroo steak</title>
  <content>
A woman claims her kangaroo steak had a bullet in it after buying it from Woolworths.

Share

AN Australian woman claims she's found a bullet fragment in her kangaroo steak, which she purchased from supermarket giant Woolworths.
Taking to Facebook, Kath Milroy Pattingale posted a photo of the steak - which clearly shows the golden shell sitting in the centre of the meat.

The post has since been deleted after receiving more than 22k likes.Source:Facebook
"Mmmmmm thanks Woolies - nothing more appetising than a bullet in my kangaroo!," her post read, which has been liked more than 25,000 times.
"This pic was taken on a chopping board when we were cutting up the meat (a 60mm thick fillet) after taking if off the barbie - it didn't make it to the dinner plate!"
Ms Pattingale claims she left the meat in the fridge for a Woolworths representative to look at.

The woman claims her kangaroo stead had a bullet shell in it.Source:Facebook
Her post was met with 12,000 comments, with some social media users claiming it could be a stitch up.
"Looks like a con to me," one person posted.
"Certainly Woolworths would run their meats through a metal detector before sending it off," another wrote.
A Woolworths Australia spokesperson told news.com.au in a statement that they "take all customer concerns seriously and are investigating the issue raised".

The post has since been deleted
News.com.au has contacted Ms Pattingale for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Pattingale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mmmmmm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath Milroy Pattingale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
