<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423618492313356</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/sleepy-greyhound-a-perfect-flatmate-for-working-couple-in-brunswick/news-story/d6191219972f481def18f83b5e24c8f7</url>
  <title>Racing retiree chillin' away from the track</title>
  <content>
AFTER running rings around the racetrack, an apartment is the last place you would expect a greyhound to feel at home.
But the sporty dogs are perfect for living in small spaces, as they prefer to sleep most of the day, new owner Tom Thompsett said.
Mr Thompsett and his wife Libby adopted Saj the three-year-old greyhound through Greyhound Racing Victoria's adoption program a few weeks ago.
"We were looking for a dog that wouldn't mind being in a home with full-time workers and wouldn't mind being by himself as the only animal," Mr Thompsett said.
"He's energetic for 15 to 20 minutes, we take him around Princes Park, then he has a bit of food and sleeps."
Greyhound Racing Victoria spokesman Luke Holmesby said greyhounds could run at up to 70km/h, but only needed a tiny amount of exercise because of their fast-twitch muscle fibres.
"They're genetically built for short bursts of exercise and not so much stamina," Mr Holmesby said.
"The exercise they do have doesn't need to have them running super-quick and they naturally tire out pretty quickly."
Mr Thompsett said Saj had been a wonderful addition to his family and encouraged others to adopt a greyhound.
"We have been really pleased with Saj and he's a great dog to be around," he said.
For more information about the Greyhound Adoption Program, visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Thompsett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Holmesby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Holmesby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Thompsett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greyhound Adoption Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAJ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greyhound Racing Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
