<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423652852052472</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/qld-premier-hits-back-at-nz-trade-jab/news-story/1661a0342eb8f4752d7b97323d00c0dd</url>
  <title>Qld premier hits back at NZ trade jab</title>
  <content>
Shae McDonald and Sonia KohlbacherAustralian Associated Press

Share

Queensland's premier has accused New Zealand's trade minister of not reading her government's plan to preference local businesses before he publicly slammed the plan.
Annastacia Palaszczuk says local businesses would receive weightings of up to 30 per cent in the consideration of government contracts under the Buy Queensland procurement policy.
Announced at Labor's state conference last weekend, it would mean reconsidering Australia and New Zealand's agreement, which was "not good" for Queensland.
New Zealand Trade Minister Todd McClay on Friday expressed his disappointment at the announcement and labelled Ms Palaszczuk "short sighted".
She was quick to respond with a return jab.
"I understand that the New Zealand trade minister hasn't even read the policy," Ms Palaszczuk said.
"I'm more than happy to send him a copy so he can be familiar with the policy.
"What I want to see is local people being able to have the opportunity to put forward their case about keeping jobs within close proximity."
Mr McClay said he had doubts about the policy's legal viability and claimed it went against standard trade procedures.

Queensland exported $5 billion worth of goods and services to New Zealand every year, he added.
Mr McClay said he had not spoken to Ms Palaszczuk and was seeking advice from lawyers about the legality of the new policy, to be implemented on September 1.
"I haven't seen all of the detail of what she's proposing....I don't see how it can work and it's going to cost a lot more money," he said.
The criticism comes as the Queensland government announced that state exports had continued to "boom", with $65.9 billion in goods sold overseas in the 12 months to June.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shae McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Trade Minister Todd McClay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McClay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonia KohlbacherAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buy Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
