<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424258442449565</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/oneminute-auction-battle-scores-seven-figure-sale/news-story/b751e38ed9ea84f934c2303165cb2dcf</url>
  <title>One-minute auction battle scores seven figure sale - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
sold in a minute at its July 29 auction.

A TOWNHOUSE has sold at an auction lasting less than sixty seconds.
The speedy result followed a rapid-fire bidding battle that took it to a seven-figure sale price more than $200,000 above the reserve.
Professionals Whiting and Co St Kilda director Dannie Corr said the property at  was the subject of a short, sharp contest.
"When bidding started, I'd say it took under a minute," Mr Corr said.
The competition began with a $1.4 million bid, which was already above the reserve price for the property, he added.
"The opening bid was what we call a Muhammad Ali bid - they were wanting to make a knockout bid which it certainly was, save for one other person," Mr Corr said.
"So just the two of them competed like guns firing."
The hammer fell at $1.5 million, with the opening bidder winning the keys.
Mr Corr said the sale price was approximately $250,000 above the reserve.
"It was a very good result," he said.
Mr Corr said the two bidders were both local buyers, who had been motivated by seeing an earlier auction a few doors up the road achieve a hefty sale price.

Timber floors, a fireplace and a paved courtyard are features of the home.

The three-bedroom townhouse features a rooftop terrace, a double garage, and a neutral interior with timber floors, stone benchtops and a fireplace.
It is walking distance from Albert Park Lake, the beach and the St Kilda light rail.
"I think a lot of it was about the position," Mr Corr said.
"Its also a very appealing home, it was bright and it had a very St Kilda feel."
The property attracted strong inquiry throughout the campaign, he added.
"It received a lot of interest, some interstate, too," Mr Corr said.
St Kilda West offered a great deal of appeal to buyers considering its small size, with a mix of property styles and good amenities, according to Mr Corr.
"It's only a very small pocket, and has a lot of period architecture and wide, tree-lined streets," he said. "It has the beach, parks, transport and access to restaurants and bars."
SEE SUBURB PROFILE:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Park Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whiting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURB PROFILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dannie Corr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Corr</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muhammad Ali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
