<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424597744870916</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/sa-racing/one-more-daisy-can-bloom-in-wet-weather-at-morphettville-for-trainer-glen-kent/news-story/a4abc70ae56331e3202bab17ed2b9274</url>
  <title>Rain won't stop Daisy from blooming</title>
  <content>
GLEN Kent hopes a couple of proven wet-track performers can tame the wild weather forecast for Morphettville on Saturday.
Adelaide is expecting between 5-10ml of rain on Friday, with that expected to escalate on Saturday afternoon with the forecast of showers, the chance of thunderstorms in the late afternoon and winds between 40-60km/h.
Kent and co-trainer Wayne Francis's Finniss Lodge stables have three strong chances, led by talented mare One More Daisy, who is chasing her fifth win from her past nine starts in town. Kent said it was an opportune time for the mare to take another step up in grade, taking on some seasoned Adelaide sprinters in Riziz and Daytona Grey, along with well credentialed Victorian sprinter Husson Eagle
"This is a good test for her this weekend,'' Kent said. "She gets in on the minimum and a few of the better horses probably not in the best form.
"There looks to be a bit of speed in the race and if she can get something done tomorrow and run top three, we'll head to a race like the Wylie with her.'' Stablemate Patch Hero hasn't missed a placed from three heavy-track appearances and Kent said the mare would be suited by the smaller field on Saturday.
"She got a bit lost last time. She wasn't beaten far,'' he said.
"She's a horse who is better in a smaller field which she gets on Saturday. I've put the winkers on her and she's probably at that stage where she's looking for that bit of gear."
Zipnotized is another with an affinity for the soft going. The veteran mare has never missed a placed in six starts on heavy tracks. "She loves the wet. She should be thereabouts with the help of the claim", the trainer said.

Kent said he had scaled back numbers for the 2017-18 season, with a focus on early-season SA features including the Spring Stakes with talented sprinter Lope De Capio.
"We're back from 30 to 20, concentrating on a smaller team this season,'' Kent added.
"It's more about the quality over quantity. We've got a lot of two-year-olds in here now and a few nice three-year-olds coming through who should be at the races shortly.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daytona Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patch Hero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daisy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zipnotized</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wylie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lope De Capio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riziz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GLEN Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kent</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Francis's Finniss Lodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One More Daisy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Husson Eagle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphettville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
