<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424344341796684</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/daisy-hill-students-learn-the-benefits-of-outdoor-classes/news-story/0d47ef7be80dde9e882f3d2d8b7af81e</url>
  <title>Teaching in the great outdoors</title>
  <content>
A DAISY HILL school has taken up the call for teachers to move their classes outdoors more often.
Teachers at the school decided to step into the great outdoors after environmental lobby group Planet Ark published a report this month which suggested outdoor learning improved academic outcomes, resilience, and emotional intelligence.
The school, which made headlines this year after changing its name from Slacks Creek State School, will plant at least 50 trees with the help of Bunnings.
Head of curriculum at the school Stacey Dabelstein said students would also participate in Schools Tree Day as part of a greater push to make their schoolyard greener.
"Our Preps have been so interested and intrigued in plants this year that we started a garden club," she said. "The students provide fresh herbs, fruit and vegetables to the cooking classes along with beautiful flowers."
Schools which have adopted the measures said having more classes outside was not about more play time but rather creatively adapting the curriculum.
Daisy Hill students will also be planting for National Science Week between 12 and 20 August, the theme being Future Earth which focuses on sustainability science.
According to Planet Ark, more than half of Australian teachers are spending next to no time with their students outside the classroom.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future Earth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planet Ark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Science Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slacks Creek State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schools Tree Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAISY HILL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stacey Dabelstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
