<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423609902378409</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/entertainment/sofia-vergara-poses-nude-in-womens-health-magazine/news-story/089c5ebe284475b98a51dd8891129f52</url>
  <title>Vergara: 'I can barely cover my boobs'</title>
  <content>
SOFIA Vergara recently turned 45 on July 10th and she's proudly flaunting her birthday suit.
The Modern Family star posed completely nude for  . And the highest-paid television star in the world claimed flaunting her curves was a breeze.
"I've always been very comfortable with my body," the actress told the magazine.
"You know, I'm Latin so we grow up going to the beach in a G-string. I used to do work for the Latin market in my 20s. Like I would do calendar shoots, very sexy and everything. And you know things have changed ... how much you take care of yourself is a reality. We all age and you have to embrace it."
However, Vergara admitted she was a bit nervous about the upcoming photo shoot. Right before, Vergara was filming Bent in Rome and "ate like an animal." She wasn't exercising and then two days before the shoot, she came home with pneumonia. Looking over at photos of potential poses sent by the creative team also didn't help.
"They're all of tall models holding their boobs with one arm," she said. "But I can barely cover my boobs with two arms - I'm a 32-triple-D! My boobs are real, and I had a baby. If I grab them, I can't even cover the nipple!"
These days, Vergara is attempting to have a regular fitness routine, but even she gets tempted to stay in bed.
"Like I find any excuse not to do it," she said. "[I'm] Taking a couple of yoga classes. I'm very bad at it. I don't have much patience. So I'm always trying to find something that I can do."
She also added, "I don't know if I'm strong. I have bad knees and very thin bones; I can barely do a push-up. I wish I could be a little more athletic, but when you're born with these gigantic boobs ... I've had them since I was 13 and they've got bigger when I was pregnant and had the baby."
And even though her husband, Magic Mike actor Joe Manganiello, is a lifelong athlete, she still can't seem to enjoy any workout sessions.
"It's like torture for me," she explained. "I'm in a bad mood two hours before, I'm in a bad mood while I'm doing it, I'm in a bad mood at the end because I have to schedule the next class."
Vergara did say it's gotten easier for women like her to proudly embrace their shape in front of cameras.
"It's not just the Barbie doll on the cover," she said. "It's real women. So it's getting better. I think before it was a little bit more strict to how women were supposed to look ... It's not about having muscle or cut abs. I don't have abs because I'm not 'I need to be a fit model with the perfect body.' That would take too much effort!"
The September 2017 issue of Women's Health hits newsstands August 8.
This article was originally published on
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Mike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modern Family</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofia Vergara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G-string</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Manganiello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vergara</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
