<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424344341796714</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/man-accelerated-stolen-mustang-towards-police-court-documents-allege-20170804-gxp4xb.html</url>
  <title>Man accelerated stolen Canberra Mustang towards police, court hears</title>
  <content>
A Griffith man who allegedly accelerated a stolen car towards a police officer at a petrol station before taking off was later caught when his alleged co-offender dobbed him in, court documents say.
The ruby red Ford Mustang had been reported stolen the morning of August 3. But it was only a few hours later that police spotted the car at a 7-Eleven in Fyshwick being filled up with petrol.Photo: Supplied
Police pulled their four-wheel drive in front of the Mustang, got out, and told the two men to get on the ground, the documents say.
The man in the driver's seat allegedly "aggressively reversed" even as the other man was trying to remove the fuelling nozzle.

The driver then accelerated towards an officer.
"In fear of his life the police officer drew his firearm and took aim at the vehicle while simultaneously attempting to avoid the Mustang," the police statement tendered in court says.

Surveillance video captured the alleged events.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The driver was able to flee the scene but police chased the other man on foot. They arrested him and he allegedly dobbed in the driver: "The driver was Ash, he left me here, he lives at Stuart Flats."
Police caught up with a man named Ashley Brian Figura, 23, in Griffith. He was out-of-breath and denied any involvement in the matter, but a police officer from the events at the petrol station allegedly identified him as the driver and he was arrested.
Police found the Mustang at an address in Manuka later on Thursday and returned the car to its owner.
Mr Figura appeared in the ACT Magistrates Court on Friday, where he was charged with dangerous driving, driving a stolen car, failing to stop for police and driving while disqualified. He did not enter pleas.
A police officer who gave evidence in Mr Figure bail application said investigations were continuing but police were "heading towards" charges of aggravated robbery on the alleged car theft.
She said alleged offenders were still outstanding in relation to the matters, and police were still interviewing witnesses.
Police also believe Mr Figura is connected to other alleged crimes.
The officer giving evidence said police are investigating robberies at the Kingston and Yarralumla IGAs. A white Volkswagon had been linked to the crimes and a white Volkswagon was also linked to the alleged theft of the red Mustang, the officer told the court. Police believe there are links between Mr Figura and the Volkswagon.
The officer said that in the car on the way to the police station Mr Figura made threats against his alleged co-offender, calling him a "dog" and saying that he couldn't believe he'd done this to him.
In refusing the man bail Magistrate Peter Morrison made reference to the alleged threats, as well as the man's behaviour in trying to avoid apprehension, and the other offences being investigated.
The man also had a "not insignificant" criminal history, the magistrate said, and time in prison was likely if the man was found guilty.
He formally refused Mr Figura bail.
The case will return to court on August 18.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Figure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Figura</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fyshwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Peter Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarralumla IGAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mustang</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Brian Figura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Flats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Mustang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Mustang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
