<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424425946176824</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834511/devils-hunting-major-scalp-in-final-hit-out/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Wests looking to break top four drought against league leaders</title>
  <content>
EDGING CLOSER: Wests coach Brett Kimmorley will be looking to end a run of outs against top four teams on Saturday. Picture: Sylvia Liber

WESTS will be looking to end a run of outs against their top four rivals when they face next-door neighbours and league leaders Collegians on Saturday.
The Devils fought out a thrilling 16-all draw with Thirroul last week, with the one-point seeing them leapfrog the Butchers into third spot.

Centre Junior Vaivai had the chance to put his side ahead after leveling the scores with late try, but his attempted conversion was waved away, leaving Wests without a win against top four opposition this season.

With a final-round bye to follow Saturday's clash, Brett Kimmorley's men will be desperate to snap the run of near misses and take some much needed confidence into their finals campaign.
Having gone agonisingly close to a breakthrough last week, assistant coach Pete McLeod is confident his side can break the drought this week.
"You go to Thirroul and it's always tough to win," McLeod said.
"We knew they'd got beaten by Dapto the week before so we knew they'd be up for it and they were. We stuck with them early, I think both teams completed about the same, and we led at halftime.

"They took their opportunities in the second half and scored three tries off kicks. You normally you don't come home at the back-end and beat Thirroul and, while we didn't get the win, we were able to level the scores which was good from our guys.

"It was a tough result, we were obviously going in hoping to win it and if Junior kicks a goal we win, but we had a couple of other opportunities. We're going to have to take them this week against Collies."
With the exception of a 31-0 pasting at the hands of Dapto in round eight, all their losses have come by eight points or less and McLeod said he's never had cause to question his side's effort.
"We've been in every game this year up to our eye balls," McLeod said.

"Even against Dapto [in round eight], yeah the scoreline didn't look to great at the end, but with 15 minutes to go it was 10-0 and we had our opportunities there as well.

"The results haven't gone our way every time but it's never a question of effort it's more execution."
One of those tight losses came to the Dogs by six points in round six and McLeod said it would be massive for his side to knockoff the competition leaders in their last match before the finals.
"It's really a good test before the semis to play Thirroul and Collies because they're the sides we'll be playing in the semi-finals," McLeod said.
"They play very different styles of footy and we'll be faced with a different challenge this week but the boys are up for it.

"We know we've got to beat good teams if we want to go further in this competition. Our last two games, including last week, are against top four sides.

"We've got the bye next week and we want to compete against the best teams in the comp and Collies are certainly that so to get a win against them would be huge for the boys confidence."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Kimmorley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centre Junior Vaivai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete McLeod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLeod</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
