<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424683644218248</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/stamford-park-mens-shed-hopeful-of-setting-up-new-site/news-story/a024dd2b91ec8ad3c9f3af06eab67e0c</url>
  <title>Push for permanent Men's Shed</title>
  <content>
THE Stamford Park Men's shed group still doesn't have a shed, but the resourceful bunch is hoping to change that.
The group of about 30 men, mostly retirees are based in the guest quarters of the historic homestead.
With plans to convert that into a restaurant as part of the $13 million Stamford Park masterplan, the men's shed could be headed to another corner of the park.
President Barry Treadwell said that would let them have a more permanent base. They have been at the homestead for seven years and are keen to stay in the park.
"We've been maintaining five acres (2.02ha) of grounds surrounding the homestead and we have become very attached to the old lady," he said.
He said they were happy to help build a new shed.
"We've got builders, welders, fitters, electricians, anything you can name, we can help with," he said.
The members have an average age of about 70 and do a lot of work on maintenance, planting vegetable gardens and helping with community projects.
Knox councillor Nicole Seymour, who chairs the Stamford Park Project Steering Committee, said talks were ongoing about finding the right spot for the group.
She was hopeful the men would stay in the park grounds, and would remain in their current spot in the meantime.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Men's Shed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Barry Treadwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stamford Park Project Steering Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stamford Park Men</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stamford Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
