<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424258442449640</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/novel-perth-meth-rehab-centre-in-court-win/news-story/a062c07e9bc81b9fbf78f2cdb182cbc8</url>
  <title>Strict WA meth rehab centre in court win</title>
  <content>
A tough-love rehabilitation centre for male drug and alcohol addicts in Perth's Swan Valley can stay open for now after a Supreme Court ruling gave it a second chance to secure local council approval.
Shalom House needed the permission to operate, which the City of Swan refused and also appealed against a State Administrative Tribunal decision to refer the matter back to the council for reconsideration.
The Supreme Court has sent the case back to the SAT for determination, which Shalom House has welcomed as a good result and one step toward an outcome.
"It means that it stays open, and we are able to continue our work in restoring the lives of men and families in our community," founder and chief executive Peter Lyndon-James said.
When the case commenced, Shalom House had just over 30 residents, one property and a handful of staff.
But it has grown to 120 residents and more than 50 staff and volunteers across 10 properties, with high rates of meth use playing a big role in increasing demand for its services.
"The circumstances have changed significantly, so it would be great for the lines of communication with the City of Swan to open," Mr Lyndon-James said.
"We are optimistic about the future and look forward to this matter being resolved."
Shalom House claims to be Australia's strictest rehabilitation centre and says its program seeks to restore all aspects of the resident's life including finances, relationships, mecial issues, employment, education and training.
Mr Lyndon-James himself broke free from 26 years of addiction and doesn't hesitate to turf out residents if they break the rules, including smoking tobacco.
"If you are not 150 per cent serious about changing your life, we suggest you try somewhere else," the Shalom House website warns.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lyndon-James</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Lyndon-James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth's Swan Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shalom House</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Swan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
