<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424726593891961</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/artist-lydia-ciconte-selling-her-brighton-penthouse/news-story/8dac6214d1015e228ba41c29c6adc165</url>
  <title>Artist Lydia Ciconte selling her Brighton penthouse - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Lydia Ciconte's apartment at 32 Outer Cres, Brighton, has been designed to look like an art gallery.

PAINTER Lydia Ciconte is selling her Brighton penthouse, which she designed to resemble an art gallery.
The artist, who creates her paintings with her fingers, combined two apartments to create the home, where she's lived with her family for almost seven years.

Inside Lydia Ciconte's apartment at 32 Outer Cres, Brighton.

The three-bedroom plus study residence is one of 14 apartments in a boutique block at
32 Outer Cres.
"We designed it all around the art collection, in terms of where the paintings were going on each wall," she said.
"We made sure the ceilings were high, that there were areas to entertain and balconies."

The space is more than 274sq m internally.

She said she'd loved the apartment's position, walking distance from her Hampton studio and across the road from her daughters' school, and the fact she could "lock up and leave" it to visit her coastal property on weekends.
Harcourts, Brighton, director Rebecca Bevan said the space was more than 274sq m internally.
It's being sold privately with a price guide of $3.2-$3.4 million.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Bevan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outer Cres</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harcourts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lydia Ciconte</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
