<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424683644218245</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/gold-coast/step-inside-one-of-the-coolest-queenslanders-on-the-gold-coast/news-story/b422511a9ab5c921ba09d8ebc39c97e2</url>
  <title>Step inside one of the coolest Queenslanders on the Gold Coast - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
41 Sydney St, Labrador.

WELCOME to a charming Queenslander in one of the trendiest suburbs on the northern Gold Coast.
Around the corner from hip cafe precinct Chrin Park, 41 Sydney St is as cool as they come but it wasn't always this way.

41 Sydney St, Chirn Park.

Homeowner Renee Litonjua and her partner David have given the home a true Queenslander-style makeover with sleek modern finishes and a fresh colour palette combined with French doors and a sun-drenched balcony.
"It isn't a real Queenslander if it doesn't have a veranda or timber flooring," Ms Litonjua said.
"David and I are obsessed with this style of home and we wanted to give it a modern feel but still adhere to some of the traditional elements in a Queenslander."

41 Sydney St, Chirn Park.

Red iron bark timber flooring brings the home to life while a new kitchen and bathroom create a contemporary vibe.

41 Sydney St, Labrador.

Ms Litonjua said the couple used a few simple styling tricks to bring the home to life but the hardest part was choosing which colour to paint the door.
"We absolutely could not decide on what colour to paint the door, and believe me when I say there are hundreds of different shades of white," she said.
"I found a picture of a blue coloured door on Pinterest and hunted down the lady who took the photo.
"Apparently she lived in New Zealand and the colour was a duck egg blue but of course when we went to get it there was different variations.
"I think we nailed it in the end."

41 Sydney St, Chirn Park.

The couple have given the whole house a cosmetic makeover with classic handrails, batwing doors and a fence.
"It is as modern as they come but of course it still retains its traditional character," Ms Litonjua said.
"If David and I could pick it up and take it with us - believe me, we would."

41 Sydney St, Labrador.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Litonjua</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chirn Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslander-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chrin Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney St</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinterest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Litonjua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labrador</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
