<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423691506758778</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/queen-street-mall-gunman-lee-matthew-hilliers-parole-bid-dismissed-20170804-gxpaii.html</url>
  <title>Queen Street Mall gunman fails in jail release bid</title>
  <content>
The man who sent Brisbane's central shopping strip into lockdown when he pulled a handgun on a police officer more than four years ago has failed in his bid to get out of jail early.
Lee Matthew Hillier, 38, took the parole board to court in June after it approved and then cancelled his application for parole, declaring him an unacceptable risk of reoffending.Photo: Andreas Kouremenos
The life-long drug user told a court hearing last month he wanted to to go to rehab before his full release so that he would not be "put onto the street full time with ... no direction."
Panic gripped Brisbane's CBD on March 8, 2013, when Hillier was asked for ID by a police officer and instead pulled out a handgun.
The siege lasted for an hour and a half and saw terrified workers and shoppers in the city's Queen Street Mall evacuated and specialist police called in.
Hillier was eventually shot with a mixture of lethal and non-lethal rounds, before police discovered the handgun had not been loaded.

He was sentenced to 4 1/2 years in prison, with a parole eligibility date set for later in 2013.
Even if Friday's application for a review of his parole cancellation had been successful, it would likely have shaved less than a month off his jail time because he is due for release next month.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The father-of-three claimed the board had failed to take into account his personal situation in cancelling his parole, namely his looming full-time release date.
Representing himself in the Supreme Court via videolink from Lotus Glen Correctional Centre near Cairns on Friday, the self-confessed drug addict claimed "everyone" seemed to focus on one bad thing he did in prison, rather than all the good things he achieved.
Hillier offered to withdraw his application after counsel for the Central and Northern Queensland Regional Parole Board Michael Woodford pointed out several flaws in his arguments.
Chief Justice Catherine Holmes dismissed the application, urging Hillier not to think too much about the result and to instead focus on turning his life around after his full-time release from prison on September 8.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lotus Glen Correctional Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Street Mall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Queensland Regional Parole Board Michael Woodford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillier</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Justice Catherine Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Matthew Hillier, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andreas Kouremenos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
