<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424348636764085</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/put-a-glow-stick-in-your-kids-nighttime-barf-bucket/</url>
  <title>Put A Glow Stick In Your Kid's Nighttime Barf Bucket </title>
  <content>
Photo: /Flickr
Having a sick kid is hard. Having a sick kid who's throwing up is hard and messy. Having a sick kid who's throwing up in the darkness of the night is hard and messy and terrifying.

To increase the chances that poor Harper will aim successfully into the bucket when the lights are off and she has 1.8 seconds to locate it, place a  inside.  shared the story of when his three kids were all sick at the same time.

"As they are all under five, the use of the barf bucket was hit-or-miss ... mostly miss," the redditor wrote. "... My kids don't like night lights - they complain they are too bright. I wanted them to be able to have the barf bucket just in case. So I thought to put a glow stick in their bucket so it would give them something to help find the bucket - plus they really liked the idea and felt it was special/cool."

Other parents gave  for making the barf bucket even more effective:

Add a little bit of water to the bucket to cut down on the smell and make it easier to pour out later.

Line the bucket with two bags - a paper bag (which structurally stays open) inside of a plastic bag.

Tie a string to the glow stick and let it hang outside the bucket.

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flickr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glow Stick In Your Kid's Nighttime Barf Bucket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
