<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423657147019849</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/money/wealth/sydney-man-comes-forward-a-week-after-lotto-draw-to-claim-105-million-win/news-story/06036435b55f7e3b01402f590f2e08e9</url>
  <title>Sydney man comes forward a week after Lotto draw to claim $1.05 million win</title>
  <content>
What it's like to win lotto
1:16

Hear the reaction when you are told you have won $20 million dollars.

November 17th 2016
9 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

A Sydney man took over a week to claim his $1.05 million win. Picture: Melvyn Knipe

Natalie Wolfe

Share

IT MIGHT'VE taken a while but Sydney has just added another millionaire to its long list after a man showed up over a week after wining a division one prize in Lotto's $20 million Superdraw.
The man, who chose to remain anonymous, hails from the southern suburb of Miranda and became one of 19 division one winners last weekend with a prize of $1,052,631.
Despite the huge win, the family man didn't even realise he'd won until this morning.
"I checked my ticket online and saw how much I had won, so it's a nice surprise!" he told NSW Lotteries.

The Miranda man was one of 19 division one winners.Source:Supplied
While $1 million doesn't get you very far in Sydney these days - especially in the property market - the man admitted his win was definitely going to make living in one of the most expensive cities in the world a little easier.
"It's nice to have won some money! "It's going to make living in Sydney in little bit easier!" he told NSW Lotteries.
"It's just going to take some of the pressure off the every day living in Sydney and be able to give my son the education I want to give him," he added.
The brand-new millionaire, who also revealed he rarely plays Lotto, said he'd be spending his winnings on family and charity.
"I'll also be able to donate some money to charities who have helped me in the past," he said.

The winning ticket was bought from Miranda's Giovenco's Newsagency on Kiora Road - a statistic the shop's owner Gerard Giovenco was ecstatic about.
"We were waiting and waiting for someone to come forward and have been telling all of our customers a division one winner had been sold here. I hope the winner enjoys their prize!" Mr. Giovenco
"It's so good to hear that another one of our customers is a millionaire!" he added.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Wolfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melvyn Knipe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Giovenco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiora Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Giovenco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miranda's Giovenco's Newsagency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miranda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lotto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Lotteries</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superdraw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lotto's $20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
