<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423953499767009</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/entertainment/movies/movies-that-deserve-a-spot-in-the-rotten-tomatoes-zero-per-cent-club/news-story/a3da3d23618ae74b29c341ecaa891f88</url>
  <title>Zero Per Cent Club: Movies not one critic liked</title>
  <content>
IF YOU'RE a movie maker, the most offensive thing that can happen to your film is if it joins the Zero Per Cent Club.
Currently there are only a few hundred members in the club and entry is only gained when a movie receives not one single positive review from film critics on Rotten Tomatoes.
Basically, if a movie ends up on the list, it's best to avoid it at all costs.
Here are the movies that well and truly deserve their spot in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club:
JOE DIRT 2: BEAUTIFUL LOSER - 2015
If took David Spade 14 years to make a sequel to his 2001 film Joe Dirt, but he probably wishes he'd never bothered.
Joe Dirt 2 was written by David Spade who also starred in the film alongside Christopher Walken, Seinfeld actor Patrick Warburton and Sugar Ray singer Mark McGrath.
Here's what some critics had to say:
"You'd think that after 14 years, they'd have more than stale fart jokes and weak callbacks to bits that weren't funny in the first place." - Las Vegas Weekly
"Sometimes the cast doesn't seem so sure it's a real movie, and, especially for the first act, it feels like they shot everything in one take, and left them all in the movie. Maybe they were afraid to yell cut." - RogerEbert.com
LONDON FIELDS - 2017
How did it all go wrong for this movie? It boasts an impressive cast including Johnny Depp, Billy Bob Thornton and Cara Delevingne, but not one critic could find something nice to say about it.
In London Fields, Amber Heard plays a clairvoyant who has a premonition of her death and then starts a love affair with three different men, one of whom she knows will kill her.
Here's what some critics had to say:
"Whatever director Matthew Cullen and writer Roberta Hanley have cooked up with this screen adaptation, it's nothing if not a debauched hodgepodge for the senses that dares you to abandon it at almost every turn." - The Playlist
"Most scenes lack pace, are performed badly and are accompanied by a running commentary of action we can see for ourselves. It's car-crash filmmaking." - Independent
London Fields

PRECIOUS CARGO - 2016
Never heard of it? That's probably for the best.
Bruce Willis and former Saved by the Bell star, Mark Paul-Gosselaar, star in this dud movie about a crime boss who tries to make off with loot that belongs to another thief.
Here's what some critics had to say:
"What persuaded Bruce Willis to accept a role in this cheap-looking, poorly scripted, irredeemably derivative crime thriller is a question only he, and his agent, can answer." - Daily Mail
"The stupid plot, dismal dialogue, moral turpitude and dispiriting torpor of this movie makes watching it utterly pointless." - Toronto Sun
"You will be hard-pressed to remember anything about it even only a few minutes after watching it, which should come as a relief to everyone involved with its production." - RogerEbert.com
Precious Cargo

LIFE ON THE LINE - 2015
What do you get when you take John Travolta, Sharon Stone, Kate Bosworth and Devon Sawa and make them star in a movie about a crew of highwire workers who get hit by a deadly storm?
A piece of s**t, that's what.
Here's what some critics had to say:
"Life on the Line is supposed to be a moving story about men working electrical lines. Viewers, however, might require a high-voltage shock just to endure it." - New York Daily News
"The country songs that play over the credits offer more arresting detail about life on the line than the film manages in 100 minutes." - Village Voice
Life on the Line

THE RIDICULOUS SIX - 2014
Putting the word "ridiculous" in the movie title was actually pretty apt.
This Netflix film starred numerous Hollywood A-listers including Adam Sandler, Terry Crews, Nick Nolte and Taylor Lautner, but the Western satire just took things way too far.
Not only was the Sandler-led flick just blatantly terrible, it was also offensive to a huge number of people.
By the time the movie wrapped, only four of the original 100 Native American actors on set had stayed in the movie.
Here's what the critics had to say:
"The Ridiculous 6 is everything wrong with Hollywood for the past two decades." - The Wrap
"Peer through this dopey haze long enough, and you can't fail to notice the cavalier racial attitudes, the endlessly pliable women; you'd have every right to be outraged, were it not now par for the Sandler course." - The Guardian
The Ridiculous 6

DARK TIDE - 2012
Oscar winner Halle Berry struggled to find a decent flick to star in after winning her Academy Award win for Monster's Ball (see: Catwoman) and this shark movie was another miss.
Playing a character described as a "shark whisperer" who is haunted by the memory of a shark attack probably should've tipped the talented actress off, but hey, everybody makes mistakes.
With a budget of $US25 million, the movie struggled to crack half a million at the box office.
Here's what the critics had to say:
"The only palpable emotion from Dark Tide is sadness for Berry, treading water in dreary efforts like this." - Los Angeles Times
"It is often impossible to figure out what's going on." - New York Times
Dark Tide

BALLISTIC: ECKS VS. SEVER - 2002
Antonio Banderas and Lucy Liu weren't enough to help this movie and, with 116 reviews on Rotten Tomatoes, it is the worst reviewed film in the history of the site.
On paper Ballistic: Ecks vs. Sever sounded great - a movie about two opposing secret agents who team up to fight a common enemy - but clearly, the movie struggled to portray its exciting synopsis on screen.
By the end of its release, it had lost over $US50 million at the box office.
Here's what the critics had to say:
"Banderas mopes through this hideous and unintelligible enterprise like a bloodhound with a hangover, while Liu elects to look cool in leather in lieu of a performance." - Urban Cinefile
"For many viewers, the big question may be not whether Ecks and Sever will get together, or why they are fighting in the first place, but why am I sitting here, anyway?" - Associated Press
Ballistic: Ecks vs. Sever

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara Delevingne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Fields</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sugar Ray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Bob Thornton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandler-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Walken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catwoman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Cullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Daily News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Village Voice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RogerEbert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ecks</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark-Paul Gosselaar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seinfeld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dark Tide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bandera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Dirt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Lautner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Native American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Depp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Spade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Bosworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halle Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Cinefile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Spade 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Willis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Dirt 2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Banderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEAUTIFUL LOSER - 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberta Hanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECKS VS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Crews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy Liu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas Weekly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monster's Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Travolta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LONDON FIELDS - 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood A-lister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Sandler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Nolte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LINE - 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Warburton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CARGO - 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ridiculous 6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amber Heard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TIDE - 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devon Sawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIDICULOUS SIX - 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
