<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424090938722141</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/bum-photo-making-people-happy/3208842/</url>
  <title>The bum photo making people happy</title>
  <content>
A BLOGGER has begged her followers to see themselves as others would - rather than just focusing on 'faults'.

Louise Aubrey, who posts on Instagram under the moniker , shared two identical photos of herself wearing a bikini.

She then pointed out what others see - and what she does, reports .

A post shared by Louise| PARIS |Thinker & Maker (@mybetter_self) on

The results were thought-provoking, with Parisian student Louise's annotations highlighting just how cruel women can be to themselves.

She wrote: "I am guilty. I am here to always be completely honest, because I feel social medias (sic) need more of it.

"As much as I preach self love and truly made some progress accepting myself, there is something I really struggle with: pictures.

"Whenever I see a picture of me, the first things which catches my eyes are my FLAWS. I always see what is wrong.

"I really do not look at people's flaws first when I look at a picture of someone else. On the contrary, I tend to focus on their assets.

A post shared by Louise| PARIS |Thinker & Maker (@mybetter_self) on

"We really need to learn not to be so harsh on ourselves. It is not healthy. I am going to work on it, and I hope you will too."

Louise noted that strangers would see her "big smile, long legs and strong butt", but she saw a "big nose, back fat and cellulite".

Speaking more about the image to , she explained that there are a lot of reasons why people feel bad about themselves.

She said: "Self-criticism comes from several causes.

"The society we've evolved in overemphasises our physical appearances.

A post shared by Louise| PARIS |Thinker & Maker (@mybetter_self) on

"The influence of role models, the use of photo editing; it puts a great pressure on our shoulders and nourishes the feeling of not being worthy enough."

Louise, who blogs about fitness and healthy eating, has also demonstrated the difference between good and bad camera angles - and the difference good posture can make.

This article originally appeared on and was reproduced with permission.

Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Magistrate says break-ins frustrate community clubs
National Park mascot 'Hilaire' caught and being treated.
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Self-criticism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilaire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parisian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Aubrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
