<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424391586437969</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-04/facial-infection-putting-dog-in-and-out-of-hospital</url>
  <title>Facial infection putting Dog 'in and out of hospital'</title>
  <content>
Mitch Honeychurch has been in hospital with a facial infection

WESTERN Bulldogs midfielder Mitch Honeychurch is battling a facial infection that has seen him hospitalised several times over the past week.

The 22-year-old was a late withdrawal the day before last week's win over Essendon, and isn't registered on the club's injury list.

AFL.com.au understands the fourth-year Bulldog experienced symptoms of the infection following the round 18 trip to Cairns to play Gold Coast, and that saw him seek treatment at a hospital.

Coach Luke Beveridge said on Friday that Honeychurch may take some time to recover from the ailment.

"Mitch is still a bit crook, he hasn't returned (to the club) this week because he's really ill, so that's really unfortunate," Beveridge said.

"He's had an infection, been really crook and been in and out of hospital.

"His energy is down, he's virtually got none, and it might take him a little while to recover, unfortunately.

"He's not in at the club, (and) he hasn't been in all week."

Out of contract at season's end, the setback comes at a frustrating time for the Eastern Ranges product, as he'd played six games straight from round 13 after largely being out of favour for the past two seasons.

Recruited to Whitten Oval with pick 60 in the 2013 NAB AFL Draft, Honeyhurch has played only 22 games in that period.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Ranges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitten Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Honeychurch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honeychurch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honeyhurch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
