<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424520435458537</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/linkedin-launches-tinder-for-mentors/</url>
  <title>LinkedIn Launches 'Tinder For Mentors'</title>
  <content>
Australians will be amongst the first in the world to be be able to pass or accept - the LinkedIn version of swiping left or right - on choosing a mentor using a new LinkedIn service. According to reports, LinkedIn has selected a small group of potential mentors from whom people can choose a potential mentor.

says the new service is free and will, over time, be opened up to everyone so anyone can be come a career and life swami, assuming someone accepts or swipes right on you.

Once you choose a mentor and they accept, you can terminate the relationship at anytime - even after just one day. So it really is a lot like Tinder!

I've been fortunate in my career to chance upon some really great people who have helped me make better decisions and smooth out some of my rough edges. But those meetings were a result of good fortune rather than good planning. And people I thought would be great mentors turned out to be less helpful.

This move by LinkedIn is positive. But it's good to see there's a kill switch in there in case things don't work out.

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LinkedIn Launches</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinder For Mentors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LinkedIn</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
