<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423910550093476</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/technology/innovation/inventions/sas-soldiers-trial-star-warsstyle-bulletproof-helmets-with-heatseeking-technology/news-story/b89ac0e94ac52ef8a380331b8b7da3b5</url>
  <title>SAS soldiers trial Star Wars-style bulletproof helmets with heat-seeking technology</title>
  <content>
The Devtac Ronin Kevlar Level IIIA Tactical Ballistic Helmet is extremely futuristic and is even bulletproof. Picture: Devtac
SAS SOLDIERS are trying out "Star Wars"-style bulletproof helmets in the war against terror.
The hi-tech gear - dubbed the "Boba Fett helmet" after the hit movie's infamous bounty hunter - uses heat-seeking technology to hunt down enemies, reports .
It picks up signals from other people through "friend or foe" vision and is air conditioned to protect against heat and gases.

And its super-strong plates can deflect shots from guns, shrapnel, blasts and fire. Picture: DevtacSource:Supplied
Troops benefit from a GPS system that projects maps on to the visor.
And its super-strong plates can deflect gunshots and protects against shrapnel, blasts and fire.
The creators of the Devtac Ronin Kevlar Level IIIA Tactical Ballistic Helmet claim it's "literally bullet proof."
It is said to protect soldiers' heads from a shot from a Magnum 44 round.
The incredible piece of kit was first used by US special forces operators from the Navy SEALs and Army Delta Force.

The similarities are uncanny.Source:News Corp Australia
Now it is being tried out by SAS soldiers.

A military source told the : "For years the defence industry has been trying to find a way of protecting the head and this is the next development."
"The helmet, already being used by special forces, is much more versatile than just stopping bullets."
"It is fitted with the latest communications technology and will help the soldier see the enemy no matter what the circumstances."
.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navy SEALs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DevtacSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAS SOLDIERS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Wars-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Wars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Army Delta Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devtac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devtac Ronin Kevlar Level IIIA Tactical Ballistic Helmet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boba Fett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnum 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
