<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423996449440476</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/frankston-dolphins-to-return-to-vfl-competition-in-2018-after-afl-victoria-grants-its-licence/news-story/29d567d7360e56d45ad3dc83ba43345a</url>
  <title>Licence granted: Frankston back in VFL</title>
  <content>
FRANKSTON will return to the VFL competition in 2018 after today having their licence application approved by AFL Victoria.
The Dolphins' licence was stripped last year after the club fell into voluntary administration under a crippling debt in excess of $1 million.
Since then the club has been committed to engaging its key stakeholders and last month presented to AFL Victoria a strong application to re-enter the VFL, with a focus on community involvement and "a closer relationship with football clubs across the Peninsula".
The pitch also included its record membership base of more than 1200.
The Dolphins also appointed highly-respected former Hawthorn recruiter Gary Buckenara as its general manager to help lead its bid to return to the league.
Buckenara has been a key player in driving fundraising events with top-level past and present Australian sporting talent.
"AFL Victoria was always committed to continuing to work with key stakeholders in the region - including Frankston FC - to ensure there would be a state-league presence there into the future," AFL Victoria chief executive Steven Reaper said.
LICENCE GONE:
DEBT DEMOLITION:
"The Frankston FC and all involved have shown their commitment to regain their licence in the VFL, establishing a strong strategic plan focused on governance, community engagement, sponsorship and membership that will assist the club and the region into the future
"Frankston FC has worked closely with AFL Victoria and on local relationships that will see the club become a central part of the talent pathway in the region once again, with a strong commitment to playing a broader role in growing the game in the Frankston and Peninsula area.
"The club now has over 1,200 paid members and a timeline in place to remove its remaining debt over coming years, providing a more sustainable VFL presence moving forward - and like all VFL clubs, Frankston FC will need to continue to meet criteria for the continuation of a VFL licence into the future."
Last year the state government announced it would waive a huge chunk of the club's debt, with reports that figure was about $450,000.
Buckenara, who helped put together Hawthorn's three-peat premiership list, will now play a crucial role in building the club's playing list for next season.
Frankston will join North Melbourne's stand alone team as the two new entrants into the competition next year.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston FC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Buckenara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckenara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Reaper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Victoria</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
