<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424206902841217</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/education-highlighted-at-first-garma-festival-forum-2017/8775038</url>
  <title>Garma Festival 2017: Young Indigenous Australians concerned about education</title>
  <content>
Young Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander leaders from across the country have used the first forum at Garma to call on the Prime Minister for Indigenous-focused tertiary education and more support at school.
The education panel kicked off the festival in north-east Arnhem Land which is the premier forum for Indigenous affairs in Australia.
Gumatj man Winston Yunupingu, 20, told the panel he found it difficult transitioning from his traditional culture in Arnhem Land to a school in Melbourne.
"It's difficult for a young Yolngu man to get a good education [in Arnhem land] and getting the values that non-Indigenous kids get and how they grow up," he told the panel.
"We don't get what they were provided, we grow up in a little town so going to a big city school is hard."
Yorta Yorta man Corey Ackington, 22, from Victoria told the panel Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander culture needed to be the emphasis of education for the next generation of Indigenous children.
"The forefront of education needs to be culture ... to create a culturally safe environment for kids to study in - then there won't be a problem."

The group of young leaders from Brewarrina in NSW to Arnhem Land in the NT are meeting with the Malcolm Turnbull at the festival to take their requests to him.
Barkindji woman Bianca Williams from Brewarrina in western NSW called for an Indigenous university.
"We need an Indigenous higher education institution at university ... right now we have to adapt to white versions of tertiary education."
Indigenous children not meeting their peers

Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Social Justice Commissioner June Oscar told the Garma education forum that despite education being a human right, Indigenous children were falling behind.
"How is it acceptable that our children living in remote Australia are between three and five years behind their peers by the time they reach Years 5 and 9?" she said.
"That approximately 80 per cent of children are not going to school once they reach the age of 12?
"That achievements are amongst the worst in comparison to the national averages?"

Ms Oscar said in order to fix these problems, governments have to take responsibility over injustices which face Indigenous Australians.
"We can't continue the discourse of deficit about the gaps that exist between our peoples and the broader population with issues such as education, without a conversation about the responsibilities of government," she said.
"Ongoing deaths, injustice, intolerance and above all inaction only feed an existing discontent that rests with Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander peoples.
"Our peoples need confidence that like all other Australians that inadequacies with our laws, our police, our detention centres must be addressed."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winston Yunupingu, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander Social Justice Commissioner June Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous-focused</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolngu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bianca Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barkindji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorta Yorta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumatj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brewarrina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Ackington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
