<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423906255126170</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/perth-disability-justice-centre-to-be-reviewed-after-escapes/news-story/aa9451c651ca210e9bf6fd4c61697633</url>
  <title>Justice centre review after escapes</title>
  <content>
A DISABILITY justice centre in Perth will be reviewed following community criticism over the escape of two detainees.
The Bennett Brook Disability Justice Centre has been operating since August 2015 as an alternative to prison for people with an intellectual disability or cognitive impairment who are unfit to stand trial.
There was a public backlash after two of the three inmates in the Lockridge facility fled by scaling a perimeter fence on New Year's Eve 2015.
They were returned within days without incident, but local residents were outraged, saying the centre should be closed until a security audit was completed.
An independent review last year concluded the Disability Services Commission, which runs the centre, was doing all it reasonably could to meet its risk assessment and management obligations.
But Labor promised, while in opposition, to undertake another review into the facility and on Friday delivered on that commitment.
The review will examine the extent to which the centre is fulfilling its purpose, the appropriateness of its location and options for the future of the facility.
Disability Services Minister Stephen Dawson said experienced consultant Alan Carter would conduct the inquiry, which would also include community consultation.
"Alan Carter has significant skills in the areas required to conduct this external review having worked in the corporate sector and in the government and not-for-profit sectors," he said.
The facility can house up to 10 people, but there are currently only two inmates at the centre.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett Brook Disability Justice Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Carter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Minister Stephen Dawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Year's Eve 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disability Services Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
