<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424340046829336</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-union/australia-rugby/has-australian-rugby-fallen-so-far-that-the-wallabies-couldnt-even-win-super-rugby-20170729-gxldar.html</url>
  <title>Would the Wallabies win Super Rugby? Unlikely. </title>
  <content>
 It will come as a surprise to absolutely nobody that an Australian team will not feature in the Super Rugby final this weekend.
As a result of colossal boardroom failures, which has seen Australian rugby suffer at every level, the game has never been in worse shape in this country and may never recover.Photo: Stuart Walmsley
With a club to be axed by next season and record low crowds turning up to watch our lacklustre national side - Australian Super Rugby is well and truly on its knees
To assess just how we've fallen I pose this question - would the Wallabies win Super Rugby?
I think it's a hard no.

The Kiwis current dominance is unprecedented and the Super Rugby trophy may not even be heading to New Zealand this year with the Crusaders having to overcome the Lions in Johannesburg on Saturday.
Australia's five teams haven't fared well against foreign opposition in general this year with just five wins, but for the sake of this column we'll stick with our dismal trans-Tasman record.
The Kiwis delivered Australia the big old bagel after we earned exactly zero wins from 26 attempts against our cross ditch rivals this season.
I say rivals but it's not much a rivalry anymore, the Brumbies loss against the Wellington Hurricanes in the quarter-final two weeks ago made it a whopping 32 straight trans-Tasman losses.
The Brumbies came within a converted try three times against the Kiwis this season, but if we're honest the only real chance of victory in those was a smash-and-grab against the bottom-placed Auckland Blues.
The Wallabies picked up where our Super Rugby teams left off in the June Test series with an unconvincingly win against Fiji, before losing to Scotland and then scrapping home against Italy.
Watch any New Zealand Super Rugby derby this season and you'll see an intensity level that dwarfs anything the Wallabies have produced since the 2015 World Cup final.
Speaking of that final, I can already hear the Wallabies diehards screaming that a side which can make a world cup decider could easily take out a domestic competition.
Those same diehards will know we only got there beating Scotland (then ranked eighth) in the quarters 35-34 thanks to a gift final-minute penalty and then ousted Argentina (then ranked ninth) in the semi who were bought down by the occasion.
The Scots showed in June who deserves to place higher on the current rankings and don't be surprised if the Pumas knock us off in the Rugby Championship next month.
The Wallabies have lost three of their the past five Tests and with back-to-back Bledisloes in two weeks time, the bookies have Australia at $1.10 to extend that record to five losses from our past seven outings.

Dejected Wallabies after losing to the British and Irish Lions 41-16 in 2013. Photo: Carlos Furtado

This where the evidence gets most damning for the Wobblies - those losses came against Scotland, England and Ireland - which alongside Wales form a team known as the British and Irish Lions.
The Lions, who only picked two Scots, didn't exactly shine on their recent 10-match tour of New Zealand as the Blues, Highlanders and Hurricanes all denied the world's most famous touring side victory.
Sure, they led for three minutes in the three Tests and somehow managed to return home with a drawn the series, but they got a lot of help from a bloke by the name of Sonny Bill Williams.
Australia wouldn't have gone close to beating the Lions in June which means the same team that would have destroyed the Wallabies couldn't even beat half the Kiwis' Super teams.
I'm no mathematician but those numbers don't stake up well for our national side.
Finally - if this crazy concept ever came to be - what kind of crowds would the Wallabies draw?
The turnouts were diabolical this season and for good reason, we were hopeless across the board.
However, the Wallabies would be very competitive in Super Rugby and at the end of the day fans simply want to see their team win, history proves they're willing to pay for that privilege.
If a roving team played three games of winning rugby in Brisbane, Sydney, Canberra, Melbourne and Perth each season, I think the fans would come back in droves.
Maybe this radical idea is the only way to revitalise the game in this country and to be honest it's the only way I can see Australia featuring in a Super Rugby final in the next decade.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wobblies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Hurricanes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June Tests</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwis' Super</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highlanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Walmsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlos Furtado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOHANNESBURG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scots</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
