<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423910550093496</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834245/did-someone-say-free-pizza/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Pizza Hut to give away free margherita pizzas, Domino's returns the favourite to the menu</title>
  <content>
Pizza Hut is giving away free margherita pizzas over the weekend. Photo: Neil Newitt.

While Domino's may have sent pizza lovers into a frenzy after announcing they were ditching the beloved margherita, rivals Pizza Hut has come to the rescue.  
The fast-food chain announced on Thursday that they will be giving away 10,000 free margarita pizzas across the weekend - "because we love the most classic pizza".

So how do you get your hands on Pizza Hut's delicious giveaway? 

There's no catch, just be the one of the first 10 customers at your local store on Friday, Saturday or Sunday to place your order. 
But get in quick, because stores across the country are expecting lines out their door by the 11am opening time. 

Coincidentally, just two hours after this culinary giveaway was announced on Facebook, Domino's came back to the pizza party with their own margherita announcement. 

"Australia, we've heard you - the Margherita is staying on the menu if you want it! Order now and save the Margherita," the post said. 
This change of heart comes just days before the fast-food giant's new menu is set to launch.

"The key focus points for this new campaign will drive a quality halo for the whole brand, ensuring that as a brand Domino's stands for more than just cheap $5 pizzas," the company said in the document.

The move comes at a time when the company is also reportedly also seeking to reduce the size of its pizzas.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Newitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margherita</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pizza Hut</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
