<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423605607410969</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/broken-elbows-and-roadside-dental-work-in-russia3a-round-the-w/8771654</url>
  <title>Scottish adventurer Mark Beaumont braves broken bones  in quest to cycle around the world in 80 days</title>
  <content>
Despite broken bones and teeth, Scottish adventurer Mark Beaumont's gruelling bid to set a new record by cycling around the world in 80 days is on track
Now crossing the Nullarbor, Mr Beaumont, 34, has been riding 16 hours a day for the past 32 days and is nearing the halfway mark of his cycling odyssey.
The inhuman scale of the challenge is part of a lifelong goal to push his body to the limit while circumnavigating the globe 40 days' faster than anyone before.
The plan has been three years in the making.
To test if he could maintain the rate of about 380 kilometres a day for 80 days straight, Mr Beaumont spent 14 days riding 5,600 kilometres around the entire coastline of Britain.
If he finishes, circling back to Paris where he began, Mr Beaumont will have ridden 28,968 kilometres in 80 days.

On the Nullarbor, just west of Eucla on the South Australian border, he is now aiming for Brisbane via Adelaide and Melbourne.
"It has been a lot colder and tougher than I expected,'' Mr Beaumont said.
''I'm riding from about four in the morning to about 9.30 at night. This morning it was three degrees, so that's a cold start."
Speaking from the Eyre Highway, Mr Beaumont said the wind was the biggest factor.
''To do the same speeds, to cover that distance, you're putting a huge amount of power through the pedals and that starts to become pretty unsustainable.
"You'll absolutely fly if you get a westerly. If I get an easterly, it just blows you backwards."
Despite poor weather conditions along the south-west coast of Western Australia, he is on schedule.
"Every day I'm riding four times four-hour sets, so 16 hours a day on the bike," Mr Beaumont said.
"The conditioning to do that is quite extreme. Most elite-level riders could maybe do that one day, but I've just done it for the past 32 days. Your body takes a huge amount of abuse."

On the road with him are several support vehicles, a bike mechanic, his physiotherapist and his performance manager.
"The first thing I do every morning is jump on the scales and it's the last thing I do at night to make sure I'm not losing weight," Mr Beaumont said.
"You could so easily just waste away to nothing."
Serious crash in Russia

Team members work with nutritionists and medical professionals in the UK to monitor and maintain Mr Beaumont's health, sometimes having to improvise.
"On day-nine I had a serious crash in Russia, in the dark, in the rain and fell on my face," Mr Beaumont said.
"I broke a tooth and smashed my elbow."
He can't move his elbow properly and suspects he has fractured a bone.
"It was bloody painful, my left elbow is still not healed. I can hold the handle bars, but I can't bend it fully.
"There's probably a hairline crack in their somewhere," Mr Beaumont said.
To prevent a tooth infection, his support team had to perform a roadside dental procedure.
"The British Embassy in Moscow managed to get some fancy dental kit and get it to us on the road," he said.
"On the roadside my performance manager rebuilt my tooth."

Dream since the age of 12

Mr Beaumont has set records for cycling across the Americas and Africa and has tried his hand at ocean-rowing across the Canadian Arctic.
"I've worked towards this for the past 20 years. It's not something that I just rolled out of bed and tried to do," Mr Beaumont said.
He said this latest challenge was about testing the physical limits of his mind and body.
"This is me putting all my chips on the table and going for broke, so there's never an issue of motivation,'' he said.
"There's never a moment, regardless of the pain or regardless of the tiredness where I'd consider backing down."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beaumont, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Embassy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beaumont</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eucla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nullarbor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Beaumont</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian Arctic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eyre Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
