<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423996449440412</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/sa-lawn-bowler-nathan-pedersen-receives-australian-call-up-for-hong-kong-tournament/news-story/0872d82d9154d378815f83dafa50e98f</url>
  <title>Forget work, this young gun bowls for a living</title>
  <content>
NATHAN Pedersen will travel to tournaments in Sydney, Perth, Tweed Heads and Hong Kong in the coming months as he carves out a living playing the sport he loves.
But it is on the lawn bowls green, not the tennis court or golf fairway, where the young South Australian is leaving his mark on the national and international stage.
"It's crazy and pretty full on," Pedersen, 22, said.
"It's definitely nothing like (tennis star) Nick Kyrgios or someone playing golf, and I'm not making a killing.
"But I'm going away to tournaments and making what I would be if I was working full-time in a normal job so it's pretty good.
"Bowls has really started to blow up and change in the last three or four years, and it's definitely good to be right in the middle of it."
Pedersen represents the new breed of bowler - colourful and full of confidence.
The Modbury gun was again thrust into the spotlight last week when he was named in an Australian pairs combination for the Hong Kong International Bowls Classic.
Pedersen, who will team up with new partner Ben Twist at the uncapped November tournament, will aim to become just the third player to win the title three times.
His selection came a month on from his Australian Open singles victory which landed him a $13,000 payday and the No. 4 spot on the national men's rankings.
"It's been unreal," said Pedersen, who claimed the Hong Kong event with Corey Wedlock in 2015-16.
"Obviously all the hard work and winning a few things helps with the selection.
"I feel I'm growing and getting better every time I play."
Pedersen, who fits casual work for a transport company around his bowls commitments, took up the sport aged nine when he followed his grandparents on to the greens at Rosewater.
He is a member of the Emerging Jackeroos - the feeder squad for the senior Australian side - and spent last year playing professionally for powerhouse Sydney club Cabramatta.
"The bowling clubs over there have got a lot of money because they've got a lot of pokies," Pedersen, of McDonald Park, said.
"It was like a full-time job and I was getting pretty well looked after."
The $64,000 Everest of Bowls in Perth, the Australian Indoor Championships in Tweed Heads and the Australian Championships in Merimbula, NSW, were next up for Pedersen.
He hoped eye-catching displays would increase his chances of being a bolter for the Commonwealth Games on the Gold Coast next year.
"I just need to keep doing the right things and trying to win stuff," the former West Lakes and Ascot Park bowler said.
"But I wouldn't be shattered if I didn't make it because ... everything after the Commonwealth Games will be in my sights."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Indoor Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Twist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merimbula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Wedlock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest of Bowls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pedersen, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Kyrgios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong International Bowls Classic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ascot Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pedersen, of McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATHAN Pedersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tweed Heads</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emerging Jackeroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pedersen</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
