<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424644989512072</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/latest-news/indigenous-leaders-collaborate-for-reform/news-story/88b80675de00eac96d7183ab26145d5e</url>
  <title>Indigenous leaders collaborate for reform</title>
  <content>
The nation's top indigenous leaders have come together to collaborate on a collection of essays in favour of an indigenous voice to parliament, a treaty-making mechanism and a reconciliation commission.
High profile Aboriginal Australians including Noel Pearson, Warren Mundine, Jackie Huggins, Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu, Megan Davis and Stan Grant will launch A Rightful Place: A Roadmap to Recognition at Garma Festival in north-east Arnhem Land on Friday.
Constitutional reform will take centre stage at the four-day event, where Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull will be under pressure to commit to the proposals.
It comes after Opposition Leader Bill Shorten called for the immediate establishment of a bipartisan joint parliamentary select committee to finalise a referendum question on the Aboriginal advisory body.
In the book's foreword, Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu said the country is at an important crossroads where constitutional recognition will be "a symbolic reckoning" to restore peace and harmony for future generations.
The Gumatj clan leader advised politicians to take heed from the Yolngu principles of makarrata, or reconciliation after a struggle.
"I want to have my people's grievances settled in a calm and proper way. And then I want unity and togetherness - a shared future," he wrote.
"This must now also be the work of all Australians."
Noel Pearson said Dr Yunupingu has dealt with the the prime ministerial "merry-go-round" of power over past decades yet still has an existential fear for the future of his people, with little self determination achieved.
Mr Pearson acknowledged that a national vote on amending the nation's founding document to recognise Aboriginal Australians carries risks of provoking division.
"Any successful case must transcend the natural political and cultural polarities of Australian society, and seek and seize political bipartisanship," he wrote.
"The only path to closing socio-economic gaps is for indigenous Australians to become active agents in our own development."
Leading constitutional lawyer Megan Davis said the Referendum Council's Statement from the Heart was initially deemed excessive by some political elites because it "did not align with their vision of recognition as symbolic and minimalist" or align with biases about societal attitudes.
Stan Grant offered a preamble proposal for a Makarrata Declaration, and said the constitution must "meet the aspirations of those locked out at the nation's birth" so that they can be given "full voice to shape our destinies and complete our union with our fellow Australians".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makarrata Declaration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Mundine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolngu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie Huggins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan Grant</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumatj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rightful Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Pearson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Davis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council's Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
