<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423652852052420</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/comment/sisters-in-law/what-exactly-is-a-trust-and-do-you-have-to-be-rich-to-set-one-up-20170804-gxpacw.html</url>
  <title>What exactly is a trust and do you have to be rich to set one up?</title>
  <content>
The latest hot topic  is discretionary trusts and  to make them less beneficial.
When we think of trusts, we usually associate the concept with rich business people, property moguls and .Photo: Penny Stephens/The Age
What exactly is a trust and can anyone set them up?
A trust is a structure set up by a document called a deed, which holds any sort of asset for the benefit of an individual (beneficiary). A "trustee" has the obligation to hold the asset for the beneficiary, as opposed to the asset being in the individual's name.
The assets held by a trust vary. They generally include assets that generate an income, for example a house, money, shares, machinery or vehicles.
Many people set up a trust for tax-minimisation purposes, which is a big part of Labor's motivation to change the laws.

The Labor Party's proposal is designed to raise $17.2 billion over 10 years. The changes, whereby there will be a 30 per cent tax rate for distributions to people over 18 years, is argued to affect only 2 per cent of taxpayers.
A discretionary trust is the most common type of trust. where the trustee (the person in control) can decide how to distribute the trust income and can control the assets of the trust.
In a discretionary trust, the trustee makes a decision who to distribute the trust income to, usually based on which individual beneficiary is in the lowest tax bracket and thereby minimising the tax that is paid.
A common example of a discretionary trust's asset is an investment property and the rent paid by the tenants is the income generated. Often this rental income is distributed to the children of the family in order to minimise tax that must be paid.
Another common example is a farmer who distributes the trust's income to each family member. The Labor Party intends to make farmers exempt from their proposed changes to the law.
Trusts can have a further advantage, which is asset protection or avoiding paying debts. Assets held within the trust usually cannot be taken by a creditor.
So for example, if a boat skipper has no insurance and injures a water skier by running over them, they may be liable to pay a large sum of money as a result of their negligence. However, if the skipper has no assets in their name and the family home is an asset of the trust, then the family home cannot be touched.
Anyone who wishes to set up a trust should obtain taxation and legal advice before doing so.
Alison and Jillian Barrett are both principals at Maurice Blackburn Lawyers. The Queensland sisters are experienced lawyers and passionate social justice campaigners. Alison juggles motherhood, as well as heading up a major legal practice area. Younger sister Jillian also leads a team of lawyers and sports a double degree in Law and Journalism.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jillian Barrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Stephens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maurice Blackburn Lawyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jillian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
