<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424640694544736</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/parramatta-eels/set-of-six-why-were-witnessing-the-rise-and-rise-of-the-parramatta-eels-20170804-gxpfw2.html</url>
  <title>Set of Six: Why we're witnessing the rise and rise of the Parramatta Eels</title>
  <content>
﻿1. Mitchell Moses has gone to another level
He can't tackle. He can't grind out a game. He takes bad options. All criticisms of Mitchell Moses as he tried to find some form at the Tigers. In truth, you wonder how many of their fans were sad to see him walk out the door. Turns out the kid can play. And then some. After an understandable period of finding his feet after a mid-season switch of club, Moses has turned it on as Parramatta make a hard run at the finals. And it's not just the attack either. Moses' kicking game has improved and he's clearly thriving under Brad Arthur, who always had faith that Moses would flourish sooner rather than later. You need a gun half to win a premiership. Looks like the Eels have their man. Corey Norman ain't bad either.

Up Next

Cherry-Evans: Defence the issue for Manly

00:43

More Rugby League Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Eels notch sixth straight win

The Parramatta Eels continue their impressive form with a 20-4 win over the Canterbury Bulldogs.

2. The (no) Commitments
It's nice to have stars and all. But the cool kids are making sure they have players that are really good - but not good enough to get picked by either NSW and Queensland during the Origin blackout. While teams like the Storm (who the Eels beat ahead of game three earlier in the month) were missing as many as six regular starters, the Eels managed to escape without a single player in sky blue and maroon. It's difficult to overstate how important that could be in the wash-up for Parramatta, especially with new signings in key positions trying to learn the ropes. They've managed to bound into the final rounds of the season on a six-game streak, rather than having to reset and find momentum with players resting, missing or injured.

Making waves: Mitch Moses has had a massive impact since a mid-season switch from Wests Tigers to Parramatta. Photo: AAP

3. Good weekends at Bernie's

They say a fish rots from the head. Is that true? Aside from leaving a few whiting out in the sun for a couple of days, let's leave that to the experts. What we do know is that the Eels have been a far better football side with a decent administration and the absence of boardroom madness and salary cap scandals. It's hardly rocket surgery to know that players perform better when they aren't worrying about when the next pay might lob into their Dollarmite accounts, or whether they are likely to be shipped out to free up cap space. Gurr, a veteran administrator and former Roosters boss, was given the CEO's job in September last year. He's pulled all the right strings since and the Eels are now making headlines for all the right reasons, while just a handful of players remain unsigned for next season.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

One that got away: Souths fans will be pained to see Nathan Brown having a stellar season after leaving. Photo: AAP

4. Paint the town Brown
It pains South Sydney fans to see Nathan Brown turning into and out-and-out star since moving west to the Eels. You could easily make a case that Brown has been the buy of the year, with the blue-collar lock turning in big numbers ( 133 av run metres, 15 carries, 30 tackles) in his 18 appearances for the Eels. He's been at the heart of a no-nonsense forward pack that is doing far more than just getting the job done, as they say in the classics. Veteran prop Tim Mannah has been in decent nick, while the likes of Kenny Edwards, Manu Ma'u and Suaia Matagi have been giving their halves every chance of getting the Steeden on the front foot.
5. Arthurian legend
Not has Brad Arthur put himself in the running to coach rugby league's ever-evolving first-name last-name fantasy squad (always captained by Shane Rodney, however), he's turning out to be a pretty handy mentor back on Planet Earth. Even in the midst of the 2016 chaos and as the Eels came out the other side, Arthur showed patience, calm and persistence. Now he's free to do what he does best, he's proving exactly why he's so highly regarded in the coaching ranks. His game plans are rock solid, it's clear players respond to him and crucially, he's becoming one of those guys players want to go and work for. Whatever else transpires for them this season, it's clear they have the right man at the top.

Patience and persistence: Brad Arthur is enjoying his best season with the Eels. Photo: AAP

6. They aren't Souths. Or the Bulldogs.
We don't want to be mean. Alright, only a little bit. But the point is, while teams with better rosters on paper are struggling to get performances to match, the Eels are getting every last drop of effort and talent out of their squad, plus a bit more. While some of the Rabbitohs forwards could drop a ball surgically attached to their hands and the Dogs go through the motions (very slowly), the Eels are playing energetic, upbeat, positive rugby league without any of the reputations to weigh them down. They went play-for-play with the Broncos (a team that can make the grand final) before getting away from them, before taking care of business against the Dogs in a match they know they should have won. The good news is they have a soft draw to end the year, with Knights, Titans and Rabbits all at home, as well as an away trip to Brisbane.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moses</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dollarmite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planet Earth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Moses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Eels</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Rodney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Moses</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manu Ma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steeden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Arthur</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gurr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthurian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suaia Matagi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
