<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424898392586464</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/putting-food-in-the-pantry-for-national-homelessness-week/news-story/d6602960cbf91263db085ad15bb74fad</url>
  <title>Putting food in the pantry for National Homelessness Week</title>
  <content>
CRAFTY can-raising efforts have kicked off in Chelsea to help feed people in need.
Chelsea CareWorks has teamed up with Mordialloc MP Tim Richardson to push a food and fundraising drive ahead of this year's National Homelessness Week.
Dubbed 'CanOrCoin4HomelessnessWeek', the campaign's mission is to collect a tonne of food or a tonne of money by the end of August.
All donations will go to Chelsea CareWorks' Your Pantry service, which helps people who struggle to put enough food on the table.
"We want this to be an annual thing," Mr Richardson said.
"We want Chelsea CareWorks to own this and every year we will have 'CanOrCoin4HomelessnessWeek' and raise that support."
Chelsea CareWorks - run out of the Chelsea Church of Christ - opens the pantry on Mondays (9am-12.30pm) and Wednesdays (7.30am-1pm) so anyone can access and collect the food they need.
Community support worker Fiona Bright said non-perishable food items such as pasta, tuna, tinned vegetables and sauces are among the most popular.
And although the church accepts donations year-round, Ms Bright called on people to dig deep throughout August.
"We can wake up in the morning and all of a sudden our whole lives could be completely transformed," Ms Bright said.
"Losing jobs can be biggest thing that sets people 10 paces back.
"We need to understand that can happen to anybody and not be so quick to judge - we need to help our community."

Local schools, businesses, community groups and sporting clubs can get behind the cause and compete to become the most generous donors.
The instructions are simple - get your community group together; gather your cans and coins; organise a "weigh in" and post your results on social media with #CanOrCoin4HomelessnessWeek.

You can then arrange for donations to be picked up, or drop them off at Chelsea CareWorks or Tim Richardson's office.
Phone 9773 0301 or 9772 4544 for more details.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Bright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Church of Christ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesdays (7.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Homelessness Week</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bright</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea CareWorks' Your Pantry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea CareWorks</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday, 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mordialloc MP Tim Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CanOrCoin4HomelessnessWeek</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
