<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424941342260577</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834801/gill-back-in-play-for-blues-as-finals-loom/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Gill back in play for Blues as finals loom</title>
  <content>
City's Reed Van Huisstede playing against Terrigal last month. Picture: Marina Neil

Newcastle City forward Nick Gill returns for Saturday's Black Diamond AFL showdown against fellow heavyweights Terrigal-Avoca as the Blues chase a spot in the top two.

Gill has not played for six weeks due to injury but returns for the penultimate regular-season game.

City are four points behind second-placed Cardiff, who should be too strong for Nelson Bay at their Hillsborough fortress on Saturday but face the ladder-leading Panthers in the final round.

City coach Mitchell Knight said his side were approaching full strength as they tried to repeat their win over Terrigal a month ago at No.1 Sportsground.

- Mitchell Knight
"We had quite a few guys out at the start of the year and we've been working to get a few guys back," he said.

"We've had a pretty good run. Ideally we'd like a top-two spot.

"At the same time you've got to win finals to get in the grand final and win the flag.
"We're not overly concerned about it, but it would be nice to get the opportunity to go straight through to a grand final.
"In the past we've finished third on the ladder and had to play two consecutive games to get in the grand final. We've won the flag from third or fourth position."
City, who have won seven games in a row, also get back Courtney Knight, who was away last week when the defending premiers cruised past the Marlins.

MItchell Knight said he would not enter the game with any special plan to curb key midfielder James Webster, who returned for the Panthers last week against Warners Bay. 
"He's a very good in for them. He's one of the best onballers the competition's ever seen," Knight said.

"We won't be too concerned about him this week. We'll just go out and try to play our own brand of footy, but if they get on top, we'll look at match-ups."

City have a superior percentage to Cardiff's and likely will finish above them if they win their last two games and the Hawks don't.

Warners Bay travel to last-placed Killarney Vale hoping to keep alive their slim finals hope. They are eight points behind Nelson Bay but can catch them with wins over the Bombers and City.

Killarney Vale will host a reunion of their 1987, 1997 and 2007 premiership sides at Adelaide St on Saturday.

The Marlins have struggled to field a consistent line-up this year and had only 21 players last week at home against the Blues.

Their task won't get any easier on Saturday against the Hawks, who will be desperate not to open the door for City in the top-two race.   
"They're definitely a contender," Knight said of the Hawks. "It will be interesting to see come finals. Hopefully everyone can have full squads in. It will be interesting to see their best 22."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Gill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Webster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardiff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillsborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtney Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrigal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Bays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Killarney Vale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrigal-Avoca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City's Reed Van Huisstede</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday's Black Diamond AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Knight</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
