<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424937047293137</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/malcolm-turnbull-defends-refugee-deal-after-trump-phone-call-transcript-leak-20170804-gxpik1</url>
  <title>Malcolm Turnbull defends refugee deal after Trump phone call transcript leak</title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull has defended the legitimacy of the deal to resettle refugees in the United States despite revelations he told Donald Trump in January .
Mr Turnbull attempted to play down the controversy over a leaked transcript of the infamous phone call between Mr Turnbull and Mr Trump soon after the US President took office.
The transcript, published by The Washington Post, reveals Mr Turnbull convinced Mr Trump to , including telling him as business people it was important to honour transactions, the US had no better friend and assuring him Australia could be counted on to help in the future.
While the government has denied the deal was a "people swap", Mr Turnbull told Mr Trump Australia would "hold up our end of the bargain by taking in our country 31 [inaudible] that you need to move on from" and "we will take anyone that you want us to take" - believed to be references to an agreement to resettle refugees living in Costa Rica.

The Prime Minister said on Friday he had stood up for Australia's national interests in his "courteous" and "frank" conversation.

Questioned on why the deal should not be characterised as a people swap, Mr Turnbull said he was not going to comment on the leak of this "supposed transcript".
"Let me just say that the nature of our relationship with the United States in this area is one of mutual assistance," he said.
"So we help the Americans, they help us, it's in the context of a very big relationship of mutual support."
Mr Turnbull said resettlement of refugees has "always been subject to American vetting procedures, that's always been part of the arrangement".

While Mr Turnbull said it would always be better for conversations to remain confidential, he would continue to be forthright in future talks with Mr Trump despite the risk of further leaks.
He thanked Mr Trump for honouring the agreement and said they enjoyed a "warm relationship".
Labor, the Greens and refugee groups accused the government of misleading the public over the deal.  
Greens Senator Nick McKim said it was clear the PM had lied when he denied the deal was a people swap.

"Since the US deal was struck, not one man, woman or child has been released from detention to the US," he said.
 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa Rica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Senator Nick McKim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Trump Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
