<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424297097155925</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/auctioneer-dons-unicorns-on-his-feet-during-sale-of-highett-home/news-story/8a6ac21ecb6bda0bb2fdfff87eb10108</url>
  <title>Auctioneer dons unicorns on his feet during sale of Highett home - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, surged $53,000 beyond reserve.

HIGHETT has a new unit price record after a "recipe for success" soared $53,000 beyond reserve.
And the $1.535 million deal was done in a pair of rainbow, unicorn slippers.
Buxton Sandringham senior sales consultant Scott Hamilton said the vendors of  bought 20 pairs of the eccentric footwear for those looking through the double-storey townhouse.
"She didn't want the floors getting dirty," Mr Hamilton said.
"The auctioneer ended up wearing a pair on the auction day."
SUBURB PROFILE:

, has oak floors that run through the ground floor's spacious, shared areas.

Mr Scott said it took just two eager bidders for the home to sell for the eye-watering sum.
"We were quoting $1.35 million-$1.485 million, and the reserve was $1.482 million," he said.
He said the vendor owned an old house on the block, before deciding to develop two townhouses.
"I advised them before building, and it was important we looked at what was selling well," he said.
"They included a double-garage, as well as a full-sized bedroom, bathroom and two living areas downstairs.
"It was a recipe for success."
CoreLogic recorded a 3.4 per cent lift in Highett's median unit price, which includes townhouse sales, across the 12 months to April. The new figure is $600,000.

Buxton Sandringham's auctioneer put his best foot forward in unicorn slippers.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buxton Sandringham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
