<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424176838069624</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/social-housing-done-on-the-cheap-a-combustible-issue-20170803-gxog9w.html</url>
  <title>Social housing done on the cheap is a combustible issue</title>
  <content>
Flammable, inflammable. It's one of those weird English instances of the word and its inverse meaning the same.
Following London's Grenfell inferno, the NSW government promises to audit all buildings and require owners to replace dangerous cladding.  But the word in the Building Code of Australia is not inflammable, or fire-resistant, or flame-retardant. The word is non-combustible.
That's a serious test. Few materials qualify. Concrete, glass, steel, brick, is about it. So it's likely many more than 1000 buildings are implicated, and unlikely that self-inspection and "asking Councils to check their data sets", as Fair Trading Minister Matt Kean proposes, will cut it.
It's also ironic that this same government is so hell-bent on demolishing the Sirius, which as public housing does everything right, including being non-combustible.Photo: AP
We tend to quarantine these issues - this is fire safety, that's social housing. But, like London's other Great Fire of 1666 (which gave us the Sydney terrace house), the June 2017 inferno has changed city-building everywhere, tsunamiing liability-anxiety through the construction industry. Suddenly, building material is no mere technicality with aesthetic and cost implications. It's a significant moral choice.
Moral? Absolutely. It's not just cost versus safety. It's about whose cost (theirs), whose safety (ours) and whose responsibility (anyone, anyone?) In other words, it's about the use and abuse of power. "Social murder," as one headline had it, may be a little strong but, as in war, there's one class of people making the decisions and another class wearing them. So perhaps it is time to ask, whose city is it?

It's not just a single dodgy aluminium-and-polyethylene sandwich-material we're talking about here. Of the thousands of buildings erected across Australia since the '90s that look like they dropped straight out of some ghastly digital world without texture, hormones or weight, many, perhaps most, are clad in materials whose fire behaviour is unguaranteed and essentially unknown. Architects across the country are scuttling for their insurance cover.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

When Brisbane's gleaming, silver-skinned Princess Alexandria Hospital, designed by Cox architects, was found recently to have 24,000 square metres of combustible aluminium cladding, it was just the tip. We have townhouses skinned with plastic wood, apartments sheathed in combustible synthetic sandwich-board, shopping centres clad in foam-core steel sheet. Materials that flame, ignite and emit hydrogen cyanide. They're everywhere.
True, our code is more stringent.  In Sydney, Grenfell would likely have had sprinklers (internal) and two escape stairs, not one. But these may have made no difference. The essential problem at Grenfell, fanning a dozen small errors into a towering inferno, was a catastrophic failure of governance.
As Canberra engineer Peter Mulherin notes, "the Grenfell fire is just one manifestation of a 21st century malaise of poor governance and cost-based motives driving degraded quality in our built environment".
As in the UK, our fire regulations are vague, non-mandatory and, to an unknown extent (being certified by the developer's payees) unenforced. The BCA is complex and technical but, as in the UK, compliance is now optional. You can comply, or you can choose to be  "fire-engineered" to performance standards.
This, notes Professor Mark Stephens from Edinburgh's Herriot Watt University, presumes that in-lab mimicry of fire's complex and notoriously unpredictable behaviour is accurate. Is it? We only know when it's too late. Caveat emptor.
Other problems abound. The genuinely non-combustible is often visually identical to the poisonously flammable. Private certifiers are easily pressured to pass materials as being safer than they are. Developers sit on regulatory and community boards. And in what Mulherin calls a "porous" regulatory environment, global manufacturers, standing outside verification or responsibility, easily bamboozle specifiers with faux-technical assurances.
Yet we use these buildings all the time. We live, work, study, play and recuperate in them. We trust them, because we have to. Social housing makes this trust issue even more poignant.
Housing is a noun, but also a verb - and when it's a verb much depends on whether it's active or passive. We in Australia are extraordinarily passive about housing as mass-produced by those who honestly care nothing for our welfare. Social housing in particular, though, is almost always done to people, not by them.
Grenfell, owned by the local borough (Kensington and Chelsea) was reclad on the cheap to please the local eye. It seems that a faulty fridge caught fire, or possibly exploded, around midnight on June 14th, and although the fire brigade arrived en masse inside six minutes several factors - including combustible cladding, poisonous insulation and a "containment" policy that kept people in their flats instead of evacuating - conspired to kill dozens.
Critical in the catastrophe was the neo-Liberal context which, emplacing developers on core decision-making bodies including the Tenant Management Organisation, reduces everything to dollar value. Similar thinking underlies then-minister Mark Speakman's refusal to list the Sirius on grounds of "financial hardship" to the owner, Property NSW. This argument, rejected by the court, presumes that social housing should be cheap housing. If the land poor people occupy becomes fashionable, you chuck 'em out, smash the community, send them to woop-woop for a third the cost.
The obvious flaw in this argument, as noted in Sydney recently by Chilean Pritzker prize-winning architect Alejandro Aravena, is that this puts poor people out past the services, transport and opportunities that are their only hope of betterment, and so perpetuates poverty down the generations.
Aravena's answer is brilliantly simple. His firm, Elemental, has pioneered "incremental" housing, which builds half the house - the hard half, including plumbing, structure and stair - leaving the rest for completion by its occupants. This saves enough to locate such housing where it belongs, on expensive, highly serviced inner-city land.
So, yes, audit building materials and fire safety, by all means. But we must also, all of us, get pro-active in creating habitat that works for us - socially, economically, physically. If that means self-build or co-housing or some reinvention of these, great! Enjoy! Meanwhile reinstate mandatory fire rules and government inspections, and recognise Sirius for what it is, a world-leading social-housing flagship.
Twitter @emfarrelly
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aravena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grenfell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirius</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Alexandria Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tenant Management Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chilean Pritzker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Mark Stephens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alejandro Aravena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Trading Minister Matt Kean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Speakman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulherin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edinburgh's Herriot Watt University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Mulherin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Code of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London's Grenfell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
