<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424468895850360</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/sa-man-jailed-over-illtreating-dog/news-story/8d70f8b3ea629e491e93f90d307008a2</url>
  <title>SA man jailed for ill-treating dog</title>
  <content>
A South Australian man has been jailed for a month after whipping a neighbour's dog and feeding her sausages filled with lead filings and glass.
Peter Kelliher appeared in Mt Barker Magistrates Court on Friday where he was given a three-month sentence, with one month to be served immediately and two months suspended, the RSPCA says.
Kelliher had pleaded guilty to two counts of ill-treating an animal and causing serious harm and 12 attempted ill-treatment charges for hitting the dog and for leaving sausages filled with lead filings and glass in his neighbour's yard for their dog Mia to eat.
As well as the immediate jail term, the court also imposed a three-year good behaviour bond, banned Kelliher from having custody of any animals for 12 months and ordered him to pay more than $12,000 in compensation and vet bills to Mia's owners.
The golden retriever survived the attack but has ongoing health problems.
At a previous hearing her owner, Heidi Fabian, told the court the incident made her physically ill and she could not fully grasp the viciousness and malice of Kelliher's actions.
"You are so fundamentally evil," she told him in a victim impact statement tendered to the court.
After Friday's hearing, RSPCA chief inspector Andrea Lewis said Kelliher's actions involved a "deliberate and deceptive act of cruelty" that had shocked the community.
"An immediate prison sentence sends a strong message that animal cruelty is a very serious matter that will not be tolerated," Ms Lewis said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidi Fabian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Barker Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelliher</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Kelliher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
