<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424898392586517</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/lifestyle/food-and-wine/natural-wine-the-wine-winemakers-are-whining-about-20170801-gxn8gz</url>
  <title>Natural wine: The wine winemakers are whining about</title>
  <content>
Skin contact, clay amphoras, biodynamic vineyards and filtration - most wine drinkers are unlikely to care much about trends and tricks in the winery. 
Yet when it comes to the debate around whether 'natural wines' have peaked, there is some consensus: it's been one of the most influential trends in the wine sector in decades, and it's impacting wines across the industry. 
So-called 'natural wines' - sometimes called orange or lo-fi wines - are, at the most basic, wines with minimal intervention from the winemaker. This can mean using clay amphoras, similar to those used to make wine for thousands of years, to whole-bunch ferments, , through to no filtration or additives, and pretty much anything else.
Purists prefer the grapes to be grown organically or bio-dynamically, but that's not always the case.  

Natural wines are increasingly found peppering top-end restaurant wine lists, though are not yet stocked as a category by Woolworths' liquor chain Dan Murphy's.

Dan Murphy's wine panel head Peter Nixon says the trend is making a lot of noise, and they are watching it closely. He compares it to the influence of hippie or even punk rock music on the broader music landscape in that it has pushed winemakers to reconsider how they approach their craft. 
But he says, so far, it's really only the chain's stores in Victoria's Collingwood or Sydney's Alexandria that have much demand for that style of wine.
Within the tight-knit industry, there's furious debate about whether the natural wine movement - championed by wine events including Rootstock - is hijacking attention from traditional wine and has gone too far. 
Bindi winemaker Michael Dhillon created a mini-stir in the industry with a , which brought out defenders and champions of the industry debate.

Canberra-based Bryan Martin, a winemaker at Clonakilla, says he likes the idea you can do anything you want. 
"It's just wine," he says. "It is something people get hot and bothered about, but it's nothing new we are doing."
Melbourne-based sommelier Banjo Plane-Harris, who also has a distribution company specialising in wines made with minimal interference, agrees it's a significant trend, but disputes it's taking over wine lists and edging out more traditional, science-based winemaking. 
"Look at the lo-fi movement in Europe - they are far more passionate and hard-core. There's not very many true natural wine bars in Australia," he says.

"And for those that say [natural] wine lists are at the exclusion of other good wines, any wine list is at the exclusion of other wines. It's a personal expression of the sommelier and the restaurant. It's like saying when you go to a Chinese restaurant they didn't have spag bol on the menu. Of course they didn't!"
Wine critic Max Allen, a columnist for this newspaper, is a . But he agrees that, like the rest of the industry, the popularity of the trend means there's plenty of poor wines that are worming their way onto wine lists and into retailers under the banner of natural wine.
"Effectively natural wine kicked off as a reaction against the perceived industrialisation of wine. It's a revolution or reaction against one kind of orthodoxy, now replaced with another orthodoxy," he says. "There are too-cool-for-school venues out there that have imposed a strict policy on what they'll accept ... what difference is that from the mid-90s not stocking your wine if less than 96 points from Parker or Halliday."
But Allen stresses the significance of the trend can't be ignored, and it has filtered down in various guises to make all winemakers think about their own process of making wine.

"The natural wine thing has been fantastic for Australian wine, it's given us a whole heap of new options to drink, it's expanded the boundaries of what's acceptable, it's taunted and provoked the rest of the wine making community to challenge and question themselves about how they make wine," he says, though he notes the focus on what happens in the winery sometimes takes the focus away from vineyard practices. 
Martin agrees. He notes that under Australian regulations, 130 things (including tannins, colours, yeast, milk, eggs) can be added to wines without having to be disclosed and the trend has put the focus back on minimal intervention wine making. 
"I'm treading on the edges a bit, I want to be creative and expressive, and don't want really faulty wines. One of the problems is a lot of people that make wine this way, is they are experimenting and a lot of wines have faults coming through," he says. "I've seen so many dreadful wines anyway made by big companies.. As long as the wine is beautiful, you can use whatever term you want...I don't think it's a fad, it's an ideal, as much as being organic is."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra-based Bryan Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bindi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Alexandria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rootstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clonakilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banjo Plane-Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Dhillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halliday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Nixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
