<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424133888395917</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/re-signed-coach-tells-falcons-players-to-grab-titl/3208848/</url>
  <title>Re-signed coach tells Falcons players to grab title chance</title>
  <content>
RUGBY LEAGUE: Re-signed Sunshine Coast coach Craig Ingebrigtsen is urging his charges to grasp a genuine chance to win the state league premiership.
His team is second in the 14-team Intrust Super Cup through 21 of 25 of rounds and it boasts a near-full strength squad, bolstered by fringe players from NRL powerhouse Melbourne.
There's stability at the club and a loyal supporter base which hopes the Falcons can snare a second title, and its first in eight years.
The coach, who has extended his contract until the end of 2018, certainly believes that's possible.
"I think there's an opportunity to win one and I think it's sitting right in front of us, we've just got to be good enough to take it," he said.
The Sunshine Coast is competition favourite with bookmakers, ahead of a clash with the Cutters at Mackay on Saturday night (6pm).
And Ingebrigtsen wants to win a premiership for the club's fans.
"I see the supporters who come to games...I want to be successful for them because they've been through a lot," he said.
The Sunshine Coast wallowed without a link to an NRL team from 2011-2014. Then there was the tragic death of forward James Ackerman in 2015.
But a club revamp, the connection to the Storm, the arrival of Ingebrigtsen and some astute player signings prompted optimism and then last year, the Falcons surged from 12th place to third.
The side is poised for even greater things this time around.
"The club's been through so much on and off the field - they've struggled financially, they've struggled with the death of a player and with not winning games - and the pinnacle would be for this club to win a premiership and in my reign that would be great," the coach said.
"But the best thing for the club is we're developing a great culture where people are actually ringing us (wanting to play there). There were days players would come to the Falcons because they weren't wanted by other clubs but we're now getting phone calls daily with people wanting to play for us and that's a good sign.
"Last year we had a great year and against all the odds we got one game short of the grand final and this year we've got a really good roster, a great coaching staff, a good CEO, a good chairman and a great board and everyone's on the same page."
The Falcons will be without back Alex Copelin for the clash against the Cutters though (fractured nose) but Jahrome Hughes or Ryley Jacks is expected to lace-up, with Ingebrigtsen telling the Daily on Thursday that the former was more more likely.
This year's Cutters squad boasts Tom Murphy, a Sunshine Coaster who was captain of the Falcons last year.
He left to play in France and when he returned his old club lost the tug-of-war for his services.
PROFESSIONAL surfer Julian Wilson says he is enjoying married life
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Magistrate says break-ins frustrate community clubs
Artists preparing for the annual Ink Attack Tattoo Convention
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
Stand-alone freehold property in Maroochydore 'eat street' precinct
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Ingebrigtsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Copelin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingebrigtsen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ink Attack Tattoo Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryley Jacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jahrome Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Re-signed Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUGBY LEAGUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
