<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423609902378468</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/work-begins-to-fix-deadly-wantirna-pedestrian-crossing/news-story/a878fccd5aaee882ad4cb919c1c13cd7</url>
  <title>Work finally starts to fix deadly crossing</title>
  <content>
WORKS to upgrade a deadly Wantirna crossing have started and will be finished by the end of the year, the State Government says.
The zebra crossing at the Mountain Highway and Boronia Road intersection will have pedestrian-controlled traffic lights added under a $280,000 safety improvement.

The Boronia Rd slip lane will also be realigned to slow down vehicles and give drivers better visibility of pedestrians.
Construction of the project began yesterday. It followed the deaths of two people at the site in the past eight years.
Knox Leader has campaigned to make the crossing safer since the death of Ringwood grandmother Kathy Curlis on July 18 last year.
Truck driver David Stubbs, of Ferntree Gully, was recently sentenced to three-and-a-half years in jail for dangerous driving causing the death of Mrs Curlis.
Stubbs was driving his truck when he rear-ended the car in front of him, which propelled into her.
The drivers of both vehicles came to the aid of the 60-year-old but she did not survive the night in hospital.
Authorities were warned as far back as 2009 about safety concerns at the site after an 83-year-old man was struck and killed.
Brendan Edwards, who works near the intersection, welcomed the upgrades but said it "should have been done a long time ago".
"I've lost count of the amount of times I've almost been killed by cars and trucks," he said.
"All the time you see near misses and hear the screech of tyres."
Mr Edwards and colleagues wrote to VicRoads in 2009 urging them to redesign the crossing but their request was rejected at the time.
Roads Minister Luke Donnellan said the crossing was "dangerous and has a history of accidents, which is why we've stepped in to make these important upgrades".
He said motorists should take extra care travelling through the intersection, with reduced speed limits and road workers on site.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Curlis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boronia Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roads Minister Luke Donnellan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wantirna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountain Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knox Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stubbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy Curlis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boronia Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Stubbs, of Ferntree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
