<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424941342260492</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/national/fifo-worker-uses-drone-to-get-pic-of-mowbray-river-crocodiles/news-story/494392a55579d596c95fc130ad2ecb5a</url>
  <title>Majestic snap of FNQ nature</title>
  <content>
WHEN Andrew Silligan went through the photos he took of a pair of crocs sunning themselves on the banks of the Mowbray River, he noticed something unusual.
The Fly In-Fly Out worker used a drone to capture a magic photo of the reptiles but could not work out whether the croc in the foreground was missing its front left foot, or it was buried in the mud.
Mr Silligan was head to Port Douglas for lunch with a mate when he spotted the animals yesterday morning.
"We drove past and my mate said that's not a croc it's a log, it's always there, but I disagreed and after we stopped the other one came out of the water behind him," he said.

"I travel a lot for work in the Gulf country so I see them a lot.
"I used a drone to get down there and usually they don't hang around much when you start flying overhead but this one just raised its head a bit and then laid back down.
"If it is hanging out by the highway it's probably clear nothing bothers it much."
Mr Silligan had heard from some nearby fishermen the crocodile had been sunning itself in the same spot for the past two days.
"His front left leg looks like it's a stump, but I'm not sure. I can't tell if it's just buried in the mud," he said.
"If something tore that off, it means there's a lot bigger one in there. I wouldn't be standing on the bank fishing."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fly In-Fly Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mowbray River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Silligan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FNQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Silligan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
