<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424511845523800</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834722/centrelink-accused-of-intimidating-clients-with-afp-letters/?cs=7</url>
  <title>Centrelink accused of intimidating clients with AFP letters</title>
  <content>
Centrelink is under fire for letters using the AFP's logo and language critics say is intended to intimidate clients into updating their personal details.

The agency has sent out the letters within months of prolonged controversy over the wording of notices it sent to welfare recipients about possible "robo-debts", and after Department of Human Services officials were forced to defend them.
Letters sent to welfare recipients in late July have an AFP logo beneath Centrelink's and tell them to keep their personal details up to date, before listing a series of penalties if they commit welfare fraud, including a prison sentence and a criminal record.
"The majority of our customers do the right thing and tell us about any changes to their information. We also know that sometimes people make honest mistakes, however customers who deliberately withhold or provide false or misleading information could be committing fraud," it said.
The DHS tells clients it has established a taskforce with the AFP to detect people committing welfare fraud.
"We are sending this letter to remind you of your ongoing responsibility to keep your information up to date," it says.
The DHS has been contacted for comment.
Social services body ACTCOSS director Susan Helyar said the letter was deliberately intimidating and would confuse people into thinking it was from the AFP.
She said the letter made assumptions about recipients.
Opposition Human Services spokeswoman Linda Burney said the government's approach to ensuring the income security of vulnerable people was to delay, defer and deny.
"Whether it's the robo-debt debacle, or inserting the AFP's logo onto Centrelink letterheads, this government is only interest in victimising and harassing vulnerable Australians," she said.
The DHS started Taskforce Integrity targeting welfare fraud in 2015 and has targeted Ipswich, Adelaide and Tasmania.
Department secretary Kathryn Campbell defended the DHS' use of letters to contact welfare recipients about "robo-debts" at a Senate estimates hearing in May, denying that clients initially received debt letters.
"They're initial clarification letters where the recipient or former recipient has been able to provide clarification which means there is no need to continue with the process," she said.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Human</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathryn Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Helyar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taskforce Integrity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Burney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACTCOSS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DHS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
