<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424941342260548</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/celebrating-dustin-fletcher-another-lap-of-honour-for-essendon-games-recordholder-20170804-gxpo2q.html</url>
  <title>Celebrating Dustin Fletcher: Another lap of honour for Essendon games record-holder</title>
  <content>
An icon of the Essendon Football Club and one of only three players to reach the 400-game AFL milestone, Dustin Fletcher will be celebrated by the Bomber faithful before Saturday's game against old foes Carlton at the MCG.
It's fitting that the festivities  to honour Fletcher are happening this weekend as the super-veteran enjoyed some of his more memorable moments against the  Blues.
Fletcher,  a scrawny 17-year-old schoolboy, made his AFL debut  in round two, 1993, when the Dons played in a famous draw against Carlton. With the scores tied,  Blues captain Stephen Kernahan had a chance to grab victory with a kick after the siren but his shot slammed into the behind post for no score.  The same season  Fletcher played in the first of his two premierships when the Bombers enjoyed victory against the Blues on grand final day.
There were other notable moments against the Blues, of course, one when Fletcher laid a pivotal tackle late in another draw  six years ago. Jeff Garlett was breaking towards goal  in the round-four game before Fletcher, in a typical desperate defensive move, got a hand on the Blues forward and brought him to ground.
Fletcher played his 400th and final AFL game in round nine two years ago and wasn't able to get back on the park to add to his tally that year. Even though Fletcher was part of the grand final motorcade of retiring players that year, Essendon have decided that their games record-holder deserves a farewell of his own in a  home game.
That didn't happen last year because Fletcher was serving a season-long ban for his role in the club's 2012 drugs saga, even as a retired AFL player.
Naturally, Fletcher is looking forward to the lap of honour.
"I don't think you realise, until you finish, how much it means to the fans. I'm looking forward to Saturday," he told SEN.
"I've been lucky enough to do one [farewell lap on] grand final day, but there were a few things happening there [the drugs ban] and I wasn't allowed around [again]."  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Garlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Fletcher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Kernahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
