<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424644989512113</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/photos-of-starbucks-reserve-bar-what-its-like-2017-7</url>
  <title>Starbucks is opening premium stores in the US where you can buy coffee flights and cold-brew floats  --  take a look inside</title>
  <content>
On a recent coffee run in the Bay Area, I learned not all Starbucks stores are created equal.

Most stores make you want to duck in and duck out, with their fluorescent lighting, lack of comfort seating, and swarms of cranky, under-caffeinated customers. A Reserve bar is different.

Last year, the big-box coffee chain , Reserve, with 1,000 new coffee bar locations across the US in 2017. The bars turn the ritual of grabbing a cup of coffee into an experience. Baristas prepare small-batch coffee using a variety of uncommon methods, like siphon brewing. They also sell coffee flights and cold-brew floats.

I visited a Starbucks Reserve bar in Redwood City, California, an outpost of Silicon Valley. Here's what it was like - and what it cost me.

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Source:

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

We chatted while she worked behind the counter -- something I wouldn't normally do.

The barista relocated from a Starbucks store in nearby Woodside, California, to the Reserve bar about three months ago. It's a highly coveted place to work for Starbucks employees.

'I wanted to work here since it opened,' the barista told me.

The company invests a significant number of hours in training baristas at Reserve locations. They learn to use the more uncommon brewing equipment and participate in regular tastings to experience the new Reserve coffees, which rotate through the menu every three months.

'I feel like a real barista,' she said. 'It's like working at a winery. It's so legitimate.'

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

There's still a Starbucks sign above the entrance. For some, it will signal that the Reserve bar is just another place to get work done. Starbucks will have to continue investing in the customer experience and diversifying its menu offerings in order to create something new.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melia Robinson/Business Insider</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starbucks</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserves</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starbucks Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay Area</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REDWOOD CITY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
