<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424941342260533</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/my-good-side-roxy-jacenko-shares-awkward-topless-photo-with-a-bag-over-her-head/news-story/4e316c4e8190223e20748820cc0473bb</url>
  <title>Roxy Jacenko shares awkward topless photo</title>
  <content>
ROXY Jacenko has gone topless on Instagram - but it's not the racy kind of selfie you'd expect.
While the Sydney PR queen is usually all business, she's taken a moment to have a little Friday fun and shared a scantily clad photo of herself to her Instagram story.
In the snap, Jacenko wears only tiny grey sweatpants, a beige-coloured bra - and some kind of bag on her head.
On closer inspection, it appears to be a cloth sack with the words "Jimmy Choo" printed on it.
Her hands flail in the air as her right boob bulges out and she presumedly gasps for air.
"Thanks @hollyasser for always getting my good side," the mum-of-two captioned the photo of the intimate moment, tagging one of her Sweaty Betty employees Holly Asser.
The lighthearted moment comes just one day after about her marriage to Oliver Curtis - which when he was sentenced for insider trading.
"I'd spoken to a lawyer about divorce, and he knew that, I'd told him" Jacenko told news.com.au.
"I told him I wasn't sure what was going to happen in the future ... it was without question the worst 12 months of my life."
Mr Curtis, 31, was released from jail on a good behaviour bond after he was convicted of conspiracy to commit insider trading 12 months ago.
But following Curtis' release, the pair have since tried to get their relationship back on track. In June, Curtis surprised his wife with an elaborate second proposal at a Four Seasons hotel room in Sydney.
"I never thought I'd walk in to a room and there would be someone with a ring and balloons and marry me again," she said.
"When he came home, the children were happy and everything was easier. I had someone to help me. Life became much easier."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Curtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Choo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Curtis, 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Asser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Seasons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacenko</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy Jacenko</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweaty Betty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
