<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424769543565640</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/jailed-union-boss-to-testify-over-jackson/news-story/a53a3683f8408de32a6916a5d5ba2a32</url>
  <title>Jackson case to hear from jailed HSU boss</title>
  <content>
Jailed former union boss Michael Williamson has been named as a witness in the theft and fraud case against Kathy Jackson who previously blew the whistle on his misconduct at the Health Services Union.
Williamson is among several former and current HSU high-ranking officials expected to give evidence at a committal hearing in the Melbourne Magistrates' Court in November to determine whether Jackson should stand trial.
National secretary Chris Brown, NSW union boss Gerard Hayes, and senior officers Peter Mylan, Rob Hull, Barry Gibson, Craig McGregor, and Neil Bowker will also give evidence, the court was told on Friday.
Jackson, who was not required to appear in court, faces 164 theft and fraud charges.
The charges relate to 70 allegations of misrepresenting $500,000 worth of personal expenses as union costs.
Among the charges is an accusation she stole $50,000.
Williamson was sentenced in 2014 to at least five years in jail for "leeching" nearly $1 million from the union and then recruiting others to hinder a police investigation.
He will give evidence from a NSW jail via video link, but it's expected many of his former colleagues will fly to Melbourne for a week-long hearing beginning on November 20.
Jackson is accused of using union credit cards to pay for international flights and luxury hotels, including stays in Hong Kong, Las Vegas and New York.
She is also accused of improperly spending at a treadmill outlet, a high-end auction house and a furniture store.
The defence plan to question Mr Mylan, Mr Hayes and Williamson about union documents linked to the charges.
"They were all involved with the management of the boxes of documents," lawyer Philip Beazley said.
"All these minutes are missing with the exception of one or two boxes."
Mr Beazley has previously told the court the missing documents show Jackson's union spending was legitimate.
On Friday the Sydney based lawyer said the HSU's national secretary, Chris Brown, is a "key figure" in the management of the union's documents.
Jackson, who lives in NSW, has had her bail extended until her committal hearing begins.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Beazley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Hull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hsu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mylan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beazley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Mylan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Williamson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williamson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Bowker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
