<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651423828945714024</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/sweet-honey-and-that-book-20170804-gxp8py.html</url>
  <title>Sweet Honey and that book</title>
  <content>
When my Outlook diary unexpectedly depopulated in January, I was determined to turn a challenge - unemployment at the age of 61 - into an opportunity.
First, and most important, there was that book I put aside when I joined the ranks of ministerial advisers in 2013. Next came the important projects around the house that I'd been putting off. And I would finally be able to improve my fitness and wellbeing through a rigorous program of exercise.Photo: Supplied
What retired friends impressed upon me was the need to maintain a proper weekly schedule of activities. The key thing, as I understood it, was to be organised, and to eliminate all forms of disturbance and distraction from my affairs.
So then I went out and bought a puppy.
They say that women forget the stress of caring for a newborn in time to go through giving birth all over again, and that without this instinctive memory lapse the human race would extinguish. Now I'm thinking something similar applies to dog rearing.
Our previous two dogs were Labradors: smart, docile, permanently hungry. I trained them to a reasonably high level, and I guess that by the time they reached the end of their long and happy lives the generalised disruption of the puppy stage had receded into prehistory. So why not go again, especially when I am working from home and need a loyal, quiet companion?

Labradors are ideal for young families. But this time we had to think about a dog that, with any luck, we'd be wrangling into our mid-70s. At that stage, I don't want to be lifting a 35-kilogram Lab in and out of the basket of my mobility scooter. And, as a side issue, after 30 years, we were sick of living with a permanent coating of golden Labrador fur on everything we owned. So what kind of dog now?
A mere 100 hours of internet research and $3500 later, I drove home from Bathurst early last month with Honey, an eight-week-old, second-generation Cavoodle. That means her mother was a Cavoodle (a cross between a poodle and a King Charles Cavalier Spaniel) and her "father" was a poodle. (The inverted commas are because I am her father now. If the poodle has an issue with that, he knows where to find me.)
Like all second-gen Cavoodles, Honey doesn't shed a hair. She weighed 3.2 kilograms when I took her for her 16-week shots on Thursday and, I guess, she will eventually get to about twice that.
I'm sure she'll be a fantastic dog in six or eight months, once she is properly trained, and there is a lot of upside to her even now as a puppy. For example, she is the single cutest creature that has ever set paw on the face of the planet.
Unfortunately, my book, my house and garden projects and my fitness program have all had to be shelved over the past eight weeks. The same goes for paying bills and basic personal hygiene. If I'm not following Honey around, waiting to "correct" her if she tries to relieve herself, then I am cleaning up what I failed to correct. Or I am putting away her toys, or taking her to puppy class or to the vet for needles. Or I am building her social media profile.
Or, more pleasantly, but still wasting precious time, I am lying late in bed because Honey is snuggled up against me and I don't want to disturb her. You see, there are both pros and cons to a non-shedding dog.
When we got our first Lab, we were childless, and Annabelle filled that gap. We called each other "Mummy" and "Daddy" when she was around and my wife rubbed expensive hand lotion into her paw pads. Then we had a human daughter, and virtually overnight the dog turned into a dog.
Now, we're at the other end of it all and the whole madness resumes. There are no children except for Honey. Unfortunately, in the odd way things work, there is now someone who gets bumped for her, in just the way that happened to Annabelle 25 years ago.
And that would be our nine-year-old cat, Isis. She's named after the Dylan song, not the terrorist organisation, though to be honest she resembles the terrorist organisation more than she resembles the Dylan song.
Annabelle took her downgrade with enormous good nature. Isis, not so much. To Honey, friendship with Isis is the holy grail. Just to be allowed to sit beside her in front of the heater would be enough - and she has the scratches to show for it.
Very likely, in a few months, things will settle and our house will cease to resemble some circus act where, in a reversal of stereotypes, a cat chases a yelping dog around all day. At that stage I'll get back to the book.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annabelle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweet Honey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Charles Cavalier Spaniel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cavoodle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labrador</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annabelle 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
