<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424425946176768</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/japans-shinzo-abe-reshuffles-cabinet-to-reboot-popularity-and-economy-20170804-gxpe4w.html</url>
  <title>Japan's Shinzo Abe reshuffles Cabinet to reboot popularity and economy</title>
  <content>
Tokyo: Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe has appointed a new Cabinet hoping to breathe new life into his conservative government, whose support among voters has plunged after a series of scandals and missteps.
Mr Abe turned to a group of moderates and experienced policymakers in the reshuffle, which had been planned for some time but was made more urgent by the resignation last week of the defence minister, who was accused of misleading Parliament.Photo: AP
Mr Abe's Cabinet choices, as well as comments by the Prime Minister and senior aides, suggested a change in policy focus toward bread-and-butter issues like the economy and away from more politically contentious ones, particularly Mr Abe's drive to amend the pacifist constitution.
"I want to unite and move forward by returning to the early spirit we had when we took back the government in 2012," Mr Abe said.

After winning office in December 2012, Mr Abe initially went to work on the economy, seeking to lift Japan's sluggish growth rate with a stimulus program known as Abenomics. The approach won him high approval ratings.
But more than 4 1/2 years later, only about one third of voters say they support his administration, according to opinion surveys by the Japanese media.

For the post of defence minister, Mr Abe chose Itsunori Onodera, a long-time lawmaker who held the same job in the first Abe Cabinet in 2012.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr Onodera succeeds Tomomi Inada, who resigned under pressure last week over allegations that she had withheld information from Parliament about dangers faced by Japanese soldiers on a United Nations peacekeeping mission in South Sudan. The episode added to the problems faced by Mr Abe, who was dealing with accusations of  and conservative sympathisers, which he has denied.Photo: AP
The post of foreign minister went to Taro Kono, one of the most liberal voices in the governing Liberal Democratic Party. Mr Kono is known for his vocal opposition to nuclear power after the meltdowns at the Fukushima Daiichi plant in 2011, a position that has put him at odds with his pro-nuclear party.
Mr Kono's father is Yohei Kono, a former foreign minister who, as chief Cabinet secretary in 1993, issued a landmark apology to women from Korea and elsewhere who were coerced into working in Japanese military brothels during World War II. The Kono Statement has long been resented by the nationalist right wing of the Liberal Democratic Party.
Tobias Harris, a Japan analyst at Teneo Intelligence, a political risk consultancy based in New York, said on Twitter that the line-up of new ministers "looks like a policy wonk Cabinet".
Mr Kono succeeds Fumio Kishida, a moderate rival to Mr Abe who is considered a potential successor as prime minister, and who did not receive a spot in the new Cabinet.
Mr Abe's second term as the party's president expires next year. The party changed its term-limit rules this year to allow a third term, but without a sharp turnaround in his public support Mr Abe is unlikely to persuade party members to let him stay on.
"It's clear that after all the gaffes and scandals his goal is to avoid mistakes," said Renho Murata, the departing leader of the opposition Democratic Party, which has so far failed to capitalise on Mr Abe's declining poll numbers. "It's a Cabinet that leaves no impression whatsoever," said Ms Murata, who announced her resignation last week.
Mr Abe selected another rival, Seiko Noda, to be his new minister of internal affairs and communications. Noda challenged Abe for the party leadership when his first term ended in 2015. She is one of only two women appointed to the 20-member Cabinet, along with the justice minister, Yoko Kamikawa, a ratio that could open Mr Abe to criticism that he is retreating from a pledge to promote more female leaders.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abe</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abenomics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Murata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renho Murata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yoko Kamikawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abe's Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yohei Kono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teneo Intelligence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abe's Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Onodera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kono</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobias Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Democratic Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sudan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taro Kono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Itsunori Onodera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democratic Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Shinzo Abe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fumio Kishida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomomi Inada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seiko Noda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kono Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fukushima Daiichi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
