<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424945637227919</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/16/40/future-of-tent-city-in-deadlock</url>
  <title>Future of Sydney's 'Tent City' deadlocked as lord mayor and state government shift blame</title>
  <content>
The future of the 'Tent City' in Sydney's Martin Place is at an impasse with the state government and the City of Sydney council unable to come to agreement on a way forward. 
A meeting was held with Family and Community Services Minister Pru Goward, Lord Mayor Clover Moore and NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller to try and figure out a way to remove the makeshift camp set up in the heart of Sydney's business district.
The hour-long meeting ended with both Ms Goward and the Ms Moore blaming one another. 
"The situation is they don't want to do it, they want me to do it," Lord Mayor Clover Moore said. 
"I think it's very sad that the Lord Mayor of our biggest and greatest city should want to play a political game with this," Minister Goward said. 
The sticking point is where the responsibility lies with moving the people on. 
The lord mayor can use Section 125 of the Local Government Act, which allows council officers to remove the tents, stoves and gas bottles but not the people themselves. 

Related Articles

The minister can use the Crown Lands Act which would allow them to go to court and serve the people warrants directing them to leave.
NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller said it's important these people are treated sensitively but admitted action will eventually need to be taken. 
"Camping on the streets of Sydney can't be a long term solution," Commissioner Fuller said. 

Representatives from Family and Community Services set up desks in Martin Place for the 43rd time in recent months.
Offers of temporary emergency accommodation are being made to the homeless with 62 people having taken up that offer.
'Tent City' has become a dicey political issue, with political figures from all three levels of government weighing in. 
"It's very concerning when some people who have set up the 'tent city' are refusing to accept that assistance," NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian said. 
"My message to Gladys Berejiklian and Minister Pru Goward is it is not good enough to start blaming the homeless people of Sydney for the problems that have been created here," Labor senator Sam Dastayari said. 
Lord Mayor Clover Moore has said she will consider taking action if a list of demands around homelessness and affordable housing are met.
Minister Goward responded in writing and agreed with some but not others.
NSW Police are hoping for a resolution over the weekend.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastayari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Section 125 of the Local</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Lands Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Goward</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tent City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
