<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424876917749693</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/lend-lease-accidentally-releases-its-results-its-shares-rise-2017-8</url>
  <title>Lend Lease accidentally releases its results, its shares rise</title>
  <content>
Property group Lend Lease accidentally publicly released part of its annual financial results before they were ready.

The misstep sent its shares 1% higher to close at $16.66.

The accidentally released numbers show full year EBITDA (earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortisation) at $1.2 billion, up from $1.05 billion in 2016.

Profit after tax was also higher at $758.6 million, up from $698.2 million in 2016.

"While preparing for our Annual Report online release scheduled for 28 August, a testing environment appears to have been inadvertently made accessible to the public through an automated search engine," the company said.

"Unfortunately six pages of the draft Annual Report as a result appear to have been accessed by members of the public. The breach has now  been rectified and all further testing has ceased."

Lend Lease says the numbers are still in draft and not approved by the board of directors.

"However, we expect that the FY17 results to be released to the market on 28 August 2017 will be in line with what is disclosed," the company says.

Here are the key numbers from the accidental release:

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBITDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annual Reports</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lend Lease</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
