<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424511845523812</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/transcript-shock-turnbull-conspired-with-trump-on-refugee-con/news-story/8f2165a80f4a26a10b44fbd60bee90fd</url>
  <title>TRANSCRIPT SHOCK: TURNBULL CONSPIRED WITH TRUMP ON REFUGEE CON</title>
  <content>
The leaked transcript of their talk shows Malcolm Turnbull conspired with Donald Trump to cook up a fraud of a people swap. 
It show him agreeing to take in many fake refugees from Costa Rica in exchange for Trump just pretending he might take our boat people on Nauru and Manus Island.
Here is the  of their first talk after Trump became president. It shows Trump is rightly furious with the deal that predecessor Barack Obama made to take up to 1250 of our boat people on Manus Island and Nauru:
TRUMP: I am taking 2,000 people from Australia who are in prison and the day before I signed an Executive Order saying that we are not taking anybody in. We are not taking anybody in, those days are over... I look like a dope. The only way that I can do this is to say that my predecessor made a deal and I have no option then to honour the deal... Yes, I will be seen as a weak and ineffective leader in my first week by these people. This is a killer.
Then Turnbull makes a suggestion. Trump can just pretend to honour the deal, while actually taking nobody from Manus Island and Nauru:
TURNBULL: Every individual is subject to your vetting. You can decide to take them or to not take them after vetting. You can decide to take 1,000 or 100. It is entirely up to you. The obligation is to only go through the process. So that is the first thing.... It does not oblige you to take one person that you do not want. As I have said, your homeland officials have visited and they have already interviewed these people. You can decide.
Eventually the penny drops with Trump:
TRUMP: I am still going to vet them very closely. Suppose I vet them closely and I do not take any?
And this is the con that Turnbull agrees to, desperate to save his big people-swap "fix" - foolishly signed in a hurry with Obama just before Trump took over:
TRUMP: Suppose I vet them closely and I do not take any?
TURNBULL: That is the point I have been trying to make.
TRUMP: How does that help you?
TURNBULL: Well, we assume that we will act in good faith.
Then Turnbull makes clear that in exchange for Trump just honoring the deal without necessarily taking in anyone, Australia will take in as many refugees as Trump wants from Costa Rica - "refugees" who wanted to the go to the US:
TURNBULL: . I say this to you sincerely that it is in the mutual interest of the United States to say, "yes, we can conform with that deal - we are not obliged to take anybody we do not want, we will go through extreme vetting" and that way you are seen to show the respect that a trusted ally wants and deserves. We will then hold up our end of the bargain by taking in our country 31 [inaudible] that you need to move on from.
That "31" is obviously a transcription error.
Turnbull later continues:
TURNBULL: Basically, we are taking people from the previous administration that they were very keen on getting out of the [sic - transcription error?] United States. We will take more. We will take anyone that you want us to take. The only people that we do not take are people who come by boat. So we would rather take a not very attractive guy that helps you out than to take a Noble [sic] Peace Prize winner that comes by boat.
So Turnbull would rather take a "not very attractive guy" from the Costa Rican refugee camps - and "anyone that you want us to take" - if Trump just agrees to a deal that obliges him to take not one or our boat people (says Trump) or just 100 (says Turnbull).
I can see why this sham helps Turnbull.
But how does it help Australians?
Why is our government agreeing to take in "anyone" from Costa Rica, including "not very attractive" guys?
PS
Here is someone else exposed by this transcript.
Remember Foreign Minister  here? No deal for us to take in refugees from Costa Rica if the US took our boat people from Manus Island and Nauru?
Asked if she would call the arrangement a people-swap deal, Ms Bishop, who is in the US to meet with Vice President Mike Pence and Secretary of State Rex Tillerson, said: "That's not the way I would characterise it."
And days later, :
Foreign Minister Julie Bishop has slapped down the immigration minister for linking the US asylum seeker deal to the acceptance of Central American refugees...
'We have a humanitarian and refugee program, it's quite separate from the agreement we have reached with the United States and our officials are currently working with the United States in progressing that agreement,' she said.
She lied. The transcript proves it.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suppose I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa Rica</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Minister Julie Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRANSCRIPT SHOCK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peace Prize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Order</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TURNBULL CONSPIRED WITH TRUMP ON REFUGEE CON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa Rican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
