<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425117435922952</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/neafl-kade-klemke-hopes-to-attract-riverina-talent-to-canberra-demons-20170804-gxpawa.html</url>
  <title>Klemke looking to inspire Riverina talent</title>
  <content>
​Canberra Demons captain-coach Kade Klemke says taking a game against the Greater Western Sydney reserves to Wagga Wagga will encourage more Riverina talent to try their hand in the capital.
The Demons squad has been bolstered by six Riverina products for their clash with the Giants at Robertson Oval on Saturday.Photo: Canberra Demons Media
Leeton's Lucas Meline and Mitch Hardie, Ariah Park's Mitch Maguire, Temora's Jack Turner, Coolamon's Nick Plemming, and Henty native Klemke will all line-up for the Demons.
The Demons are backed by Eastlake but began playing under the "Canberra" banner to entice players seeking a future at the highest level.

Klemke said it was important the club was seen as a viable option for players across Canberra and regional New South Wales to launch an AFL career.
"The thing with the Demons is of course we want to be a representative side for the Canberra region but we also feel that southern NSW and the Riverina is our region as well," Klemke said.

"We want kids down that way to know that they don't have to go down to Melbourne.
"They can come to Canberra if they want to play state league footy and we're starting to see that now with those six boys playing and hopefully we'll have more in the future coming up the road."
Klemke took the chance to give something back to the region by meeting with local coaches, while players arrived on Friday to run clinics.
The former Queanbeyan Tiger said he hoped the crowds would flock to Robertson Oval to cheer on some of their finest exports in new colours.
"I do think we'll have a lot of support down in Wagga with the boys we've got playing," Klemke said.
"They have a lot of family and mates that will hopefully be coming along.
"There are a couple of Giants boys from down that way as well so it's a wonderful way to engage the Riverina community.
"NEAFL footy is improving each year so it's a great opportunity for boys to have a look at the standard and think about coming up to Canberra."
NEAFL ROUND 19
Saturday: Canberra Demons vs. GWS Giants Reserves at Robertson Oval, 12pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kade Klemke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ariah Park's Mitch Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolamon's Nick Plemming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastlake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Hardie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temora's Jack Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robertson Oval</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL ROUND 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants Reserves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leeton's Lucas Meline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverina</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Klemke</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Tiger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Demons Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga Wagga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
