<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425284939650452</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/pakistan-reshuffle-aimed-at-2018-poll/news-story/629a3e7a480f2ed65f0ad40a79fe073f</url>
  <title>Pakistan reshuffle aimed at 2018 poll</title>
  <content>
Pakistan's new Prime Minister Shahid Khaqan Abbasi has formed a cabinet filled with allies of toppled leader Nawaz Sharif, in a reshuffle that appears aimed at bolstering support before general elections due in mid-2018.
Ishaq Dar, a powerful finance minister, returns in the same role despite a criminal investigation ordered against him by the Supreme Court.
Another staunch Sharif ally, Khawaja Asif, will be foreign minister after having simultaneously run the ministries of defence and power.
The cabinet has almost doubled in size to 47 members, sworn in during a televised ceremony on Friday after a reading from the Koran holy book in the mainly Muslim nation of 190 million people.
"It's a massive cabinet," Pakistani writer and analyst Zahid Hussain said.
"It shows that it's all about the next election."
But no decision appears to have yet been made by the ruling Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz party (PML-N) over whether Abbasi will stay as premier or step down after a brief period to make way for Sharif's brother Shahbaz, as outlined previously.
Nawaz Sharif resigned last week after the Supreme Court disqualified him for not declaring a source of income he denies receiving.
However, he retains control of PML-N and put forward Abbasi as temporary prime minister until Shahbaz becomes eligible to take over by winning a by-election.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Shahid Khaqan Abbasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shahbaz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharif</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PML-N</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nawaz Sharif</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ishaq Dar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbasi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zahid Hussain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khawaja Asif</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
