<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424992881869224</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/breaking-news/rapper-accused-thought-man-hit-on-him/news-story/6918b0e9d69f646dffb54045bea45d43</url>
  <title>Rapper accused 'thought man hit on him'</title>
  <content>
A founding member of Grandmaster Flash and the Furious Five stabbed a homeless man to death because he thought the man was hitting on him and he feared he would be robbed, a New York prosecutor says.
Rapper Kidd Creole, whose real name is Nathaniel Glover, was returned to jail without bail by Judge Phyllis Chu on Thursday after an initial appearance in a Manhattan court on a second-degree murder charge.
Assistant District Attorney Mark Dahl said Glover, 57, a lyricist with the pioneering group, gave a detailed account of the encounter.
Defence lawyer Patrick Watts told the judge the evidence was "circumstantial".
Dahl said Glover was heading to his job at a building where he did security and maintenance when he encountered John Jolly, who asked him: "What's up?"
Dahl said Glover told him after his arrest he thought Jolly was hitting on him and thought he was gay "and that infuriated him".
The prosecutor said Glover kept walking but became convinced Jolly was going to rob him when the 55-year-old approached him in a "threatening voice and manner", saying: "All I said to you was 'What's up!'"
Dahl said Glover reached into his sleeve and pulled out a steak knife, leaving Jolly with two stab wounds to the chest.
Jolly picked up a beer after the stabbing and took a swig, the prosecutor said, then he collapsed and was taken to the hospital.
Glover "turned around and went to work" immediately after the stabbing, he said.
Dahl said Glover washed blood off his hands and the knife before deciding to go home.
He said Glover told him he tossed the knife into a sewer grate in the Bronx.
Grandmaster Flash and the Furious Five is best known for their 1982 song The Message.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furious Five</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant District Attorney Mark Dahl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jollys</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glover</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grandmaster Flash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Jolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Phyllis Chu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathaniel Glover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dahl</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Watts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidd Creole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
