<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425156090629317</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4833308/jets-feel-chinese-foreign-investment-crackdown/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Jets feel Chinese foreign investment crackdown</title>
  <content>
SAVIOUR: Martin Lee in Newcastle in June 2016 after announcing he had bought the Newcastle Jets. Picture: Marina Neil

If Martin Lee wanted to buy the Newcastle Jets now - instead of 12 months ago - would he be allowed?
The Ledman Group chairman forked out an estimated $5.5 million in June last year for the club and its A-League licence, which expires in 2034.
"We see a bright future for football across Asia, and the Hyundai A-League is at the forefront as one of the top professional leagues in the region," Lee said at the time.
"The investment aligns with Ledman's activities in several sectors of the sports industry, and I'm excited by the potential of the club."
Lee's entry into the A-League dovetailed with the Chinese government's push, under football-fan president Xi Jinping, for China to become a world power in the sport.
The wealthier Chinese Super League clubs were forking out stratospheric transfer fees for Europe-based stars and Chinese businesses were investing mightily in clubs like Manchester City (China Media Capital and CITIC Capital), Inter Milan (Suning), AC Milan (Yonghong Li) and Atletico Madrid (Wanda Group).
Lee's investment was small beer by comparison, but he was believed to be the first Chinese businessman to own a foreign club outright.   
FFA boss David Gallop, after what the governing body said was exhaustive due diligence, described the Ledman buyout as a "watershed moment for Australian football".
The FFA had just spent a year propping up the club after revoking Nathan Tinkler's licence, which came five years after it removed Con Constantine as owner.
"It's a marker of Australia's growing engagement with Asia and points towards our future integration with the fastest-growing football region in the world," Gallop said the day Lee took over.
"We now have a direct investment from China into the A-League."
But, 12 months later, the political and economic landscape in China has shifted.
- Lawrie McKinna
The government started cracking down on foreign investments at the end of last year as Chinese companies and individuals chased opportunities abroad in the face of a weakening economy.
The measures include more red tape for Chinese seeking to convert yuan into foreign currency and extra vetting of foreign investments worth $5 million or more.
Outbound Chinese investment subsequently plunged 48 per cent in the first six months of 2017 after jumping 44 per cent in 2016.
Peter Cai, a China expert from the Lowy Institute, said the main target of the policy was businesses borrowing heavily to make "irrational" investments overseas.
"The rule of thumb nowadays is that if your business is manufacturing cars, you can't go by a sports club. Your future investment has to be your core area of competency," he told the Newcastle Herald.
"If you can prove to the regulator that this is part of your core business, how it can increase your productivity, that's fine, but if you invest outside your area of core activities, you need to demonstrate to them why this makes sense, why it's not like a stupid bet."
The government has also expressed concern about wealthy Chinese parking assets offshore, and central bank governor Zhou Xiaochuan singled out sports and media investments for such criticism at the National People's Congress in March.

People's Bank of China governor Zhou Xiaochuan at a media conference at the National People's Congress in March.
Pan Gongsheng, the head of the State Administration of Foreign Exchange and a deputy governor of the central bank, told an economic forum in March that some Chinese football club buyouts were designed to circumvent restrictions on shifting capital out of the country.
"A number of Chinese companies have acquired football clubs or shares in clubs overseas in the past year. It would be a good deed if the deals help to improve the quality of football in China, but is that really the main reason?" Pan told the China Development Forum, Shanghai Securities News reported.
As recently as July 18, state official Yan Pengcheng, spokesman for the National Development and Reform Commission, said: "Regulative authorities will continue to pay close attention to foreign investment in industries such as property, hotels, entertainment, cinemas and sports clubs."
Business publisher Forbes reported recently that "there is little chance that the restrictions will loosen up in the near future" and Chinese authorities "won't hesitate to implement additional capital-control measures".
The end of the government's love affair with foreign football investment extends to the player market. Levies introduced this year have effectively doubled the cost of foreign transfer fees for CSL clubs, and the number of overseas players allowed in match-day squads has been cut from four to three.
So what does all this mean for the Jets?
Chief executive Lawrie McKinna told the Herald that the new rules on currency conversion had made life more "difficult" for Jets staff.
"It has affected cash flow a wee bit. We have to plan. You're exactly right. You can't just drop money in now like it was in the beginning," he said. "It's a lot harder. We have to plan and actually do it all properly so that basically we can pay the bills.
"Now, obviously, because it's season-ticket time, that looks after us for a wee while."

Lee with FFA chief executive David Gallop in June 2016.
McKinna said the cash-flow complications would not hinder the club's ability to sign players or run the business.
"No, not at all. We have the budget approved. That budget's budgeted for during the year. It might be every three or four months we can get money dropped in. It doesn't affect us at all.
"It's just planning when we need to get the money in. We have to forecast it because, you're exactly right, it's harder. You can't just straight up transfer half a million dollars. You just can't do that anymore. It takes a while to get it through the system."    

The last thing fans, players, staff and the FFA want is more complications at the Jets, who had been the league's problem child before Lee took over.
Cai said it was difficult to predict how Chinese policy would influence investments like Lee's. 
"We have a lot of things going on in China, economic reform, regulatory change, the upcoming 19th party congress, so there's a bit of uncertainty within the system," he said. 

None of this suggests Lee's ability or desire to run the Jets is compromised at all, but the shifting policy direction in his homeland is a reminder that business in China is far from straightforward and that circumstances beyond his control can have a bearing on the club.
That was a risk the FFA took when it agreed to sell Lee the licence.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhou Xiaochuan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Development</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawrie McKinna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Jets</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Super League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Gallop</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Administration of Foreign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Con Constantine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yan Pengcheng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pan Gongsheng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reform Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yonghong Li</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Cai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITIC Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Tinkler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledman Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanda Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inter Milan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai A-League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Securities News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National People's Congress</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Media Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowy Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AC Milan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Lee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Development Forum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xi Jinping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atletico Madrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
