<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424949932195257</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828322/on-for-young-and-old/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>On for young and old</title>
  <content>
Rewarding: Dr Barry Springthorpe said his career had included "worrying times, but it's mostly been very happy times". Picture: Marina Neil

Paediatrician Dr Barry Springthorpe never had a "burning desire" to study medicine while at school.
But after a rewarding career that has taken him across the world and made him a trusted carer for up to three generations of some families, he can see no reason to retire - even as he marks his 80th birthday, on Friday. "It's been a major part of my life and I feel I've still got something to contribute," said Dr Springthorpe, a father to five and grandfather to 10. "I just enjoy relating to kids - perhaps I've never grown up?

"I know a lot of fellows who retire when they don't want to and it's like having a limb chopped off. They lose their social group and their connection to the world. I hope I'm still practising when I'm 90."
Dr Springthorpe's waiting room in Newcastle East is lovingly wallpapered with colouring-in creations from his patients, a testament to the number of lives he has touched. "I would have seen many many thousands of patients," he said. "I do have some coming in with their grandchildren. For people to have a long term regard for you and seek you out for their families is gratifying and reassuring."
Dr Springthorpe had considered architecture while in his final years at Fort Street High School in Sydney, before settling on medicine. "I was influenced by the GP we had and thought 'That would be a good thing to do'," he said. "Once I had decided, it was nose to the grindstone."
The day he started at the University of Sydney he was in a group of 600 students, but this had halved to 300 by the start of second year.
He moved to Royal Newcastle Hospital for his internship in 1961 and spent two and a half years working between 80 and 120 hours each week, before moving to the Royal Alexandra Hospital for Children for 18 months and to Crown Street Women's Hospital for six months. "Immunisation was in its infancy," he said. "Children were dying of diphtheria, tetanus, polio and whooping cough."
Dr Springthorpe then moved to England, where he completed a Diploma of Child Health at Great Ormond Street Hospital and worked for six months as a general practitioner in Yorkshire.  He spent another year working in Ontario before relocating to Taree.
Dr Springthorpe was a father to three by the time he decided to specialise and return to The University of Sydney to study paediatrics for four years.

He then established the Child Development Unit in the former Union Steam Ship Company building on Watt Street, where for five years he worked with children with disabilities or who had been abused. "I was involved in the prevention of and dealing with child abuse and managed to save a few kids by picking up and averting problems," he said. "I also had appointments to various hospitals - to the Calvary Mater, Western Suburbs Hospital [at Waratah], Christo Road Private Hospital and John Hunter."
Dr Springthorpe opened his private practice just a few metres away in 1981. "Once upon a time the cutoff was 12, then it moved to 19, which still applies in terms of hospitalisation," he said. "I see everything, from newborn feeding problems, to rare disorders, to problems at school and adolescent angst - your frontal lobes that control reason and decision making don't fully develop until your 20s, when you start to think 'Wow, Mum and Dad have learned a lot in the past few years'."

He has also continued to see some patients into adulthood, including a woman in her 20s who visits every fortnight to have an infusion of imported medicines and one man in his 40s. "Continuity of care is terribly important, whether it's someone looking after your car or the butcher - and pretty hard to come by in this day and age."

Dr Springthorpe retired from being on call at 70 and now works three mornings each week, which gives him time with his family, to ride his bike, play lawn bowls and paint.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Springthorpe</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christo Road Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watt Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Alexandra Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Child Development Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Barry Springthorpe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diploma of Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Union Steam Ship Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calvary Mater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorkshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Street Women's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Newcastle Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Suburbs Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Ormond Street Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ontario</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fort Street High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
