<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425074486249297</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/music/neil-finn-gives-fans-a-frontrow-seat-to-the-recording-of-new-album-with-live-concert-stream/news-story/203a91da9989860a7d7bad844d4e3913</url>
  <title>Neil Finn gives fans a front-row seat to the recording of new album with live concert stream</title>
  <content>
'Leaps and Bounds'
2:37

Paul Kelly and Neil Finn perform "Leaps and Bounds" ahead of their upcoming Australian tour.

November 8th 2012
5 years ago

Neil Finn is live-streaming songs from his new album. Picture: Shane Reid

Kathy McCabeNews Corp Australia Network

Share

NEIL Finn fans will get to witness the magic of music-making, and maybe a few hilarious mistakes, when he begins an ambitious month-long series of concerts to record his new solo album.
In what it is believed to be a world first, Finn will livestream a concert from his Roundhead Studios every Friday in August where he will road test new songs and play a few old favourites for his legion of fans worldwide.
His new album Out of Silence will then be recorded live in front of his fans on August 25 and then released on September 1.
WATCH BELOW:

Neil Finn will record his new album live via webcast on August 25. Picture: SuppliedSource:Supplied
The Crowded House frontman was an early adopter of the live possibilities of the internet having performed for fans online since 2001.
Backstage before his concert at the Domain during the Sydney Olympics he imagined the possibilities the internet offered performers even as other bands were suing their fans for illegal file-sharing.
"I'm looking forward to the day when you can wake up and write a song in the morning, record it in the afternoon and have it out there that night,'' he said in 2000.
Crowded House drew thousands of viewers when the band delivered a behind-the-scenes webcast at the rehearsals in his Auckland studio ahead of their sold out concerts last November.

Crowded House attracted tens of thousands of people to watch their rehearsals on Facebook Live last year. Picture: Dylan RobinsonSource:News Corp Australia
"During these Friday sessions you will be witness to a series of musical happenings featuring friends, family, fellow songwriters and singers playing tunes both old and brand new," Finn said. "You can follow the progress of new song arrangements as we build towards the last stream on August 25.

"This final performance will be the actual recording of my new solo album."

Finn has enlisted many of his favourite musicians and singers to help with the project and has been rehearsing the A-list choir at his studios ahead of the first "concert" which will stream on his Facebook page from 5pm AEST.
His singing group includes legendary Kiwi songwriter Don McGlashan; EJ Barnes (Jimmy's daughter) and his nephew Harper Finn, son of Tim.

EJ Barnes will be singing with Finn. Picture: News Corp Australia.Source:News Limited

Don McGlashan is a member of Finn's new band. Picture: SuppliedSource:Supplied
Finn said the success of the Crowded House rehearsal concert last November made him enthusiastic about doing more live shows from the studio for his fans.
"You go straight to the internet and you can communicate with the audience directly. I try and keep them pretty loose and kind of like you're in a lounge room which suits my kind of performing. So webcasting just seems like a natural place to be," he told The Spinoff.
While the first three initial concerts to workshop the new songs will run for about 90 minutes, Finn believes it will take three hours to record the new album on August 25.
It will then be mixed and mastered and released a week later.
But it won't all be about the music. Finn has also invited people to send questions and he will Skype with some of those fans during the show.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppliedSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skype</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Finn</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crowded House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EJ Barnes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don McGlashan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper Finn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGlashan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finns</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan RobinsonSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November @ 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy McCabeNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roundhead Studios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
