<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424988586901769</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/steven-may-says-the-gold-coast-suns-are-already-planning-for-finals-in-2018/news-story/317971280ccdc548836d44f33d524b73</url>
  <title>Suns start chase for 2018 finals</title>
  <content>
SKIPPER Steven May says the Suns' campaign for the 2018 finals has started.
May said now there was no chance of making their inaugural finals series this year the focus at the club had shifted to September next season.
"This is the start of next year, it is all about trying to make next year's finals,'' he said.
"So there is a lot on the line for us, we may be out of the running this year but there is a lot to play for as individuals and as a team.
TEAM NEWS:
INJURY LADDER:
"There are players playing for contracts, young kids getting opportunities to stake their claim for next year and as a group it is important we finish the year strong to act as a launching pad for next year.''
May returns to the side after two weeks out with a hamstring injury to take on Fremantle at Subiaco Oval.
He said there was no risk in playing following the 5hr.45min flight across the country and revealed he was close to taking on Richmond last week.
He said there was no way he would have sat out this game once he was passed fit.
"I was almost ready to go last week but just failed to tick off some high speed drills so they didn't want to take the risk,'' he said.
"But I've done all that now and I can't wait to play, it's only been two weeks but it feels like I have been out for a lot longer.''
May said the rowdy Fremantle home crowd was no longer intimidating for the Suns after they won there last year.
He said while it may be a cliche in footy, the Suns had learned that silencing the crowd with early scoreboard pressure was the key on road trips.
"When you have 35,000 people all going for the home team and screaming for every free kick or cheering everything your opponent is doing it can be tough,'' he said.
"It is also hard to speak and communicate with each other on the field.
"We found if you can get a two or three goal lead the crowd goes pretty quiet.
"Last year the silence was deafening, we remember that and it is what we have to try to do again.
"I enjoy that, being the underdog in front of a big home crowd and trying to cause an upset.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
