<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425160385596699</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/malcolm-turnbull-in-the-middle-of-a-factional-mess-over-climate-samesex-marriage-20170802-gxo850</url>
  <title>If Turnbull allowed a free vote his leadership would explode</title>
  <content>
With nary a scintilla of irony, Tony Abbott, in one interview this week, advocated breaking one election promise while defending the sanctity of another.
Scrap the Renewable Energy Target but keep the faith on a same-sex marriage plebiscite.
In his weekly chat with 2GB's Ben Fordham, Abbott, who sees a rerun of his cheap power prices campaign as his best shot at getting even with Malcolm Turnbull, is ramping up his opposition to any energy policy that has, in part, emissions reduction as an aim.
Be it the Renewable Energy Target (RET) or the proposed Clean Energy Target (CET), he disparages it all as "green theology". Price and reliability, says Abbott, should be the sole drivers of where the government goes from here, not the Paris climate targets (to which he agreed as prime minster) nor any other green hocus pocus.

AP

To underscore his intention to lead the internal push against a CET, the avowed member for Warringah has been travelling far and wide of late, visiting an alumina refinery in Gladstone, Queensland last week, and the , all to empathise with the operators about hideously high priced and volatile power, which occurred under the policies he implemented as prime minister.

As well as opposing a CET, which looms as the best opportunity in a decade to secure bipartisan support and end the investment drought in energy, Abbott wants the RET scrapped. His immediate option is to build a coal-fired power station, something the government itself is not ruling out, but not as the sole solution.
To scrap the RET would be a breach of faith with the electorate. The government went to the last election with a policy designed under Abbott that 23 per cent of electricity generated by 2020 be done so from renewable sources.
To kneecap the policy now would not only constitute a broken promise, but, as Mathias Cormann has stated, would have consequences for jobs and investment. People have made commercial decisions based on that target. Sovereign risk would be a factor.
Not to worry. Abbott tore down Turnbull in 2009 over energy policy and while there remains a slight chance at best that he will ever be leader again, he could well wreak havoc by generating a fair groundswell of resistance towards a CET among fellow conservatives.

Treasurer Scott Morrison is among those pushing back at what everyone knows - and fears - is coming.
In a speech in Adelaide last week, he took a swing at Abbott by noting a so-called clean coal power station would take seven years to build, cost $2 billion, and that no-one in the industry wanted to build one anyway. It is not a solution on its own.
With Labor prepared to dump its policy for a more robust emissions intensity scheme and agree to a CET to give industry the investment certainty it craves and bring the price and supply stability the chief scientist says it will, Morrison agreed this week that both major parties needed to compromise.
"Australians want their political parties to meet in the middle and deliver certainty on energy policy, because only through certainty will there be downward pressure on energy prices.

"This requires sacrifice, from both sides, putting aside ideological positions to strike a deal that delivers genuine results for Australians struggling to pay their power bill."
This week, so he can threaten them with regulation if they do not give their customers better information on how to switch plans and providers to lower their bills.
The government does not need Abbott or a focus group to tell them energy prices are the number one cost of living concern in the community. But nor can it simply abandon its Paris commitment to reduce emissions by 2030, scrap the RET and only build coal-fired belchers.
So no matter what it does, it will never be good enough for those whose prime motivation is mischief.

Demonstrating just how bleak the next few months will be, this fight awaits Turnbull as he must also settle what has become a fiasco over same-sex marriage.
He agrees with Abbott the government took a plebiscite as policy to the last election and there cannot be a free vote without some form of public consultation first.
The significance of this week is that it was the moderates who were stirring the pot. They have sat back for ages as the conservatives defied authority and destabilised as they spoke out and threatened to cross the floor on myriad issues, be it energy, section 18C of the Racial Discrimination Act or a
So now it's the moderates' turn.

They argued strongly this week the obligation to a plebiscite was discharged when the Senate blocked the legislation and it was time to get the issue of the agenda.
Perfect in theory, politically impossible in reality. As much as he personally loathes the idea of a plebiscite, if Turnbull allowed a free vote next week, his leadership and the Coalition would explode. At a minium, the Nationals would defect and the Liberal Party base would have kittens.
So, unable to control the extremes of either faction, at which there could be a secret ballot to define where everyone stands on same-sex marriage.
If people are to be believed, there will be strong support to try again with the plebiscite legislation.
Given the Senate will reject that, plan B will be to have a postal vote. A postal vote is not compulsory and not properly representative. Primarily, the energised on either side will get out and vote. A major national poll would be cheaper and vastly more accurate.
Consequently, both sides have already said they will ignore its findings, essentially making it a $30 million box ticking exercise in that the government will be able to argue it has discharged its responsibility towards giving the people their say.
Then, presumably, there will be a free vote in Parliament.
If this is how this issue unfolds over the next six months or so, it is likely to do so in parallel with an internal blue over the CET. Given the utter disregard for discipline and authority from both sides of the factional fence, this government is on course to become a quivering blob by Christmas.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Fordham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warringah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RET</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clean Energy Target</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C of the Racial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renewable Energy Target</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discrimination Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CET</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
