<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424984291934412</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/callan-ward-and-dylan-shiel-hope-gws-giants-launch-afl-premiership-charge-20170802-gxo9gc.html</url>
  <title>Giants hope to launch premiership charge in Canberra</title>
  <content>
They entered the year as flag favourites and there's been plenty made of a supposed decline, but none of that talk has breached the Greater Western Sydney Giants' four walls.
The Giants have been the walking wounded at this year and plenty of pundits have written them out of premiership contention as they move closer to crunch time.Photo: Dion Georgopoulos
But after a mid-season slump the Giants are now looking to relaunch their AFL premiership charge against the Melbourne Demons at Manuka Oval on Saturday.
On the same day it was announced was called into the squad to replace injured forward Jon Patton.

They've also been  leading into the finals.
Giants co-captain Callan Ward says Patton "probably could play" but it isn't worth the risk despite the club's recent resilience against the backdrop of an injury crisis.

Ward has backed Himmelberg to play a crucial role when he comes into the side for his 11th game at AFL level.
"He's a hometown hero here. He loves playing here, just like the whole team does, but Harry definitely loves it here for sure," Ward said.
"Great re-signing for us as a club. He's obviously a guy that loves playing footy, loves training and loves the boys, extremely popular amongst the group. When you talk about Canberra, he just loves playing here.
"I think we'll be fine [without Patton]. Harry will come in and play his role for the team, just like Jon's been doing for the last month or so. It's very important for a team to have good depth and I think we've got that here."
Ward believes the Giants' best football isn't too far away despite an "inconsistent" couple of months that has seen them win two of their past seven games - with two draws in the mix.
Giants midfielder Dylan Shiel isn't even sure how the public see their flag chances but he believes sitting third after what they've been through is a pretty good indication of what the club is capable of.
Himmelberg had a stint in Canberra before being drafted and he shapes to be the latest example of players stepping up in the absence of a big name, with family making the mad dash from the United States to watch on.
"I'm not sure how the general public are looking at it but I think it's a good sign that we've had a really rough year with a lot of injuries, and injuries to key players at the footy club, and we're able to maintain our position on the ladder," Shiel said. 
"It magnifies the importance of the program the club has got in place at the moment. When someone gets injured and has to be removed from the team, the person that replaces him can perform that role for the team and we're still able to get the results that we want.
"There's no denying the club has had a rough patch of football and winning definitely makes things go away.
"Obviously the last six weeks have been hard but over the course of the season we've had to play a lot of guys who haven't played a lot of games in their career, but they've been able to come in and perform well enough for the team to get the win."
Shiel expects a  will come into the clash looking to "prove a point" following a heartbreaking loss to lowly North Melbourne.
AFL ROUND 20
Saturday: GWS Giants v Melbourne Demons at Manuka Oval, 1:45pm. Tickets available from .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callan Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shiel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ward</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Shiel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL ROUND 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Himmelberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dion Georgopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
