<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425246284944109</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4832970/hospital-to-undergo-full-bypass-treatment/?cs=310</url>
  <title>Hospital to undergo full bypass treatment</title>
  <content>
FULL PACKAGE: The Berejiklian government has agreed to fund a full traffic interchange on the Newcastle Link Road. Parliamentary Secretary for the Hunter Scot MacDonald said it would "future proof" the road. PICTURE: Jonathan Carroll

THE state government will spend an additional $13 million on building a full traffic interchange at the John Hunter Hospital after pressure from health officials to extend the project.
Parliamentary Secretary for the Hunter Scot MacDonald announced on Friday that the government had changed its mind on building the full interchange in the final stage of the inner-city bypass, after . 
The government had initially planned to build a single north-facing access to the John Hunter Hospital off the interchange because traffic modelling conducted by the Roads and Maritime Service showed some 5000 fewer motorists would use a south access.
But after lobbying from the health department - and an agreement that the extra $13 million needed for the full interchange would come from NSW Health's budget and not the Roads and Maritime Service - the government changed its mind.
Hunter New England Health chief executive Michael DiRienzo said health officials had stressed the "growth" expected at the hospital campus in the coming years.
"I think this is a really good outcome [because] it's about what we have now, but also about what's coming around the corner," he said.
"It's very much about planning for the future."
Mr MacDonald, who has  for the hospital, said Premier Gladys Berejiklian had taken a "personal interest" in seeing that the full interchange was built.

"I am grateful the NSW Government has been able to respond to clear messages from the community," he said.
"All the trends show a very significant increase in the number of people using this health campus, whether it's the hospital, the private hospital, or the Hunter Medical Research Institute, and I think it's the option that made most sense in the end."
The John Hunter Hospital currently generates about 15,000 trips per day, and Lake Macquarie's Labor Mayor Kay Fraser said the improved traffic flow from the project would also benefit her ratepayers.

"It's an outcome that all our residents will benefit from, but it will be especially welcomed by our residents in New Lambton Heights, Rankin Park and Cardiff Heights who had been advocating for the full interchange," she said.

"It's also a positive that motorists currently travelling on the Inner City Bypass through Lake Macquarie will benefit from the bypass extension."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardiff Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Scot MacDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr MacDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inner City Bypass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter Hospital</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael DiRienzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter New England Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Link Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Lambton Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rankin Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Medical Research Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Services</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie's Labor Mayor Kay Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
