<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425113140955573</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/vaneck-to-expand-china-a-share-etf-offering-20170804-gxpevq</url>
  <title>VanEck to expand China A share ETF offering</title>
  <content>
The Australian arm of one of the world's largest exchange traded fund specialists says talk ofis "overdone," as it makes plans to offer investors more access to the country's increasingly open capital markets.
will be an "incremental" push for both active and passive fund managers to include China A shares in their offerings, VanEck Australia managing director Arian Neiron said.
"Most people talk about the likes of China's GDP, the headline numbers, shadow banking and China's indebtedness. We think that's overdone, overcooked," Mr Neiron said.
"A lot of fund managers, the likes of Platinum's Kerr Neilson are invested heavily in the China and believe the story. They have done their due diligence and we're very much aligned to that as well.

"The investor appetite for China A shares, it's there. It's not significant right now and I think a lot of it is the education. With China A shares being included in the MSCI indices, as that incrementally happens it will become more and more of a topic."

The decision in June by the shares in its global emerging markets benchmark index, worth about $US1.6 trillion ($2.1 trillion), is a being touted as a .
The MSCI indices are globally the most widely used regional benchmarks and the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock exchanges combined are the the second-largest sharemarket in the world after the US.
Andrew McAuley,the chief investment officer, discretionary portfolio management, Credit Suisse Private Bank, The Australian Financial Review"When this was announced a few weeks ago it was greeted as a significant change, but one that would take a number of years to play out.
"In the short term it will probably have little impact as the weight allocated to onshore Chinese equities and away from Australian equities is small.

"In the long term we believe that the proportion Australian stocks represent of regional equity markets will fall, and that it is inevitable investment funds will flow out of Australian equities into other regional markets, particularly China."
Mr Neiron agreed and said that for VanEck, which in Australia offers the only China A shares strategy in the market, it would be a case of a slow approach to the "rapidly developing" China market.
"We don't want to deliver fads," he said.
"I think the MSCI doing this incrementally is assuring the market that it's not going to be an opening of the floodgates in terms of inclusions. They don't want to shock the market."

US-based VanEck in June became one of two managers, the other being fellow ETF giant Vanguard, to be awarded a quota by China's State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) to buy mainland China shares and bonds.
The "significant" quota, as part of the granting of a Renminbi Qualified Foreign Institutional Investor (RQFII) licence, is giving it extra firepower to explore additional ETF opportunities in mainland China.
"It could be around the likes of China technology. It's a big part that effectively the markets have overlooked," Mr Neiron said.
In June the Financial Review revealed VanEck, which manages $US44 billion globally, which includes more than $US9 billion in fixed income, was poised to enter the Australian ETF bond market.

This will expand its stable of 12 domestic and international equity ETFs which have attracted $708 million to date.
Since the ASX introduced fixed-income ETFs five years ago they have become extremely popular with investors. The fourth largest of all Australian ETFs is the Betashares Australian High Interest ETF, which has attracted $1.1 billion in investor funds since April 2012.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse Private Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanguard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arian Neiron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VanEck Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Neiron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VanEck</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renminbi Qualified Foreign Institutional Investor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shenzhen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian ETF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's State Administration of Foreign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McAuley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Platinum's Kerr Neilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian ETFs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betashares Australian High Interest ETF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSCI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETF</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RQFII</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETFs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China A</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based VanEck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
