<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425164680564041</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/kirk-given-the-captaincy-for-eagles-on-proud-day/3209042/</url>
  <title>Kirk given the captaincy for Eagles on proud day</title>
  <content>
COREY Kirk will be bursting with pride and flying high when he runs out as captain for the Goodna Eagles on Saturday night against West End.
The club stalwart will be the captain at Woogaroo Field after regular leader Ramon Filipine gave him the green light to have the 'c' next to his name for the club's Goodna Indigenous Appreciation Round clash. Filipine is of Samoan heritage and said it was only fitting that Kirk, a proud Indigenous man, should lead the team.
"To captain this side is one of the biggest honours I have had in rugby league but this week, for the Indigenous round, I have let Corey captain the side and he will run the boys out," Filipine said
"I think it is fitting, because it is their day."
The duo work together for the Aboriginal Employment Strategy (AES) and are close on and off the field.
Kirk said Filipine's character came to the fore when he asked him to lead the team.
"It is a real kind gesture from Ramon," he said.
"I am very honoured to lead the boys out in the Indigenous round. The whole concept behind bringing the Indigenous round to Goodna came from Ramon last year.
"He said 'what do you think?'.I said 'it is a great idea'.
"That is a real testament to his character, being non-Indigenous and really wanting to get behind the cause. We ran our inaugural one year, which was a great success.
"It wasn't hard to get volunteers behind the cause. We had more people than we have ever seen here at Goodna. The 'house of pain' was packed. We are looking to build off that this year. The boys are really pumped."
Filipine said the event had brought all of Goodna together. "Our sponsor this year is Preston & Co. John Preston paid for our jerseys . He is non-Indigenous and his kids play juniors.
"We invited him along last year and he wanted to come on board because he loved the concept, so a big thank you to him."
Goodna-based councillor Paul Tully said the Goodna area was a diverse community, showcasing almost 90 different nationalities.
"In the Goodna region the Indigenous community has made a tremendous contribution and this event is an opportunity for it to be recognised. It will bring the entire community together," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramon Filipine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Filipine</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Tully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodna Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woogaroo Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodna-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodna Indigenous Appreciation Round</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodna</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Kirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Preston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal Employment Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
