<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425134615792484</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/it-was-bryan-fullers-idea-for-thestar-trek-discovery-novel-to-be-a-prequel-to-the-prequel/</url>
  <title>It Was Bryan Fuller's Idea For The Star Trek: Discovery Novel To Be A Prequel To The Prequel</title>
  <content>
All Photos Courtesy Simon & Schuster

Bryan Fuller may no longer be involved in CBS' Star Trek: Discovery, but his legacy in building the series can still be found, even in the most unexpected ways. This includes the topic of its first tie-in novel.

At the Star Trek Las Vegas convention, publisher Simon & Schuster unveiled the cover and plot details for Desperate Hours, the first in a series of novels and comic books set in Discovery's universe. The novel is set one year before the events of Discovery, diving into Lieutenant Michael Burnham's work on the Shenzou and her growing relationship with Captain Philippa Georgiou.

So, why is the first book a prequel to the prequel, instead of expanding the universe with stories about less-explored characters? You can thank Fuller for that. Author David Mack revealed that he worked extensively with Discovery's writers and story developers while developing Desperate Hours, and the topic of the book came from Fuller himself - most likely before he left the project.

"They have kept me in the loop throughout the season with all the scripts and the story development. There were a few false starts, but eventually it allowed us to collaboratively create this story, which by the way sprung from a direct request by Bryan Fuller," Mack said. "He basically asked that we write a book on this basic premise."

Desperate Hours comes out September 26, two days after Discovery premieres. You can read the book synopsis below.

[]

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant Michael Burnham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novel To Be A Prequel To</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shenzou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Philippa Georgiou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Trek Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS' Star Trek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryan Fuller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Mack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Trek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schuster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photos Courtesy Simon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desperate Hours</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryan Fuller's Idea For</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
