<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425031536575626</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/consumer-affairs/energy-retailers-drop-fixedrate-plans-after-electricity-price-hike-20170803-gxp4rq.html</url>
  <title>Energy retailers drop-fixed rate plans after steep electricity price hike</title>
  <content>
The big three energy retailers have dropped their fixed rate electricity plans, citing "low customer demand", despite recent average bill hikes of 17 per cent.
Fixed-rate plans offer consumers a set price for every billing period, regardless of how much electricity they use.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Paying the lazy tax

The energy companies don't make it easy for anyone to shop around. Michael Pascoe comments.

EnergyAustralia, AGL and Origin have all dropped their fixed-rate offering in the past few weeks.
It comes ahead of a talks hosted by Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull next week, to discuss the increasing strain of power bills.Photo: Darren Pateman
A key point of discussion will be consumers who are pushed from discounted market rates to higher priced standard contracts or non-discounted plans often without realising it.
Simon Downes, editor of financial comparison site Canstar Blue said, at a time when "consumers will be shopping around to find the best deals...it's hugely disappointing that fixed-rate plans had been taken away."

"This is significant because we analysed fixed and variable rate plans in the lead-up to July price rises and found fixed-rate plans were giving consumers a great opportunity to beat the price hikes and save in the long run."

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

He said fixed-rate plans offered some certainty over energy prices for two years, "but now everyone will be left running the gauntlet of variable rates, which can change at any time".Photo: Andrew Quilty
However, retailers say the plans were not as popular as some might think.
An EnergyAustralia spokeswoman said customer feedback suggested its Rate Fix product was not delivering what customers wanted.
"We're in the process of designing an alternative product. Our existing customers on the Rate Fix plan aren't impacted by this change; their rates will continue to be fixed for the guaranteed two-year benefit period."
Currently, less than 1 per cent of EnergyAustralia's residential customer base is signed up to the product.
AGL also removed its residential fixed-rate plans due to low customer demand.
"Since launching our guaranteed discount product AGL Everyday, customers have shown a strong preference for usage discounts over fixed rates," a spokesman said.
"As an indication, when presented side by side on our website, less than 3 per cent of customers chose fixed-rate offers over usage discounts." 
The AGL Everyday product includes a guaranteed discount off usage and supply charges that is not conditional on paying on time.
Origin removed its Rate Freeze product in response to a stronger uptake of its Predictable Plan product, launched in March last year.
While Rate Freeze locked in a customer's underlying energy rate, their bills were still subject to variations in usage. Instead, the Predictable Plan offers one fixed-rate set for 12 months that does not change based on usage.
"Origin's Predictable Plan helps protect customers against price rises and nasty bill surprises by allowing them to lock in a fixed monthly or fortnightly price for their energy for 12 months," an Origin spokesman said.
St Vincent de Paul Society's Gavin Dufty said the move by the big three pointed to where energy prices were likely to head from here.
"It suggests to me they are more likely to go up than down. It indicates there is volatility in the market if a retailer can't offer a fixed one or two year contract."
Since October last year, the average standing offer annual bill for a typical five-person household has increased from $2188 to $2569.
The average cheapest market contract annual bill has increased from $1821 to $2059.
Canstar estimates one in four households in NSW is stuck on an expensive standard contract, "subsidising the savings enjoyed by engaged electricity customers".
"Consumers need to be aware that the providers can, and do, change their prices whenever they please, unless you are locked into a fixed-rate plan," said Mr Downes. 
Australian Energy Council chief Michael Warren said talking about retail bills and customer deals at next week's power talks would not solve the problem of unsustainable bills.
"A bipartisan, national clean energy target remains the key reform to drive new investment and bring down electricity prices," he said on Friday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Downes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Downes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin's Predictable Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Pateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rate Fix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Energy Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Society's Gavin Dufty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rate Freeze</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Vincent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canstar Blue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL Everyday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Pascoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Predictable Plan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnergyAustralia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
