<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425074486249341</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/accounting/remaining-old-guard-cpa-directors-to-follow-alex-malley-and-step-down-20170804-gxplk6</url>
  <title>Remaining 'old guard' CPA directors to follow Alex Malley out the door</title>
  <content>
A campaign by angry CPA Australia members to topple the remaining "old guard" directors of the nation's biggest accounting body has triumphed, with the current board now all set to retire by the end of the year.
The announcement, sent to members on Friday afternoon, comes after a Senate committee on Wednesday announced it would call the CPA board to appear and explain their actions .
CPA directors Graeme Wade and Michele Dolin will both retire early from the board on 30 September. Fellow director Richard Petty and temporarily appointed director Tim Youngberry had already planned to step down on the same day. Chairman Jim Dickson and director Sharon Portelli will also retire early, on December 31.
Mr Wade and Mr Petty have both been on the board since 2006 and were close associates of Alex Malley, the former CEO of the accounting body.

The long-term board members have overseen a period at the nation's largest accounting body where seven of their number resigned and  amid a member uprising over the way the body was being run.

Chairman Mr Dickson said the board had been involved in active discussions with members about the best way forward for the accounting body.
"Over the past few months the board has focused on key initiatives to position CPA Australia for the future. We want CPA Australia to be strong, unified and forward looking. The orderly succession of directors is another major step in achieving this objective," he said.
while . 
Until the announcement, the call for complete board renewal had been resisted by the directors. A CPA representative said as recently as Wednesday that "the board and the management of CPA Australia don't believe that an entire spill is in the best interest of the organisation."

Rebel CPA Brett Stevenson welcomed the move as a "major breakthrough" for members.
"This is a major announcement to enable CPA to move ahead without some the baggage that has caused the problems we are in," he said. "It at least has enabled some integrity in the appointment of the new directors in September. And that is what is needed if CPA is going to move forward."
"It certainly means we do not have to go ahead with a spill motion of the current board because they are all going now anyway."
In the Friday message to members, CPA also revealed it will offer its public practice members, , additional insurance coverage for free.

This means that members with a public practice certificate who are currently required to have a minimum of $2 million in professional indemnity insurance will have provided with an additional $3 million in coverage for free.
CPA's Nomination and Remuneration Committee will also be expanded to include three external members as well as Mr Dickson and Mr Youngberry. The new members are Rhonda O'Donnell, a Trustee Director at MTAA Super and member of the RMIT Council, and Leanne Rowe, a former non-executive director at Medibank and former Deputy Chancellor at Monash University, and lawyer Geoff Rees.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Petty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leanne Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Petty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTAA Super</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remuneration Committees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Youngberry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Youngberry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medibank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Jim Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trustee Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Malley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Portelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michele Dolin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA's Nomination</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhonda O'Donnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Mr Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Brett Stevenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Rees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
