<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425284939650413</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834272/jets-keeper-eyes-cup-date-with-messi/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Jets keeper eyes cup date with Messi</title>
  <content>
PLAYING FOR KEEPS: Glen Moss (left) and Jack Duncan have been pushing each other at Jets training as the club hunts for a new goalkeeper coach. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

JETS keeper Glen Moss has been selected in the New Zealand squad to take on the Solomon Islands in the final Oceania stage of World Cup qualifying and secure a potential date with a Lionel Messi-led Argentina.
Moss is one of three keepers alongside Canada-based Stefan Marincovic and Phoenix youngster Oliver Sail for a home-and-away series against the Solomon Islands in Auckland on September 1 and Honiara five days later.
The winner will take on the fifth-placed South American side in November for a place in the World Cup finals in Russia in 2018.

Jets keeper eyes cup date with Messi

exit
"When I checked the other day Argentina were fifth," Moss said. "That would be a big big game. I love representing my country, especially in these crunch games."
Moss, 34, was the No.2 behind Marincovic at the Confederations Cup in Russia in June where the All Whites went down to the host nation 2-0, Mexico 2-1 and Portugal 4-0 in the group stage.
They are red-hot favourites to beat Solomon Islands and advance to the play-off against the South Americans but Moss is not taking anything for granted.
"Gone are the days when us and Australia were beating these teams 10-0," he said. "We are coming up against sides with foreign coaches. They get FIFA money for facilities and infrastructure. Last time we went to Honiara we lost in the build up to the Brazil World Cup. These are by no means walk overs, we are in for tough games."
In the meantime, Moss is battling Jack Duncan for a starting spot against Adelaide in the FFA Cup round of 32 clash on Wednesday.
"We are only five weeks into pre-season and it is the most enjoyable pre-season I have had in a long time," Moss said.
Moss had spent the past five seasons at Wellington Phoenix, where wet and windy conditions are a constant.
"If it is not blowing at 100-120km an hour, it's nothing, it's a breeze," Moss joked about the blustery conditions at Ray Watt Oval on Friday. "The conditions in Wellington are tough, especially after you have done five or so pre-seasons. It is certainly a lot more pleasant here. Here we are able to come out in the sun and do our stretching. You can work for longer and recover better."
Moss and Duncan are working without the guidance of a specialist coach at the Jets after the departure of Jess Vanstrattan to Melbourne City last week.
Jets chief executive Lawrie McKinna said they were "talking to a few" potential replacements.
"There is only a small pool of coaches here with the required accreditation," McKinna said. "You need to have a level two goalkeeping coach licence and be enrolled to do level three. We spoke to Ante Covic and Clint Bolton but they don't have the proper badges." 
Moss said that he and Duncan had been following a program Vanstrattan formulated before his departure.
"We are ticking along doing Jess's program," Moss said. "At this stage of the pre-season where a lot it is conditioning, we can drive ourselves."

"I have been trying to lead the session as much as I can. The first day I came out early to set up drills and Jack had already set them up and was doing them. To work with such a motivated young goalkeeper, I have learned a few things. I have had some very good coaches. Jonathan Gould was at the Phoenix and got a move to West Bronwich Albion in the Premier League. I still stay in touch with him and try to pick up the latest drills and techniques."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Watt Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moss</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawrie McKinna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi-led Argentina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Whites</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oceania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solomon Islands</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marincovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honiara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confederations Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada-based Stefan Marincovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Phoenix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Duncan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Sail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Moss</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Gould</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Bronwich Albion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moss, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ante Covic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanstrattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess Vanstrattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
