<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425671486713933</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/former-sandy-bay-football-club-players-to-gather-to-remember-clubs-heydays/news-story/b45a83ebf912a3c20ea552368939cecb</url>
  <title>Players remember club's heydays</title>
  <content>
NONAGENARIAN Noel Ruddock doesn't remember much about his first game for Sandy Bay in 1945 but there's one thing he will never forget.
That is how much the rugged ruck-rover, and the last surviving member of the original '45 team, loved playing football for his beloved Seagulls for almost two decades.
In 1997, Sandy Bay played its last game against Clarence at Bellerive and when the final siren sounded, the club was consigned to the annals of history.
Now, 90-year-old Noel will be front and centre when Sandy Bay celebrates the 20th anniversary of the club's demise at Wrest Point on August 18.
"I have a lot of terrific memories of my days at the club - not so many about premierships - but we had a great bunch of players. They were more like friends," Noel said.
Noel's first game for the Bay was against North Hobart at North Hobart Oval, kicking off his career as a tough and elusive onballer.
He played in a state premiership for the Seagulls in their second season and TFL premiership in 1952.
Unlike today's players, they didn't get paid much.
"I got nothing. And I found out later on that Stumpy Westell, our full-forward, was being given 10 shillings for every goal he kicked. No wonder he always want me to kick the ball to him," Noel said.
"I was pleased just to play."
Noel played for the Bay for 18 years and was gutted when the financially stricken Seagulls went under.
"It was shocking. I was really disappointed. I'm an accountant so I understand how money comes into it so much," he said.
Nigel Palfreyman is a former captain of Sandy Bay and Nick Probert a gun onballer. Both played in the club's last game.
"It's a club with a lot of history and it meant so much to a lot of people, so to go out there and play for the last time was very emotional," Palfreyman said.
Probert said the 20th anniversary was a chance for the Sandy Bay Past Players Association to mark a significant milestone.
"It's about being able to commemorate the entire era of the footy club from 1945 to 1997," he said.
"Connecting to the players who were at the club is really important."
The historic moment 20 years ago did not hit home until later.
"When you're younger you don't recognise the significance of moments like that. It's only now we're 20 years down the track we can look back and realise how important it was," Probert said.
"Seeing old players in tears after the game, and having Clarence come into the room, and having [Sandy Bay legend] Graeme Mackey speak, then the reality started to sink in."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Probert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Bay Past Players Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TfL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellerive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Mackey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palfreyman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seagulls</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Probert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Palfreyman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Ruddock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wrest Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stumpy Westell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Bay</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Hobart Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
