<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424937047293146</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/matt-priddis-overlooked-for-west-coast-eagles-clash-with-st-kilda/news-story/ed123b4712ff4618cbbf64f041ab32eb</url>
  <title>Eagles overlook healthy Priddis</title>
  <content>
MATT Priddis has been overlooked for Sunday's must-win game against St Kilda at Etihad Stadium.
The 32-year-old has flown east as the team's travelling emergency, with the Eagles choosing to instead bring in Chris Masten for an injured Tom Barrass (groin) as their only change.
Priddis trained during the week and was declared available by Eagles coach Adam Simpson this morning, meaning he has been left out of the Eagles' best 22 on selection.
The decision comes after the club said the midfielder was being rested last weekend to manage quad soreness.
One of the club's most decorated players, Priddis announced he was retiring from the AFL at the end of this season at a press conference last week.
Junior footy team penalised for winning by too much

Speaking three hours before the team's departure from Perth, Simpson refused to reveal that Priddis would miss out on selection or the reasons for the decision.
"It was a good performance last week," Simpson said.
"Tommy has unfortunately hurt his groin, so he's unavailable.
"Like we said, the team will be announced in a couple of hours.
"He (Priddis) has got through that (injury). He's trained all week so he'll be available... I know there's been lots of questions on it.
"I think we've been as open and transparent as we can be. I really hope we continue to respect the man and what decision he made and enjoy and embrace the last five weeks of his career.
"We need to move on pretty quick. I know there's still the commentary, but from our end we've been saying the same thing since last Friday, haven't we?"
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Masten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Barrass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
