<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425375133965251</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/best-of-townsville-burgers/news-story/a398d598662867380177c2925f670bbf</url>
  <title>Townsville's best burgers</title>
  <content>
IT'S a tough job but someone had to do it.
Bulletin reporter Danni Shafik sacrificed her waistline to try Townsville's best burgers according to our readers.
The search was tough but there could only be one winner with the Real Burger Co taking out the top spot with its decadent selection.
RELATED:
RELATED:
RELATED:
RELATED:
Bridget and Sandy Contarino opened the Hyde Park shop in December, 2015 and were thrilled to receive Bulletin readers' top vote.
"We put a lot of effort, passion and love into it so are really thrilled that Townsville has noticed and our hard work shines through," Mrs Contarino said.
Townsville can be proud of its burger selection that shows great variety, combined with local produce and originality to make up some great combinations of the popular food with something for every palate.
All the nominated joints made it a difficult decision as I enjoyed every bite taken on this challenge.
Real Burger Co
The Real Lot - $15.90
Real Burger Co owners Bridget and Sandy Contarino have created a local gem with their passion for food.
"A lot of people have heard that we source our ingredients from around town," Mrs Contarino said.
"We are picking local produce from local farmers and it's going straight on your burger. We have a beautiful fat ratio in our patty, making it tender and tasty."
The real lot was oozing upon presentation, making me reach for the napkins from the get go in order to hack right into it.
It was the fresh patty and yolk that dominated in my mouth, making me continue to hack into the centre as the remaining toppings joined forces to pack flavour in every bite.
T.U.B.E.
Aussie Classic - $15.50
TUBE stands for The Ultimate Burger Experience, and it certainly lived up to the name.
The venue has been open on The Strand for six years, and following success, opened a second store in Mt Louisa in May.
Owned by Kalvin Moore and Paul Sichter, Mr Moore said it had been a hard six years, and the crew worked hard at giving support back to the community.
The Aussie Classic burger I tasted had everything on it, with great proportions to balance out the flavours in one mouthful.
The dose of barbecue sauce was generous and the thick cheese was evident as it covered the patty.
Every ingredient was layered perfectly and although it was challenging to hold together, the effort involved was worth it, to get everything in one hit for maximum goodness.
South Townsville Takeaway
Fish Burger-$10.50
This small takeaway store has got it all from fish and chips to burgers galore.
Mel Bonner owns the store, along with husband and wife Gavin and Ciara Maughan.
The trio took the reins in December last year and Ms Bonner said the burgers had hit the top five because they were made with love.
The fish burger had tasty mackerel, along with a crunchy toasted bun, tartare sauce and the salad essentials making it a lighter and refreshing meal for any occasion.
There was just the right amount of each ingredient in this one to make every bite capture the goodness of all the contents.
Otto's Fresh Food Market
Wagyu beef burger - $15
Everyone in Townsville knows Otto's means quality. The variety of fresh produce that comes from the beloved venue, owned by Dan and Sandra Peel since 1966, is astounding. This American style burger was served in a basket with handmade fries with all the basic essentials making it a classic feast. Chef Sophie Anderson said the burger was made with Australian Wagyu beef, with fresh made rolls baked daily in their artisan bake house. "We only use the best local ingredients," she said. The standout was the red cheddar that did wonders when combined with the American mustard and homemade wagyu patty. A pickle topped it off keep it tangy yet simple and the garlic aioli brought on that extra kick of flavour that would never disappoint.
Dad & Dave's Tucker Box
Fred's Lot - $11
This small store on Ingham Road was the underdog, but came out with a bang as owners Fred and Angelina Torrisi delivered the goods from the popular shop they have run since 1994.
Mr Torrisi says if you can't make a good burger after 23 years, there's something wrong.
From first sight it was evident that Fred's lot was going to go down a treat.
The special handmade burger came with plenty of fresh salad and the size, this was definitely the Godzilla of burgers.
There was nothing forgotten between the fresh bread as I took a bite of all the inclusions with egg, beetroot, pineapple, barbecue sauce and bacon.
A good sized patty that was thinner and spread out gave room for the salad ingredients to shine in this one.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chef Sophie Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Classic - $15.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred's Lot - $11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Otto's Fresh Food Market</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burger-$10.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Lot - $15.90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bonner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyde Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burger Co</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridget</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ciara Maughan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Contarino</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagyu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Contarino</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Burger Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danni Shafik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultimate Burger Experience</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Louisa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Townsville Takeaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalvin Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel Bonner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelina Torrisi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave's Tucker Box</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godzilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Sichter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Classic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Wagyu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Otto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.B.E</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Peel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingham Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Torrisi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
