<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425413788671651</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/warmer-waters-prove-to-be-a-perfect-podpleaser/news-story/09df387f285b147a8c0f578d106cfbaf</url>
  <title>Warmer waters prove a pod-pleaser</title>
  <content>
A POD of orcas has made a rare visit to waters off the Tasman Peninsula, surprising experts and providing a striking spectacle for onlookers.
UTas PhD student Ben Sellers, who is studying killer whale diets and foraging range, says there has been a small number of reported sightings of killer whales off the East Coast, but said they are uncommon for this time of year.
"It is a little bit surprising for whales to be sighted, but the recent warmer weather may be one reason why they were spotted," Mr Sellers said.
"During winter time, we think orcas stay in more northern waters ... but it is possible that because less people are on the water in winter, there is less of a chance of sightings."

Mr Sellers has found it was becoming more common for sea life in Australian waters to migrate south.
"Dave Donnelly of Killer Whales Australia has said that we are seeing a lot more animals pushing down the East Coast of Tasmania to have a look around," he said.
Mr Sellers' research into orcas will explore killer whale feeding ecology and movements.
James Kitto is a University of Tasmania student.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Donnelly of Killer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Kitto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Sellers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whales Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sellers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Coast of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTas PhD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
