<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425499688019169</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/milkshake-travels-600km-interstate-to-terminal-cancer-patient/news-story/7b3fa61aa1dd8601688b31206abb1443</url>
  <title>Milkshake travels 600km interstate to terminal cancer patient</title>
  <content>
Fifty-year-old Emily Pomeranz died Friday of pancreatic cancer. Picture: Facebook

Share

A WOMAN in hospice care in Virginia had a dying wish fulfilled last month - one last mocha milkshake from a popular suburban Cleveland restaurant.
Fifty-year-old Emily Pomeranz died Friday of pancreatic cancer. With help from a friend in Virginia and the longtime owner of Tommy's in Cleveland Heights, the shake arrived from interstate four days earlier.
A photo of a smiling Pomeranz holding the shake and the "The Milkshake Mission" story have travelled much farther than the drink's 600km trip.
Restaurant owner Tommy Fello initially wasn't sure how it could be accomplished after getting a call from Pomeranz's friend Sam Klein. Fello made it work, packing the shake in dry ice and shipping it overnight.
Fello says the photo of Pomeranz proves giving is better than receiving.
Klein posted the photo of Pomeranz on Facebook with this message.
"I want to share a great story with you about a place we all know and love: Tommy's Restaurant on Coventry (in Cleveland Heights, OH). Tommy's is famous for its incredible food and milkshakes. If you grew up on the east side of Cleveland, you have probably had the milkshakes. Although I now live in the Washington, D.C. area, I still get to Tommy's every time I am in Cleveland. Recently, a dear friend of mine, Emily Pomeranz, who also grew up in Cleveland Heights (and also lived in the D.C. area) was moved to hospice as she had pancreatic cancer (her third cancer in her 50 years of life). I went to visit her in hospice a few weeks ago and asked her if she needed anything. "A Cleveland Indians hat," was her first response. So, I brought her one the next day. And, she said with a smile, I wish I could have one more Tommy's mocha milkshake. Knowing that she couldn't travel to Cleveland, I emailed the general information email address on Tommy's website, asking if there was a way to get a milkshake the 375 miles (603km) from Coventry Road to Arlington, Virginia where she was in hospice. A few days later I got a call from Tommy Fello, the owner of Tommy's. "Yes. We will figure out a way to do this," is what he said.
Sure enough, after a little research on shipping and two trips to the UPS office, he shipped a carefully packed Tommy's mocha shake to Emily. This was a huge surprise. She was thrilled. She shared it with her family. She talked about it for days and days. She shared the story with her friends back in Cleveland and here in the D.C. area. It was something that made everyone smile. A woman's request for one last milkshake from her favourite restaurant. Wish granted! Sadly, Emily passed away last week. She leaves behind a treasure trove of memories; a legacy of laughter, joy and caring; grieving family and friends. But, she was able to fulfil her wish of one last Tommy's milkshake thanks to the caring and good heartedness of Tommy at Tommy's. So, my friends, if you are in Cleveland Heights, or anywhere near there, please stop in at Coventry, order one of those incredible milkshakes and ask for Tommy (he is the one cooking in the middle of the restaurant) and say, 'This one is for Emily. Thank you for sending one to her.'"
The post has been 'liked' over 7,000 times.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pomeranz</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coventry Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Heights</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommy Fello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Indians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milkshake Mission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virginia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coventry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Pomeranz</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Klein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommy's Restaurant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARLINGTON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D.C</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommy</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Klein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
