<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425370838997924</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/canberra-brave-stephen-blunden-becomes-fastest-aihl-player-to-score-100-goals-20170803-gxp3c1.html</url>
  <title>Canberra Brave Stephen Blunden becomes fastest AIHL player to score 100 goals</title>
  <content>
Stephen Blunden contacted every team in the Australian Ice Hockey League in a bid to bring his talent down under and only one responded.
If they'd known the Canadian import would become the fastest player in league history to net 100 goals, it would have been more than just the Canberra Brave who offered him a chance.Photo: Rohan Thomson
Blunden has been loyal to the capital side ever since they picked up him four years ago but the 28-year-old has confirmed this season will be his last on the ice before he returns home to "become an adult" in the real world.
The prolific goal-scorer netted against the Adelaide Adrenalin on the road last week to become the first player in the league to net 100 goals in just 71 games.
Blunden was made aware of the record-breaking feat after the 10-5 win and said the record was "pretty cool" but he's more focused on delivering the Brave a maiden championship.

"It's nice to pick up the record but I want to finish my career with championship, the record is just a nice cherry on top," Blunden said.
"I came out here four years ago after I emailed every team and Canberra was the only one that wanted me so I've stuck with them.
"I definitely never thought my hockey career would take me anywhere near Australia and to be here for four years is awesome."
Brave coach Robert Starke praised his import for the professionalism he brings to the team and said there is no player more disciplined with their preparation than Blunden.
"Steven's game is highly offensive, he's a threat every time he steps on the ice and leads by example," Starke said.
"He's been a Brave since its inception and was one of the first imports the Brave signed and he's certainly a game-changer.
"His true value came to light over the past few months, he was out injured for six weeks and scored six goals in his first game back and nine goals in last three games, he's a dominate force who lifts our team."
Blunden said he will continue to play socially when he returns to Canada and added he won't miss the physciality of the Australian league.
"It's a lot rougher behind the scenes here with stick work and stuff. If you run around being a dickhead back home someone is going to answer you. Whereas here it's tougher because you get kicked out of the game if you fight," Blunden said.
The Brave host the Sydney Ice Dogs at the Phillip Swimming and Ice Skating Centre at 5:30pm on Saturday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Ice Dogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Starke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Swimming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Brave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ice Skating Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Blunden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Adrenalin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIHL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blunden</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ice Hockey League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Brave Stephen Blunden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
