<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425671486713917</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/victoria/geelongmade-furphy-beer-grows-by-300-per-cent-in-three-years/news-story/af4ca77ec7c7d51ac736b9d6cc1fdecb</url>
  <title>Geelong-made Furphy beer grows by 300 per cent in three years</title>
  <content>
Furphy head brewer Warren Pawsey on the busy production line. Picture: Glenn Ferguson

Nicholas PayneGeelong Advertiser

Share

FURPHY beer has taken Victoria by storm, growing 300 per cent year-on-year since its humble launch on a few local taps in 2014.
The beer's popularity has seen Furphy head brewer Warren Pawsey and his team expand their operation at Geelong's Little Creatures brewery with a massive $20 million upgrade - but Mr Pawsey said even that might not be enough to keep up with demand.
"Three years ago this month we launched Furphy, and we were doing one brew and it was lasting five or six weeks - now we're doing 20 times that, or more," he said.
"We just spent $20 million in the last 12 months putting in new tanks and expanding our production capacity, thinking that was going to last us a couple of years, but with the rate we're going we'll be bursting at the seams."
Mr Pawsey said they'd been forced to massively accelerate their plans, as Victorians of all stripes have fallen in love with Furphy.
"We had a five year plan, but it's really totally overwhelming, the uptake," he said.
"We originally just did draught, just in pubs in Geelong, and in our first month there were 20 outlets, from that it's just been just constant growth."
He said part of the appeal was the beer's place as a midpoint between mainstream brews and some of the craft labels that drinkers may find too intimidating to delve into.
"When we designed it, we wanted to make an easy-drinking beer that appealed to people - not that Little Creatures doesn't, but Little Creatures have a lot of hops in them and for someone who's used to drinking something more mainstream that's a big change," he said.

"We were looking for something that was an easy step for people who were into mainstream beer."
Furphy is now so popular in Victoria that any plans to expand interstate have had to be put on hold, as brewers fight just to keep up with local demand.
We always said it was made in Victoria for Victorians, and we'd be crazy to sell it anywhere else if we can't supply Victoria," Mr Pawsey said.
"Anything's possible, but we're struggling to keep up with Victoria right now, it's becoming an adored brand here and you can't be exporting it if someone here wants it."
Furphy and Little Creatures marketing manager Ash Cranston said the brand was now "well and truly" on the way to becoming Victoria's most beloved beer brand.
"The Victorian public have well and truly embraced Furphy - we have seen strong growth since launching the years ago, growing 300 per cent year-on-year and are now one of the fastest growing beer brands in Victoria," Mr Cranston said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Cranston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Creatures</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cranston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas PayneGeelong Advertiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong-made Furphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Pawsey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pawsey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Little Creatures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
