<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425602767235845</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:53</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834215/turn-over-an-old-leaf-in-readers-paradise/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Turn over an old leaf in readers' paradise</title>
  <content>
Bookworms: Volunteers John McLaughlin, Judy McLaughlin and Vic Levi in front, Lesley Gent and Don Munroe in back. Picture: Marina Neil

AVID readers start lining up for the Friends of the University of Newcastle's biennial book fairs before the doors open.
Organisation president John McLaughlin said the queue starting from the Great Hall will have reached the carpark about 200 metres away 30 minutes before the event starts. "Then it's an absolute free for all," Mr McLaughlin said. "We will fill this auditorium, it will be teeming with people stepping over each other for four hours straight. There is a terrific resurgence in interest in books - people realise they're not just reading material, they're part of their lives. They're a companion for a train or bus trip, a record of history, a gift from a dear friend."

The organisation expects thousands of book lovers will attend its 17th fair, which will be held on the Callaghan campus from 10am to 5pm on Saturday and Sunday and 10am to 4pm weekdays except Thursday, when it will close at 7pm. It will also open next Saturday. Mr McLaughlin said 500,000 items would be available, comprising mostly books spanning more than 60 genres - the most popular is fiction - but also records, CDs, DVDs, sheet music and magazines from 50 cents.

The stage will be reserved for special or rare items, including Flowers and Views of The Holy Land, a book of pressed flowers and paintings dated December 9, 1917 and a souvenir of the British occupation of Jerusalem.

Grahame L Walsh's Bradshaw Art of the Kimberley; magazines from Bruce Bairnsfather's Fragments from France series; a signed copy of Australia's last bushranger Jack Bradshaw's Highway Robbery Under Arms Without Shedding Blood and two original pressings of The Beatles' Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band are also for sale. "We have used bookshop owners or collectors who come from as far away as Sydney, Katoomba, Melbourne and the Gold Coast and know exactly what they're looking for. They'll spend up to $3000."

Lorna George, the wife of the then vice-chancellor Don George, started the fair 34 years ago after attending a similar event at the University of NSW. It raised $7000.

Since then, the fair has grown to collect $89,000 in 2015 and raise a cumulative $800,000 for assets, scholarships and research. Mr McLaughlin said proceeds from this year's event would go to nine one-year scholarships worth $4000 as well as research grants.

He said volunteers would start work in October to organise donations for 2019.

"Some people cry when they give us their books - they say they want them to go to a good home. We find lots of lovely notes in between pages, as well as money and once, even a will.

"There's sometimes very sad messages on the flyleaf."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVDs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorna George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerusalem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonely Hearts Club Band</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Bradshaw's Highway Robbery Under Arms Without Shedding Blood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friends of the University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Views of The Holy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOOKWORMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic Levi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beatles' Sgt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grahame L Walsh's Bradshaw Art of the Kimberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McLaughlin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McLaughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Munroe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesley Gent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy McLaughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Bairnsfather's Fragments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volunteers John McLaughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
