<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425336479258933</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/womens-teams-play-off-for-celebratory-silverware/3209067/</url>
  <title>Women's teams play off for celebratory silverware</title>
  <content>
AUSSIE RULES: Although Maroochydore's finals hopes are dashed in the state's premier women's competition, there's still plenty to play for.
The Roos will hit the field on Saturday (11am) against the UQ Lions in the final game of the season.
To tie in with the 50th anniversary of the naming of the Sunshine Coast, the teams will be competing for much more than a win, rather a piece of celebratory silverware.
The sides will contest for the inaugural 50th Anniversary Women's Cup at Maroochydore Multi-Sports Complex.
Maroochydore coach Stuart Jackson hoped to finish the side's debut year in the Queensland Women's AFL with a victory.
"We've been looking for an extra win and we've only beaten Zillmere so far this year," he said.
"This is our last chance and the girls are pumped and ready."
He said playing for the cup was a great way to cap-off what had been a tough season.
"It's a significant event for the Sunshine Coast and the football club has jumped on board and managed to tie it in with the white ribbon foundation too," he said.
It's the first year the Roos women have competed in the QWAFL, and they are placed sixth on the seven-team ladder.
"We've got a very young team at the moment...we have the youngest team by a couple years on average," he said. "But we've got a lot of young talented players that have been through state programs and they should come good in a couple years time when they get a few games under their belt."
The sport's popularity has boomed on the back of the national competition, according to Jackson, with the club able to field a side in the division two competition too.
"The numbers are growing every year and we've doubled in numbers since last year so we're able to put two teams in," he said.
"A lot of the clubs are now putting in for a licence to host women's teams and junior girls teams so there are a lot more opportunities."
Maroochydore's men will host University of Queensland at the same venue (2pm) while Caloundra plays Coorparoo and Noosa hosts Burleigh.
Avoid the area if you can with significant delays reported
Coast's newest eatery opens bringing Italian to the beach
Teen spends big on mum's partner's credit card
Coast researchers welcome govt inspection of white spot studies
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Although Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Multi-Sports Complex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QWAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday: 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Women's AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UQ Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anniversary Women's Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coorparoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zillmere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Rules</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
