<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425637126974788</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/the-economy/rba-sees-economy-growing-at-3-a-year-jobless-rate-to-edge-lower-20170803-gxpam6.html</url>
  <title>RBA sees jobless rate edging lower, gradual wage growth </title>
  <content>
Wages remain at their lowest share of total income in half a century and the growth in average earnings is at its lowest level since the early 1990s, the Reserve Bank has confirmed, after the central bank cut its economic growth forecasts by half a percentage point for the rest of this year. 
In an otherwise optimistic quarterly  released on Friday, the RBA said employment growth was expected to pick up over the second half of 2017 and produce an income boost, even if the pick-up in wage growth is gradual. 

Up Next

CBA headline the reporting calendar

04:01

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Reserve Bank holds cash rate

For the eleventh consecutive month, the RBA keeps the cash rate on hold at 1.5 per cent. Vision courtesy ABC News

It highlighted employment gains in health and social assistance and education as key drivers, with the rollout of the National Disability Insurance Scheme over the next few years providing further encouragement for healthcare workers. 
Retail relief

For consumers, the central bank signalled the entrance of new retailers into the Australian market, such as US giant Amazon, should provide some relief. 

Figures released by the Australian Bureau of Statistics on Friday showed retail trade posted a 0.3 per cent increase in June, a little above expectations of a 0.2 per cent increase, to give total trade an increase of 1.4 per cent for the June quarter. 
"The arrival of further new foreign retailers will be an important influence on consumer durable prices over the next few years," the RBA said, before also highlighting another boost to family budgets from smaller than usual increases in childcare fees and private health insurance premiums. 

Energy inflation

But it warned that a "lack of industry investment widely attributed to uncertainty over electricity and environmental policies" had driven "a sharp rise in wholesale prices for gas and electricity", which could eventually be passed on to household power bills. 

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The announcement of price increases by a number of electricity and gas providers points to a significant pick-up in utilities inflation in both the September quarter 2017 and the March quarter 2018," the bank said. Photo: Ben Rushton
On housing, the bank said the slowdown in risky investor lending after a crackdown by the banking regulator has been largely offset by an increase in credit to owner-occupiers. 
The bank said it remained too early to assess the full impact of all of these changes. Photo: Nicholas Rider
Apartment warning

In a warning to inner-city apartment investors in Sydney and Melbourne, the RBA said recent state and federal budget measures intended to restrain foreign investment had not had the time to have their full effect, which was "uncertain". 
"The effects are likely to be largest in housing markets where foreign buyers have been most active, particularly inner-city apartments," the bank said. 
Earlier this week, the , where it has sat for a year.
The RBA reinforced that decision on Friday, saying this was providing "appropriate support" for the economy.
In revising down its growth predictions by half a percentage point for this year [to 2 to 3 per cent], and a quarter-point in the first half of next [to 2.5 to 3.5 per cent], partly due to the strength of the Australian dollar, the bank cited global factors including a slowdown in trade with Australia's major trading partners including China, Japan and Korea.
"Growth in Australia's trading partners is expected to ease over 2018 and 2019, largely because of longer run factors, such as the decline in the working age population in a number of important trading partners," the bank said. 
Trump concerns

It reiterated its concern over the policies of the Trump administration in the US. 
"Considerable uncertainty remains about the economic policies of the US administration, but the prospect of substantial tax reform in the United States has diminished," the bank said. 
"As a result, fiscal policy in the United States is likely to be less expansionary than previously expected, although the risk of more restrictive and protectionist trade policies has also lessened." 
It said Australia's growth could be "derailed" by escalating geopolitical tensions or increased global trade protectionism.
Economist Paul Dales from Capital Economics said the new growth forecast implied that the RBA might be in position to raise interest rates a little earlier that it previously thought.
"That said, we doubt gross domestic product growth or inflation will live up to the bank's expectations, meaning that rates may stay at 1.5 per cent for another two years yet," he said.
With AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Dales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Disability Insurance Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Rider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Economics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
