<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425499688019161</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/prisoner-sentenced-over-brutal-bashing-of-inmate-at-wellington/8776360</url>
  <title>Prisoner sentenced to nine years jail for brutal bashing of fellow inmate in NSW jail</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A NSW prisoner who brutally assaulted another inmate at the Wellington Correctional Centre, leaving him with a traumatic brain injury, has been sentenced to nine years in jail.
The impact of the 2015 attack was "calamitous" for the victim and his family, District Court judge Warwick Hunt said.
Robin Irvine had been in prison for just nine days and was appealing his sentence for negligent driving causing death when he was assaulted by Richard Tohifolau.
Mr Irvine's sister Rebecca Irvine said no sentence could reflect .
"We're happy that the trial and the sentencing is over, however for us and as a family this is a life sentence no matter what sentence was given to the offender today," she said.
"It's a life sentence for our family and we are really hoping this can prevent this happening to another family."

Victim found on floor surrounded in blood

There had been a degree of preplanning in the attack Tohifolau carried out, Judge Hunt said.
Irvine's cellmate had been ordered to leave, other prisoners were left guarding the cell door and a towel was placed over the window as a sign to others not to come in, Judge Hunt said.
Initially Tohifolau was alone in the cell with Mr Irvine for eight minutes.
In sentencing, the judge said it took more than an hour and a half for Corrective Services NSW to notice what had happened at lunchtime.
It was not until a guard was conducting a search of the group of cells or pod that Mr Irvine was discovered on the floor surrounded by blood.
Irvine in coma for six months

Irvine was taken to Orange and then sent by helicopter to Westmead Hospital in Sydney.
The judge said Mr Irvine's injuries had been life threatening, leaving him in a coma for six months and unable to walk or give evidence in court.
He now has a significant traumatic brain injury and requires 24-hour care.
The judge told the court he could find no motive for the attack, nor could he be convinced of Tohifolau's remorse for his crime.
Tohifolau was recorded saying to other inmates "he's a full blown veg ... I don't give a f***."
However, an apology was tendered in the court.
"I am deeply sorry Mr Irvine has suffered such terrible injury and damage to his life. I never meant that to happen," the statement said.
Corrective Services NSW showed 'lack of duty of care'

Judge Hunt said Tohifolau had experienced disadvantage during his childhood, including a violent father and was only 19 years old when he assaulted Mr Irvine.
He said Corrective Services should immediately place him on a violence program, in his interests and that of the jail population and the community at large.
"We need Corrective Services to not have the lack of duty of care that was shown in this case," he said.
Moved to tears outside Sydney's Downing Centre Court, Mr Irvine's father David said Corrective Services should have been more vigilant.
"There's not even an emergency button you can hit," he said.
He said the assault occurred the week the smoking ban came into force and it had been the last day of the tobacco "buy up".
Mr Irvine's family is .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westmead Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irvine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Irvine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tohifolau</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Irvine</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrective Services NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin Irvine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrective Services</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Hunt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Correctional Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Tohifolau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Downing Centre Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
