<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425113140955617</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4835070/league-defence-not-the-focus-for-fury/?cs=302</url>
  <title>League defence not the focus for Fury</title>
  <content>
OUT OF MIND: Kemblawarra's Lachlan O'Connor and his teammates will face Albion Park this weekend. Picture: GEORGIA MATTS

Fury coach Luke McGuire insists the League Championship is no longer high on Kemblawarra's radar as the IPL prepares for a title defining round 19.

Six of the top seven clubs in the competition will lock horns over the weekend in what shapes as one of the biggest rounds of this season. 
Ladder leaders Bulli face fifth placed Port Kembla, Wollongong Olympic (2nd) host Wollongong United (sixth) while McGuire's third placed side meet Albion Park White Eagles (7th). 
Both Bulli and Olympic's matches come 24 hours before Kemblawarra. 
It means the Fury, who trail Bulli by five points, will know exactly what result they need to stay in touch with the top of the competition with four rounds remaining.
However, McGuire is adamant it won't be on his team's mind when they host the White Eagles at Macedonia Park. 
"We aren't really focused on defending the title at the moment because we are trying to get a few things in place for the finals," he said. 
"We need to rely on things to fall our way elsewhere to get back in the frame, so [the title] isn't really on our radar."
McGuire's focus has also been on getting his injury-hit squad healthy heading into finals.
He believes they profited from the weekend off seven days ago as the Bert Bampton Cup decider took centre stage. 
"We are a little bit closer to everyone in the squad being towards full fitness which is all you can really ask for at this stage of the season," McGuire said.
"Some of our boys are closer to that 80-90% mark rather than towards the 50% mark they were before."
While the Fury had the weekend off, their rivals on Sunday were on the wrong end of a 1-0 defeat to Bulli in the Cup decider.
The loss summed up a frustrating season for Park, who were outstanding last season on route to beating the Fury in the IPL grand final. 
"It's a lot of pressure playing in the grand final like they did the year before and they have probably found it hard to gel the same as they did this season," McGuire said.
"I know they were missing two or three guys for the Cup game last week against Bulli, but we will be expecting nothing more from them than a tough encounter on Sunday."
In other matches on Saturday, Woonona Sharks will host Tarrawanna, who are the only side in the leading pack not playing another team in the top half. 
The fixture will also be an 'Old Boys Day' for the Sharks.
"We'd like to welcome everyone who has played a part in the club's long history back for the occasion," Sharks committee member Frank Shaw said.
Elsewhere, Cringila Lions will look to move even further from the drop zone when they host South Coast United at Crehan Park. 
On Sunday, Corrimal Rangers face-off against Picton Rangers in a massive six-point game.

Picton (10 points) are bottom of the league, but can move above Corrimal (11 points) with a win at Memorial Park. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal (11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park White Eagles (7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kembla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kemblawarra's Lachlan O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Shaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Picton Rangers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Matts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bert Bampton Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal Rangers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Picton (10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedonia Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cringila Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Boys Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Olympic (2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crehan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulli</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kemblawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memorial Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarrawanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woonona Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
