<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425327889324216</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/china-officials-fired-for-spellsfeng-shui/news-story/5173d1e352d819333e59846e37661afc</url>
  <title>China officials fired for spells,feng shui</title>
  <content>
Two Chinese officials have been sacked for involvement in "superstitious activities", including casting spells to aid promotions and attending geomancy courses under the guise of business trips, state media reports.
Members of the ruling Communist Party are not supposed to follow any religion in officially atheist China and the government takes a particularly harsh line on officials who practise what it deems are superstitious folk beliefs.
Xinhua news agency said on Friday that Tang Yuansong, a former county housing official in the central province of Hunan, went on five feng shui training courses under the guise of "investigation tours", starting in 2008.
Each session cost 54,000 yuan ($A10,000), which Tang claimed back as business expenses, Xinhua said.
Tang also earned 5000 yuan a year for practising feng shui for others, it said.
The other person sacked, also a former county official, had "asked others to set up an altar to cast spells and paid 100,000 yuan in tribute each time, with hopes of being promoted", Xinhua said.
Both have been expelled from the party and will be further investigated for suspected criminal acts.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xinhua</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tang Yuansong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communist Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
