<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425589882333805</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/brad-scott-happy-to-preach-teamfirst-will-step-aside-as-north-melbourne-coach-if-its-best-for-club/news-story/74efe545105d6aad5ece73d8138794f6</url>
  <title>Realistic Roos coach's incredible honesty</title>
  <content>
A SELFLESS and honest Brad Scott says he is prepared to step aside from his position should North Melbourne decide that a change in coach is needed.
Scott is contracted to the Kangaroos until the end of 2018, but his tenure as senior coach has been heavily debated throughout the 2017 season, particularly with his side sitting in the bottom four of the ladder after three straight preliminary final appearances between 2013 and 2015.
The speculation around his future has been amplified too by Scott himself, who has taken the unique approach of reiterating that he and North would "keep analysing'' whether he should coach again in 2018.
Scott on Friday night said he makes no apologies for his realistic approach, adding if he is to "preach team-first" attitudes that he must be "setting the example from the top".
"I've tried to be as honest and upfront with everyone as I possibly can," Scott told SEN on Friday night.
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 20 PREVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
"I think it's a little unusual that a coach would say, 'look at the end of the year we'll sit down and assess what's best for the football club'. My view is that that's what everyone should do.
"I'm trying to set an example for our players that we really want to build a really solid foundation for our club and we've got to do what's right for the football club - and that includes me.
"So if that means that I'm the best person to coach the club going forward then that's what will happen. But if the club decides 'hey look we think we can do better' then that's what should happen. That's the same for players as well.
"I'm contracted for next year, so it's a simple equation that if North really want me to continue to coach next year then that's where I'll be ... I've been really clear on that.
"It is a bit perplexing at times to hear the speculation. I understand it, my focus is just making sure we do everything we can to win the next four games and continue to build that foundation."
Asked if he would be happy to sign a long-term extension at North, Scott said: "I'm happy to commit to whatever the club thinks is best. I think it's really important that you sit down and do a really thorough analysis of what's best."
Scott said he was thrilled with the output of his current midfield brigade, including Jack Ziebell, Ben Cunnington and Shaun Higgins, but added that his club needed to add some pace "more than most" other clubs.
The North coach categorically denied a rumour that he was planning a trip to New Zealand after the season to catch up with Dustin Martin's father.
But asked if Martin was in the club's recruiting plans, Scott cheekily replied: "I'd say there are 17 other clubs who could find a spot for him."
Scott also wouldn't be drawn into a war of words with dual premiership coach Mark Thompson, who told Fox Footy's AFL 360 on Wednesday that Scott had done "an average job at an average club".
"We've certainly been really pleased with the development of our young players. That's not to say it's been a 2017 thing. We've worked really hard through 2014, 2015, 2016 developing players," Scott said.
"Our development guys were doing a hell of a lot of work behind the scenes to get a guy like Braydon Preuss to come in and look like an AFL player when he made his debut."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Ziebell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braydon Preuss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 20 PREVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Cunnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
