<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425418083639049</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/good-weekend/frank-robson-better-to-live-fast-and-furious-than-slow-and-safe--isnt-it-20170802-gxnoi3.html</url>
  <title>Frank Robson: better to live fast and furious than slow and safe - isn't it?</title>
  <content>
On a bedside computer screen in the cardiac catheter laboratory, an orb-shaped network of dark arteries jumps and twitches against a pale, amorphous background. My eye seizes upon a single vein and tries to follow it through the twitching object, which looks a bit like a jellyfish space monster from an early series of Doctor Who. But there are so many arterial twists and turns that my eye blurs and then arbitrarily closes, as though this peek inside my own heart has already contravened some immutable law.
"Nice music," offers one of the technicians, whose shrouded, rustling forms surround me in the gloom. "Thanks," I say, having chosen the accompaniment for my angiogram - Mark Knopfler's soundtrack from Local Hero - only minutes earlier at the invitation of one of the nurses. (Hmmm, I pondered when the offer was made, what would go well with having radioactive dye shot into your heart?)Photo: Russell Shakespeare
I'd forgotten just how appropriate my choice was. As someone covers me with an X-ray blanket, Knopfler's insistent, spiralling guitar pieces give way temporarily to his vocal with fellow Brit Gerry Rafferty, the two of them complaining piteously, "Why can't it be alright?/ Why can't I sleep at night?/ ... Why must there be this price to pay? ... That's the way it always starts/Sitting here and waiting on the beating of my heart."
As much as I love the sound, the lyrics have a trapped, panicky feel that seems to mock the new, medically responsible me. Until last year, when The Thing happened that set me on this fresh course, I was a defiant, pack-a-day smoker, given to rounding off my intake of bracing carcinogens with several uplifting after-dinner joints. It was a pattern I'd followed for decades, interspersed with bouts of high-risk exercise and acts of childish defiance that amounted to spitting repeatedly in the face of death. (I would, for example, shred the luridly illustrated health warnings on cigarette packets and use them as filters for joints.)Photo: Panther Media GmbH / Alamy Stock Photo
As I revealed authoritatively in a piece for this magazine about turning  I was a "showy arsehole" and a prime candidate for sudden death: "I know these things, yet cannot or will not change. I don't want to stay alive just to keep breathing. I don't want to wear soft clothing, or creep about clutching at my partner's arm with a trembling claw, or worry about things that might reduce my 'quality of life'."
Yeah, well ... The Thing that happened put paid to all that bullshit. I'll get to what it was soon enough, but what it led to was the emergence of the High Coronary Calcium Score, followed by Total Capitulation and the End of All Smoking, followed by Great Sadness and Nostalgia, followed by Shortness of Breath and the Emergency Ward, followed by the Twitching Jellyfish Angiogram and Intimations of Crushing Doom. Oh, and the Sad F...ing E-Cigarette, whose cloying vapours cling to me now like white feathers to a coward. 

I know when the "end" begins. It is late in 2009, and my partner Leisa Scott and I are on the final day of a coastal sailing adventure that has lasted almost three years. As we near our home port of Mooloolaba on Queensland's Sunshine Coast, the north-easterly we've ridden south from Fraser Island picks up to 30 knots, and our old trimaran surfs down following swells with just a small patch of headsail flying.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

It's a hot, bright afternoon when we and everything around us - clouds, waves, leaping fish, diving birds - seem to be part of the same chaotic, irresistible surge of movement from north to south. Which is why, instead of starting the diesel and motoring responsibly into Mooloolaba, we opt to blast in under sail. People gape from the parallel rock walls that form the port's entrance as we shoot silently through with that wild wind behind us, too distracted to realise this is the closing scene.
And then, in a twinkling, we are around the corner and becalmed near a marina, where a group of old guys sits on a pontoon drinking beer and playing with toy boats. It is like being catapulted from one world into another; there's no time for winding down, or talking about the end of our fabulous adventure. One minute we are out there, living it, the next we aren't. For me, it has felt pretty much that way ever since.
I guess I could have kept on sailing, or found some new diversion. Somehow, though, nothing else seems to hold the same appeal. Being younger and more committed to her career, Leisa soon readjusts to life ashore. But living on a sailboat had been a dream of mine since childhood, and when the experience was coming to a close I felt the way I often do during the last stages of a holiday - oddly paralysed, as though there wasn't enough time left to do anything but wait for things to end.
Except this time I seem to have conflated holidays with life itself. Not coincidentally, I've also reached the age bracket when - according to cigarette packets and other experts - the wages of reckless living start to rain down hard, killing the fortunate quickly and condemning others to years as wheezing liabilities on the public purse.
There seems no reason why I should be excused from these statistical outcomes, which means - as I noted in my - "five or 10 years should see me out". (Behind the bravado, of course, I've been fervently hoping I possess the same longevity gene as my father, who smoked all his life and died of old age at 93.) I fag on for another half-decade while undergoing routine colonoscopies (thumbs up!), much-feared chest X-rays (all clear!), and various blood tests in search of trouble ahead.
No matter what position I assume in bed, each breath feels less than automatic, as though it mightn't necessarily lead to another breath in that way we come to expect.

But trouble rarely comes from the direction you're watching. Who could have guessed, for example, that the first sign of a dickie heart would be a bent dick?
When this condition first presents itself early in 2016, I think I'm hallucinating. "What the f...!" I scream. "I seem to have developed a dorsal chordee of about 30 degrees!" (Actually, that's how a urologist describes it soon afterwards when diagnosing Peyronie's disease of the penis. Named for the French surgeon who identified it, Peyronie's curvature is produced by scar tissue forming in the fibrous covering of the erectile bodies of the penis.)
My real reaction at the time of discovery, after prolonged cursing, is to embrace the idea that things could be worse. Leisa tries to play along. "Look at these ones!" she gasps, summoning online images of penises with 90-degree bends, or deformities so severe they look like pistols whose barrels have somehow doubled back and drawn a bead on their owners. Then we read that while some cases improve spontaneously over time, and some stay the same, others get worse. There's no effective treatment, and surgical straightening (fraught by risks of diminished size) is deemed a last resort. How perfectly dispiriting! Three cheers for the ageing process!
But wait... there's worse to come. At the urology clinic (where a drunk in the waiting room keeps leaning across to recommend "Asian renta-pussy" for all penile ailments), the specialist warns that because Peyronie's can be an indicator of heart disease, I should stop worrying about cocks turning into Glocks and get myself a coronary calcium scan. Caught up in the horror now, like a rat on a treadmill, I race to comply.
The heart scan procedure takes just 30 minutes; a couple of days later, I'm at my first ever appointment with a cardiologist, who explains that my whopping calcium score of 940 (near the top of the second-highest category!) means the artery walls in my heart are carrying a heavy calcium build-up, and that in medical terms I am already suffering coronary artery disease.
Which, as America's Beast with Tiny Hands might tweet, is really, really bad! But at my next appointment I have two electrocardiograms (one while exercising) that show my heart is functioning normally for my age, and that because the plaque is evenly distributed I actually have "low probability of significant obstructive coronary artery disease". The doctor urges me to quit smoking, as they always do, yet doesn't need to see me again for two years. Which is really, really good!
So, taking stock: I've gone from A-OK to having a bent dick and sticky plaque shit inside my heart, yet despite these setbacks I can still have sex, and walk a dog hard for at least an hour, although not at the same time. It's probably true that neither setback will be improved by continued smoking, but would quitting really make any difference in someone my age? Or would it just mean dying irritable? (Especially now that I'm permanently on low-dose aspirin for blood fluidity and statins for lowering cholesterol.)
For a couple of weeks, puffing pensively, I can't make up my mind. Then Leisa, who smokes only at home and began the latest of her many attempts to quit a week earlier, comes in from a rough day at work, sees me smoking and insists on having one. For some reason, although the pattern is well established, it's the first time I recognise myself as a sinister enabler whose addiction could easily spare me and kill her. ("Enabler!" sneers the Former Me. "Since when do we use words like that?")
We have our last cigarettes together a fortnight later, the day before flying to New York for a holiday. It is a testing week: smashed by a travel virus yet desperate for cigarettes and unable to sleep, I roam alone through Manhattan's endless canyons in the early hours, sucking so hard on my new e-cigarette that blisters rise on the end of my tongue. Every so often, if enough nicotine-infused vapour can be generated and dragged violently to the back of the throat, there's a sensation fleetingly reminiscent of smoking. (E-cigarettes are like evil ghosts imitating lost lovers; I'm still using one, and probably couldn't have quit without it, yet each time I bring it to my lips its awful fraudulence is revealed anew.)

According to Robson, 'E-cigarettes are like evil ghosts imitating lost lovers.' Photo: Russell Shakespeare

On the sleepless streets of the decaying city, real smokers watch my angry vapour trails with amusement. In this period of initial withdrawal everything seems acutely annoying or deeply disappointing, including my own mottled visage glaring back from shop windows like old Mr Burns from The Simpsons.
The city's landmarks spark memories of being here decades earlier: a group of us tumbling from bar to bar through snowdrifts; taking turns to score dime bags from black kids in dark alleys; discussing my "vast Antipodean" second novel (which never quite got finished) with studious young editors at W.W. Norton; being "lost" for 48 hours after a frenzied party in a jazz cellar... and all the while back then the whole world turning on, lighting up, smoking, smoking, smoking.
Sniggering, the old geezer I become buys an obscenely lifelike pull-on plastic Trump head from a 24-hour joke shop and bears it back to the hotel. Poor Leisa wakes to find The Beast with Tiny Hands, an e-fag clamped in its cruel mouth, studying her from a bedside chair while the real Trump, cheered on by the helpless fools who would soon make him president, abuses and threatens Mexicans from a TV screen at the foot of the bed.
Almost a year later, I wake at 4am and can't get back to sleep. Elements of a vivid dream linger, but it's my short, shallow breathing (as though I've suddenly traded lungs with a chain-smoking midget) that's keeping me awake. No matter what position I assume in bed, each breath feels less than automatic, as though it mightn't necessarily lead to another breath in that way we come to expect. Trying to stay calm, I run through possible causes from the official Tax on Past Fun handbook.
Emphysema kicking in? Even when I tore up ciggie packet warnings for filters, I tried to avoid the shiny black and red emphysema ones. But no, a month-old chest X-ray shows all clear on that front.
Asthma? Never a problem in the past, but now that I've given up everything and embraced Mortal Fear it's probably among scores of psychosomatically triggered ailments lining up to jump me.
Anxiety, induced by weird dreams? Only a month earlier, I kicked free of my last long-time prop, cannabis, and began lurching about unaided. A week or so after that I was assailed by graphic dreams: not nightmares, exactly, yet disturbingly detailed and obsessively themed. (In a recurring one, I spend days searching but can't locate a single person I know.) This dream barrage has happened before whenever I've stopped using marijuana for more than a few days; apart from enhancing sleep, dope also masks all conscious memory of dreams.
Which can be a real advantage: the dream I have before waking at 4am is set in the Oval Office, where I'm receiving a shoulder massage from someone behind me with wispy orange hair who seems to have become forever part of my fear of death. Needless to say, I don't get back to sleep. The midget-breathing persists through breakfast, so I check into the emergency department of our local hospital and spend most of the day undergoing heart tests.
"The patient presented with SOB," says my discharge letter, which also notes that I may have "unstable angina". There's nothing to indicate an imminent heart attack or stroke, yet the cardiologist I saw in 2016 books me in for an angiogram in a fortnight's time. The results, he suggests, could indicate how long I have left for this mortal coil.
A few mornings later, while I'm under my desk reasoning with the dog over some socks he's stolen, the shortness of breath returns. Dutifully, as instructed by the last lot of doctors and nurses, I hurry back to the hospital and settle in for another day of being tested for Lurking Death.
In the emergency waiting room, where a plump woman in a wheelchair weeps bitterly over some just-received news, I let a call from my 88-year-old half-sister go to message. Iris lost her husband Keith to heart disease six years ago, and doesn't need to hear about my anxiety over a bit of irregular breathing. Although still in good health, she hates being alone and is less enthusiastic than me about our shared father's so-called longevity gene. Not long ago, Iris left me a message that ended, "I've got an awful feeling I'm going to live a long, long time."
By noon I've progressed to a day-bed in the emergency ward. Like last time, the tests are all showing nothing amiss, and my psychological pendulum - which only hours earlier was registering alarm - has swung back to a bemused contempt for my new-found inclination to jump at shadows. From the neighbouring bed I can hear a man about my age chronicling his ailments to a busy young doctor. It's a long list in the querulous tones of someone who seems to believe the maintenance of his life is the responsibility of "the system", as he keeps calling it. "Yeah, well, I wanted to have the second implant but the system let me down on that as well."
I close my eyes and think about sailing. I think about the surge felt through the body when wind fills a sail and translates it into momentum, and how some people who experience this simple alchemy never stop wanting to feel it again. An elderly yachtswoman we met while cruising lost her husband and sole crew-mate to a stroke at sea. She lashed his body to the deck railing and brought him in to port, but no one could persuade her it was time to sell the yacht and move ashore. "The sensation of sailing is curative," she told us. "I can feel it keeping me alive." (Although, as Leisa later pointed out, it didn't work too well for her hubby.)

Frank Robson wearing the Donald Trump mask he bought in a 24-hour New York City joke shop while pining for cigarettes. Photo: Courtesy of Frank Robson

On the night before my angiogram, free of such distractions as joint-rolling and chocolate consumption, I devote 30 deeply satisfying minutes to studying the hospital's booklet about the operation. "Once your procedure is complete, you will be taken to recovery [where] a nurse will press firmly on your groin for 10 minutes," it promises in closing. (It turns out that this blood stemming process occurs only if a catheter is introduced via the femoral artery.) I complete my thrill-a-minute evening by packing, as instructed, a small bag in case doctors need to place permanent stents (small metal tubes) to aid blood flow in restricted heart arteries during the angiogram, which would mean an overnight stay.
It's still dark when Leisa drops me at admissions next morning. Paperwork done, I'm the first day patient waiting when the cardiac catheter laboratory doors open at 7am. Soon, shaved at wrist and groin, my clothing replaced by a floppy green loincloth, I'm attached to a saline drip and left to sprawl in an antique recliner until the angiogram begins. It occurs to me that this is the point where I should be nervously regretting the way I've lived. But I don't. I don't regret the truckloads of cigarettes, or the cascading mountains of dope, or the rivers of grog, or the fatty indulgences and sugary treats, because I love the life I've lived in a way I know I wouldn't had "moderation" played a bigger role.
Smoking, especially, has been part of my idea of who I am for half a century, and parting with it has been the hardest element of coming to terms with what remains of being alive.
"Whether I actually smoke or not, my personality is a smoker's personality," suggests German writer Gregor Hens in his post-smoking memoir, Nicotine. Perhaps only those of us who have truly embraced this wicked, ugly, damaging and infinitely soothing habit can see the truth of such a declaration. Why do otherwise sane people keep smoking despite the risks? Addiction has a role, but in many cases it's more because they've somehow come to see being a smoker - like having blue eyes, or curly hair - as part of who they are.
For a long time, I truly believed I would smoke until I died; that smoking and I would end it together in a fiery suicide pact at around this time. Now, of course, 65 doesn't seem quite so old, and living more sedately seems preferable to dying suddenly on a public street with a shocked stranger looking into my eyes. And given that I have no belief in any existence beyond this, it makes perfect sense to "rage against the dying of the light" - as the mercurial Dylan Thomas put it before drinking himself to death at 39.
But there are limits. Watching the weary, resigned faces of several veteran heart patients in nearby recliners, I decide this angiogram will be as far as I go. No more pursuing symptoms down rabbit holes: if I'm lucky, and my heart doesn't need stents or surgery, I will accept my bouts of midget-breath as general wear and tear and get on with things.
Once I'm stretched out in the operating room, the procedure happens quickly. With Knopfler marking time, a plastic sheath is introduced to an artery in the right wrist, and a catheter fed through the sheath to the coronary artery. Contrast dye is then injected through the catheter to help identify any narrowing within the heart's arterial network, or scarring or damage to the heart's main pumping chamber, the left ventricle. Incredibly, there is no pain as these outrages occur, just a chill so pervasive it feels like ice in the blood. After 15 minutes the angiogram itself is complete. The surgeon tells me there is "minor disease" affecting my left main coronary artery, but nothing requiring stents and nothing to explain my occasional shortness of breath.
Now, though, he wants to extend a "pressure wire" into the heart's less accessible right side, where he suspects there may be a hidden blockage. This involves introducing a chemical to the blood that causes the heart to react as though under great physical stress; the ensuing blood pressure reading within the heart will determine whether blockages exist. "The baseline is one," explains the surgeon. "If your reading under pressure falls to 0.80 or lower over four minutes you will need stents. If it's higher, no stents." 
A nurse warns that the heart-stimulating chemical will feel "horrible" but wear off quickly. The discomfort in my chest begins almost immediately, soon becoming a sickening, crushing sensation that makes me gasp like a beached fish.
"Short breaths, short breaths!" cautions the nurse.
"Point 99," calls whoever's monitoring heart pressure. "Point 97... point 94."
I'm grateful for the call, despite fearing how low it might get, because it's some sort of distraction from what now feels like everything I've ever heard about the "wrenching, grinding" effect of heart attacks.
"Oh, Jesus!" I groan, and a hand grips my shoulder.
"Two minutes," someone announces.
"Point 93... point 92."
"Three minutes."
"Point 91... point 91..."
"Four minutes." "Point 91... point 91." 
And that's it: the pressure falls no lower.
"We're done!" someone calls, and almost instantly the suffocating feeling lifts, replaced by sweet, easy breathing. The surgeon says there is some disease in my right coronary artery but it's not functionally "significant". I won't need stents or surgery. But I will need to keep taking low-dose aspirin and cholesterol lowering medication for as long as I live, along with a high-fibre diet and a heart-specific exercise regimen.
"But no smoking?" I venture, just to be sure.
"Definitely not!" the doctor growls.
I can live with that, I joke to myself.
When the nurses start ripping sticky electrodes from my chest hair, I close my eyes and think of sailing - not past sailing, but the sailing I might do in the future, now that it seems the holiday may not be over after all. Who knows, there may even be time to leave the coast and cross an ocean or two. I visualise myself, e-cigarette jutting manfully, diving from the mast into a Tahitian lagoon, or rounding Cape Horn with ice in my beard.
Minutes later, as they wheel me out to the recovery area wrapped in a freshly-warmed blanket, Knopfler's intermittent guitar - mute for some time - springs suddenly into one of its terraced ascents, rising like a bird on a thermal until it reaches heights I don't remember hearing before.Frank Robson's musings from 2011 on turning 60 reveal a man who still thought he was bulletproof.

• " 'I'd rather die while I'm living than live while I'm dead,' boasts the ubiquitous Jimmy Buffett. It has suited me to live by such bold credos." 
• "The real pathos of ageing isn't the inevitability of death, but the long, slow shuffle into an alien landscape."
• "Am I afraid of dying? Instinctively, of course ... but in theory the idea of going to sleep forever doesn't sound too bad." 
• "In the home straight, death becomes the ultimate bureaucrat: it wants you to fear it, to plead and pray and grovel and maybe offer a bribe in return for a little more time." 
• "Among the worst ways to go, it seems to me, would be in some sort of drawn-out struggle where survival hovers just beyond reach."
• "Why is everybody so ritualistically positive? Don't they know that in a few short years they're all going to f...ing die!"

A note from The SMH and The Age editors: Get the best weekend articles delivered straight to your inbox each Friday, with our Weekend Insight newsletter, available exclusively to subscribers. Sign up here: , 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Buffett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregor Hens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leisa</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther Media GmbH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Hero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knopfler</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lurking Death</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mortal Fear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Shakespeare</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>End of All</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Horn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W.W. Norton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Former I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hmmm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leisa Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtesy of Frank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tahitian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Past Fun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitching Jellyfish Angiogram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shortness of Breath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Sadness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekend Insight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intimations of Crushing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alamy Stock Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Robson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiny Hands</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit Gerry Rafferty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America's Beast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Total Capitulation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peyronie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E-cigarettes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Coronary Calcium Score</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Knopfler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sad F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
