<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425070191281944</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4835224/weather-warning-wild-winds-to-whack-the-illawarra-south-coast/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Weather warning: Wild winds to whack the Illawarra, South Coast</title>
  <content>
File photo. Strong winds whip up sand on Shellharbour beach in August 2015. Picture: Sylvia Liber

Illawarra and South Coast residents have been told to batten down the hatches with a vigorous cold front set to whip up wild winds this weekend. 

The front is expected to pass over southeastern parts of NSW during Saturday morning, bringing with it strong northwest to southwesterly winds that have the potential to reach damaging strength.
The Bureau of Meteorology on Friday afternoon issued a severe weather warning for the Illawarra and parts of the South Coast. 
The bureau says damaging winds averaging 60 to 65km/h, with peak gusts in excess of 90km/h, are possible locally from early Saturday morning until mid-afternoon over the southern and central ranges.

The damaging winds are due to extend to the coast in the Illawarra and in northern parts of the South Coast.

"The most likely time for these gusts to occur is late Saturday morning," the warning said. 
Winds are expected to ease later in the day.
At sea, a strong wind warning has been issued for Illawarra and Batemans coastal waters on Saturday.
For those heading to the snow, blizzards are possible from early Saturday morning until late afternoon over the higher parts of the Snowy Mountains. 
The National Parks Service of NSW has advised people to consider postponing back country travel until conditions improve.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snowy Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Parks Service of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
