<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425160385596678</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/sensitive-details-of-vulnerable-children-in-care-released-in-department-bungle-20170804-gxp6qd.html</url>
  <title>Sensitive details of vulnerable children in care released in department bungle</title>
  <content>
The personal details of children in care, including whether they were sexually active, was accidentally sent to the mother of one of the children in a troubling information breach.
A spreadsheet was emailed to the mother outlining the name, birthdate, location, and specific concerns and alerts relating to all children in the care of a large service provider in a regional Victorian city.Photo: Angela Wylie
A 13-year-old boy is listed as being on bail and displaying sexualised behaviours, a 15-year-old girl who has issues with self-harm, substance abuse, and absconding is "out with the boyfriend" and "will not be returning tonight", and a 14-year-old boy is noted as needing help with "self-care" and being verbally abusive and physically threatening.
The spreadsheet appears to be a handover document which was meant to have been sent to an overnight supervisor.
It contains notes about when some children are expected home, or whether they are likely to contact staff to be picked up.
There are concerning levels of detail about some children.

"If staff contact to request permission to conduct a room search or laptop/USB search, given concerns in regards to inappropriate sexual material, permission to be granted," the alert for a 15-year-old boy reads.
The document also shows that a 17-year-old girl who is only three months from turning 18 and being released from residential care was considered to be such a high risk of attempting suicide that staff had to call triple zero immediately if she absconded.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

A 16-year-old boy on parole is listed as out, and that he will "contact staff to be picked up later on tonight".

While the locations listed only mention the name of the housing unit where the children are being held, and not the address of the unit, there is enough detail for it to be found.
Details of the 2015 breach emerged as the mother shared with Fairfax Media her experiences of dealing with the Department of Health and Human Services and child protection services since her daughter was taken into care four years ago.
She agreed to share her concerns now that her daughter has turned 18 and left the system.
The heart-wrenching decision to turn her daughter over to child protection came after a violent incident at home, one of a  of family violence complaints being made by parents against their children.
It had troubling consequences the mother could have never imagined, such as her daughter racking up seven criminal charges within six months of leaving home, being moved hundreds of kilometres away, to a home and situation she appeared to thrive in, but then being moved back again without her parents being told, and the acceptance and facilitation by her daughter's carers of two relationships her daughter had with older men.
The first of these boyfriends, a 17-year-old who her then 15-year-old daughter had regularly been allowed by care agencies to stay with in a local hotel, ended when he was charged within days of his 18th birthday with child sex offences because of the relationship.
"Why was she left worse off than when she went in?" the mother said.
"And is this what happens to every child in care?"
She is a particularly strong advocate for the establishment of a facility which allows DHHS to monitor children for the first few weeks of them being taken into care, before they are moved into residential homes. 
This would allow them to better understand how they interact with others, their risks and their needs, particularly in relation to education.
The state government is looking at new ways to divert children away from residential care, including by better supporting their parents.
Targeted care packages, funded with $62 million over four years, aim to help transition children from residential care to better arrangements.
And a $5.6 million, two-year trial announced last October will provide professional foster carers to at least 28 children, helping them to transition from or avoid entering care.
A department spokesman said the information breach was not formally reported at the time, although the mother claims she told two department employees within months of it occurring.
The department is now working with the service provider to address the incident.
"Any claim of a privacy breach is taken very seriously ... we will work to ensure there has been no negative impact on the young people involved."
In July last year, Minister for Families and Children, Jenny Mikakos, commissioned an independent review of a sample of child protection privacy incidents over a five-year period.
The department accepted its seven recommendations, and has since updated the child protection manual to ensure staff are clear about their roles and procedures in relation to privacy, changed IT systems to remove the automatic population of some personal details, and formally reviewed the department's privacy functions.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Mikakos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Wylie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
