<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425379428932577</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/phoenix-to-go-retro-in-honour-of-milestone/3209070/</url>
  <title>Phoenix to go retro in honour of milestone</title>
  <content>
BASKETBALL: The Clippers' 1997 CBA national title remains one of the biggest sporting achievements for the Sunshine Coast, and 20 years on the Phoenix will honour the milestone with a blast from the past.

The Phoenix men's and women's teams will don retro jerseys from the Clippers triumphant year, for clashes against Townsville teams on Saturday.

It will be the club's final games of the season in the Queensland Basketball League.

Along with the retro outfit, there will be a reunion of the 1997 squad from 11am at the Clippers Stadium.

The Clippers was the first Queensland club to win a national title and were based at Maroochydore.

Maroochydore are also known as the Clippers and form part of the Phoenix with Caloundra and Noosa.

Phoenix men's coach Brayden Heslehurst said it was important to reflect on the milestone.

"Even though we are called Phoenix, we are a merger of all the clubs and we want to recognise that history and really celebrate the past of each," he said.

Heslehurst hoped to mark the 20th anniversary with a win against the Heat.

He considered Townsville a dark-horse to win the competition but was still confident the Phoenix could claim victory.

"It's a tough challenge but we've showed throughout the season, with so many single digit losses, that we can take it up to anyone and this week will hopefully be no different," he said.

"We want to play the same basketball we did last week. It was the best ball movement and style of basketball we've played all year."

University of the Sunshine Coast Rip City men's and women's teams were due to face Townsville at Sippy Downs on Friday night before travelling to Brisbane to take on the Capitals in games on Saturday.

Avoid the area if you can with significant delays reported
Coast's newest eatery opens bringing Italian to the beach
Teen spends big on mum's partner's credit card
Coast researchers welcome govt inspection of white spot studies
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast Rip City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Basketball League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clippers Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heslehurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clippers' 1997 CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brayden Heslehurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clippers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
