<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424894097619147</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/leaders/the-refugees-getting-under-donald-trumps-skin/news-story/60049f62a922dd460bea4f0fd9af65f2</url>
  <title>The refugees getting under Donald Trump's skin</title>
  <content>
Refugee deal makes me look bad: Trump
3:54

The infamous January phone call between US President Donald Trump and Malcolm Turnbull has been leaked.

August 4th 2017
9 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Imran Mohammad has been living on Manus Island for about four years. Picture: Matthew Abbott

Share

WHEN Imran Mohammad read the transcript of two of the most powerful leaders in the world talking about him as just a "product", he could only do one thing - cry.
The Rohingya refugee from Myanmar was first taken to Manus Island about four years ago at the age of 19. He is one of almost 2000 refugees who have been languishing in island detention after trying to enter Australia by boat.
To US President Donald Trump these people are unwanted. In a  of a conversation Mr Trump had with Australia's Prime Minister, he was very clear he did not want to honour a "stupid deal" made by his predecessor Barack Obama to consider them for resettlement in America.
Mr Trump complained about having to take "2000 people that Australia does not want".
And he is right. Many of these people have been sitting in camps in Nauru and Manus Island for up to four years while Australia figures out what to do with them.
They come from countries including Iran, Myanmar, Afghanistan, Pakistan, Darfur and Sri Lanka.
Despite 1781 of them being assessed as refugees by the governments of Nauru and Manus Island, they will not be allowed to live in Australia.
As Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull informed Mr Trump: "We know exactly who they are. They have been on Nauru or Manus for over three years and the only reason we cannot let them into Australia is because of our commitment to not allow people to come by boat".
The candid conversation about the future of these 2000 refugees has shone a spotlight on these largely forgotten people.

"I just cried as I was reading the transcripts of the most two powerful leaders in this world," Mr Mohammad said in remarks provided to news.com.au. "Their words made me feel like I am just a product to them and I can be traded for anything.
"I am just a human being and there is no need to play with my life.
"All I want is to respect and love others and be loved and respected in return. All I need is a sense of belonging to a safe country so that I can live a life that every human deserves."
Human Rights Law Centre legal advocacy director Daniel Webb, who has visited Manus Island three times, told news.com.au that the overwhelming majority had been assessed as refugees who had fled serious persecution overseas.
"We're talking about 2000 innocent people across Manus and Nauru, including 169 children, people of different ages and from different parts of the world with different stories to tell," he said.

Imran Mohammad has been living on Manus Island for about four years. Picture: Matthew AbbottSource:Supplied
"What they have in common is they've had four years of their lives ripped away from them. The only thing they want, the only thing they've ever wanted, is to a chance to build a life in freedom and safety."
Many of the people have been living in camps for four years and Mr Webb said US deal had brought the refugees hope and optimism for the first time in years. However, those hopes had now been dashed.
"The transcript shows that Malcolm Turnbull was clearly more concerned with appearances than with reality," he said.
During the phone conversation, Mr Turnbull made it clear that the US was under no obligation to accept any refugees, and the former White House spokesman Sean Spicer later confirmed the refugees would be.
There has also been speculation the US would take Australia's refugees in exchange for Australia taking .
"The US deal has always been shrouded in uncertainty and full of holes," Mr Webb said.
"There's never been any information, in terms of numbers, what timeframe, and the government never had a responsible and humane plan for the people left behind.
"Now the plan is looking shakier than ever."
Mr Spicer told reporters that the deal specifically dealt with 1250 people, although Mr Trump mentions "2000 people" in his phone call.
In defending the deal, Mr Turnbull tells the President: "It does not oblige you to take one person that you do not want".
There's no indication of what would happen to those who failed to pass the vetting process.
The Australian Government has already announced the detention centre on Manus Island, which currently houses about 850 men, will be closed on October 31.
Authorities have been encouraging the men to move into town but refugees say it's not safe.
Last week refugees said , with one 27-year-old Sudanese refugee cut on his leg by a machete.
There have been  as authorities try to lock the gates and clear one of the accommodation compounds.
"The Australian Government is bulldozing the Manus facility but the men trapped inside it have nowhere safe to go," Mr Webb said.
"After four years of fear, violence and suffering, they deserve a chance at building a life in safety - not to be squeezed into a place where they are terrified or unsafe."

Two injured Afghan refugees (right and second left) from the Manus Island detention centre being helped after allegedly being attacked by a group of Papua New Guinean men while out on a day release. Picture: Matthew Abbott/GetUp/AFPSource:AFP

Standoff as Manus Island Refugees Block Police From Entering Compound. Credit - Anonymous via Storyful
0:45

Protests inside the Manus Island Regional Processing Centre escalated on August 4 when refugees blocked police from entering the Foxtrot compound. Papua New Guinea (PNG) police had earlier shut the gates barring refugees from leaving Foxtrot compound, according to activists from the Refugee Action Collective. The standoff follows protests after the authorities cut off the water and power supply to the compound. A resident of Foxtrot Compound told Storyful they were able to jury rig a power connection by tapping into the supply from the neighboring Mike compound. Refugees said that the PNG police, with the assistance of PNG immigration and Wilson Security, tried to enter the Foxtrot block to turn off the utilities again. At time of writing, the refugees and PNG authorities and security were standing off at the the gate connecting Foxtrot and Mike. Refugees identified the man seen in the video above wearing a yellow shirt as being from PNG Immigration. PNG officials had earlier announced that the Foxtrot compound would be demolished and refugees needed to move to Mike, Oscar, Delta blocks or to new accommodation at East Lorengau. The refugees detained on Manus Island are being faced with moving to a new transit centre, settling on Manus, or returning home after Australian and the PNG government agreed to the closure of the processing facility earlier this year. The facility's compounds are due to be demolished and the centre closed by end of October. The United States had agreed to take at least 1,250 refugees currently detained on Manus and Nauru but comments from US President Donald Trump to Australian Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull have cast uncertainty over the Obama-era deal. Refugees on Manus have voiced fears for their safety following violent robberies and attacks on several refugees who have moved to the East Lorengau transit centre. The Department of Immigration and Border Protection in Australia have not responded to requests for more information. Credit: Anonymous via Storyful

August 4th 2017
3 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama-era</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rights Law Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island Regional Processing Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myanmar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohingya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Webb</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Abbott/GetUp/AFPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew AbbottSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imran Mohammad</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island Refugees Block Police From Entering Compound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtrot Compound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-8.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mohammad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darfur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Lorengau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson Security</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sudanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Refugee Action Collective</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
