<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425413788671646</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/cyclist-seriously-injured-in-inglewood/news-story/2908d6f5c9bb5a03aac8d8f0158959ec</url>
  <title>Cyclist hit by truck in Inglewood</title>
  <content>
A CYCLIST has been rushed to hospital after being hit by a truck in Inglewood.
The male cyclist was knocked from his bike at the Walter Road West and Dundas Road intersection shortly after 4pm.
Emergency crews have closed the road outside the Mount Lawley Golf Club.
The cyclist was trapped underneath the truck for a short period of time, before being freed by fire crews and treated by paramedics at the scene.
The man was then rushed to Royal Perth Hospital, with the extent of his injuries currently unclear.
Earlier on Friday, a man aged in his 70s was rushed to hospital after a crash in Port Kennedy around 11.30am.
Police say the elderly man's vehicle collided with a car that was stopped on the side of Mandurah Road, near the Stakehill Road intersection.
The elderly man was rushed to Royal Perth Hospital in a critical condition.
A second man, who was sitting in the stationary car, was taken to Rockingham Hospital with minor injuries.
And two men have had lucky escapes in two separate crashes in Perth's south.
A man, aged in his 20s, was able to walk from his car after it rolled on the Kwinana Freeway near the Karnup Road exit on Friday afternoon.
And a man, who is aged in his 30s, sustained only minor injuries when his car hit a tree on Eighth Road in Armadale shortly after 2pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eighth Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Lawley Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karnup Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Road West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Perth Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stakehill Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dundas Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockingham Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armadale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwinana Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inglewood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandurah Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
