<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425461033312773</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/brexit-causing-3-million-eu-citizens-to-be-discriminated-against-for-jobs-and-housing-2017-8</url>
  <title>Brexit is already causing EU citizens to be discriminated against for jobs and housing</title>
  <content>
LONDON - EU citizens living in the UK are being increasingly discriminated against when applying for jobs and housing, following the vote to leave the EU, a new report has claimed.

The dossier, compiled by the pressure group 'The 3 million,' documents evidence that EU jobseekers are now being asked for proof of British or Irish citizenship before being considered as potential employees or tenants

The group also report EU citizens having trouble making holiday bookings at travel agencies, as well as rental properties being advertised as being available for British citizens only.

It is illegal for employers to turn down applicants based on nationality or for companies to deny service to a customer because of their nationality.

Brexit secretary David Davis has been urged to clarify what the government's position on EU citizens, after the pressure group compiled allegations that European citizens are facing new hurdles applying for work.

"I am sure that you would agree these reports are a cause for alarm, reflecting uncertainty across the business sector and discrimination experienced by EU nationals," Labour's shadow Brexit minister, Paul Blomfield, wrote in a letter to Davis.

"The lack of detail forthcoming from the government is contributing to this climate of uncertainty and confusion."

Blomfield called on the government to "respond to these instances and provide the certainty that businesses and EU citizens require."

Labour's shadow Brexit secretary Keir Starmer added that this was proof that "uncertainty for EU citizens already leading to discrimination."

Prime Minister Theresa May  to allow EU citizens to stay in the UK post-Brexit in July if they apply for a "residence document", although  such as being able to bring family members over.

A Department for Exiting the EU spokeswoman said: "We are crystal clear that it is completely unacceptable for people to experience discrimination because of their nationality: any such discrimination is illegal."

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Theresa May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blomfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keir Starmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Blomfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
