<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425031536575580</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/united-hockey-raise-breast-cancer-awareness-on-chris-mackinnon-weekend-20170801-gxmrk1.html</url>
  <title>Awareness more important than money ahead of Chris MacKinnon weekend</title>
  <content>
Creating awareness for breast cancer sufferers and their families will far outweigh any figure raised during the Chris MacKinnon memorial round on the weekend, according to United president Nicole Wicks.
Pink will once again descend upon the National Hockey Centre in Lyneham as United host the fifth edition of the event, which raises money for the National Breast Cancer Foundation.Photo: Katherine Griffiths
The day is named in honour of United club stalwart Chris MacKinnon, who lost her battle with breast cancer four years ago.
Numerous clubs will wear commemorative pink jerseys for games, with both United's first and second grade men's and women's teams playing against Central on Saturday.

An inaugural breakfast on Sunday morning will raise funds while there is also an auction and raffle as the club builds on the $40,000 it has raised in the past three years.
"It's grown in awareness rapidly and a lot of people are now more understanding of the whole pink phenomenon around hockey," Wicks said.

"I think to actually put a figure on anything like this is very difficult, it's dependent on what people can afford and I think a lot of it isn't just a financial gift it's also an emotional gift.
"It's about being there for the support of not just the MacKinnons but any other family in both the hockey and wider Canberra community that's been through this type of devastating loss."
Breast cancer is the second most common cancer diagnosed in Australia.
Wicks said the weekend was an opportunity to remember club legend McKinnon and she hoped the awareness it created would grow with each passing year.
"It holds a lot of importance to the club, Chris' involvement and her input over the years was phenomenal," Wicks said.
"I think what she put forward and she gave, all the encouragement and support meant a great deal for the whole community.
"I hope that each year, all of these events that we've put in place actually do grow and I hope that people never forget, not just Chris but the actual importance of the whole event.
"It's very important and I think the more we look at it and the more we encourage it the larger it will get and that's only for the best."
CHRIS MACKINNON WEEKEND - Round 17
Women's Capital League 1: UC v Old Canberrans at 12.15pm, Tuggeranong Vikings v ANU at 1.45pm, United v Central at 3.30pm, St Patricks v Goulburn at 4.45pm. All games at National Hockey Centre, Lyneham on Saturday. North Canberra - bye
Men's Capital League: Tuggeranong Vikings v Old Canberrans at 4.45pm, United v Central at 5pm, St Patricks v Goulburn at 6.30pm. All games at National Hockey Centre, Lyneham on Saturday. 
To donate, visit: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHRIS MACKINNON WEEKEND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Canberrans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital League 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyneham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulburn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MacKinnon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Patrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris MacKinnon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Breast Cancer Foundation.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Hockey Centre</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong Vikings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Wicks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinnon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
