<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425027241608204</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834746/levi-v-luke-in-kiwi-test-case/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Levi v Luke in Kiwi Test case</title>
  <content>
KNIGHTS hooker Danny Levi won't get a better chance to remind the New Zealand rugby league selectors of his capabilities than when he goes head-to-head with Issac Luke at McDonald Jones Stadium on Saturday.

APPRENTICE: Danny Levi
Luke is the incumbent Kiwis dummy-half and a veteran of 37 Tests in the black-and-white jersey.
The 30-year-old shapes as a first-choice selection in New Zealand's squad for the end-of-season World Cup squad, but he is likely to need an understudy.
Brisbane's Kodi Nikorima and Manly's Lewis Brown have been used as stopgap hookers by the Kiwis in the recent past, but Levi is the standout candidate to become Luke's long-term successor.
The 21-year-old from Wellington was a standby player for the Kiwis for last year's Anzac Test, and was considered a good chance for the 2016 Four Nations series until he succumbed to a back injury that required surgery.

MASTER: Issac Luke
Kiwis coach David Kidwell has been monitoring his progress and a strong showing against the Warriors might be enough to secure a World Cup berth.

"For sure, it's definitely been on my mind,'' Levi said.
"At the moment I'm still 100 per cent trying to get a win for the Knights.
"But it's definitely there. It's getting closer to it, so I'm obviously going to be thinking about it, but my main job is to make sure I'm focused just on this game, not trying to do anything incredible."
Levi said he spoke to Kidwell earlier in the season and was advised "to work on a few things", which he has since improved.
His contribution in last week's win against St George Illawarra was described as "outstanding" by Knights coach Nathan Brown.

Levi's countryman, Shaun Kenny-Dowall, will miss the game with a hamstring injury. Chanel Mata'utia will replace him.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanel Mata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Kidwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Kodi Nikorima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Issac Luke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly's Lewis Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Kenny-Dowall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Levi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
