<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425241989976745</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/17/37/inside-story-of-covert-sting-that-unravelled-cocaine-cowboys-international-smuggling-operation</url>
  <title>Inside story of covert sting that unravelled cocaine cowboys</title>
  <content>
The Australian fitness instructor whose arrest helped unravel an alleged international cocaine supply chain is facing jail on a drugs conviction.
Craig Phelps and former Rio Tinto mining executive Bennett Schwartz have pled guilty to charges relating to the investigation, after an undercover police sting unravelled the plot.
Schwartz was last year dragged off a plane in front of his innocent partner by the Australian Federal Police, who charged him with importing a commercial quantity of illicit drugs.
Criminal lawyer Ljupka Subeska said the privately-educated Schwartz had likely been targeted as the "easiest to roll".
"He had a lot to lose - a mining executive, private school, getting married," Ms Subeska told A Current Affair.
"He would have looked like the weakest link."
Schwartz was using his computer to track two large cocaine shipments that were being smuggled from the US in the post.

Related Articles

Police seized his Blackberry Phantom phone and mimicked him to communicate with a man known as "Dr Octopus" - who cannot be named for legal reasons.
A rendezvous was arranged and Dr Octopus allegedly dropped $40,000 in the back of an unmarked police car he thought belonged to Schwartz.
Later, police allege, "Dr Octopus" sent a text message to Schwartz's phone asking him to "pack a sausage maker".
The kitchen appliance was allegedly a reference to 16 kilograms of cocaine, bound for Phelps.
Phelps took possession of the package from undercover investigators at his Newcastle home.
He was arrested and charged, before being freed on $1 million bail.
He has now pleaded guilty, while Schwartz remains behind bars.
Phelps refused to speak to A Current Affair when approached outside court, making use of his fitness background to attempt to run from the cameras.
Police have also alleged that an earlier shipment of cocaine received by Schwartz came from ex-college football star and US drug baron, Owen Hanson.
The Australian-born Hanson, a former star athlete for the University of South Carolina, was arrested in a joint operation by US and Australian law enforcement in 2015.
He pleaded guilty to running an international drug operation and is now serving 20 years in a US prison.
Phelps is facing his own sentencing next year.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-born Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Phelps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Subeska</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett Schwartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schwartz</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ljupka Subeska</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owen Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Current Affair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Octopus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackberry Phantom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phelps</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolinas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
