<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424941342260469</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834699/query-over-lead-soil-solution/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Query over lead soil solution</title>
  <content>
Jim Sullivan in Boolaroo. Picture: Ryan Osland

A decision to allow North Lake Macquarie residents to dispose lead contaminated soil at a Newcastle tip for a reduced fee is "not good enough", according to critics.

The NSW Environment Protection Authority (EPA) has worked with Newcastle City Council to change Summerhill Waste Management Centre's environment protection licence and procedures, to allow it to accept contaminated soil from properties near the former Pasminco lead smelter in Boolaroo.

Residents living within the Lead Abatement Strategy area can start on August 14 to register to deliver the soil, which has been classified as restricted solid waste, by calling 4908 6800.

The government has waived the $138.20 waste levy for affected residents, who will pay $275 per tonne including all fees for disposal.

Boolaroo Action Group spokesperson Jim Sullivan said residents should be able to dispose soil within the Lake Macquarie local government area and for free.

"$275 a tonne plus you'll have a mountain of paper work to comply with regulations - that's extremely onerous for households to find that time and money," Mr Sullivan said.

"Here we have an organisation and a government that licensed and regulated an industry to pollute, knowing they were contaminating people's properties and impacting people's health.

"Now they want the community affected by the contamination to fund its clean up?

"They [not the residents] should be funding 100 per cent of this."
Mr Sullivan said the EPA collected "hundreds of millions of dollars" annually in levies and should put $10 million into a future fund for affected residents.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Sullivan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Sullivan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lead Abatement Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Osland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pasminco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boolaroo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Environment Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boolaroo Action Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summerhill Waste Management Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
