<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425632832007460</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/cricket/australias-selection-quandary-for-bangladesh-tour--who-replaces-mitchell-starc-20170804-gxp5z8.html</url>
  <title>Australia's selection quandary for Bangladesh tour - who replaces Mitchell Starc?</title>
  <content>
While the nervous wait for a new pay deal is over for Australia's cricketers, for a handful of fast bowlers there is now a waiting game of another kind.
National selector Trevor Hohns confirmed 13 squad members when the touring party for Bangladesh was announced on June 16, leaving one fast-bowling berth - a replacement for the rested Mitchell Starc - to be determined through what was essentially a "bowl off" on last month's slated Australia A tour of South Africa.Photo: AP
However, that tour was scrapped because of the battle over the new memorandum of understanding, with an in-principle heads of agreement finally brokered on Thursday.
Now Hohns must decide who will be will be the 14th member, for only three fast bowlers were chosen - Josh Hazlewood, Patrick Cummins and James Pattinson, the latter recently returning from a strong stint in English county cricket.
Jackson Bird, Chadd Sayers, Chris Tremain and Jason Behrendorff were the four quicks chosen for the "A" tour but were denied an opportunity to press for Test selection.
CA said on Friday a final call would likely be made early next week, for the squad is due to go into camp in Darwin next Friday.

One option could be to delay a call and give the four fast bowlers a chance to impress at the camp.
Nathan Lyon, the most successful off-spinner in Australian Test history, and left-arm finger spinner Ashton Agar will lead the tourists' slow-bowling division against a Bangladesh side that shapes as a strong opponent on home soil. Hilton Cartwright was chosen as the batting all-rounder who can provide medium-pace while Glenn Maxwell, also a batting all-rounder, can provide off-spin, although skipper Steve Smith has not been keen to use him with the ball.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Australia will need to quickly counter their issues on the subcontinent, for the Tigers, despite being the ninth-ranked nation, have recently had drawn series at home against South Africa and England and had a breakthrough win against Sri Lanka in Colombo in March in what was the country's 100th Test. Their previous victories on foreign soil since being granted Test status in 2000 were against Zimbabwe and the West Indies.
They were ready to head into a pre-series camp on Saturday, and will soon have former Australian leg-spinner Stuart MacGill to provide advice. MacGill, who recently settled an injury claim against CA, will be the Tigers' spin-bowling coach for three months, according to head coach Chandika Hathurusingha.
Starc returned home midway through the Test tour of India in March with a fractured foot but was able to resume in the Champions Trophy tournament in England. However, it emerged after that trip that his foot had not healed properly and, with a home Ashes campaign approaching, it was best he again rest.
CA has completed a detailed security inspection in Bangladesh, with players - due to arrive on August 18 - and the travelling media to be in a special convoy from hotels to venues, as England had last year.
The series will go ahead with the finer details of the MOU to be thrashed out. Players were to vote on the in-principle agreement on Friday, with full support set to be granted.
One point of debate between CA and the Australian Cricketers Association will be what should happen to the $3 million in player wages that were docked from July 1 when the old MOU expired. CA was to direct this money to grassroots cricket. A backflip from CA has meant the players will be back paid, sparking questions as to whether there should be a donation to grassroots - one of the key battlegrounds through the industrial-relations spat.
The ACA says it has also protected the "window" allowing players to annually participate in the lucrative Indian Premier League in April and May, although CA says this fixturing has nothing to do with the game's governing body. Rather, it's solely the responsibility of the Board of Control for Cricket in India.
CA confirmed on Friday that the women's Ashes series, a multi-format, points-based system, would begin on October 22 in Brisbane, with two one-day internationals in Coffs Harbour on October 26 and 29. The series also features a day-night Test at North Sydney Oval from November 9 and three Twenty20s, in North Sydney (November 17) and Canberra (November 19 and 21).
The availability of Australian captain Meg Lanning, nursing a chronic shoulder injury, will be determined when she returns home this month.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Bird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashton Agar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Cummins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Indies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MacGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pattinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hohns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Tremain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Board of Control</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Starc</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Behrendorff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hazlewood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg Lanning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadd Sayers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart MacGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zimbabwe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chandika Hathurusingha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilton Cartwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Hohns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
