<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425718731355123</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/20/01/young-boy-awaiting-liver-transplant-meets-sporting-heroes</url>
  <title>Archer's surprise: Young boy on waiting list for liver transplant meets his sporting heroes</title>
  <content>
If football is a game built on courage, then the Western Bulldogs have been given a reminder of some real courage.
Five-year-old Archer Irwin is on the waiting list for a liver transplant after suffering chronic liver failure for almost his entire life.
An avid fan of the reigning premiers, Archer's favourite player is Marcus Bontempelli, and today his journey to the Whitten Oval was rewarded with a special surprise.
As part of the AFL's promotion of 'Donatelife Week', Archer will be flown up to Brisbane to be the club's mascot for Saturday's match against the Lions.
He'll not only spend time with his idol but he will also run out on the ground with the team.
The normally chatty young fan was lost for words after the presentation but soon looked forward to "playing footy with the big boys and running through the big banner".
For mum Nikki, the weekend comes as a moment's relief from her son's lifelong struggle.

Related Articles

"I wasn't expecting to feel so emotional," Mrs Irwin said.
"There'll be plenty of tissues watching him come out. It's very rare we get to see him so happy and carefree."
Indeed, Archer's big moment accompanies a very important message.
Just one third of Australians are registered organ donors despite more than 60 percent declaring they'd be willing to donate.
As such, there are currently around 1400 people waiting for a transplant in Australia.
According to Mr Bontempelli, awareness is the key to changing that statistic.
"The thing is making people aware of the greatness it can create for others, particularly someone as young as Archer," he said.
"Who knows what it could mean for many people and families, so it's a great message that we all probably need to be a bit more aware of."
Mr Bontempelli's sentiments were echoed by Mrs Irwin who admits the past few years have been a struggle, with Archer in and out of hospital on several occasions, often being very ill.
"Having a partnership with the AFL, with such amazing supporter bases can create so much more awareness and hopefully encourage people to have the most important conversation with their family," she said. 
That conversation is about organ donation, given in Australia a person's next of kin can overturn their wishes.
Registering is as simple as filling in a form online.
While a transplant might be some way down the track for young Archer, more immediately is that flight to Brisbane.
Jetting off from Melbourne Airport, there was little chance of Archer parting with his new Bulldogs jumper.
For players like Mr Bontempelli, that might be the most rewarding part of their support.
"It's great to have him along to do something small for him in a way that probably means so much to him," he said.
"It is sort of a goosebumps moment when you get young kids coming out and the way they react being close to you.
"We love, especially in Archer's situation, being able to put a smile on his face."
For more information on Donatelife week, or if you wish to become a registered organ donor, head to the .
 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DonateLife</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DonateLife Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitten Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archer Irwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archers</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Irwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bontempelli</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
