<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424902687553924</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/west-coast-eagles/west-coast-coach-adam-simpson-plays-down-priddis-rift-talk-20170804-gxpq4o.html</url>
  <title>West Coast coach Adam Simpson plays down Priddis rift talk</title>
  <content>
West Coast coach Adam Simpson has urged people to move on from the rift rumours involving himself and Matt Priddis, saying it's important to celebrate the AFL career of the retiring midfielder.
Priddis announced his retirement last week - less than two months after signing a one-year contract extension.Photo: Scott Barbour
Reports have suggested Priddis was pushed into retirement because of the club's need to replenish their midfield with younger players.
Priddis, who will play out the season, said part of his decision was related to the club's list management.Photo: West Coast Eagles
But he denied there was a rift with Simpson when asked about it on Thursday.
"My relationship with Adam is awesome. He is a mate," Priddis told Mix 94.5.

"One thing I tried to make as clear as I possibly could was, 'let's just be honest, mate'.
"That is where we have got to go and it was a mutual decision, and I am really comfortable with it.
"It takes into account list management, my form, my role going forward."
Simpson played down the situation when asked about it on Friday.
"We need to move on pretty quick," Simpson said.
"I know there's still the commentary, but from our end we've been saying the same thing since last Friday, haven't we?
"I really hope we continue to respect the man, what decision he made and enjoy and embrace the last five weeks of his career."
Priddis is a chance to return for Sunday's clash with St Kilda at Etihad Stadium.
The Brownlow medallist has been named in West Coast's extended squad, alongside Nathan Vardy.
The Eagles (10-8) sit in eighth spot on the ladder, but a loss to St Kilda would leave them facing an uphill battle to qualify for the finals.
- AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mix 94.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Vardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Barbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
