<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425336479258937</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/teams/titans/titans-aiming-to-crush-the-top-four-dreams-of-archrivals-broncos/news-story/4de1688ac416dbaf5fe1e1870a89a7be</url>
  <title>Titans desperate to shed chokers tag</title>
  <content>
Oates returns for Broncos

ORIGIN prop Jarrod Wallace has expressed concerns over the Gold Coast™s mentality as the Titans attempt to shed the tag of being the NRL™s biggest chokers.

The Titans have an opportunity to crush the top four dreams of archrivals Brisbane in Saturday's derby at Cbus Super Stadium.

It is a clash the Gold Coast has traditionally struggled in, losing 17 of 22 games against their "big brother", including the past six encounters.

But ironically it is the type of game the Titans could fire a shot in given their 2017 form.

The Titans have knocked off reigning premiers Cronulla twice, competition leaders Melbourne and fourth-placed Parramatta this season.

But they have also lost to bottom three sides Newcastle, Wests Tigers and South Sydney, results they will rue when the club misses the finals for the sixth time in seven years.

Last week's 26-4 defeat to the Tigers was the Gold Coast's worst loss of the season and Wallace admitted they may have taken their opposition lightly.

HENRY:

"The Tigers turned up and played some really good footy and it cost us in the end," he said.

"They out-enthused us from the first kick-off. They beat us through the middle then beat us out wide.

"I don't know if it's a mindset that they weren't in the top eight, so it'd be an easy win. You can't have that mindset. There are no easy wins in the NRL.

"No matter how bad or good a team is playing, you have to play consistently. Until we do that, we won't be a top eight team.

"We've got to get through the end of the year."

There was high expectation on the Gold Coast this season following last year's drought-breaking finals appearance.

With Jarryd Hayne joining late last season and a promising halves duo of Ashley Taylor and Kane Elgey, much was expected of the Titans.

But they have failed to fire a shot in 2017, not winning more than three straight games as injury and poor form crushed their campaign.

In the Tigers loss, league legend Wally Lewis said he was stunned by the Titans' reluctance to play what was in front of them, a trait that made the Gold Coast one of the tougher teams to defend early in the year.

"They just stuck to a pattern," Lewis said.

"There is a basis for sticking to a game plan but if something pops up, you need to take control of those opportunities.

"You can't plan them. They just take place. You read the play and make the most of it.

"So often now, the team game plan is the most important feature. Teams stick to it over and over. You can tell what they're going to do.

"When there is no pressure upon them, teams turn it around. People start saying 'why didn't they play like this all year?'. Unfortunately that's the way it tends to go."

Wallace, who will confront his former club for the second time on Saturday night, said the Gold Coast had to loosen the shackles to salvage something in the last five weeks of the season.

"We definitely can't make it in the top eight but we want to go out with a bit of a bang in 2017," he said.

"We want to try and get some back-to-back wins and at least have a bit of fun and go into the off-season with a few wins under our belt."

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Hayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cbus Super Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Elgey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
