<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425886235082681</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/vince-lia-finds-new-home-at-adelaide-united/8776212</url>
  <title>Ex-Phoenix midfielder Vince Lia finds new home at Adelaide United after emailing clubs</title>
  <content>
Former Wellington midfielder Vince Lia has signed with Adelaide United after a concerted email campaign by the veteran to secure an A-League contract.
Lia, 32, was dumped by the Phoenix despite a 10-year career with the club as a foundation player.
He did not necessarily expect to be without a side for next season.
"I guess as a footballer you've got to have confidence in yourself and it's part and parcel of the game," Lia said.
"You're going to come off contract. It's a horrible feeling but it's part of the game and you know at some stage it's going to happen.
"You just have to stay positive and keep yourself as fit as possible and when the opportunity does come up you need to be ready."
Lia decided the best way to secure a new deal was to email every A-League club.
"I've had an agent in the past but I think, for A-League clubs, I've been around long enough for them to know who I am," he said.
As it turned out, the Reds responded with an offer of a trial.
"It wasn't as daunting as it is when you're a kid but still you're under pressure to perform and do well enough to earn yourself a job essentially," Lia explained.
Lia to provide much-needed experience to new-look side

Fast forward a week and Lia secured a one-year contract under the Reds new German coach Marco Kurz.
"He's pretty structured and he likes things done together," Lia said of his new gaffer.

"He's come in with the German style of football and he's tried to impose that and he's got three or four months to get us playing the way he wants which is long enough.
"I guess we have a look and see what position suits me best. Hopefully I can get my way into the starting 11.
"If not, I'm here to play my role. Whatever that role is I'm happy to play it."
Lia played 24 games with Melbourne Victory before heading across the Tasman where he wore the Phoenix shirt in 198 games.
He is the oldest player in the United squad but will offer leadership to a club that has lost the quality of skipper Eugene Galekovic, Dylan McGowan, Marcelo Carrusca, Cirio and Iacopo La Rocca.
"We do have a couple of older guys but a couple of them are foreigners and English is their second language, so they're not necessarily going to be the loudest ones on the field," Lia said.
"I guess where I can come in and lead from behind and just use my experience to play that important role."
The Reds have won two trial games against local competition but start their season with an FFA Cup match against Newcastle United next Wednesday night.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LIA</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eugene Galekovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Lia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iacopo La Rocca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Victory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cirio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-Phoenix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcelo Carrusca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Kurz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lia, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
