<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425933479723952</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/indian-police-hunt-mystery-hair-thief/news-story/8a729b0eb8639a39fe750b251d23820d</url>
  <title>Indian police hunt mystery hair thief</title>
  <content>
Police are investigating a mysterious raft of attacks in which Indian women say they are waking to find someone has chopped off their hair.
A top official in northern Uttar Pradesh state says police have advised people not to believe or spread rumours following the death of a 65-year-old woman who was beaten by a mob on suspicion she was a witch responsible for the hair theft.
Anand Kumar said on Friday village committees had been ordered to quash rumours about ghosts or witches cutting off women's braids.
Similar claims have come from neighbouring Haryana and Delhi suburbs, police said.
They have spread fear the hair could be used to cast spells.
In the state capital, Lucknow, police said a rumour began last week about someone cutting off the hair of women.
"Within days it has spread to areas around Delhi and western Uttar Pradesh. Now almost every day, police are getting complaints from women about this unknown ghost," said Manish Rakesh, a police officer.
Some psychiatrists believe the stories might be due to mass hysteria or hallucination.
"Ghosts do not cut the braids of women. This is mischief, nothing else," said Rakesh Gaur, a psychiatrist at Jawaharlal Nehru Medical College in Agra.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anand Kumar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haryana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delhi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manish Rakesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucknow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rakesh Gaur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uttar Pradesh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jawaharlal Nehru Medical College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
