<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425164680564053</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834704/eagles-accept-a-league-test-in-title-run/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Eagles accept A-League test in title run</title>
  <content>
Dylan Holz returns for Edgeworth against Valentine.

EDGEWORTH will juggle their push for a premiership triple-double with a trial against A-League club Western Sydney Wanderers next Wednesday night.
The Herald understands the Eagles will play Wanderers at Pluim Park in Lisarow in a closed practice match organised several weeks ago.
It is believed the Wanderers contacted Edgeworth, who they beat 5-1 in an FFA Cup round of 16 game in 2016, about the hit-out, which comes as the Eagles try to secure a third consecutive Northern NSW NPL minor premiership.
The back-to-back major premiers are two points clear of Hamilton and three ahead of Lambton Jaffas with two rounds remaining.

The Eagles take on fifth-placed Valentine on Saturday at Cahill Oval in a vital game for both sides. Valentine are a point outside the top four and a loss could end their play-off chances.
Dom Bizzarri and Dylan Holz are expected to return for Edgeworth, while Valentine could be without Daniel Minors, who has a foot injury. Minors, who trialed at Wollongong recently but has agreed to join Broadmeadow next season, came off early in the 2-1 loss to Hamilton last week and has not trained this week. On a positive note, Josh Carroll returns from suspension for Valentine.
Coach Darren Sills believed this season would be a positive for Phoenix, regardless of the next two results. 
"The club's done really well this year, and if we miss the semis, we miss them," Sills said. "It's our fault, not the referees' or anyone else's, if we don't. At the end of the day, the club's gone from third last [in 2016] to possibly fifth this year and as long as we improve heading into that next licence period, we should be all rosy. People will want to start coming back to our club, which is what we want."
In the other match on Saturday, Jaffas play sixth-placed Maitland, who are five points short of fourth-placed Broadmeadow and remain only a mathematical chance of making the finals.

On Sunday, Broadmeadow celebrate Old Boys' day at Magic Park looking to bounce back against the Jets Youth after their 4-2 extra-time FFA Cup loss to Moreton Bay on Wednesday night.
Dino Fajkovic is suspended after getting a second yellow card in extra time. Leading Magic goalscorer James Virgili, who was substituted in the 77th minute  - three minutes after Moreton Bay went 2-1 ahead - came through the game unscathed.
Hamilton coach Michael Bolch expects Kane Goodchild to lift again when they take on Lake Macquarie at Macquarie Field.

"Goody will be champing at the bit," Bolch said. "He was dropped to the bench last week, then came on and scored a good goal. He's only one off leading goalscorer, so I'm sure he'll have a point to prove."

Rhys Cooper is away and Sean Pratt (knee) and Tommy Spencer (ankle) remaining sidelined for Hamilton. The Roosters have goalkeeper Benn Kelly out suspended.
Hamilton, who will part ways with Bolch and several players at season's end, are challenging for top spot on the back of an unbeaten seven-game streak featuring six wins.
"There's a good vibe among the group," Bolch said.
"They know it's the last year together for a lot of them. There's a lot moving on from the club so it's coming together nice towards the end of the year."
Hamilton, the 2017 club champions, have reportedly secured Jets Youth player Cody Carroll for next year.

Also Sunday, Charlestown finish their season while farewelling coach Shane Pryce and Bears-bound veteran Josh Maguire against back-to-back wooden spooners Weston at Lisle Carr Oval.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cahill Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Holz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Pratt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommy Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Pryce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Minors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaffa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisle Carr Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pluim Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bears-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney Wanderers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Boy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benn Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bolch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Virgili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAMBTON Jaffas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Sills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisarow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhys Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jets Youth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dino Fajkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cody Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edgeworth</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern NSW NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Goodchild</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Bizzarri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
