<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424937047293165</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/nt-indigenous-employment-scheme-axed-alleged-rorting/8775964</url>
  <title>Northern Territory Indigenous employment scheme axed after alleged rorting</title>
  <content>
A Northern Territory Indigenous employment scheme has been axed after it was discovered a number of businesses had allegedly rorted the system of thousands of dollars.
The Indigenous Employment Provision Sum (IEPS) scheme was brought in by the Country Liberals Party (CLP) in 2014 to incentivise companies to hire Indigenous people in the Territory.
The Gunner Government has now suspended it effective immediately after it uncovered at least six different companies allegedly falsely said they employed Indigenous workers to claim the benefits.
"This program was certainly well intentioned, well meaning, and was all about ensuring that we had more Indigenous Territorians in jobs," Deputy Chief Minister Nicole Manison said.
"We've felt like there is no way we should be continuing with the program, that we need to suspend it at the moment."
"We need to have a look at what comes in to replace it, but most importantly we need to hand this over to police so they can have a look at the matter."
The Government did not give a total sum of the amount defrauded or which businesses were involved, but said the figures ranged from thousands of dollars to tens of thousands for each of the six companies.
Audit into scheme missed rorting

Ms Manison said it was up to the hiring companies themselves to check whether the employee was Indigenous.
"Generally that is something that the company goes and confirms that they do have Indigenous people being employed, however some questions have been raised around that," she said.
"There were checks and balances through the Department [of Infrastructure, Planning and Logistics] and of course if you have concerns about programs you can always refer it onto the Auditor-General."
Ms Manison said the exposure of the scheme to fraudulent activity was uncovered by the Infrastructure, Planning and Logistics Department in March, when the first of the six cases was then referred to the Auditor-General.
A CLP-commissioned audit report, delivered by KPMG in December 2016, did not identify the alleged rorting incidents.
But Ms Manison said the report did find there were a range of other reasons the scheme was ineffective.
"Other concerns have been raised to companies about the process of putting the program into place, whether or not it was achieving the genuine Indigenous employment outcomes," she said.
"Industry that had raised concerns about flexibility of how the program rolled out, so there were a range of concerns across the board, we were already looking at the program and ways to make improvements."
The Department of Business Innovation and Trade are now working on a program to replace the IEPS.
The matters have been referred to NT Police.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Chief Minister Nicole Manison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Manison</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Liberals Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Employment Provision Sum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Territorians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logistics Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLP-commissioned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gunner Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Infrastructure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IEPS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auditor-General</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
