<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425199040303057</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/organisation-fined-for-tug-of-war-death-of-school-boy/8776028</url>
  <title>NT Christian Schools fined $50,000 for student's death during 4WD tug-of-war</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A Northern Territory education body has been fined $50,000 after a student was killed in a tug-of-war-style game with a four-wheel drive at a school sports day in 2015.
NT Christian Schools - which operates eight schools in the Territory - pleaded guilty in the Darwin Local Court to failing to comply with health and safety duties.
Jethro Dhamarrandji-Baker, 12, was run over and killed by a four-wheel drive that he and fellow students were towing at the Gawa Christian College carnival on Elcho Island two years ago.
The activity, known as a troopy pull, mimicked the process of getting a car out of a bog and was introduced as a novelty event by the school in 2012.
Four-wheel drives are known colloquially as "troopies" in the NT.
Lawyer for NT Work Safe Mark Thomas told the court "a significant financial penalty" should be imposed as a deterrent, but that he did not intend for the school to go broke.
The maximum penalty for the offence is $1.5 million.
Defence lawyer Jodi Truman said NT Christian Schools was already running at a loss of several thousand dollars and had been for the past five years.
The court heard the school group relied heavily on government funding and did not charge the parents of Indigenous students fees.
Troopy pull safety 'done on the fly'

Mr Thomas told the court the school seriously "dropped the ball" on a number of safety fronts, including failing to do a formal risk assessment or review of of the activity.
The court heard on the day of the incident teachers did not follow safety precautions set up in previous years.
Previously a safety strap was put between the rope and the car to ensure students were running a safe distance from the vehicle.
But in the 2015 event, the combination of a new sports teacher who had not been briefed on how to run the event, a non-school vehicle and a volunteer driver led to the rope being attached directly to the vehicle.
The court heard there was less than three metres of space between the car and some of the students.
"It would appear everything was done on the fly," Mr Thomas said.
Mr Thomas said a photograph showed Jethro about two metres from the front of the car.
Ms Truman said Jethro, who was the grandson of one of the Gawa elders who was involved in setting up the school, was loved and by staff and teachers.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Thomas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawa Christian College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jethro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jethro Dhamarrandji-Baker, 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elcho Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodi Truman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Christian Schools</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Truman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Work Safe Mark Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troopy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
