<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425804630702606</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/woman-has-a-hit-out-to-aid-brother/news-story/b0462b2739ec849d013fc5210fdc2226</url>
  <title>Woman has a hit out to aid brother</title>
  <content>
TOWNSVILLE woman Vanessa Izzard is set to take to the boxing ring for the first time in a fundraising effort for her dying brother.
Mrs Izzard learned her older brother Chris O'Toole had stage four lung cancer last October. The disease is terminal and comes after a lifetime of health issues.
Mr O'Toole was born with Marfan syndrome, an inherited disorder that affects connective tissue. He also has a hole in his heart.
Mrs Izzard is set to raise money in the Fight for your Cause charity boxing event. She wants to take her brother to Tasmania in his final days.
"With his health issues he's never left home and always lived with his parents," she said. "I want to give him something to look forward to. He's got nothing except for our family."
Mrs Izzard said she would train three times a day for the bout in October.
"I don't care if I get bashed. It will be all worth it at the end of the day," she said.
To donate, visit Mrs Izzard's GoFundMe page "Fight for Chris".
Fight for your Cause has raised more than $200,000 for local charities in recent years, and will take place on October 14 from 6pm at Townsville RSL Stadium.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Izzard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville RSL Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marfan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanessa Izzard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Toole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris O'Toole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Izzard's GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
