<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425332184291605</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/boxing-mma/mikaela-mayer-to-make-her-professional-debut/news-story/a44cfaff5bd8ef5afc85cdd7030b2d20</url>
  <title>Boxing beauty tipped for UFC stardom</title>
  <content>
Conor McGregor's challenge

REMEMBER the name Mikaela Mayer.

The 27-year-old American makes her professional boxing debut on Sunday, as the main support bout to the Vasil Lomachenko-Miguel Marriaga WBO Super Featherweight title fight in Los Angeles.

Mayer has been signed by legendary boxing promoter Bob Arum and his Top Rank stable, and the hype surrounding the California native has already begun.

The fighter made her name on the amateur scene, claiming a number of national boxing titles, before representing the United States at the 2016 Olympic Games in Rio.

Only a few years ago, a female in combat sports had a hard time being taken seriously, let alone sitting so high on the bill as Mayer will at the weekend.

But Arum, who has promoted the world's most high profile fighters, says Mayer is special.

"I really think that she has the goods, that she will be able to help us bring women boxing to the fore," Arum told .

Arum has a longstanding rivalry with UFC president Dana White, but the promoter has

has praised the organisation for the way it built its womens' division, capturing the world's attention - something he says Top Rank will do with Mayer.

"I really want to acknowledge the debt that we owe to UFC because they took this Ronda Rousey and they made her into a tremendous star. She ended up becoming the biggest pay-per-view star that they had and if they could do it with Ronda Rousey, we believe we can do it with Mikaela."

Mayer herself has admitted she might not have made it onto the Mixed Martial Arts scene were it not for the impact Rousey had on women's combat sports.

"MMA was a good fit simply because it's embraced the ladies and put them on the sport's biggest platforms, unlike boxing," Mayer told .

"That's where women were getting their respect and acknowledgment. I was close to doing it."

Thankfully for Arum and Top Rank though, their vision for Mayer (and the money offered) was enough to secure the former Olympian - and they hope to build a brand to rival a star like Ronda Rousey.

"I wanted a big promotion behind me and the money had to be right. They (Top Rank) are trusting women's boxing and me, so it's a big honour," Mayer said.

Arum also praised the UFC for the impact it has had on promoting fighters - even those that do not come out victorious.

"UFC has taught us that a loss is not a death sentence," Arum said.

"If a guy loses a fight, but he loses heroically, and he gives 100-percent, people want to see him fight again and you can bring him back again.

"(Marriaga) lost the fight to Valdez, but he fought a very, very courageous fight, right? So now when you're looking for somebody to put in with Vasyl Lomachenko, you remember the performance that he had. Now he didn't get the decision against Valdez, but everybody gave him the props for a great performance.

"And that's what we've got to do more and more in boxing. We cannot write fighters off because they lose a fight."

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dana White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vasyl Lomachenko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayer</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mixed Martial Arts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rousey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arum</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top Rank</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Arum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valdez</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikaela Mayer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vasil Lomachenko-Miguel Marriaga WBO Super Featherweight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronda Rousey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikaela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
