<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425718731355113</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4832933/rosebud-steeled-for-merewether/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Rosebud steeled for Merewether</title>
  <content>
KEY PLAYER: Adamstown captain Clare Cummings, right, was looking forward to hosting competition heavyweights Merewether on Sunday. Picture: Max Mason-Hubers

Adamstown captain Clare Cummings always had faith Rosebud would turn around their Herald Women's Premier League season but was happy to carry the underdogs tag in the first leg of their semi-final against Merewether on Sunday.
Rosebud were last year's minor premiers but after eight rounds of this season had won just two games.
At their lowest point they sustained 6-0 and 9-1 losses to Merewether but have quietly rallied since Lou D'Amico took over from Ben Herron, who stood down as coach on May 2, and ended up comfortably finishing third.
"At the start we maybe had a little bit of pressure on us because we'd done so well the year before but we also lost a lot of players, a lot of leaders too and we had people 16 and 17 stepping up," Cummings said.
"I always knew we would be able to turn it around, that we had enough power to do it. We've been working pretty hard and are more excited than anything."
Cummings felt there was a lot less pressure going into the home-and-away semi-finals this year.
"Merewether have got a lot of experience and have played in the big games and no one expects us to do anything. We're happy with people thinking that," she said.
Adamstown have lost strike weapon Lauren Allan, who is headed back to the United States for football, but will take confidence from beating United 3-2 in their last meeting.
"That was one of the best games we've ever played and it's nice knowing we've beaten them but we're going to have to be better again," she said.
Mid North Coast finished fourth and host minor premiers Warners Bay at Taree Zone Field on Saturday in the opening leg of their semi-final.

Warners Bay have won all three encounters between the two sides this season but Mid North Coast led 1-0 last weekend before the defending champions levelled through a penalty then found a second-half winner through Jenna Kingsley.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Women's Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenna Kingsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Herron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Cummings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lou D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adamstown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mid North Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree Zone Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cumming</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
