<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425160385596681</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/sport/cricket-australias-david-peever-lays-down-like-sally-20170804-gxpo9g</url>
  <title>Cricket Australia's David Peever lays down like Sally</title>
  <content>
From the inevitable to the belated. As was pre-ordained by the real distribution of authority between this dispute's two parties, the professional players of our national sport have dispatched their so-called masters over the proverbial O'Reilly Stand. 
Cricket Australia's chairman David Peever directed the governing body's pricelessly quixotic 10-month crusade, fought with wooden swords. He will wear the administration's abject capitulation wherever he goes, Rio Tinto's former ribbon-cutter now the punchline on his own novelty t-shirt. We reckon he always fancied himself the lead man in a case study of industrial relations fortitude - just not one about the other side's! In the Long Room at Lord's last week, fewer than three miles from Rio's global headquarters in St James's Square, his ECB peers (all too aware Peever was never in charge of a single mine, nor a single miner, as the company's grandly-titled "managing director") might well have been snickering into their champagne flutes. 
For CA to now claim the deal bitterly clinched (in principle) this week was a mutual compromise - a faithful meeting in the middle - is not to put lipstick on a pig, but on its puckered arse. To wit:
Revenue sharing, James Sutherland said, was "an outdated model" and "an untenable situation for any business." Under the new deal, players get 30 per cent of forecast revenue (the definition of which has barely changed) and 27.5 per cent of any upside.

Supplied

Half ($29 million) of that upside from the 2012 deal already earned by players had to be rolled into the new deal - it will now be fully paid. 

"Players without contracts will not be eligible to receive back pay when a new MoU is eventually agreed," CA said on June 30. All uncontracted players will now be back-paid from July 1.
Australian Cricketers' Association director Simon Katich arguing for a leaner governing body "demonstrates why the current fixed-percentage model is hurting cricket." CA will now cut $25 million from its own budget.
"The preconditions you set out in your letter are unacceptable to CA," Peever haughtily wrote to the players' union in May. Every single one of those preconditions are in the deal he just signed.
Yep, Peever was right about one thing: this was no Rio Tinto IR blueprint - despite him importing underling Mark O'Neill and consultant Ken Bacon from the mining giant's (human) carbon dioxide department - because no leader of that great company has ever been bent over a barrel like this! There's an Eric Clapton song we bet Alistair Nicholson and Greg Combet can't stop humming: 

Josh Robenstone

Lay Down Sally...
I've been trying all night long just to talk to you...
All of that untold damage to public confidence, the angst for broadcasters and sponsors, and the enmity cricketers now nurse after the attempts to divide men from women and internationals from state reps, and our finest athletes' portrayal as greedy, for what? For all the players to get exactly what they asked for and for CA to look as hapless as it truly is. 
So now what? The chairman takes full responsibility and steps down? Yeah right. Far easier to throw Sutherland under the bus - he's had a good 17 years. But after this debacle, how can CA's lead negotiator Kevin Roberts (whose previous stint at 2XU was hardly award-winning) succeed him? Andrew Jones from Cricket NSW is no more popular with senior players. And the rest of Sutherland's team is tremendously unimpressive. Stories  of the disdain shown for commercial partners; we in the media have first-hand experience of the very same. Jolimont Street needs a genuine clean out. 

The very same personnel who needlessly turned this negotiation with players into a national wildfire are now responsible for striking the sport's next broadcast deal. Ten is broke and Seven's summer sport is tennis. There is no competitive tension. That's bad enough before Nine's Hugh Marks sits at the bargaining table across from Moe, Larry and Curly.
But it's the CA board, too, which desperately needs some heft - of smarts, not of bellicosity. Though we can't see Peever inviting anyone of that description inside this circus he's running.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Peever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia's David Peever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Katich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Bacon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sutherland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto IR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolimont Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Clapton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Robenstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Combet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St James Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Reilly Stand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark O'Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine's Hugh Marks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peever</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
