<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426105278419096</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/rugby-league-match-centre/live-nrl-2017-north-queensland-cowboys-v-melbourne-storm-20170804-gxpshu.html</url>
  <title>Live NRL 2017: North Queensland Cowboys v Melbourne Storm</title>
  <content>
Melbourne cruise to another win - after the heavy casualties the hosts suffered in the opening 20 minutes, it was always going to be an uphill slog. There were some sloppy parts to this game from Melbourne but they showed enough class to easily win here. Thanks for following, we'll be back tomorrow. 
Smith misses and that's the end of that. 26-8. 
The Fox adds a cherry on top - goes straight out of dummy half from deep in his own half, pushes through Lowe and Feldt and easily outruns the chasers to the try line. 
Game petering out now as both teams know the game is won for the visitors. Who is going to stop them in September? 

Wide ball to Feldt, who puts it down! Nine minutes to go and Melbourne are definitely home here. 
The ball goes to ground and the Storm turn it over inside their own 10, before an offside penalty on the last gives the Cowboys a fresh set. 
Great positional work from the winger as an inside out play saw Martin halfway through a gap, and then trying to pass over the top to his unmarked winger only for Addo-Carr to pluck it out of the air. 
Sloppy from the Storm as they throw a forward pass after the dropout. Scrum for the Cowboys, 13 minutes to go. 
Chambers kicks ahead, Vunivalu chases but Coote forces it dead. Excellent set after points and they force a repeat set. 
Smith converts and it's 22-8. 
Another grubber in behind them, Linnett tries to take out the Fijian without the ball and if he hadn't been strong enough to push through the tackle and score anyway, that may well have been a penalty try. 
The kick back towards the posts is touched by Coote and then batted back by Slater! Six more for Melbourne! 
Kaufusi goes within inches once, then a couple of plays later he gets over the line but is held up! 
Cronk breaks through the middle and then kicks for himself but this time Feldt shows safe hands to cover it up - the pressure is immediately back on after Lowe loses it on tackle one! 
After all the pressure, Slater reads a kick well and comes away with it. Just over 20 to go. 
Two penalties for the Cowboys after the Storm are caught with it on the last - Scott gets a desperation kick away after the first is blocked, and the Cowboys then win a penalty to get them up the other end before O'Neill goes close and wins another. Huge chance to hit back here. 
The Storm are working it out from their own line and Coote is called for lying in the ruck. 
Kenny Bromwich off after copping an elbow to the throat. He should be fine but he'll have a HIA test. 
Granville kicks and Tim Glasby snatches it out of the air! Great take. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Bromwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addo-Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vunivalu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feldt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowboys, 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coote</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slater</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Glasby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fijian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaufusi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Cowboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
