<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425160385596673</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/coburg-homes-conversion-to-79-star-ecohouse-gets-building-design-gong/news-story/e4818e4abbc017359d07fa7d32d3a396</url>
  <title>Not so cheesy extension a sustainable success</title>
  <content>
BUILDING sustainability features into a home brings more than green kudos according to the award-winning builder of an innovative Coburg home extension.
Jeremy Spencer from Postive Footprints said The Cheese House extension, which converted an energy-guzzling old-style weatherboard house into a 7.9 star energy-producing home, was now earning money for the owners by producing more energy than the family used.
"There's still a feeling (energy efficient measures) might be an expense that people can't pay, but if anything it becomes cheaper over time.....this house is now making money for the owners." Mr Spencer said.
"For your own house, anything you can do to make it more sustainable has a payback."
The Cheese House, so named because of it's asymetrical rounded shape - designed to minimise shading over a neighbour's block - was recently awarded two Building Designers Association of Victoria awards for best residential Environmentally Sustainable Design and best Alteration and Addition between $200,000 and $500,000.
Mr Spencer said the walls, floor and roof of old section of the house had been insulated and windows double-glazed while passive solar principles had been employed on the new section to maximise the use of the sun during winter.
Recycled bricks were used internally for their heat mass benefits, and the exterior was clad in Colorbond, "an iconically Australian product" and "low in embodied energy" - the amount of energy needed to create it.
"It's also low maintenance - the clients didn't want to be painting - and highly recyclable," Mr Spencer said.
The owners, concerned about rising gas prices, opted to go all electric and even the hydronic heating, traditionally gas-powered, runs off efficient electric heat pumps.
A 4.7kW solar system ensures the house runs on credit.
A Brunswick property, Joan 7.3., designed by Bios, was awarded best New House $300k - $500k and a received a commendation for Small Lot Design.
Details: bdav.org.au/awards
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheese House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environmentally Sustainable Design</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New House $300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spencer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan 7.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Designers Association of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Small Lot Design</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Postive Footprints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
