<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424906982521397</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/young-buyers-compete-for-sevenfigure-carnegie-townhouse/news-story/17d9fafb5378524f3de57e05a64b898c</url>
  <title>Young buyers compete for seven-figure Carnegie townhouse - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
A NEW townhouse has notched a sale price $100,000 above its reserve in Carnegie.
Woodards Carnegie director and senior auctioneer Ruth Roberts said the home at  was hotly contested by three bidders on July 29.
"It was a very quick and keenly fought auction, and in very strong increments," she said.
"It started at $1.4 million, went up in $20,000 bids, and was on the market at $1.5 million."
The home sold under the hammer for $1.6 million to a young couple, Ms Roberts said.
She added that the runaway result was achieved at the hands of mostly younger buyers.
The sale price put the property first on the list in the Real Estate Institute of Victoria's top five unit sales in the state for the week ending July 30.
The four-bedroom home features a very large main living area, modern finishes, and an outdoor entertainment space.

The property offers modern finishes and an open layout.

Ms Roberts said the market in Carnegie and surrounds was continuing to perform very strongly, and that buyers were keen to score a spot while they could in what they saw as a growing area.
"There are more buyers than there is stock," she said.
"And it's not showing any sign of slowing down. People seem to be thinking that they just need to get in."
A flow-on effect of buyers priced out of suburbs up the bay was one factor attracting buyers to the region, Ms Roberts said.
"Part of it is the natural push out from Elwood and St Kilda," she said.
Carnegie's very wide variety of dwelling types was also a drawcard, as were its Koornang Rd shops, multiple transport options, and the area's schools, Ms Roberts said.
SEE SUBURB PROFILE:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koornang Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Roberts</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodards Carnegie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate Institute of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURB PROFILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnegie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
