<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425164680564037</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/lifestyle/clear-july--how-i-gave-up-plastics-for-a-month-20170802-gxo2ye</url>
  <title>Do you think you can't give up plastic? I did, for a whole month</title>
  <content>
by
Jeff Allan

How do you solve a problem like household plastic? I set out to reduce my dependence on single-use items like shopping bags and Glad-Wrap. Here's how I fared.
Coffee

First, the easy stuff. Many coffee cups have a plastic lining and can't be recycled. Then there are the lids. This was quickly tackled. I hate the smell of plastic keep cups, but I was able to purchase a smart glass one and have it delivered to my office within days. I take it everywhere with me. I feel so hipster.
Shopping

I bought a pack of compact carry bags (success!), but usually didn't have them with me at the time (fail). Instead, I grabbed up single vegetables - ignoring the that makes this so convenient - and dumped them by the handful on the checkout belt. Not ideal. It took me most of the month to get into rhythm. I also refuse to shop at the big chains that commit the shameful practice of single-wrapped vegetables. Vote with your feet.

Home

Food preservation was the hard one. Glad-Wrap must be my most loved kitchen invention. Fortunately my partner is a Tupperware (or equivalent) aficionado, so there is a container of every possible size in our cupboard. Even for my half-cut lemon. The second challenge was kitchen scraps. We already had a half-forgotten worm farm in the garden so, checking the critters were still alive, I got back into the habit of feeding them our vegetable scraps, while the dog took care of proteins. Next, the bin liner. For this I found a great tip online: re-purpose plastic wraps from other groceries, like bread packets. Works perfectly.
Out n' about

Plastic cutlery was easy to say no to, ditto drinking straws. I don't go to many kids' parties or state fairs, so balloons were, too. Say no to balloons, people, these are a massive killer and really, have no real purpose in the world. Water bottles turned out to be my biggest issue. I bought two large Voss glass bottles for the car (we just drop off the empty one at home as needed and replace it with the cold one from the fridge), plus another for my desk at work. My little bit, .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glad-Wrap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tupperware</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
