<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425628537040161</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/sculpture-at-barangaroo-returns-to-show-off-australian-artists/8775846</url>
  <title>Sculpture at Barangaroo returns to show off Australian artists</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

From bamboo bowers to shifting Sydney sands, the works that make up this year's Sculpture at Barangaroo have been specially selected to complement the striking and ever-changing surrounds of Sydney's foreshore.
A total of 14 installations by nine emerging and established Australian artists feature in the second Sculpture at Barangaroo, which is modelled on its successful predecessor Sculpture by the Sea.
Curator Geoffrey Edwards said the artists matched their works with the site's range of big plazas, vistas and more intimate settings.
"It should actually stop people in their tracks, make them think for a while, make them think about the region, its histories, and the site," he said.

The work of esteemed sculptor Michael Le Grand is being celebrated with a mini-retrospective of six of his sculptures.
Other artists who are also featured are Richard Tipping, Adam King, Tereasa Trevor and Christopher Langton.
Juan Pablo Pinto worked with the Core Urban collective to produce Bower - a cocoon made from bamboo to sit in and take in the natural landscape surrounded by the concrete jungle.
"We wanted to create a place where you can contemplate the harbour, enjoy the sunset for a more intimate experience," he said.
"It creates a great contrast it really stands out and also make you question what sort of materials you want to live in."
Nicole Monks has used Sydney sand, eucalyptus, Geraldton wax and native flowers to produce her ephemeral work Terra Omnia.
"This site in particular is about reclaiming land and with this work we're reclaiming history. What was written - terra nullius - we all know that was a big fat lie really. So we're reclaiming that and writing Terra Omnia - the land of everything, all and plenty."

Last year 150,000 people visited the exhibition which is smaller this year because of ongoing construction work.
Mr Edwards said the works incorporated the whole spectrum of sculptural practice.
"We wanted artists whose work would complement this fantastic, spectacular setting and in turn we wanted this setting to be the right context for certain works. But also I wanted to choose artists who worked across the range of disciplines.
Sculpture at Barangaroo runs from August 5-20.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tereasa Trevor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Monks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Core Urban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Langton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barangaroo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Le Grand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Tipping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geraldton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terra Omnia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juan Pablo Pinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffrey Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
