<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425933479723980</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/rwandans-vote-kagame-expected-to-win/news-story/a632c9152b42f27eae09907244f78d14</url>
  <title>Rwandans vote, Kagame expected to win</title>
  <content>
Rwandan voters have queued in long lines to cast their ballots in a presidential election that incumbent President Paul Kagame is tipped to win by a landslide after 17 years in power.
Kagame has won international plaudits for presiding over a peaceful and rapid economic recovery in the tiny central African nation since the 1994 genocide, when an estimated 800,000 people Tutsis and moderate Hutus were killed.
But he has also faced mounting censure for what critics and rights groups say are widespread human rights abuses, a muzzling of independent media and suppression of political opposition.
Kagame, a commander who led Tutsi rebel forces into Rwanda to end the 1994 genocide, banned the use of tribal terms after becoming president.
Kagame's main opponent, Frank Habineza, voted early on Friday at Kimoronko, a polling station in Kigali.
He told reporters his campaign had been hobbled because it could not compete with the machinery of the state.
If elected, Habineza has promised to set up a tribunal to retry dissidents whose convictions by Rwandan courts have been criticised as politically motivated.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kagame</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rwanda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimoronko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Paul Kagame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Habineza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hutu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Habineza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rwandans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tutsi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kigali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
