<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425418083639037</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/megan-gale-sends-a-powerful-message-about-public-breastfeeding-with-instagram-photo/news-story/8ba221ac004681f2b54247f08aa2db3a</url>
  <title>Megan's powerful message about public breastfeeding</title>
  <content>
MEGAN Gale has used a revealing photo of herself nursing to send a powerful message about breastfeeding in public.
The throwback photo from two years ago shows the barefaced supermodel looking into the camera while she breastfeeds her then-newborn son River.
Gale, 41, explained to fans she posted the snap in support of World Breastfeeding Week and to fight the stigma surrounding women who choose to nurse their babies in a public setting.
"I find it so shocking that breastfeeding in public is still so frowned upon and considered inappropriate in many cases," Gale, who's pregnant with her second bub, wrote in the lengthy caption alongside the photo.
"Women are being made to feel guilt and shame for breastfeeding their child when it is not only undoubtedly the best method to feed your baby, it's also the physical function of breasts and what they're intended for.
"I have faced my own triumphs and struggles trying to breastfeed - it's harder than one can imagine. However I (thankfully) was never told not to breastfeed in public. I'd like to see someone try and tell me not to."
Gale described the process of a mum breastfeeding her baby as "the most normal, natural thing in the world" and wrote that it needs to be "fully accepted (and) not frowned upon".
She admitted she was hesitant to post her breastfeeding photo to Instagram and wondered if it was "too full on".
"But I instantly realised it's that exact train of thought that is encouraging the stigma," she added and encouraged her followers who are new mums to post their own photos.
The heavily-pregnant model is expected to give birth to her second child very soon. It will be her second child with AFL partner Shaun Hampson.
In April, she shared the news of her pregnancy with fans .
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Hampson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MEGAN Gale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gales</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Breastfeeding Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gale, 41</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
