<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425851875343622</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/victoria/melbourne-man-wants-help-to-bring-daughter-from-vietnam-for-lifesaving-surgery-20170804-gxpkc2.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne man wants help to bring daughter home from Vietnam for lifesaving heart surgery</title>
  <content>
Tim Maclatchy just wants to bring his daughter Caroline home.
In the six months since she was born in Vietnam, the Melbourne man and his partner Tram Doan have barely held their baby.
It wasn't until they brought their newborn daughter home from hospital that Caroline begun having seizures and they realised something was horribly wrong.
Caroline was born with DiGeorge syndrome, a chromosome defect that causes congenital heart disease and autoimmune disorders.Photo: Facebook
She is putting up a mighty fight, but the life-saving operations Caroline needs are complicated and beyond the experience of doctors in Ho Chi Minh City - maybe even Vietnam.
Her family desperately want her to be transported to Melbourne for life-saving heart surgery at the Royal Children's Hospital.

Unfortunately the estimated cost of the medivac flight is at least $60,000,  to give Caroline the best chance of life.
Mr Maclatchy, who has worked in Ho Chi Minh City for two years as an English teacher, said the past six months had been nightmarish for him and Ms Doan.Photo: Facebook
"It's been pretty terrible, but it's amazing what you can adjust to. At the start we were going in every three hours to feed her.
"We just got used to waking up in the middle of the night and going in to feed her.
"The bureaucracy of having to figure out birth certificates and passports and visas to get her to Australia has been pretty annoying and convoluted.
"She has an Australian passport now and we're trying to get her a Medicare card.
"We've been talking to the Royal Children's Hospital and we just want to get her to Australia because the hospital service here - they haven't had much experience."
Caroline's progress has been slow.
At the moment she can't breathe without a ventilator because her trachea, which also needs surgery, is narrow and weak.
A doctor in Hanoi might be able to perform the surgery, but Caroline can't fly on a ventilator.
"That's the catch-22. We can't fly her while on a ventilator," Mr Maclatchy said. 
"She needs to be on an oxygen mask and tank to get on a commercial medivac. 
Ms Doan said she had learnt a lot from her daughter about resilience but said the family desperately needed help.
"We really need help. If she's in Australia she'll have more of a chance because our country is a developing country."
"She will have more of a chance with ongoing treatment in Melbourne.
"We call her 'little fighter'. I have learnt a lot from her," she said. 
"If I get sick or something is painful, I remember it's nothing compared to what Caroline is going through."
.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Doan.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Maclatchy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanoi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Maclatchy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DiGeorge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tram Doan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Doan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ho Chi Minh City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
