<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425589882333781</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/cricket/queensland-spinner-mitchell-swepson-set-to-be-called-up-to-australian-test-squad-for-bangladesh-tour/news-story/2d1d9db393064427374a67f7b6d6426e</url>
  <title>Spinner Swepson set for Test call-up</title>
  <content>
QUEENSLAND spinning ace Mitchell Swepson looks set to join the Australian squad for the Test tour of Bangladesh.
Selectors are yet to settle on a 14th man for the touring party but it's understood Swepson has plenty of support and could be drafted in over the coming days.
The impressive leg-spinner went on the tour of India earlier this year and although he didn't play a game the 23-year-old remains in contention for a debut baggy green in the subcontinent.
At the moment Ashton Agar - already selected - is in the box seat to partner Nathan Lyon in a dual-spin attack for the first Test in Dhaka on August 27.
But the shock dumping of Steve O'Keefe - Australia's best bowler in India - has put enormous pressure on selectors to find the right replacement.
Agar's inconsistent Sheffield Shield record gives a glimmer of hope for a different spinner to take his place, if selectors do decide to go that way.
Seamer Jackson Bird is the other leading contender to tour, but selectors may feel three fast bowlers - Josh Hazlewood, Pat Cummins and James Pattinson - are enough when slow wickets are likely to dictate they'll only play two quicks in an attack.
As Australia's eternal search for the next leg-spinner post-Shane Warne continues, it would seem that touring Bangladesh and possibly being blooded would be an enormous learning experience in the development of Swepson.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dhaka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Bird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashton Agar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve O'Keefe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pattinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheffield Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Swepson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swepson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hazlewood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Cummins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Warne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
