<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425976429397720</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-match-report/dragons-lose-grip-on-nrl-top-eight-with-loss-to-south-sydney-rabbitohs-20170804-gxpqor.html</url>
  <title>Dragons lose grip on NRL top eight with loss to South Sydney Rabbitohs </title>
  <content>
Australian World Cup hopeful Josh Dugan faces a spell on the sidelines after injuring his ankle as St George Illawarra's tenuous grip on the  top eight was further weakened by a late South Sydney fightback at the SCG on Friday.
Souths scored two tries in the last six minutes, the second  converted sublimely from the left touchline by Adam Reynolds to give the Rabbitohs  a fourth-straight win over their arch-rivals.

Up Next

Bunnies steal late win from the Dragons

01:30

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Plays of the Week

Nail-biting finishes, ripping yorkers and hat-trick heroes, these are the plays of the week.

Dugan left the field midway through the first half after his left ankle bent awkwardly in a tackle, and could only watch on helplessly  with his foot in an ice bucket as the Dragons threw away an 11th win of the year. Having led the competition after the first seven rounds, Paul McGregor's side will slip out of the finals placings by the end of the round if Penrith beat Wests Tigers on Sunday.
Interchange forward Tariq Sims came agonisingly close in the dying seconds as the Dragons desperately searched for a winning score, but he forced a pass which was cleaned up by Bryson Goodwin and the siren closed the curtain on Souths' first win in five weeks.

Goodwin scored the matchwinner for Souths in the left corner, a minute after John Sutton touched down under the posts to keep his side in the contest.
The Dragons still have away games against Brisbane and Penrith to come this season, and they look to need a minor miracle now if they wish to play in September, considering their last four losses have come against opponents outside the top eight.

Star back-rower Tyson Frizell started from the bench and appears to still be carrying rib and ankle injuries. He played only 38 minutes and was off the field for South Sydney's last two tries.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

This was the NRL's annual throwback to its SCG days, a venue which hosted four grand finals between South Sydney and the St George Dragons between 1949 and 1971.Photo: AAP
In 1965 they attracted a record 78,056, but in Friday's early kickoff the imposing venue resembled a hollow cavern with only a smattering of 12,312 fans in attendance.
Souths stared the strongest but were unable to capitalise on early Dragons errors, and were made to pay when Jason Nightingale finished a slick backline move in the left corner, scoring his 13th try of the season.
Gareth Widdop's marginal cut-out pass across two teammates allowed Nightingale to finish the job, and the Bunker was satisfied with his emphatic grounding.
Three minutes later Joel Thompson thought he'd strolled over but a forward pass was detected in the build up.
St George-Illawarra were missing too many tackles and soon enough the Rabbitohs took advantage with the NRL's leading try scorer Alex Johnston skipping around Josh McCrone and then proving too strong for NSW centre Josh Dugan.
Next it was Damien Cook's turn to have a crack at the flimsy defence of his old club, and he beat four defenders close to the line to put South Sydney in front.
Thompson did get his try on 34 minutes, leaping highest to retrieve a Josh McCrone kick in an effort Sydney Swans coach John Longmire would've been proud of at the AFL venue.
The match then turned on its head when Sam Burgess was penalised and sin-binned for tackling a rampaging Frizell without the ball when he was set to finish another slick backline play.
Frizell was kept on the bench for the opening 25 minutes before coach Paul McGregor unleashed his star man allowing him to wreak havoc with the tiring Rabbitohs forwards.
Widdop knocked over a penalty goal, before the Dragons pinched a late try to close out the first half, Dugan's replacement Kurt Mann finishing superbly in the left corner after benefiting from Josh McCrone's crossfield kick and Nene MacDonald's quick pass.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tariq Sims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dugan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dugan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Mann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gareth Widdop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Sutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frizell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryson Goodwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Nightingale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nightingale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nene Macdonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Widdop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson Frizell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh McCrone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
