<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425289234617857</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/sam-smith-shows-off-slimmeddown-figure-as-dramatic-weight-loss-continues/news-story/1ff5a18971e0d4310c41bad2b459e50e</url>
  <title>Smith shows off skinny figure after dramatic weight loss</title>
  <content>
SAM Smith's physical transformation has continued, with the singer showing off a dramatically slimmer figure in London overnight.
The 25-year-old performer looked noticeably thinner when he arrived at an Yves Saint Lauren event. His loose-fitting jeans hung on his slimmed-down frame and he covered up his top half with a baggy, long-sleeved shirt. His trainers and facial stubble completed the relaxed look - a style that's a touch more unkempt from his once polished look.
In the past, Smith has been vocal about the pressures in the gay community to look a certain way.
"There's also a lot of body dysmorphia in the gay community, which means if you're not toned and skinny it can be awful," he told The Sun.
The slim-down is the result of a health kick the Stay With Me singer has been on for a while now. In 2015, Smith revealed after "completely transforming" his relationship with food.

At the time he credited his transformation to working with nutritional therapist Amelia Freer, the author of the book Eat, Nourish, Glow.
"It's not even about weight loss - it's about feeling happy in yourself," Smith wrote on Instagram. "Love you Amelia, and thank you for making me feel so happy inside and out."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stay With Me</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yves Saint Lauren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelia Freer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
