<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426062328745193</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/cricket/cricket-with-urgent-ground-to-make-up-after-frustrating-pay-dispute-saga/news-story/f33c7e12acd54a9dea1e5c05cf3cd595</url>
  <title>Cricket fights to make up lost ground</title>
  <content>
THE sun was yet to rise in Sydney's west at 6.30am on Friday and already David Warner, Glenn Maxwell and Peter Handscomb were out shooting a commercial for Asics.
By 10am a feeding frenzy had broken out over Big Bash League signatures and later in the day  to tour Bangladesh and potentially oust Ashton Agar for a debut spot in the attack.
The ink had barely dried on the game's long overdue Heads of Agreement and in an instant cricket woke from its restless hibernation quicker than a grizzly bear poked with a stick.
BONANZA:
ALLAN BORDER:
The war is over but there is lost ground that must urgently be made up and that was no more obvious than out in Blacktown where Warner, Maxwell and Handscomb posed shivering in the new Asics Test, one day and T20 apparel - all with empty real estate on the chest where a major sponsor's logo should be.
MasterCard is rumoured to be one sponsor in the running for naming rights on Australian shirts, and Cricket Australia hope to announce their new corporate partners within the coming fortnight.
The companies' refusal to sign on the dotted line until the game's future was secured one of the major factors that finally forced a result in the bitter stalemate between CA and the ACA.
Already Asics ads will go to air and print without the major sponsor's logo displayed on its shirts, but the official apparel brand is desperate for confirmation soon so they can start producing the official replica merchandise that will spin cash registers all summer.
New beer partner XXXX has a carton ready to go displaying the Australian bowling attack, but they haven't been allowed to press print until an MOU was agreed upon.
The moment State and BBL offices opened their doors on Friday morning, they also braced for instant mayhem.
It's understood most BBL clubs only have eight players signed for the coming season and they must now turn non-binding agreements negotiated during the MOU freeze into certified contracts.
However, it's understood some players have used the non-binding nature of their talks to test the waters with rivals and see what offers they could get, and now there is likely to be situations where clubs are fighting each other for the same talent.
State contracting should be a simpler process and the window for that will close next Thursday, with some women already signing on to their lucrative new deals yesterday and men expected to follow suit early next week.

Cricket: After 10 months of negotiations the cricket pay dispute is over. Fox Sports News reporter Tom Chadwick and foxsports.com.au's Tom Morris dissect what it all means.

Cricket pay war: Who wins?
Thursday is also the day the Australian Test team will assemble in Darwin for a training camp to prepare for the two Test tour of Bangladesh kicking off at the end of this month.
Selectors are set to add a 14th player to the squad already named, and at this stage it appears Queenslander Swepson is the favourite.
If Trevor Hohns' panel goes that way it would leave them with just three pacemen - Josh Hazlewood, Pat Cummins and James Pattinson - but give them an extra option with their spin attack.
Agar is slated to take Steve O'Keefe's place in the attack in a dual role alongside Nathan Lyon, but with a Shield bowling average of 40, there is a huge opportunity for Swepson to force his way in and make a debut in the baggy green.
Australian captain Steve Smith said the team accepted pressure will be on them in Bangladesh.
"I think there's always been an expectation there of the Australian team delivering, I don't think that's ever not been the case," Smith told Fox Sports.
"We hold our heads high and we want to play some really good cricket in this series and in India in the one dayers and then in the Ashes in the summer.
"I'm really excited about the upcoming tour to Bangladesh. It's going to be a big challenge for this group. We obviously played in India recently in somewhat similar conditions ... hopefully we can learn from those mistakes and have a bit more success in Bangladesh."
With a heads of agreement in place, both Cricket Australia and the Australian Cricketers Association are working towards signing off on the full MOU by the start of September - at which time back pay will be given to players who went without money for all of July.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashton Agar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve O'Keefe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Handscomb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mastercard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pattinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handscomb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asics Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XXXX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heads of Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Chadwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Border</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslander Swepson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swepson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hazlewood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Cummins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Hohns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
