<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425933479723929</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834194/antelmi-to-fill-void-as-wolves-face-must-win/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Antelmi to fill void as Wolves face must-win</title>
  <content>
AWAY: Nick Montgomery. Picture: GEORGIA MATTS

The absence of star midfielder Nick Montgomery has opened the door for attacking weapon Patrick Antelmi to return to the Wollongong Wolves line-up for their do-or-die clash with Rockdale City Suns this weekend. 
Montgomery will miss Sunday's meeting at Ilinden Sports Centre after returning to England this week to attend his brother's wedding.
Wolves coach Jacob Timpano admitted his brief departure will be a big loss at a crucial time, but felt his squad depth could cover the loss.
"We were aware of the wedding when he signed, but will miss him because he has been superb in midfield for us," he said. 

"But in saying that, there is no doubt that Patrick is a handy replacement to have."
Antelmi, who has had a strong debut season in Wollongong, missed a week through suspension a fortnight ago before coming off the bench last week after Timpano opted to name an unchanged eleven.
He will undoubtedly provide the Wolves with added firepower in their must-win trip to Rockdale.
Anything but a win for Wollongong (34 points) could see their top-five hopes go up in flames as they look to close the gap on fifth placed Sydney Olympic (34 points), who lead the Wolves by four on goal difference. 
It's a predicament the Illawarra club has been in for the better part of the last month of competition. 
Wollongong have responded to that pressure with four straight NSW NPL wins. 
"The character and belief of the squad under pressure has been a fantastic," Timpano said.
"Away from that, the tactical side of things took a while to gel but since it has, we've played really pleasingly." 
Wollongong beat Rockdale 2-0 when the two clubs met at WIN Stadium earlier this season. 
"It was one of the most complete performances we have put together this season against one of the most experienced teams in the competition," Timpano said.

"We are expecting another tough match this time around but at the moment we don't fear anyone. It shows how well we have done over the past month and particularly in the way we've played."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antelmi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montgomery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Matts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockdale City Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timpano</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic (34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ilinden Sports Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolves</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Antelmi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Timpano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong (34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Montgomery</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Wolves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
