<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424941342260545</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/dane-pilcher-guilty-corinne-henderson-murder-townsville/8766294</url>
  <title>Former soldier Dane Andrew Pilcher found guilty of murdering ex-girlfriend in Townsville with kitchen knife</title>
  <content>
Former soldier Dane Andrew Pilcher has been found guilty of murdering his ex-partner at her apartment in Idalia, a suburb of Townsville, in north Queensland in September 2015.

Pilcher sat slumped in the dock throughout two-week trial at the Townsville Supreme Court, maintaining his innocence.
The former soldier told the court he broke into the apartment to confront Ms Henderson after seeing pictures on social media with the man she was rumoured to be seeing, Dwayne Wickham.
He described climbing an air-conditioner and kicked through the kitchen window, and was bleeding profusely when Ms Henderson first saw him.
He claimed Ms Henderson stood in the living area holding a knife and he acted in self-defence.
But today a jury took just four hours to convict him of murder, dismissing his claims.
Pilcher stood expressionless rocking on his heels as the verdict was read out to the court.
His father swore from the back of the court room as Ms Henderson's distraught family cried and hugged each other.
'I am pretty sure she's dead.'

Police bodycam vision played to the court shows Ms Henderson dead on the floor of her bedroom.
The jury also heard a recording of the triple-0 call Pilcher made on the night. He told the operator "I have killed my ex-partner."
"She is not moving at all I am pretty sure she is dead.
"There is blood everywhere, blood everywhere ... it is everywhere.
"Oh my God what have I f***ing done?"
Pilcher did not answer when the operator asked if there had been a "confrontation", nor did he ask for an ambulance.
The vision also shows her boyfriend, Dwayne Wickham, hiding in another room, emerging when police arrive.

Case about 'sexual jealousy'

Prosecutor Michael Cowen QC told the court there were a few "societal myths" at play in the defence case, some of which belong "back in the Victorian era".
"'If I can't have you, nobody will' [is] really what this case is about, sexual jealousy," he said.
The court heard from more than 40 witnesses, including Pilcher's ex-wife, whom he called on the night Ms Henderson was killed.

In his closing address, defence lawyer Harvey Walters said his client had no intention of killing Ms Henderson.
He told the jury, his client was drunk at the time, with a blood alcohol reading of 0.162, and that he had not thought through the consequences of what he was doing.
Mr Walters said if Pilcher had gone to Ms Henderson's apartment to kill her, he had gone "terribly unprepared".
"Instead of buying a can of Red Bull at the BP, why not buy a wheel spanner... a can of fuel to incinerate her?" he said in court.
Mr Walters argued Pilcher had acted in self-defence after Ms Henderson first attacked him with a kitchen knife.
"Someone who's defending themselves can't be expected to weigh the amount of force necessary" to do so, Mr Walters told the court, saying Pilcher did not have the benefit of "a leisurely consideration".
Mr Walters disputed prosecution claims Ms Henderson had been stabbed more than 20 times, and said there were only two stab wounds with the rest being "mere cuts".
But Mr Cowen said Pilcher's claim the pair "wrestled" over the knife was "nonsense", given his larger size and relative fitness.
"She cannot have her hands on that knife when it's going through her shoulder... slashing across her back (and) damaging two ribs," Mr Cowen said.
In his testimony, Pilcher said the pair had met in late 2013, when they were both working on a fly-in, fly-out mine site.
"We loved each other," he said. "We were infatuated with each other, perhaps obsessive."
Mr Pilcher has been remanded in custody and will be sentenced later this month.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cowen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwayne Wickham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Idalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Henderson</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-19</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Andrew Pilcher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilcher</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pilcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cowen QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Walters</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
