<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425199040303032</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/the-luteru-brothers-are-shaking-up-the-john-i-dent-cup-with-wests-20170804-gxp5lq.html</url>
  <title>Luteru brothers feeling right at home at Wests</title>
  <content>
They're the three brothers belting out hits in front of adoring crowds and no, they aren't the Bee Gees.
Brothers Junior, Charlie and TP Luteru may not be chart toppers but they're certainly making an impact for Wests in the John I Dent Cup.Photo: Jamila Toderas
All three will line up for the Lions when they meet Queanbeyan in the elimination semi-final at Viking Park on Sunday.
Middle brother Charlie and Junior were born in Samoa while TP was born in Auckland, and a do-or-die semi-final clash in Canberra has been a long time coming.

Brought up in a family of six boys, the trio quickly turned to rugby - a passion that continued to grow as they attended Wesley College, the school that produced Jonah Lomu.
Junior is the oldest at 33 and was the first to cross the Tasman in 2012 to don the blue and maroon jumper.

The winger was set to retire two years later and made the call to Charlie, who had found himself playing in Dubbo, to entice him to the capital.
TP followed this year and has established himself as Wests' starting hooker.
"I got a call from Junior when I was in Dubbo," Charlie said.
"He wanted me to play one final season with him before he retired and that was four years ago.
"It's been a long journey and it's really exciting to do it as a family."
All three have earned representative honours in New Zealand provincial side Counties Manukau's age grade teams. 
Junior also played for Taranaki in New Zealand's provincial top flight, while youngest brother TP has pulled on the jersey for the Chiefs' junior sides and the Samoan Under 20s.
The family moved to Auckland when Junior and Charlie were still young but all three brothers are immensely proud of their roots.
Ingrained in their upbringing was a strong Christian culture and the trio bow their heads in prayer before every game.
"Each of us have our own rituals but we are all connected to God," Charlie said.
"Each one of us say our own prayers before heading onto the field, we were all raised up in a Christian church so religion is very big in our family."
Wests face a do-or-die clash this weekend when they run out to face Queanbeyan with the loser exiting the finals.
The side has received a welcome boost with former Brumbies fly-half Nick Jooste starting to hit some form after a long injury layoff.
Junior said while the squad was disappointed to have dropped some crucial points, they were proud of the way they had performed so far.
"We've had some really good games but then some that we really let slip," Junior said.
"All in all it's been a really good season though, certainly the best since I have been here, on and off the field."
JOHN I DENT CUP FINALS
Saturday: Major semi-final: Royals v Tuggeranong Vikings at Viking Park, 3.25pm
Sunday: Minor semi-final: Wests v Queanbeyan Whites at Viking Park, 3.15pm
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>TP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesley College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taranaki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubbo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TP Luteru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bee Gees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonah Lomu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOHN I DENT CUP FINALS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong Vikings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Viking Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoan Under 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John I Dent Cup.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counties Manukau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Jooste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Whites</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luteru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
