<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424902687553920</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/17/01/nsw-accountant-stole-500-000-from-clients</url>
  <title>NSW accountant stole $500,000 from clients</title>
  <content>
A former accountant from Lake Macquarie has admitted to misappropriating half a million dollars from his clients for his own purposes.
Nicholas James Ellis, a former accountant and financial adviser from Valentine south of Newcastle, pleaded guilty at the Downing Centre District Court in Sydney on Friday to charges of fraudulently obtaining client funds in 2009.
Ellis admitted sending 10 letters to a number of his clients through his company Tura Pty Limited which were designed to raise investment funds to purchase a hotel in Tura, the Australian Securities and Investments Commission said in a statement on Friday.
But the letters contained false and misleading statements and Ellis made off with more than $500,000 for his own purposes, ASIC said.
ASIC banned Ellis from providing financial services for six years in 2013 when it discovered misconduct which took place from 2009 to 2010.
He was found guilty of making dishonest statements after an elderly client invested $200,000 of their superannuation only to have him pay off credit card debts and purchase personal assets.
The Commonwealth Director of Public Prosecutions is prosecuting the latest charges and Ellis is scheduled to be sentenced in the NSW District Court on April 26, 2018.

Related Articles

The maximum term of imprisonment for obtaining money by false and misleading statements is five years while fraudulent misappropriation carries a maximum term of seven years in prison.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Director of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas James Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing Centre District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tura Pty Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellis</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
