<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425207630237793</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834170/hmas-wollongong-makes-rare-visit/?cs=12</url>
  <title>The ship the Royal Australian Navy named after Wollongong will be given freedom to the city this month</title>
  <content>
Welcome home: HMAS Wollongong will be visiting the city she is named after this month during a three day visit. Navy photo.

HMAS Wollongong is visiting the city she is named after this month.
The Armidale Class Patrol Boat will be given freedom to the city and the crew will take part in two official ceremonies.

HMAS Wollongong will arrive on August 25 following considerable work by Wollongong RSL Sub Branch president Peter Poulton.
Also involved has been treasurer Derek Howard, his son Petty Officer Brett Howard, of HMAS Creswell, Lieutenant Commander Scott Rivett, of the Hydrographic Office, and Paul Mac from the Figtree RSL Bowling Club.

On August 26 a ceremonial sunset will take place on the second green of the bowling club at 5pm the evening before HMAS Wollongong is granted freedom to the city. The Saturday night ceremony will involve a a volley of shots as well as simulated canon fire as the evening gun.

That freedom to the city ceremony will start at MacCabe Park at 10.45am on Sunday August 27 before the crew march to Crown Street Mall for a challenge from the chief of police and Wollongong Lord Mayor Gordon Bradbery 
The RAN Band will be involved along with the Australian Navy Cadets from TS Albatross who've been invited by HMAS Wollongong's commander Lieutenant Commander Scott Wilson. The naval cadets are celebrating their 70th anniversary and will be holding a ball on October 21.
HMAS Wollongong is the third navy ship to carry the name. The second was granted freedom to the city but Mr Poulton discovered that did not carry over when it was decomissioned. So he and Lieutenant Commander Scott Rivett spent the last two years working towards this month's event.
Mr Poulton attended HMAS Wollongong's naming in Fremantle and her commissioning in Sydney in 2007. "I am passionate about bringing her here and giving her and her crew the freedom to the city because she is named after the city we live in. And because of its role and the way it carries out its duties I think the city should acknowledge the work of the men and women who service on her."

"They carry out a very important role in protecting our borders"

Mr Poulton said he was ecstatic when he received confirmation HMAS Wollongong was coming for a three day visit and Wollongong City Council was giving her the freedom of entry to the city.
"I am ecstatic for the ships company and the Navy that due recognition is being given to the ship. And I am sure for the general community they will enjoy this once in a lifetime opportunity to see a ceremonial sunset. It is open to the public."

Mr Poulton understands the crew is interested in giving talks at local schools on the Monday.
HMAS Wollongong border security patrol boat statistics:

HMAS Wollongong is one of the Royal Australian Navy's 13 Armidale Class Patrol Boats and two Cape Class Patrol Boats.
Commanded by Lieutenant Commander Scott Wilson she is part of the Australian Border Force and is primarily engaged in fisheries protection, immigration, customs and drug law enforcement operations.
In the event of war her task would be to control the waters close to the Australian mainland.
Armidale Class Patrol Boats are highly capable and versatile warships which are able to conduct a wide variety of missions and tasks.
HMAS Wollongong has a crew of 21 and a range of 3,000 nautical miles at 12 knots and a maximum speed of about 25 knots. She weighs in at 300 tonnes, is 56.8 metres long and has a beam of 9.7 metres.
She is equipped with high-definition navigational radar, high and ultra high frequency communications equipment, gyro compasses and echo sounder. She is also fitted with a satellite navigation system that enables the ship's position to be determined with great accuracy.
Related stories:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Lord Mayor Gordon Bradbery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong RSL Sub Branch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Street Mall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAN Band</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday August 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armidale Class Patrol Boats</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Border Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Creswell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Poulton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MacCabe Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant Commander Scott Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Class Patrol Boats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Navy's 13 Armidale Class Patrol Boats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figtree RSL Bowling Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Wollongong</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TS Albatross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derek Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Navy Cadets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant Commander Scott Rivett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Poulton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant Commander Scott Rivett, of the Hydrographic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petty Officer Brett Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
