<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425456738345432</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/mine-relics-japanese-gardens-and-more-these-ipswich-sites-were-made-for-walking-20170804-gxp5p9.html</url>
  <title>Mine relics, Japanese gardens and other Ipswich sites made for walking</title>
  <content>
​Ipswich is home to an interesting and diverse array of bush, garden and city walks that are well worth checking out, all of them less than an hour's drive from Brisbane CBD.
From lakeside sculpture walks to Japanese gardens and a Jurassic forest with mine relics, here are eight of the best:

This stunning bushwalk combines nature, views and history with walking and bike trails that take in the relics of Ipswich's iconic Blackstone Castle and old mines as well as sweeping district vistas. 

Taking its name from the striking white rocky outcrop that is of Indigenous cultural significance, this reserve has tracks ranging from five minutes to six hours, including lookouts and boardwalks. 

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Ipswich's CBD is awash with grand heritage-listed buildings - churches, halls, colleges and government buildings - that are all an easy stroll from each other, with cafes en route. 

A tract of preserved bushland over the top of sealed-off mine tunnels right in the heart of Ipswich city, featuring a Jurassic forest with dinosaur prints, mine relics and water towers to climb. 

Few but the locals know about this splendid sprawl of botanic gardens with lily ponds, historic buildings, an old well and five different easy walks for all ages and abilities to enjoy. 

This quirky lakeside walk deep in Springfield suburbia is a great one for kids with scooters and bikes and an easy walk for all ages - look out for the giant sun lounge and crocodile sculptures. 

This gorgeous Japanese garden lies within the confines of historic Queens Park and makes a great spot for a contemplative stroll - combine it with a wander through Ipswich Nature Centre. 

Just outside of Ipswich CBD is this peaceful boardwalk circuit that meanders through the largest remnant of swamp tea-tree in Australia, home to eastern grey kangaroos and green tree frogs. 
This article originally appeared at .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurassic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackstone Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Nature Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
