<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425757386061589</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/israel-crown-prince-netanyahu-under-fire/8776338</url>
  <title>Netanyahu woes deepen as Israeli Prime Minister's son sued over crude Facebook post</title>
  <content>
The eldest son of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has been threatened with a libel suit after a run of bad behaviour including a crude social media post.

Key points:

Molad organisation will sue Netanyahu over Facebook posts relating to Molad's funding
His post targeted children of former leaders Ehud Olmert, Shimon Peres and Ariel Sharon
Benjamin Netanyahu faces multiple corruption allegations

Yair Netanyahu, 26, hit the tabloids last weekend when a neighbour posted an account of how the prime minister's son refused to pick up after the Netanyahu family dog at a public park and then, when confronted, gave the neighbour the finger.
He then lashed out on Facebook at a website run by a liberal think tank that detailed what it said was his lavish lifestyle at taxpayers' expense.
In the post, Mr Netanyahu alleged the site is funded by what he claimed are foreign interests, referring indirectly to the dovish New Israel Fund, which he renamed the "Israel Destruction Fund".
He signed the post with emojis of a middle finger and a pile of excrement.
The Times of Israel said on Thursday that the Molad organisation, which runs the site, served the younger Netanyahu with a notice of intent to sue.
The notice reportedly said that his posts "had no iota of truth to them" and that Molad stopped receiving money from the NIF last year.
Yair Netanyahu was also publicly rebuked by the children of former Israeli leader Ehud Olmert, who were targeted in his post, along with the children of former leaders Shimon Peres and Ariel Sharon.
Mr Netanyahu claimed in his post that the other leaders' children did not come under the same scrutiny as him.
His claims included an insinuation that one of Mr Olmert's sons had an "interesting relationship with a Palestinian man" that affected national security.
Mr Olmert's son Ariel fired back on Facebook, denying he was gay, dismissing the claims as a fabrication and accusing the younger Netanyahu of "racism and homophobia".
Ariel Olmert added that he works for a living, never slept in the Prime Minister's residence and "on principle, try to pick up my dog's doody".
His older brother Shaul then chimed in, calling Yair Netanyahu a fascist thug.
A family under scrutiny

The online exchanges have revived criticism of the Netanyahu family's perceived hedonism and sense of entitlement, .
Israeli police on Thursday disclosed that Benjamin Netanyahu is suspected of fraud, breach of trust and bribes in a pair of cases, just as his son was being pilloried in the press.
Yair Netanyahu has also been questioned - though not as a suspect - about a corruption scandal in which his father was asked by police "under caution" about ties to executives in media, international business and Hollywood.
Benjamin Netanyahu and his wife, Sara, are said to have received more than $125,000 worth of cigars and liquor from Hollywood producer Arnon Milchan, who reportedly asked Mr Netanyahu to press the US Secretary of State in a visa matter.
Australian billionaire James Packer has reportedly lavished Yair with gifts that included extended stays at luxury hotels in Tel Aviv, New York and Aspen, Colorado, as well as the use of his private jet and dozens of tickets for concerts by Mr Packer's former fiancee, Mariah Carey.
, since Mr Packer is reportedly seeking Israeli residency status for tax purposes.
The Prime Minister has repeatedly denied any wrongdoing, portraying the accusations as a witch hunt against him and his family by a hostile media.
His office declined to comment on Thursday about the latest affair.
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yair Netanyahu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ariel Sharon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Netanyahu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shimon Peres</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colorado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Packer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel Destruction Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netanyahu</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariah Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yair Netanyahu, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Netanyahu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestinians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ariel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ariel Olmert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Israel Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aspen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tel Aviv</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ehud Olmert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molad</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Times of Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Olmert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnon Milchan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
