<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425894825017384</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/too-businessoriented-to-be-called-sport-australian-codes-are-at-the-crossroads-20170802-gxnq2o.html</url>
  <title>Australian sporting codes at the crossroads</title>
  <content>
Professional sport in Australia is at the crossroads: some have travelled so far down the corporate path, they are too business-oriented to be called a sport.
Others are retreating back along the amateur path, too inherently sport-minded to be considered a business.Photo: Sean Davey
The tortured delay in Cricket Australia reaching a pay deal with its players; the indecision of the Australia Rugby Union in sacking a team; the revolt by stakeholders of Football Federation Australia; rugby league's problems in achieving a functioning independent commission and the AFL's relentless push to be standard-bearers of social equity in the nation are evidence of this confusion.
John Wylie, an investment banker and chair of the Australian Sports Commission, has been active in taking the Olympic sports down the same route as the professional codes, installing businessmen with no elite experience in a sport as chairs.Photo: Michael Dodge
Mining giant Rio Tinto, with its reputation for union-busting tactics, was seen as the ogre in CA's problems in reaching an agreement with the Australian Cricketers Association. CA chair David Peever is a former managing director of Rio Tinto Australia and recruited a Rio Tinto executive and an adviser to assist CA on the pay negotiations.
However, it would be a mistake to assume elite businessmen who take a ruthless approach to dealing with cricketers don't love sport.

Peever, for example, was a frequent attendee at Storm home games until he moved inter-state.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Nevertheless, the brutal negotiations between CA and the ACA and the stratospheric salaries paid has produced the perception that Australia's favourite summer pastime is now more of a business than a sport.Photo: AP
By contrast, the inept leadership of the ARU by former NAB chief executive Cameron Clyne, in failing to cull an Australian Super Rugby team, has pushed the code back to its roots. Rugby union people now prefer to stroll down to a suburban oval to watch a game between amateur teams, while sipping on a beer and eating a hot dog.
Rugby union boasts it has the most corporately qualified and diverse board in Australia, yet the failure of the code, when challenged by the demands of its international partners, exposes it as still too much of a sport to be a business.Photo: Christopher Pearce
Both rugby league and soccer face problems over governance, with demands from stakeholders for more power. The heads of both codes, the ARLC's John Grant and FFA's Steven Lowy, have demonstrated that their business skills have not been enough to achieve corporate stability.
Grant, a former Kangaroo, led a successful IT company but was effectively absent from the game for 20 years. This became an asset when the newly formed ARLC needed an independent chair. The code's stakeholders, none of whom trusted each other, decided that no one could sit on the commission if he/she had been involved with rugby league in any way in the previous three years, apart from being a passive fan. The pendulum swung too far to business and the fans of the code have been seeking a saviour, one with a celebrated past in the sport, since.Photo: Christopher Pearce
Lowy, the chief executive of Westfield's overseas investments, inherited the FFA's chairman's role from his father, Frank, one of Australia's richest individuals. The A-League clubs want greater representation on the congress that elects the board. Their owners are losing money but believe they have the gravitas of a Manchester United.
Ironically, that great bastion of sport/business ethics, FIFA, is sending out emissaries to end the sport's civil war.Photo: AFL Media
The AFL has its own links to Rio Tinto via recently retired chairman Mike Fitzpatrick and former AFL commissioner Chris Lynch, the mining giant's CFO. The code boasts a national leadership role in promoting gender equity, Indigenous and refugee causes and gay rights. A cynic might suggest this is done with an eye on government grants. The AFL chairman, Richard Goyder, said, when replacing Fitzpatrick, "The AFL is more than a business because of the way that it reaches into all these communities."
Goyder is the outgoing chief executive of Wesfarmers and the first chair of the AFL who has not played the game at the elite level. A former Wesfarmers chairman, Bob Every, sits on the board of Cricket Australia.
The common thread in many of the appointments to the boards of professional sports is the promotion of independence over competence.
In the rush to recruit top business people, they have neglected what might be called the affection and affinity for a sport.
Furthermore, many of the corporate heavyweights are not accustomed to the intense - sometimes personal - scrutiny from the media. What might work in the corporate world doesn't necessarily translate to the world of sport.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Peever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzpatrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Goyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Wylie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Clyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Dodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Davey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Every</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARLC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIKE FITZPATRICK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesfarmers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARLC's John Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA's Steven Lowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pearce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sports Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Rugby Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
