<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425289234617781</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834793/merrick-not-in-a-rush-to-strike/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Merrick not in a rush to strike</title>
  <content>
PATIENT: Jets coach Ernie Merrick (second from right) is prepared to bide his time to find the right marquee player. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

ERNIE Merrick will monitor the family situation of the Jets' initial marquee target, but the experienced coach says he has been "in the game too long to put all my eggs in one basket".

The Jets had been close to finalising a deal with a South American midfielder, only for talks to break down due to a health issue with the player's wife.
"We have always had a shortlist of three, who we will continue to talk to," Merrick said on Friday. "As well as a shortlist, we have another five on an extended list. We are still 10 or 11 weeks out from the season and we are very confident that we will bring in a top-quality player."
Merrick confirmed that the players shortlisted were attackers, but not all were South American.

"The top three players we identified, it is very hard to separate them," he said. "It is about getting value for money: is he a creator, is he a front-four player, is he a goal-scorer, is he a combination of all of those, is he good in one-on-one situations...the three players all offer that to some extent. Some better in some areas."

"One player is a No.10, whose passing forward is outstanding and he takes free kicks like you wouldn't believe. "Another is a goal-scoring machine. He is limited to playing as a right or central striker. Out of the three of them, I would be very happy with any. To think that we will miss out on the best is completely incorrect."
Merrick has confidence in the current strike force, which includes recent arrivals Roy O'Donovan and Dimi Petratos, and is prepared to be patient to ensure they get the right player.
"If I can get another striker, I would be pretty set that we have a full squad ready to go this season," he said. "We have good cover at the back, we have good holding midfielders, we have a good four up front who will play against Adelaide. To bring in another one to put them under pressure would be good. Plus a few of the youngsters Mario Shadow, Kosta Petratos and Joe Champness are pushing hard as well. We are not in a rush. When it is right it is right. We are really doing our homework. When we get close and the money is right, then I do even more due diligence to say that is exactly who I want." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mario Shadow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimi Petratos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrick</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie Merrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kosta Petratos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy O'Donovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Champness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
