<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425074486249313</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/food/qld-taste/stefan-opens-new-jojos-opens-at-south-brisbane/news-story/248ab641db5f3c9c8914b96a0140f9c8</url>
  <title>Jo-Jo</title>
  <content>
HAIRDRESSING magnate Stefan Ackerie and partner Rose King have unveiled the 2.0 version of their iconic Brisbane restaurant Jo-Jo™s.

The couple closed their beloved Queen St eatery in March after almost 40 years, moving it to a new home alongside the Stefan Hair headquarters and Sky Needle on Melbourne St, at South Brisbane.

"For me to have kept going with Jo-Jo's (in the city) I would have had to really gut it, gut everything," Mr Ackerie said. "It needed new escalators, it needed a new lift, it needed to take the walls out and then you had to rebuild it with new, state-of-the-art technology. So the options we had were Jo-Jo's or this (the new restaurant)."

Channelling the Mediterranean with tumbled marble stone floors, coffered ceilings, white walls and a courtyard all housed in a lofty industrial building, which will soon also include the couple's homewares, furniture, giftware and fashion store The Bach Living, the new Jo-Jo's feels fresh, bright and almost resort-like.

Several features from the original restaurant have been integrated into the new space, while a wall of black and white photos shows some of the institution's most famous customers, including tennis hero Pat Rafter, Broncos coach Wayne Bennett, rugby league legend Wally Lewis and golfing great Greg Norman.

The multiple kitchens of the original Jo-Jo's have been sidelined for a single Mod Oz menu featuring the restaurant's favourite dishes as voted by the public, including grilled king prawns and lamb ragu, plus new dishes such as burgers, lamb skewers and calamari.

"This is the right time for this part of the world and I think Jo-Jo's, where it was, is no longer the right time," Mr Ackerie said.

"Brisbane grew away from the city. People can't park, to get there is a chore. All my friends are saying, 'Oh great, now I can come to your place'."

Mr Ackerie believes the 200-seat restaurant will become an "icon for South Bank or West End".

"It's a very exciting chapter of my life to be able to do things like this," he said. "At any stage of your life is great, but to be able to do it in your twilight is amazing."

In other restaurant news, Brisbane fine dining stalwart Il Centro has officially been bought by Cha Cha Char boss John Kilroy.

Restaurateur Andy Georges and wife Marcia ran the Italian CBD favourite for 25 years and will still have a presence under Mr Kilroy's ownership.

"I won't be changing Il Centro; not the staff, not the menu or Andy's presence," Mr Kilroy said.

"Why change something that is not broken and one that has been run hands-on by one of Australia's most respected and successful restaurateurs for the last 25 years? It doesn't need to be changed."

The Georges will focus their attentions on their other CBD venture Mr & Mrs G Riverbar.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bach Living</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo-Jo</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kilroy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Rafter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs G Riverbar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cha Cha Char</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Needle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefan Ackerie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kilroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mod Oz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ackerie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefan Hair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Il Centro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
