<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424941342260490</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/cairns-in-line-for-12m-spinal-injury-and-rehabilitation-centre-after-building-better-regions-fund-win/news-story/3dbfceceb9fd7c892cd58fe354b1d69e</url>
  <title>Spinal centre taps $12m into Cairns</title>
  <content>
SPINAL injury sufferers will no longer have to travel to Brisbane for treatment with construction of a $12 million specialist service centre at Cairns North starting in November.
Spinal Life Australia was one of four Far North organisations winning bids under the Federal Government's Building Better Regions Fund.
The organisation has already bought the land at the corner of Lake and Smith Sts and will spend $8.8 million on construction, split evenly through its own contribution and the federal spend.
The facility will be the first of its kind in regional Australia, offering supported transitional, respite and holiday accommodation, specialised allied health services, a hydrotherapy pool and gymnasium.
It will employ about 80 direct staff after opening and, according to Spinal Life CEO Michael Powell, contribute $196 million into the local economy over the life of the project.
"There will also be training opportunities for personal support workers and allied health professionals across the region, which is particularly important for remote indigenous communities.," Mr Powell said.
"When someone sustains a spinal cord injury, they often have to spend many months away from home, as Queensland's only spinal injuries unit is based in Brisbane.
"This centre will allow people who experience an injury or physical disability to leave hospital sooner and return to their family and community connections, with support to assist with this transition and into the future."
Mr Entsch said the project would be "life-changing" for the 15 Far North Queenslanders on average who sustain spinal injuries each year.
Mapoon Aboriginal Council was also awarded about $1.5 million of a $1.6 million cost project to build accommodation for community members in Cairns.
The building, located in Westcourt, will be primarily used for Cape York residents in Cairns for medical treatment.
"For a lot of these people, this might be the first time they've been in the big smoke," Mr Entsch said.
"This at least gives them that level of familiarity, security and safety."
Douglas Shire Council will receive $1.125 million and contribute $375,000 of its own money to upgrade the Noah Creek Bridge at Cape Tribulation.
"It's a critical link north over the river and means they can put in a decent piece of infrastructure and remove weight limits," Mr Entsch said.
The Cairns Aquarium will receive $1 million towards a $2 million reef research centre.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government's Building Better Regions Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spinal Life CEO Michael Powell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapoon Aboriginal Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Douglas Shire Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith Sts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noah Creek Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Aquarium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westcourt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Powell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Tribulation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
