<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425418083639064</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/turnbull-recalls-yunupingu-at-garma/news-story/9c881adb1f3cce4046b1b84e0e89f925</url>
  <title>Turnbull remembers Yunupingu at Garma</title>
  <content>
Garma Festival has opened with grief at the loss of late indigenous musician Dr G Yunupingu, and with hope that Australia can pave a future towards reconciliation and constitutional reform.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull, Opposition Leader Bill Shorten and hundreds of other guests joined hands at Gulkula's Bunggul grounds in northeast Arnhem Land on Friday, in remembrance of Australia's most prominent indigenous musician, who died last week following a long battle with kidney and liver disease.
"He brought the Yolngu language to all Australians, his music will be forever cherished," Mr Turnbull said on Friday.
His wife Lucy wept with grief-stricken female Gumatj clan members after a minute's silence was held and Yolngu traditional owners sang one of Dr G Yunupingu's songs about their gurtha, or sacred fire.
Senior Gumatj man Djunga Djunga Yunupingu spoke about his late nephew's power to bridge cultures through his music.
"He was an Australian man and a maralitja man who sung in our language for your ears," he said.
Men, women and children danced and sung to the sounds of clap sticks and the didgeridoo, before Djunga Djunga Yunupingu asked the political leaders for help in achieving "two laws, two people, one country."
Gumatj clan leader Galarrwuy Yunupingu pointed to the Referendum Council's recent Uluru Statement from the Heart and report, which call for changes to the nation's founding document to allow an indigenous advisory body in parliament, a treaty-making mechanism and a reconciliation commission.
"At Uluru we started a fire. A fire that we hope burns bright for Australia," he said.
"We live side by side but we're not yet united... this is the perfect place for us to find our path to a settlement."
Mr Shorten has called for a bipartisan joint parliamentary select committee to finalise a referendum question on the Aboriginal voice proposal, putting pressure on Mr Turnbull to commit government support.
"I know you've heard a lot of balanda (whitefella) speeches, and then very little happens," the Labor leader said.
"I understand that people feel politics has failed them, and I think people have the right to be cynical, disappointed and perhaps frustrated with the lack of progress in the past."
Mr Turnbull said he was heartened to see that the Yolngu concept of makarrata, or coming together after a struggle, was the theme of the four-day festival, and stressed the long path ahead would be easier to tread if "we bring all Australians along with us".
"Our journey of reconciliation is made up of many steps, practical and symbolic," he said.
"From little things, big things grow."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulkula's Bunggul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Djunga Djunga Yunupingu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolngu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galarrwuy Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumatj</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
