<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426105278419073</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4833470/world-cup-dream-for-newcastle-top-graders/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>World Cup dream for Newcastle top graders</title>
  <content>
SQUADS: Maitland's Liam Faughlin and Western Suburbs' James Elias playing against each other at Harker Oval on June 18. Picture: Marina Neil

Less than six weeks ago James Elias and Liam Faughlin were playing first grade against each other in Newcastle.

In a few months time they could be lining up at the World Cup.
Elias and Faughlin were named on Friday in the extended Lebanon and Scotland squads respectively ahead of the year-ending international tournament taking place across Australia, New Zealand and Papua New Guinea.   
It means the Western Suburbs utility and Maitland outside back may get the chance to grace one of the sport's biggest stages. 
"Obviously it's a privilege to make the 40-man squad, but hopefully I can get on the field at the World Cup," Elias said.

"If not I'll be there supporting them anyway."

Lebanon have been handed one of the toughest World Cup assignments, which could see the Nelson Bay junior and Raymond Terrace-based teacher's aid facing off with hosts and defending champions Australia as well as England and France. 

"It was a bit of a jaw-dropping moment finding out we were playing Australia," the 23-year-old said. 

"I can only imagine the crowds, they would be pretty massive, even playing England as well. It'll be a one-off experience that money can't buy."

But for Elias, part of the Knights system for around six seasons from under 16s through to reserve grade last year, the real challenge has simply been getting there.
Not only has he recently overcome season-ending injuries, ankle and knee in back-to-back campaigns, the Corlette-based player helped Lebanon qualify for the upcoming competition in South Africa in 2015 and breakthrough for the country where his paternal grandparents were born.   
"It was one of the best experiences I've had playing rugby league," Elias said.

"It's just different playing with your country. A different sort of meaning than club footy. Players that don't normally stand out at club footy lift a bit more for the national team.

"There was big talk about it as well, being 17 years since we last made the World Cup. It's a whole cultural thing and the boys get on the back of it. It's pretty special."
Elias, who can swing between centre, second-row and lock, met with coach Brad Fittler and the Lebanon squad last month. NRL players such as Robbie Farah, Mitchell Moses and Tim Mannah have now been added to the mix. 
"It could work with you or against you [being versatile]," he said. "I don't mind both positions and I'm just happy to get on the park. If I get put on I'll play wherever." 

Elias has four Tests next to his name since 2014, including one against Malta in Sydney earlier this year.
Faughlin, the 2013 Newcastle rookie of the year, is uncapped for Scotland but played the University World Cup in Sydney last month. 

In round 14 fixtures Wests are away to Cessnock, Maitland host Macquarie (Saturday), Kurri travel to meet Central and Lakes are at home to Souths (Sunday).  
SQUAD UPDATES
Elias will play second-row for Wests when the competition leaders travel to meet the fifth-placed Goannas at Cessnock Sportsground on Saturday. Rosellas skipper Mark Taufua (ribs) was ruled out for a second straight week after failing a fitness test at training on Friday night and David Dryden will be the replacement up front. Cessnock welcome Macquarie recruit Logan Edwards into halfback but have lost prop Kurt Warden (ankle) and utility Cody Brooks (broken finger).   
Faughlin won't be playing for Maitland at Coronation Oval on Saturday when the cellar dwellers hope to turnaround consecutive two-point losses to second-placed Macquarie, who have Randall Briggs taking over at five-eighth from injured brother Scott.    
Lakes coach Dean Noonan has shifted in-form Cody Robbins to No.6 and recalled Jamie Ghoulmieh at fullback for Sunday's crucial clash with sixth-placed South Newcastle at Cahill Oval. Just four points separate them on either side of the top five with three games remaining.  
And at St John Oval regular winger Jared Nott will again slot into hooker for third-placed Central Newcastle, who meet Kurri Kurri on Sunday without Mitch Williams (concussion) and Jake Davis (knee). Bulldogs coach Ron Griffiths said star playmaker Terence Seu Seu remained sidelined with a knee injury.   

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosellas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Farah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cahill Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Taufua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Nott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Suburbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cody Brooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randall Briggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebanon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Elias</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Faughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elias</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Ghoulmieh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coronation Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Dryden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Fittler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Bays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Moses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goannas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faughlin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Suburbs' James Elias</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cody Robbins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock Sportsground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harker Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corlette-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raymond Terrace-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terence Seu Seu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Warden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland's Liam Faughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
