<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424902687553969</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/reef-unleashes-at-pro-junior-event-in-california/3208977/</url>
  <title>Reef unleashes at pro junior event in California</title>
  <content>
SURFING: Young gun Reef Heazlewood has further proved his potential with some eye-catching performances at a pro junior event in California.
The Moffat Beach teen stormed into the semi-finals at the Vans US Open of Surfiing at Huntington Beach, by winning a four-surfer quarter-final.
The Australia/Oceania pro junior title holder claimed a two-wave total of 13.50 to finish ahead of American John Mel, who had the wave of the day.
"I was having a lot of fun out there and I'm stoked to win that heat," Heazlewood said.
"I've got a great a support system here with my girlfriend Summer (Macedo), mom, as well as my team manager, so it's a good crew and means a lot to have them all here," he told World Surf League."
Heazlewood, who was due to surf in the latter stages of the competition on Friday night, has competed in some open men's Qualifying Series events this year and will look to ramp things up on that circuit in 2018.
"It's been grindy, but I'm enjoying it. It's such a good experience and looking forward to what happens next year on the QS," he said
He's also due to compete at the world junior championships at Kiama in February.
The pro junior competition at Huntington is among a host of surfing events running concurrently events there.
Avoid the area if you can with significant delays reported
Coast's newest eatery opens bringing Italian to the beach
Teen spends big on mum's partner's credit card
Coast researchers welcome govt inspection of white spot studies
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moffat Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Surf League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American John Mel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heazlewood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qualifying Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vans US Open of Surfiing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia/Oceania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Heazlewood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
