<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425461033312744</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/gws-giants-boss-dave-matthews-open-to-more-friday-night-afl-in-canberra-20170803-gxotqq.html</url>
  <title>Giants boss Dave Matthews open to more Friday night AFL in Canberra</title>
  <content>
The Greater Western Sydney Giants are open to another Friday night game in Canberra but boss Dave Matthews is confident the supporter base is strong enough to pack out Manuka Oval for any fixture.
The Giants have fuelled an AFL revival in Canberra and are expecting a huge crowd when they host the Melbourne Demons at Manuka Oval on Saturday.Photo: Jamila Toderas
It follows a sell-out crowd of 14,408 that crammed into Manuka Oval to watch the Giants take on the reigning premiers Western Bulldogs on a Friday night in April.
Crowds have flocked to see the Giants in Canberra and Matthews believes the opponent doesn't matter as much anymore, hopeful fans feel enough of a connection to the club to keep turning up.
The AFL has written to clubs and key stakeholders to begin work on constructing the fixture for the 2018 season but Matthews has no immediate plans for which games he'd like to have in Canberra.
The Giants boss says the club is aware of "some weekend and slots to avoid" in the capital as they look to capitalise on more bumper crowds at Manuka Oval.

"[A Friday night game in Canberra] was a real success. The lights are fantastic so we'd welcome it," Matthews said.
"We'd address it two ways - we'd look at where do we want games placed first and then who are the opponents that we could have.
"What matters most now hopefully to the people of Canberra is that the Giants are there and the Giants are playing good football. That's why the membership base has grown. 
"In many respects, the opponents don't matter as much now as they did in the first couple of years. But that said, to get the reigning premiers on a Friday night shows that the AFL is really committed to working with the ACT government and the Giants to develop good fixturing."
The Giants are six years into their 10-year, $23 million partnership with the ACT government to play three premiership fixtures and a pre-season match in Canberra per year.
Matthews believes the government would feel vindicated in their massive investment in the club as the Giants continue to harness the capital's AFL supporter base.
The club and the government are edging closer to starting negotiations about renewing the agreement with upgrades to the venue sorely needed.​
"We're really happy with the way things have panned out so far and I think the ACT government would be vindicated in their decision to enter into a long-term partnership," Matthews said.
"If it happened to sell out [on Saturday] that would be five of the last seven games in Canberra. That's the sort of rapid growth we've been able to work to achieve and it sets us up for a great platform into the future."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthews</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Matthews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
