<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425293529585209</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/breaking-two-trapped-serious-crash-busy-road/3209061/</url>
  <title>BREAKING: Two trapped, serious crash on busy road</title>
  <content>
UPDATE: Crews believe it will take up to half an hour to remove both patients from the cars. 

INITIAL REPORT: Two people are trapped following a two-car crash in Bundaberg. 

Crews are on scene at the head-on smash at the corner of Childers Rd and University Drv outside the airport. 

Early reports suggest one person is conscious and another is unconscious. 

One person has suffered face, leg and pelvis injuries. 

Both are trapped. 

Traffic has been blocked across two lanes and is being diverted through Samuels Rd. 

There have been calls for multiple ambulance units to attend. 

One of the cars is believed to be a Mitsubishi Triton. 

Fire crews are on scene and are helping to remove one person from a car. 

A spokesman for the Queensland Police Service said the crash was called in at 6.15pm.

More to come
Avoid the area if you can with significant delays reported
Coast's newest eatery opens bringing Italian to the beach
Teen spends big on mum's partner's credit card
Coast researchers welcome govt inspection of white spot studies
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
Key buildings and international interest set to be revealed
Check out this weekend's homes open for inspection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundaberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University Drv</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi Triton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Childers Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuels Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
