<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425585587366458</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/health/2017/08/04/19/43/how-new-technology-can-accurately-track-your-fitness-levels</url>
  <title>How new technology can accurately track your fitness levels</title>
  <content>
In the past the most effective way to keep track of your body shape and weight was to step on the scales, use a tape measure or take some unflattering before-and-after photos. 
But these rudimentary methods have been superseded by technology.
A plethora of programs already exist to track calories and kilometres.
Now body monitoring has gone 3D.
Anyone with a smartphone can jump online and create their own digital avatar to precisely compare and track their body measurements and physique over time.
Among the new programs available is Australian-made application MyFiziq.
Users simply download the program on their smartphone and take two full body photos.

Related Articles

Within a minute their own digital avatar pops up on screen.
The virtual clone is also accompanied by measurements of their chest, hips, waist and thighs. 
Developer Vlado Bosanac says the technology helps users easily see if they are actually making progress towards their health goals - from weight loss, muscle gain to toning.
"You can compare last week to this week. It will give the dimensions or millimetre change that may have taken place," he said.
Olympian Michael Klim has been using the program for a few months.
The multiple medal winning athlete turned businessman says keeping in shape is still a top priority for him.
"For me exercising and staying healthy and active is really important so this keeps me accountable that is for sure," he said.
As well as the free MyFiziq app there are several other avatar-type fitness programs now available online.
LaTrobe University Sport and Exercise Researcher Dr Christian Barton says for some tracking technology like this can help kickstart a new fitness regime.
But Dr Barton cautions that digital avatars do not deliver the full picture when it comes to internal markers of wellness. 
"Especially when it comes to something like body composition. There are probably far more important measures of health like blood pressure and blood glucose for example," he said.
But Michael Klim says if a digital clone can help get you off the couch and into the gym - that can only be a good thing.
"If I had this back in the day in the off season I would have kept myself much more accountable. And probably would have come back in better shape."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vlado Bosanac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian Michael Klim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaTrobe University Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MyFiziq</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-made</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Klim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exercise Researcher Dr Christian Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
