<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425418083639005</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/cashed-up-downsizers-driving-strong-luxury-apartment-sales/news-story/86ddaa08a3ba54727d301d724022724b</url>
  <title>Cashed up downsizers driving strong luxury apartment sales - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
SOUTH in South Melbourne has been popular with luxury downsizers.

CASHED-UP Baby Boomers have emerged as the surprise force in Melbourne's luxury apartment market.
Demand for prestige apartments at the top end of the market is spurring developers to combine apartments to create large penthouse-style pads.
RELATED:

Demand for prestige apartments at the top end of the market has prompted developers to combine apartments.

Colliers director of residential Brett Griffith said downsizers were becoming Melbourne's fastest-growing buyer demographic.
Mr Griffith said the buying power of downsizers was evident at the  apartment project, where five of the six available penthouses in the Elenberg Fraser-designed building sold in the first four weeks for prices ranging from $2.5-$2.85 million.
One downsizing family also purchased three adjoining apartments in the development, working
closely with the architects to transform them into an expansive four-bedroom, four-bathroom
home with a 113sq m balcony.

Downsizers have emerged as a strong force in Melbourne's apartment market.

Mr Griffith said downsizers were drawn to this type of development because it ticked a lot of
boxes for them.
"Their decision criteria is markedly different to that of an investor, or a first-home buyer," he said.
"They want sophisticated design, spacious living areas, and top-of-the-line appliances.
"Amenities such as private dining, landscaped gardens and children's play areas for the
grandchildren are also sought-after by this demographic."
Magnolia features an expansive lagoon-shaped pool, private bar and dining rooms, state-of-the-art health centre, and a private cinema.

Downsizers look for developments with good amenities.

In the South Melbourne development, , the two penthouses were the first apartments to sell.
Another three owner occupier buyers snapped up multiple apartments and combined them into large homes measuring 115sq m to 173sq m.
Bluestone director Josh Buxton said the number of amalgamations at SOUTH was a sign
developers would have to carefully consider their product mix moving forward.

Two penthouses at SOUTH were the first apartments to sell at the South Melbourne development.

"It's evident the downsizer market has emerged much stronger than developers have anticipated, with various projects being reconfigured to accommodate the intense demand for penthouse and sub-penthouse apartments," Mr Buxton said.
"You can see with a project like SOUTH, this segment of the market wants quality apartments
and they won't compromise on that, regardless of the cost."
Both SOUTH and Magnolia have recently launched, with limited numbers of one- and two-bedroom apartments remaining.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Buxton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Buxton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baby Boomers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Griffith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downsizers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnolia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elenberg Fraser-designed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Griffith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
