<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425199040303017</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/stan-grant-garma-festival-indigenous-australians-not-invisible/8775850</url>
  <title>Garma: In 2017, the struggle for Indigenous Australians to be seen and heard continues, Stan Grant writes</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

The plane banks right, below me is the Gove Peninsula. This is Arnhem Land. This is Aboriginal land.
The people I see around me are Aboriginal. They run businesses; they teach school.
Here is a culture; a civilisation. Here is language and law. Here the first people of this country are not invisible.

Invisibility. It is the curse of being Indigenous; to be unseen in our own land.
It isn't surprising that most Australians say they have not met an Indigenous person. Why should they?
They have been told that we are not here.
Terra nullius - empty land - is the very foundation of this country.
With the planting of a British flag two centuries ago, the rights of a people who had been here for thousands of generations were extinguished.

External Link:

Avani Dias tweet: Malcolm Turnbull watches as Yolngu officially open Garma 2017
If the "natives" - as they were known - were human at all, they occupied the lowest rung on civilisation's ladder.
My people - the nations of the eastern states - bore the brunt. Within decades of the coming of the whites we were devastated.
Disease and violence wiped out entire populations.
The survivors were herded onto missions and reserves. This was the "smoothing of the dying pillow": Aboriginal people were doomed to extinction.
But we have survived. We are here, and still in 2017 the struggle to be seen, to be heard, continues.
We are not invisible.
This is the message of this year's Garma Festival. It is embodied in a word - a Yolngu word: Makaratta.
It means broadly, to come together after a struggle.
It is that struggle that is at the heart of Garma.

A lot has changed, but still we fall short

Each year leading Indigenous thinkers, politicians, heads of business and industry come together to discuss the future of Australia's first people.
How do we break a cycle of misery, rooted so deep in our history, that holds so many people in its grip?
This has been a monumental year - a year of anniversaries: 25 years since the Mabo High Court decision - among the most significant in our nation's history; 25 years since the Bringing Them Home report revealed the trauma of the stolen generations and led eventually, to former prime minister Kevin Rudd saying "sorry".
It is 50 years since the 1967 referendum, which promised a "fair go" for Indigenous people.
The referendum remains the most successful in Australian history - more than 90 per cent of Australians voted "yes", to count Aboriginal people among the population of this country.
Yes - in 1901 the constitution said Aboriginal people would not be counted.
It also amended the constitution to give the federal government the power to make laws for Indigenous people. As the slogan at time said: "Vote yes for Aborigines they want to be Australians too."
But by 1972 a young generation of black activists reminded this country that they did not feel like Australians - they were aliens in their own land.
Half a century later, the demands of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people - demand for recognition; sovereignty; treaties - remain unfulfilled and so the embassy still stands.
It is true a lot has changed since that time - we have had land-rights legislation - Native Title, Mabo and the apology.
But still, we fall short.
We have never resolved that fundamental question: was it right to claim this land?
How do we heal that wound?
How do achieve reconciliation without justice?

Australia's legal history - our jurisprudence - tells a fascinating story.
It is a story of endless struggle by Indigenous people to prove what we have always known: we are here - this is our land.
Australian law has grappled with this question of Indigenous sovereignty throughout our nation's history.
Was this a "settlement" - as generations of school children, myself included, were told - a "peaceful" settlement? Or was this a conquest?
Did Aboriginal people lose their rights or do those rights remain?
Broken promises, vain hope and thwarted ambition

Court cases in the mid-19th century challenged the idea of British settlement. At the time the rulings were in favour of the crown - British law was the law of the colony and usurped and superseded Aboriginal law.
Other cases persisted. In one the presiding judge said the mere introduction of British law did not extinguish Aboriginal customary law. Justice Willis said "in Australia it is the colonists not the Aborigines [sic] who are the foreigners".
These legal challenges continued into the 20th century.
Successive rulings maintained the legitimacy of the crown but could not extinguish completely the Aboriginal claims.
In one famous case, Justice Blackburn ruled Australia was indeed a "settled colony" that this was a "desert and uncultivated", but he also found that Aboriginal people had a "subtle and elaborate system of law".
As he said "if ever a system could be called a government of laws ... it is shown in the evidence before me".
Of course the most celebrated case of all was Mabo - here the High Court struck down the idea of terra nullius - but it did not assert Aboriginal sovereignty as such.
The ruling found that as people were here this was not an empty land.
British common law recognised the existing native title.
When the flag was planted native title fell to the soil with the laws of the crown; the British brought with them native title as surely as they brought tea.
But the issue of sovereignty is not settled. This was not terra nullius.
Aboriginal people were indeed here with recognisable system of laws and governance. They fought and died defending their land. They are still here today.
If Australia was indeed conquered, then international law tells us that the rights of the so-called conquered people would also still remain.
The Tent Embassy stands as a reminder of sovereignty unrecognised.

The history of Australian politics is littered with broken promises, vain hope and thwarted ambition.
Writing in the newly released book Rightful Place: A Road Map to Recognition, Jackie Huggins and Rod Little chronicle the history of the Indigenous political struggle.
They go back to the early 20th century tracing a long list of petitions to government, protests of mourning, statements and declarations.
There have been promises of treaty - not delivered - and aborted self-determination.
Huggins and Little are co-chairs of the National Congress of Australia's First Peoples - Australia's only elected national Indigenous body - and have had their own struggles with government.
As they write: "First Peoples representative structures of the past and present have usually not been valued or respected by governments or politicians - at least not in any enduring way."
The essence of Makaratta: making peace

This year, Indigenous people spoke at the heart of the nation: Uluru.
The Uluru Statement called for a "voice" to be enshrined in the Australian Constitution - a representative body.
The Australian Parliament faces a challenge to make good on that demand.
But politics moves slowly. Politicians are cautious and Indigenous people wait still.
As Yothu Yindi - a Yolngu rock band - famously wrote in their hit song Treaty: "All those talking politicians."
Gallarwuy Yunupingu, the great Gumatj leader and former Australian of the Year who hosts the Garma Festival, says it is time for a final settlement.
It is the essence of Makaratta: making peace.
It is what Garma is about; the First Peoples extending a hand to those who have come after.
As Gallarwuy writes in the foreword to Rightful Place: "An action that says to the world that from now on and forever the dispute is settled; that dispute no longer exists; it is finished."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Native Title</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bringing Them Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Willis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gove Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mabo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makaratta</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yothu Yindi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolngu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Road-map</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Little</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mabo High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aborigines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Blackburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Peoples</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avani Dias</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie Huggins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumatj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rightful Place</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallarwuy Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huggins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Congress of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallarwuy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tent Embassy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
