<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426105278419121</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/new-report-identifies-sas-most-consistent-investment-hotspots/news-story/97b23cb89cb70e32d9e2bbeedd4b8946</url>
  <title>New report identifies SA's most consistent investment hotspots - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
South Australian suburb Campbelltown has been identified as one of SA's most consistent suburbs for sales. Campbelltown resident Prudence Chang and her children Nicole, Phyllis and Darren enjoy walking their dog Taro along the River and pathways. (AAPImage/Emma Brasier)

SOUTH Australian homes have long been prized by investors for their safe, steady, long-term growth, and a new property report has identified our most consistent suburbs.
Property expert Terry Ryder, of Hotspotting, has released his Price Predictor Index report for winter and identifies four SA suburbs in his National Top 50 Locations For Consistency.
These were Campbelltown and Greenwith in Adelaide's north-east, Happy Valley in Adelaide's south, and the eastern foothills suburb of Rostrevor. Mr Ryder said consistent markets indicated a stable and reliable investment.
"Those who prioritise safety in real estate investment can focus on the consistency markets - the ones that deliver almost identical sales numbers, quarter after quarter," Mr Ryder said.
"These are locations likely to record steady price growth over the longer term."
On a state level, 19 suburbs were considered consistent performers, with both the Campbelltown and Port Adelaide Enfield council areas recording three consistent performers each.
Berri and Moonta Bay were the only two regional markets to be considered consistent, while Mr Ryder identified the Goolwa district as one of South Australia's strongest growth markets, with sales increasing from 76 to 88 to 110 over the past three quarters.
According to the report, Campbelltown recorded consecutive quarterly sales of 54, 53, 51, 46, 52, 54 and 50, and Belle Property's Clarence Ling said the suburb offers great affordability.
"When people can't afford the more expensive surrounding areas they look to Campbelltown," Mr Ling said.
He said a large number of subdivisions in recent years had driven sales volumes.
Mr Ling said the fact that four consistent markets were in leafy family-friendly areas indicated buyers were seeking a particular lifestyle.
"People are looking to be close to these Hills and regional areas, but still close to the city," Mr Ling said.
Prudence Chang and her husband Eugene Kong bought their Campbelltown home last year.
Mrs Chang said Campbelltown appealed to her family for a number of reasons.
"I loved the greenery and the fact that I can see the hills from my house," she said.
"The main thing we loved was the O-Bahn because it's convenient for my children to go to school and to the city for work."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Ryder of Hotspotting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Price Predictor Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Top 50 Locations For Consistency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenwith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rostrevor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eugene Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ryder</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ling</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAPImage/Emma Brasier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goolwa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Chang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belle Property's Clarence Ling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonta Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide Enfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phyllis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O-BAHN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prudence Chang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
