<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425456738345403</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/if-only-coalition-mps-were-as-manageable-as-a-crazy-world-leader-20170804-gxpdph</url>
  <title>If only Coalition MPs were as manageable as a crazy world leader</title>
  <content>
It turns out that Donald Trump, and the unbelievable freak show that his presidency of the US daily proves to be, actually does have some positives.
At least, that is, when someone at the heart of the US government chooses to engage in some unprecedented leaking of his phone conversations with other world leaders.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has been having the week from hell ahead of the return of the parliament next week.
The conservatives and moderates in his party room are engaged in open, and intractable, warfare over same-sex marriage. His deputy, Barnaby Joyce, is in trouble over irrigated water.

AP

The Prime Minister was spending the week in Perth trying to connect with West Australians who demand he achieve the near impossible task of finding a new deal on GST that makes them happy.

Meantime, the very real threats from terrorism were on display in the r, yet when the Prime Minister talks about national security, there is often just a cynical response that charges politicians are trying to use the issue as a distraction.
And then T.
Now there are a few slightly tricky bits out of the conversation, from the prime minister's perspective, that are likely to have some echoes in our local political debate. His .
But the sheer drama of 'listening in' while our PM grimly tries to hold this erratic, profoundly ill-informed man to the topic at hand, to the substance of a deal done between our two countries, is riveting and should only do Turnbull good.

David Rowe

There always had to be a suspicion that Turnbull - never a shrinking violet in his various careers - was, and possibly is, the best person to have been at the end of that phone call in January. The transcript seems to prove it.
If only he was able to get all his colleagues warring over same-sex marriage on one phone hook-up and corral them into the position he wants on this issue in the same not pretty, but pretty effective way as he dealt with Trump.
The problem is that Turnbull doesn't really seem to have a position on this issue that he has the heart to pursue. Yes he is struggling to get his colleagues to agree to stick with the official party policy on marriage equality: a plebiscite.
But let's face it, the plebiscite policy is actually one of the last remnants of the Abbott era. It was Abbott's idea. Not Turnbull's. He is just stuck with it.

Andrew Meares

So on . It is hard to see that anything that is remotely satisfying will emerge for any of the participants.
The 'best' option would be for the party to stick with its existing policy, with a postal plebiscite being the next 'best' option. But both these stretch the idea of 'best' into a grotesque shape.
But it is not really a debate about getting a good outcome here. Just a sheer power tussle between the factions of the party.
The Coalition senator drafting a private member's bill to get the issue dealt with said on Friday a plebiscite was being pursued "at the expense of the traditions of our parliamentary liberal democracy".

AP

And of course, it is, as usual, being seen through the prism of leadership.
"Do I think that  No," Dean Smith said on Sky.
"Do I think it's disappointing that every public policy discussion and debate we have in this country at the moment is played through the leadership prism? Yes I think that's disappointing, and I'm sure the community thinks that's disappointing.
"Malcolm Turnbull will continue to be the leader up until the next election. This is not Malcolm Turnbull's test. This is a test of every member of the parliamentary Liberal Party."

Trevor Collens

But we seem to have long passed a time when members of the Coalition party room felt any collective responsibility for their government's fate.
The good thing about the simple idea that if things are going badly, it is all the leader's fault and you just get rid of the leader, is that it allows you to behave as badly as you like but bear no responsibility for what subsequently happens.
The government meantime, amid all this, is trying to push its agenda forward.
When parliament returns for the spring session, it will be dealing with legislation on citizenship, media reform, company tax cuts and an increased Medicare levy to pay for the National Disability Insurance Scheme.
The government has to work out what it is going to do on the previously proposed referendum on Indigenous recognition in the constitution - a debate which has taken a new turn in recent weeks leaving politicians scratching their heads about how to proceed.
The astonishing revelations about the will bring all the
And, not far below the surface, the issue of energy simmers.
to discuss how they can help people struggling to pay increased power bills.

Labor, meantime, recognises the spectre of chaos from its own dark days and can only sit back and watch what is happening on the other side of politics, unable to believe its luck.
Bill Shorten and his colleagues return to parliament with so much material to work with, to pursue. Yet they are also intending to keep plugging away at the equality argument which is starting to take shape as Labor has released policies over the winter break.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Collens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Disability Insurance Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
