<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425392313834757</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>http://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/how-to-use-a-feather-tickler/</url>
  <title>How To Use A Feather Tickler</title>
  <content>
Hands, lips, tongue, teeth - you've tried them all. And, though they may be wonderful, perhaps you've exhausted all of Mother Nature's tools for the time being and are looking to move on to some other kind of sensory stimulation.

You're not alone; lots of couples love exploring new ways to excite their partner during foreplay and sex. It can be hard to know where to go next without turning to the more-intimidating world of whips and chains.

Experimenting with sensory play, like light spanking, erotic massage and temperature play are great options that will instantly amp up your pleasure. However, if you're a newbie to this kind of exploration, and not sure your partner is ready for tingling cheeks, starting with something less intimidating, like a feather tickler, is an excellent option.

A feather tickler, as the name might suggest, is a device used for gentle sensory titillation. That is not to say, however, that the sensations you get from it will be mild. Feather ticklers are small but mighty and can feel amazing. And even better? They require very little skill or confidence to use, so there's no harm in just giving them a try.

Feather ticklers strike an excellent balance between super soft and deliciously sensual. They're often classified as a bondage toy but as they're invitingly unintimidating you don't need to be into bondage to use them - though they can make a great stepping stone to more advanced forms of sensory play.

A feather tickler normally consists of one, or many, feathers which are bound together at the top of a stem. This stem can be long and thin, short and thick, or even have an undulating texture depending on your preference.

The feathers can be short and downy, or long and spindly. The purpose of the feather is to awaken the body's nerve endings by providing a completely unique and new touch sensation. A light touch is all that you need to stimulate the senses by drawing blood to the surface of the skin and sending shivers down your spine. Or arms. Or legs. Or more.

How to use a feather tickler

As versatile as it is soft, a feather tickler can be incorporated into romantic lovemaking, playful pleasure sessions or even more adventurous exploration.

To use, hold on to the stem and allow the soft tip of the tickler, or the topmost feathers, to caress your lover's skin. You can start with a specific area and explore, or follow a sweeping head-to-toe body motion to give them all-over tingles.

They'll soon become extra sensitive. Experiment with a combination of strokes, employing different pressure. Combine feather light touches with long sweeping movements, always paying attention to how your partner's body reacts.

Whether you're looking for a full plume or long tips for pinpoint stimulation, there's bound to be something put there to suit your needs. An excellent first option is the  which blends a spray of coque feathers with fluffy down to awaken more than just your partner's nerve endings...

Anna Lee is a blogger and sex toy expert who writes for . You can see a list of their best-selling products .

WATCH MORE: Healthy Living News & Ideas

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Use A Feather Tickler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother Nature</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Healthy Living News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
