<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425456738345429</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/04/19/11/arrest-at-melbourne-petrol-station-ends-wild-police-chase</url>
  <title>Dramatic arrest in Melbourne petrol station ends wild police chase</title>
  <content>
Two officers have been injured arresting an erratic driver at a Melbourne petrol station after he led police on a 55-kilometre car chase through the city's south-east.  
CCTV obtained exclusively by 9NEWS shows the moment the driver of a stolen Holden Commodore pulled up at a 'United' petrol station in Huntingdale about 4pm today, leaving his lights on as he filled up the car with gas.
A staff member, who told 9NEWS they had received prior warning from police, attempted to stall the driver as an unmarked police car pulled in, ramming into the Commodore.
"Someone from the police called us from the landline and told us this was a stolen car ... This guy ran to stop him. It was a great catch," witness Tejasvi said.
Moments later, several police cars pulled up to the station to arrest the man.

Police began pursuing the driver after he was spotted driving erratically, and reportedly on the wrong side of the road, on Bungower Road in Mornington about 3:30pm today.
9NEWS understands the man was driving on footpaths and at speeds of up to 150km per hour, narrowly avoiding hitting school-aged children.

Related Articles

"Around school time, he shouldn't be on the roads. It's too dangerous. And it's peak hour traffic ... his driving was awful," Sergeant Leeanne Trusler said.
The man was then chased as he drove along Eastlink before the pursuit ended with his arrest in Huntingdale about 4pm.
Two police officers who were inside the unmarked car were taken to hospital after suffering minor injuries.
It is expected the man, who was the only occupant of the vehicle, will be charged with several driving offences.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tejasvi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bungower Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntingdale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Leeanne Trusler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Commodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
