<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425375133965237</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834274/njc-says-track-bouncing-back-for-spring/?cs=305</url>
  <title>NJC says track bouncing back for spring</title>
  <content>
Newcastle Jockey Club chief Matt Benson said the Broadmeadow course proper will be "top notch" for the September 15-16 spring carnival despite the decision to switch an August 15 meeting to the Beaumont track.

Matt Benson
Racing NSW announced on Thursday that the Tuesday meeting would be moved to the inside Beaumont track "in the best interests of the Newcastle Course Proper".
Benson said the decision was made to protect the inside eight metres of the $11.3 million course, opened in March this year, ahead of the spring carnival, which features four group 3 races and $1 million in prizemoney.
He said the inside section was dethatched of waste Kikuyu material in April to maintain drainage and the heath of the surface. The entire main track will undergo the same work immediately after the carnival and will be off-limits for a month.
Benson said "kick-back" at recent meetings was because of the thatched material and work to remove it would be done earlier next year.
"It's uncharted waters and we are still learning a lot about the track," he said. "We are working through this and learning.
"The Beaumont is racing well also, and it's really important we maintain the Beaumont's credibility as a track because we're going to have use it when we're doing renovations and other activities on the course proper."
Meanwhile, Branxton trainer Noel Boland was disqualified on Thursday for six months for pushing an NJC employee to the ground during trackwork at Cessnock on July 15.
Stewards said Boland had a heated argument with the employee before pushing him in the chest. They "took into account a recent similar incident involving Boland" when handing down the penalty.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NJC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Course Proper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Boland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Branxton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kikuyu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Benson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaumont</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWCASTLE Jockey Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
