<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425284939650468</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/breaking-news/toyotas-profit-improves-on-strong-sales/news-story/9b7a721e98077dbf471a85474a870980</url>
  <title>Toyota's profit improves on strong sales</title>
  <content>
Toyota Motor Corp fiscal first quarter profit rose 11 per cent as sales improved around the world, including in the US, Europe and Japan.
Toyota's April-June profit of 613 billion yen ($A6.9 billion), up from 552.4 billion yen a year earlier.
Quarterly sales rose seven per cent to 7.05 trillion yen.
Toyota, which makes the Prius hybrid, Camry sedan and Lexus luxury models, sold 2.2 million vehicles for the quarter, an improvement of 42,000 vehicles on-year.
Toyota and Mazda Motor Corp are set to announce later on Friday a partnership, according to a source familiar with the matter.
The deal is expected to involve a joint-venture auto manufacturing plant in the US, working together on green technology and a capital alliance.
Expenses for marketing and investments in cost-cutting efforts weighed on Toyota's quarterly profits, senior managing officer Tetsuya Otake said.
Toyota raised its fiscal full-year profit forecast through March 2018 to 1.75 trillion yen, higher than its earlier forecast of 1.5 trillion yen.
Like other Japanese exporters, Toyota is enjoying the benefits of a yen that has stayed cheaper than previously expected.
But the revised forecast is still lower than the 1.8 trillion yen earned in the previous fiscal year.
Toyota, which has been vying against the Japan-France alliance of Nissan-Renault, Volkswagen AG of Germany and US manufacturer General Motors for the spot of world's No.1 car maker, stuck to its earlier projection for global vehicle sales for the fiscal year at 10.25 million vehicles.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen AG of Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tetsuya Otake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lexus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda Motor Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Motors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan-France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Motor Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nissan-Renault</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota's April-June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
