<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424902687553948</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/de-lutis-v-de-lutis-brothers-fight-over-500-million-property-empire-20170804-gxpgd0.html</url>
  <title>De Lutis v De Lutis: brothers fight over $500 million property empire</title>
  <content>
Two brothers are at war over one of Victoria's biggest real estate empires, worth more than $500 million, four decades after their Italian family founded the dynasty.
Former Carlton Football Club director and developer Colin De Lutis lives in a Toorak mansion three doors from younger brother Paul, who has taken him to the Supreme Court over how their property and business assets will be sliced up.Photo: Supplied
Paul has wanted out of the family business since 2014 but an acrimonious argument is playing out in the Supreme Court over the break-up.
Together with their mother Anna the brothers own 38 properties worth more than half a billion dollars, amassed since the family bought a Smith Street, Collingwood, shop in 1973.
There, the family founded Westco Jeans and grew it into a chain of 160 retail outlets. It sold in 1999 for $85 million.
That money was sunk into property and the De Lutis portfolio now includes city offices, Brunswick and Sorrento development sites, Gold Coast and Mt Buller apartments, and suburban shopping centres.

Under an agreement with their late father, Colin - described by Paul as "the major driving force and the dominant personality" in the De Lutis family - owns about two-thirds of the company assets and Paul about one-third.
A court filing says this translates to Colin owning property worth $316 million and Paul $176 million.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Dividing the properties and cash has proved the sticking point for Paul. "The splits proposed by Colin left him with what I considered to be the best properties," he wrote in an initial court affidavit in 2015.
Last Friday, after several failed mediations, the first Supreme Court hearing was held.
The brothers are also now fighting over who controls the existing business - which Paul alleges Colin has locked him out of. Colin argues this is not true, but accuses Paul of incompetently managing some properties.
In an early affidavit filed by Colin, he says he hopes to resolve the dispute. "My Italian heritage dictates that family is the most important priority," he wrote.
Costs are mounting in the case, with hundreds of pages of affidavits, emails and reports by companies including Deloitte, Pitcher Partners and Charter Keck Cramer filed and top barristers including Allan Myers, QC, and senior solicitors retained by both sides.
Ms De Lutis and late her husband Luigi were Italian immigrants who ran milk bars and delicatessens from the late 1950s and in the early 1970s bought a shop in Brunswick.
They used the collateral to buy the Collingwood property where Colin opened the family's first jeans store. Colin says he started Westco there when he was "in my final years of high school, when Paul was a young child (around 10 years old)".
Anna De Lutis says she Luigi, who died in 2012, hoped to pass down their properties to their sons amicably. "Luigi often said to me that he never wanted the brothers to end up in court," she wrote.
Two other brothers, Mark and Luke, are no longer part of the De Lutis group of companies, with Colin saying that Mark was paid $10 million when he left the business, and Luke $26 million.
Both Luke and Mark had become, Paul says, "bitter about the terms of [their] financial separation".
Colin has kept a low profile despite being a former AFL club board member and, according to a 2015 biography of Eddie McGuire, the television star's best friend.
Fairfax Media contacted Colin and Paul De Lutis on Friday, and their lawyers. Only Colin replied, by text message, to say that because the case was before the courts "I really cannot say much".
"It's very, very sad that my brother Paul has chosen to sue me and drag our family name through the courts," he wrote.
In mid-2016, Colin wrote in one court filing that he had tried to accommodate his brother's requests. "Our father would not have wanted to see Paul and I end up in our current dispute," he said, adding that he was "still hopeful of resolution".
On Friday, that hope appeared gone. "Our matter will be resolved by the courts in the near future," Colin wrote.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul De Lutis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Lutis</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin De Lutis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sorrento</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toorak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luigi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms De Lutis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke $26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Buller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lutis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charter Keck Cramer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul $176</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna De Lutis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westco Jeans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
