<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425156090629321</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/anzs-shayne-elliott-says-going-to-the-bank-is-like-going-to-the-dentist-20170803-gxp3nr</url>
  <title>Dentistry and bank branches have too much in common, says ANZ CEO</title>
  <content>
ANZ chief executive Shayne Elliott says many people equate going into a bank branch to visiting the dentist, and it's one of the reasons why it's inevitable there will be a reduction in the number of bank branches over time.
Mr Elliott is preparing to undertake a as technology fundamentally changes the banking sector, with one of the major planks being the introduction of a more "agile" workplace where ANZ staff work in much smaller teams and are able to quickly respond to a fast-changing marketplace.
"The bank will have to look radically different," Mr Elliott told an ANZ customer lunch in Adelaide on Friday. The Finance Sector Union is worried there will beas a result of the restructure.
Bank branches were becoming less relevant to many consumers across the industry, he said.

"They don't come to our shops anymore," he said. Mr Elliott mentioned that one of his staff had told him that people regard a visit to a branch in a similar mould to a trip to the dentist.

"Going to the bank is like going to the dentist," he said. The advent of smartphones and other technology meant that banking had fundamentally altered, and it was time for ANZ to up-end its approach to traditional workplace practices. Many consumers did their banking on phones.
"It allows you to have a bank in your pocket," he said.
Mr Elliott said traditional structures across the bank needed to be revamped. He borrowed a line from Amazon founder Jeff Bezos on the strategic push to shrink the size of teams working on particular projects and innovations.
"If you can't feed the team with one pizza, you're too big," he said.

Praise for RBA

Mr Elliott said the Reserve Bank of Australia appeared to have the right policy settings on interest rates at the moment, and his "gut" feeling was that it may be quite a long time before they raised rates. "It does feel like it's going to be some time," he said. "Yes. I do think they've got it about right."  Much would depend on whether wages growth began to increase.
Mr Elliott also said that ANZ would continue to be part of a big push to attack the South Australian government's proposed state-based bank tax, even though it appears
He said ANZ would be campaigning against it right up until the next state election due in March 2018, even if it was killed off in the parliament. 

"Yes, we have to keep making our case. We have to keep on the front foot on that one, absolutely," Mr Elliott told reporters.
"We think it's really bad policy for a state to reach out across its borders to tax the rest of our customer base."
The South Australian government made the shock announcement that it would impose a state-based bank levy to raise $370 million in its and there has been a huge backlash by the big banks. But the South Australian Liberals under leader Steven Marshall, along with minority parties, have the numbers to block it in the upper house, which they have promised to do.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Sector Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Bezos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Elliott</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
