<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425117435922920</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/controversial-forfeit-ruling-hands-canberra-olympic-npl-capital-football-premiership-20170803-gxolca.html</url>
  <title>Controversial forfeit hands Canberra Olympic NPL Capital Football premiership</title>
  <content>
   Canberra Olympic will be crowned the NPL Capital Football premiership winners on Monday - no matter the results of this weekend.
In a controversial move Capital Football contacted the FFA Centre of Excellence on Thursday and informed the academy side they would be forfeiting the points from their round 14 clash against Canberra Olympic.Photo: Chris Nesci
The game was rescheduled at the request of the CEO after they informed Capital Football that players and coaches would be away on international duty.
Capital Football approved the postponement but Fairfax Media understands the governing body has backflipped on that decision on recommendation from the league board.
The three points Olympic gained from decision has ended the premiership race, but Capital Football are delaying an official announcement to avoid the embarrassment of deciding the league winner prematurely.

Fairfax Media understands the title race may be re-opened on appeal but only if Olympic lose against Gungahlin United on Sunday.
COE was the only side which could close the gap on Olympic in the final three rounds for what would have been a historic maiden premiership for the academy.
The decision also denied the COE a chance to end its program on an ironic winning note, with the academy set to close its doors on August 25 after the FFA said it was not producing enough talent to justify its $1.6 million price tag.
Olympic were keen to play the fixture against the CEO before its FFA Cup round of 32 match against Sorrento FC in Perth, but the rescheduling saw Olympic head west without playing in 11 days.
Olympic crashed out of the Cup and it is understood with the league title all but secured, they have no interest risking injury or suspension by playing COE in a make up match.
There have been four league winners in the past five years and Olympic are now in the box seat for a fourth championship in five years and a second straight treble.
Capital Football boss Phil Brown would not return calls.
Meanwhile, Capital Football have also backflipped on bans handed down to two Canberra FC affiliates who had lengthy bans significantly reduced on appeal.
Former Canberra seniors coach Miro Trninic and current under-20 coach Renato Jelinic were both
Trninc's suspension from spectating, playing and coaching until the end of the 2017 season and Jelinic's ban from playing, coaching or managing until the end of 2018, were both reduced to four-match suspended sentences following an appeal.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Football</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL Capital Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Nesci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miro Trninic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Olympic.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trninc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Centre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jelinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sorrento FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Olympic NPL Capital Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renato Jelinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
