<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424911277488793</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/property-with-sidebyside-potential-tops-165-million/news-story/03f551c3beeb945e500a9531e52f65b9</url>
  <title>Property with side-by-side potential tops $1.65 million - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
sold for $1.68 million at auction on Saturday, July 29.

A MENTONE property has sold for almost $1.7 million, after multiple buyers pushed it roughly $100,000 beyond expectations at auction.
Thomson Mentone sales consultant Lou Colella said the property at  attracted solid, straightforward competition at auction on July 29.
"We had four separate bidders," he said. "It got started fairly quickly and kept going."
Mr Colella said the home was called on the market at $1.58 million with just two bidders in the contest.
But once it was on the market two more joined in and carried the bidding for another $100,000 until the hammer fell at $1.68 million.
Developers had led the charge for the property, Mr Colella said.
"Because of the property itself - a very large block in a great location - it was predominantly developers looking at the property," he said.
"It was one of those campaigns that had a lot of inquiry."

A wide frontage and position in a coveted school zone added to the property's appeal.

Mr Colella said the 949sq m site on one title, with two dwellings, was a rare offering in the area.
"There are not a lot of blocks in the area that are this size," he said.
"It also had a very wide frontage, 32 metres, so that made it very unique."
It would likely become the site for new side-by-side townhouses because of these proportions, depending on council approval, Mr Colella said.
He said the property's position and school zoning had added to its appeal.
"It's in the Mentone Girls Secondary College zone, in between Mentone and Cheltenham stations and close to the beach," he said.
SEE SUBURB PROFILE:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lou Colella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Colella</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Mentone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mentone Girls Secondary College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURB PROFILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheltenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mentone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
