<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425284939650397</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/four-wheel-drive-track-damage-questions/8775114</url>
  <title>Two people questioned over illegal driving on closed Arthur-Pieman tracks</title>
  <content>
Tasmania's Parks and Wildlife Service (PWS) believes it has identified two people seen illegally driving quad bikes through an area on the state's north-west coast that has been closed to vehicles for five years.
The Wilderness Society wrote to the Environment Minister Matthew Groom asking for the riders to be prosecuted after they were .
The region has been a popular site for recreational driving for decades, but tracks in one section were closed in 2012 to protect Aboriginal heritage.
In a reply letter sent last month Mr Groom said as soon as he had become aware of the riders he immediately asked PWS to investigate.
"I can now advise that the PWS believes they have identified the offenders and I understand the individuals will be interviewed," it reads.
"The investigation will determine whether there is sufficient evidence to proceed to prosecution."

In a statement to the ABC, a spokesperson for PWS said the investigation was ongoing.
"PWS officers have taken statements from several witnesses, and have viewed high-definition footage provided by one of them," they said.
"As a result, investigators are following a specific line of enquiry."
The spokesperson said it would be inappropriate to comment further.
Following the incident a new sign has been installed advising four-wheel drives are banned in the area.
Calls for tougher penalties for repeat offenders

In the letter, Mr Groom said a considerable amount of time and effort went into ensuring drivers complied with the ban.
"It has generally been very successful, with a large number of drivers approached, any breaches of legislation investigated and offenders charged/issued with infringement notices," he wrote.
"Unfortunately, it appears however, there still remains a small group of people who choose to do the wrong thing."

Vica Bayley from the Wilderness Society said repeat offenders should face harsher penalties.
"Something more needs to be done," he said.
"People don't tolerate repeat offenders in any other sphere of justice, they get bigger fines or other sanctions."
It appears a barge has been used to ferry the quad bikes across the Pieman River to the closed area.
Mr Bayley said he was disappointed that after asking specific questions about the barge, there was no mention of it in the Minister's letter.
"It's only conceivable purpose is to facilitate people breaking the law by dropping ATV (all terrain vehicles) on the northern banks of the Pieman River," Mr Bayley said.
"It was used on the morning to bring in these two offenders that the parks and wildlife are now interviewing and Minister Groom has ignored our requests to investigate and confiscate that."
Mr Bayley said it was incumbent on the Minister to identify who owns the barge and to remove it from the coast.
Moves to reopen the tracks ongoing

While it was in opposition in 2014, the Liberal Party promised to re-open the tracks but after coming to power .

The State Government believes recreational access can be facilitated while protecting Aboriginal heritage in the area and it is referring the matter to the Federal Government for approval.
A spokesperson for the Government said that referral would be happening "imminently".
The Wilderness Society and the Tasmania Aboriginal Centre both believe opening the tracks will lead to irreversible damage of heritage sites, but local group the Circular Head Aboriginal Corporation is supporting the move.
It wants to see the area open to vehicles with local Aboriginal rangers on site to supervise and educate.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur-Pieman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Groom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildlife Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Groom</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vica Bayley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PWS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Minister Matthew Groom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Circular Head Aboriginal Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilderness Society</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bayley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pieman River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania's Parks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania Aboriginal Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
