<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425546932660060</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/health/the-foods-you-can-eat-as-much-of-as-you-like-according-to-a-dietitian/news-story/4245c3de9fcf83ea533e06da6e7ecd0c</url>
  <title>Foods you can gorge on and still lose weight</title>
  <content>
BEING told you can eat endlessly without seriously impacting your health is like being given free licence to rob a bank - or for some, a SEPHORA store.
That feeling of total abandon to literally indulge like you never have before is pretty powerful stuff.
That's why all-you-can-eat buffets and bottomless refill cups get us all hot under the collar.
Well, good news if 'portion' is a foreign word to you. Apparently there are foods you could hypothetically eat endlessly without sabotaging your diet, according to a recent article by Byrdie.
"They're mostly made up of water, are low in calories and contain fibre, which can help make you feel fuller for longer. Plus, they're packed with vitamins, antioxidants and other vital nutrients needed in a balanced diet," nutritionist Lisa Young told the publication.
Here's a quick refresher on fibre - it's an essential nutrient that your body needs in order to keep your digestive system in top notch working order. In other words, it's crucial to keeping waste moving out of your body.
So what exactly can you eat with total abandon?
They're what we've dubbed the 'fine nine': celery, blueberries, grapefruit, cucumber, broccoli, strawberries, cauliflower, oranges and kale.
It sounds too good to be true, so we asked accredited practising dietitian and spokesperson for the Dietitian's Association of Australia, Simone Austin, just how 'legit' this info is.
"I would agree with all," says Austin. "Maybe not oranges as they have a little more sugar - but if you're eating the whole orange and not juicing you are likely to self-regulate and not keep on eating heaps of them. You would get full."
"I would also add lettuce, spinach and silverbeet to this list," she adds. "Most non-starchy vegetables like leafy greens, green beans and cabbage could also be added," explains Austin.
What do these free-for-all foods have in common?
"Lots of water and dietary fibre means you will become full quite quickly. You also have to chew these foods well so you tend to eat them more slowly," says Austin.
If only the same applied to Pringles.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pringles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dietitians Association of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sephora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byrdie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
