<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425465328280141</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/sims-metal-management-shakeup-worries-analysts-20170804-gxpqx9</url>
  <title>Sims Metal management shake-up worries analysts</title>
  <content>
The two top executives at scrap metals group Sims Metals have departed the company abruptly and without explanation, drawing criticism from analysts and sending the company's shares down 12.5 per cent.
Sims said on Friday chief executive Galdino Claro and chief financial officer Fred Knechtel had left the company. Mr Claro has been replaced by Alistair Field, who was previously running the company's Australian and New Zealand Metals division. 
Sims has appointed Amit Patel as acting finance chief.
Analysts said they were concerned about the unexpected management changed.

"With performance rights and options representing a significant "pay day" for the senior management team, the timing and lack of clarity around the reasons for the management departure is of concern to us," Citi analyst Simon Thackray said.

Sims chairman Geoff Brunsdon said in a statement the company had made substantial progress under Mr Galdino who oversaw a five-year transformation strategy that is nearing completion.
"With our five-year strategic plan nearing completion, I am excited to have Alistair leading the company through the next phase of its development with the business being well placed to leverage its strengthened market position," Mr Brunsdon said.
Sims said it expected underlying earnings before interest and tax (EBIT) to be in the range of $180 million to $185 million. This compared to consensus estimates of $178 million. Net cash at June 30 is expected to be about $370 million.
In February, Sims reported first-half underlying earnings of $77 million.

Sims returned to profitability in the half-year following a cost-cutting program and helped by rising commodity prices. In February, Mr Claro said the company was expected to hit its target of 10 per cent return on capital in the 2018 financial year.
Analysts said the departures were surprising as the company's performance had improved. Citi noted the 10 per cent return on capital target was aligned with senior executive remuneration. The company is due to report its full-year results on August 25.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amit Patel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Claro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galdino Claro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Galdino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Brunsdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred Knechtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIM</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Metals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sims Metal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brunsdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALISTAIR FIELD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Thackray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
