<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425847580376128</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/breaking-news/us-confirms-strike-on-alshabaab-commander/news-story/1fadb5cedc6128909ac77d49da0e806e</url>
  <title>US confirms strike on al-Shabaab commander</title>
  <content>
Associated Press

Share

The US military has confirmed it killed a high-level commander of the al-Shabaab extremist group with a weekend drone strike in Somalia, targeting a man blamed for planning deadly attacks in the capital of the Horn of Africa nation.
A US Africa Command statement said on Friday the July 30 strike killed Ali Mohamed Hussein, also known as Ali Jabal.
It said he was "was responsible for leading al-Shabaab forces operating in the Mogadishu and Banadiir regions in planning and executing attacks against the capital of Mogadishu".
Ali also had served as the extremist group's shadow governor for Mogadishu and had been one of al-Shabaab's most outspoken officials.
The statement said the air strike occurred near Tortoroow, an al-Shabaab stronghold in the Lower Shabelle region in southern Somalia "as a direct response to al-Shabaab actions, including recent attacks on Somali forces".
It said no civilians were killed in the strike.
The killing of Ali "disrupts al-Shabaab's ability to plan and conduct attacks in Mogadishu and co-ordinate efforts between al-Shabaab regional commanders".
President Donald Trump earlier this year approved expanded military operations against the al-Qaeda-linked al-Shabaab, including more aggressive air strikes and considering parts of southern Somalia areas of active hostilities.
News of the strike came as residents said al-Shabaab had seized the town of Leego in the Lower Shabelle after it was abandoned by the Somali military and African Union peacekeepers.

The militants killed a dozen peacekeepers in the town a week earlier.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banadiir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somalia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shabaab</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somalis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qaeda-linked</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horn of Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOGADISHU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Shabelle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Mohamed Hussein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Africa Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tortoroow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Jabal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
