<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425121730890296</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/gungahlin-bulls-centre-brad-scholes-says-injury-crisis-could-make-club-20170803-gxoace.html</url>
  <title>Injuries can be the making of Bulls in Canberra Raiders Cup: Scholes</title>
  <content>
No one ever wishes for injuries, but Gungahlin Bulls centre Brad Scholes thinks they could be the making of the club after a horror year.
Gungahlin have endured a torrid season with injuries decimating the playing group across multiple grades.Photo: Jay Cronan
The semi-finalists of last year are second-last on the ladder with just four wins after losing the likes of captain Jake Elliot and playmaker Jack Scholes.
However, Jake's brother Brad believes the year from hell could be a blessing in disguise.

"We've just had a heap of injuries but it does give the younger guys a chance to come up," Scholes said.
"They've been showing some real potential so that just shows our depth.

"First grade are going to have these guys coming through who have played first grade at 17,18 and they're going to have that experience now to carry through when they are in first grade full-time, they'll be well and truly ready."
Scholes said that players across all divisions were having to play two or even three games on Saturdays just to make sure the club could field teams.
While not uncommon in country rugby league, Scholes said it was the worst he had seen it.
"I played both reserves and first grade, we had blokes from U18s playing all three grades and we only warmed up with six guys for first grade.
"We just have to keep putting in like we have been, hanging in there for each other."
That task will once again prove difficult when the Bulls travel to Yass to play against the Magpies on Saturday afternoon.
The Magpies pushed the Queanbeyan Kangaroos all the way last weekend, going down 36-28 in a free-flowing encounter.
Yass is third on the ladder and Scholes says the Magpies boast dangerous forwards, adding saying their tough attitude and quick play-the-ball made life extremely difficult for opposition teams.
Scholes was hopeful they could get skipper Elliot back from an ankle injury this weekend and said the side was desperate to end a dreadful season on a high.
"We're pretty desperate [for a win]," Scholes said.
"It would just be so great for the boys to get a couple of wins before we finish and just get the morale up."
CANBERRA RAIDERS CUP ROUND 17
Saturday: Tuggeranong Bushrangers v Belconnen United Sharks at Greenway Oval, 2.15pm; Yass Magpies v Gungahlin Bulls at Walker Park, 3pm; Woden Valley Rams v Queanbeyan Kangaroos at Phillip Oval, 3pm.
Sunday: West Belconnen Warriors v Queanbeyan Blues, Raiders Belconnen, 3pm
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yass Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders Belconnen, 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Kangaroos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Elliot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Belconnen Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Cronan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Scholes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belconnen United Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Scholes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yass</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CANBERRA RAIDERS CUP ROUND 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin Bulls</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong Bushrangers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenway Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scholes</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Raiders Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woden Valley Rams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulls</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
