<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425499688019165</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834777/keeping-kieran-quiet-is-the-key-for-knights/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Keeping Kieran quiet is the key for Knights</title>
  <content>
NOBODY knows better than Trent Hodkinson how good Kieran Foran is at his best.

Hodkinson's first season in the NRL was with Manly in 2010.
He played halfback in 24 games that season. Alongside him at five-eighth in 23 of those outings was Foran.
Since that formative campaign the two playmakers have gone their separate ways.
Hodkinson to Canterbury and Newcastle, Foran to Parramatta, the Warriors and, next season, to the Bulldogs.
These days the former playmaking partners cross paths only as rivals, which will again be the case when the Knights host the Warriors at McDonald Jones Stadium on Saturday.

And while Hodkinson will be doing his best to limit Foran's impact, he will also be admiring the opposition's linchpin. 
"I love watching Kieran play,'' Hodkinson said.
- TRENT HODKINSON
"He's a tough bugger and he's got a great skill set, so we're going to have to be on board with him.''
Foran has attracted criticism in recent weeks during a four-game losing streak that has caused the Warriors to tumble out of play-off contention.
Former Kiwis coach Frank Endacott questioned Foran's commitment, given that the 27-year-old has signed a lucrative deal with the Bulldogs starting next season.
But Foran responded by vowing to "finish the year as strong as I can" and help the Warriors climb the ladder. 
"You have got to really have a lot of pride in the jersey,'' he said.

"We have made a commitment to one another ... we have got five games to go, we get an opportunity to win all five and finish the season strongly.
"It starts this weekend against Newcastle."
In the absence of injured half Shaun Johnson, Foran has been paired with 23-year-old Mason Lino, a rookie who has only five NRL games to his name.
Warriors coach Stephen Kearney said Foran needed to be more dominant and "take ownership" of the team's attack.
"Obviously Kieran being the senior half in that position... they have got on the same page so to speak,'' Kearney said. 

FOCUSED: Trent Hodkinson is chasing back-to-back wins for the first time since he joined Newcastle. Picture: Darren Pateman, AAP
After beating St George Illawarra last weekend, the Knights are chasing back-to-back wins for the first time since rounds 23 and 24 of 2015, when they knocked over Wests Tigers and Melbourne away from home.

Hodkinson admitted they were not sure what to expect from the Warriors, who remain the most enigmatic team in the NRL.

"The Warriors are a big pack, powerful, mobile, they love an offload,'' Hodkinson said. "They've got big outside backs, so we're going to have to be on our game in defence.''
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Pateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kearney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodkinson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Hodkinson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Kearney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mason Lino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Foran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Endacott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foran</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
