<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426277077114317</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/keira-maguire-cant-watch-the-bachelor-without-getting-flashbacks-of-the-trauma/news-story/7b6b66037fcbbebe2c76e19a5ba4ff19</url>
  <title>Keira Maguire can't watch The Bachelor without getting 'flashbacks' of the trauma</title>
  <content>
Keira Maguire's Mega Meltdown
0:46

With her head trapped inside a box filled with creepy crawlies, using only her tongue to retrieve the prized stars, Keira Maguire deals with the situation in the only way she knows how. Cue mega meltdown. Courtesy: Ten

February 15th 2017
6 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Pictured in Rose Bay Keira Maguire, who is a Former contestant on The Bachelor. Picture: Tim Hunter.

Amelia SawNews Corp Australia Network

Share

FORMER Bachelor "villain" Keira Maguire is barely able to watch the current season without wincing.
The outspoken blonde who vied for a spot in Ritchie Strahan's heart said her time in The Bachelor mansion was so "traumatising" this year's season is giving her "flashbacks" of the horror.

"It's very mentally challenging being in that mansion," said Maguire, 31.
"Watching the series has really brought back a little bit of anxiety about what happened to me."
Producers maximised on Maguire's quick wit and cutting comments, polarising viewers who veraciously and relentlessly attacked her online.

Keira Maguire felt housebound for weeks after starring on The Bachelor. Picture: Tim Hunter.Source:News Corp Australia
"I was very overwhelmed. My character was getting a lot of backlash. Channel Ten could see I wasn't handling it well," she said.
"I was very vulnerable. I barely left my house for two weeks after I came out of the mansion."
When the show went to air the public vilification intensified, and Maguire spent another fortnight practically housebound, terrified of what may happen if she went out in public.

She has also called out current contestants for hamming up the cattiness.

"This season seems to be more about the drama than it is about the guy," said Maguire.
"It's like Girl, Interrupted," she said, referencing the 1999 Winona Ryder film set in a psychiatric ward.

Keira Maguire dancing with Bachelor Richie Strahan during her time on the show. Picture: Supplied / TenSource:Channel 10
"These girls have gone on the show with a mission to become the villain. I wasn't trying to be a villain when I went on the show, I just have no filter. I'm outspoken. But there's a difference between being outspoken and being molls."
On hearing Maguire's complaint of lingering trauma, a spokesperson from Warner Bros -- the production company behind The Bachelor -- confirmed she had ample access to support.
"The Bachelor psychologist is on hand before, during and after filming to support participants throughout the whole experience as they require," he said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Hunter.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner Bros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Bay Keira Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TenSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maguire, 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor Richie Strahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keira Maguire</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winona Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ritchie Strahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maguire</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelia SawNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keira Maguire's Mega Meltdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
