<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425675781681249</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/mueller-establishes-washington-grand-jury-in-russia-probe/news-story/de54556e98eeef2790bcc5575f254424</url>
  <title>Mueller establishes Washington grand jury in Russia probe</title>
  <content>
Reports Robert Mueller empanels Grand Jury
1:02

Grand jury subpoenas have been issued over the infamous meeting between Donald Trump Jr and a Russian lawyer

August 4th 2017
12 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/Politics/

Former FBI chief Robert Mueller, the special counsel investigating if Russia colluded in last year's bitter election campaign, has activated a grand jury and issued subpoenas relating to Trump's ties to Russia. Picture: AFP

Staff writers, Reuters, AFPNews Corp Australia Network

Share

PRESIDENT Trump has dismissed a grand jury investigation into his alleged collusion with Russia, stating the claim was a 'total fabrication' to make Democrats feel better.
Speaking to a campaign-rally style crowd in West Virginia, Trump said: "The Russia story is a total fabrication. It's just an excuse for the greatest loss in the history of American politics."
His words come after news broke that special counsel Robert Mueller had activated a grand jury in Washington to investigate allegations of collusion between the Trump campaign and Russia during the 2016 elections.
The activation of a grand jury implies Mueller is on the brink of summoning witnesses and issuing demands for documents in a major escalation of the criminal investigation.
Mueller impaneling a grand jury is a sign the Russia inquiry is ramping up and will likely continue for months
An earlier formal statement from the White House press secretary Sarah Sanders says Ty Cobb, the special counsel to the president, "wasn't aware" that a grand jury was being used.
"Grand jury matters are typically secret," he said. "The White House favours anything that accelerates the conclusion of his work fairly ..."
The White House statement repeated its previous assertions that "Former FBI Director Jim Comey said three times the Presdient is not under investigation and we have no reason to believe that has change."
Double rainbow 🌈
'HONEST' OUTCOME
President Trump said he hopes for a "truly honest" outcome from the Russia investigation that has consumed the opening months of his presidency, and he challenged Democrats to either continue their "obsession with a hoax" or begin serving the interests of the American people.

At the boisterous campaign rally in Trump-friendly West Virginia, Trump slammed the investigation as a "fake story that is demeaning to all of us and most of all demeaning to our country and demeaning to our Constitution."
"I just hope the final determination is a truly honest one, which is what the millions of people who gave us our big win in November deserve and what all Americans who want a better future want and deserve," he said.
"We didn't win because of Russia. We won because of you."
Instead, what the prosecutor should be looking at was Hillary Clinton's 33,000 emails, he said. He also accused Clinton of Russian ties, highlighting her approval of the sale of uranium to Moscow.
UNDER THE SPOTLIGHT
It's being reported that the grand jury has already issued subpoenas related to the June 2016 meeting between Donald Trump Jr, a Russian lawyer, and a representative of a Russian billionaire.
CNN reports the federal investigator is focusing on the financial trail between Trump, his associates and Moscow.

Donald Trum meets Vladimir Putin at the opening of the G20 summit in Hamburg, Germany. Picture: GettySource:Getty Images

Unnamed sources reportedly say the money trail provides a more 'concrete path' towards a potential prosecution than 'murkier' allegations of collusion.
Trump has publicly warned Mueller that his financial dealings should be out of bounds and investigating them would cross a red line.
PATH TO IMPEACHMENT
The establishment of a grand jury will allow Mueller - a former FBI director - to subpoena documents and get testimony under oath, as well as issue possible indictments.
"It's a significant escalation of the process," national security lawyer Bradley Moss told AFP.
"You don't empanel a grand jury unless your investigation has discovered enough evidence that you feel reflects a violation of at least one, if not more, criminal provisions," he said.
"If you secure an indictment, your next step is to arrest the defendant."

US President Donald Trump is coming under increasing pressure over alleged ties between his 2016 election campaign and Moscow. Picture: GettySource:Getty Images
The FBI initiated the investigation into Russia's attempts to influence the 2016 US election a year ago. Special counsel Robert Mueller was appointed to pursue the evidence earlier this year. FBI investigations of cyber breaches in US political organisations began as early as 2015.
President Trump has been reluctant to reveal details of his business detailings, refusing to release his tax returns in what has been a longstanding US presidential tradition.
RUSSIA RELATIONS AT 'DANGEROUS LOW'
It comes as Mr Trump tweeted that relations between Washington and Moscow had hit an all-time and "very dangerous" low after he approved sanctions against Russia passed by Congress.
"Our relationship with Russia is at an all-time & very dangerous low," Mr Trump wrote on Twitter.
Our relationship with Russia is at an all-time & very dangerous  low. You can thank Congress, the same people that can't even give us HCare!
"You can thank Congress, the same people that can't even give us HCare!", he added in reference to a recent defeat in the Senate on his health reform plans.
Yesterday, Russia's Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev posted inflammatory statements to social media in response to the passing of tough new sanctions aimed at punishing Moscow for interfering with the 2016 US election.

Russian Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev has attacked Donald Trump. Picture: APSource:AP
The President reluctantly signed the sanctions into law overnight after the US Congress passed the motion by a margin Mr Trump could not overrule.
"It ends hopes for improving our relations with the new US administration," Mr Medvedev states, targeting Mr Trump's repeated assertions that he wishes to do exactly that.
"Second, it's a declaration of a full-fledged economic war on Russia," he adds.
The Trump administration has shown its total weakness by handing over executive power to Congress in the most humiliating way
The US establishment fully outwitted Trump. The President is not happy about the sanctions, yet he could not but sign the bill
But Mr Medvedev's sting was in an attack on the US democratic process - and Mr Trump's ego.
"The Trump administration has shown its total weakness by handing over executive power to Congress in the most humiliating way. This changes the power balance in US political circles."

US President Donald Trump and Russia's President Vladimir Putin shake hands during a meeting on the sidelines of the G20 Summit in Hamburg, Germany. Picture: AFPSource:AFP
"The US establishment fully outwitted Trump; The President is not happy about the new sanctions, yet he could not but sign the bill."
Mr Medvedev states the move was a "way to knock Trump down a peg".
"New steps are to come, and they will ultimately aim to remove him from power."
BIPARTISAN MOVE TO SAVE MUELLER FROM BEING FIRED
Two members of the Senate Judiciary Committee are moving to protect Special Counsel Robert Mueller's job, putting forth new legislation that aims to ensure the integrity of current and future independent investigations.
Republican Senator Thom Tillis of North Carolina and Democratic Senator Chris Coons of Delaware plan to introduce the legislation today.
The bill would allow any special counsel for the Department of Justice to challenge his or her removal in court, with a review by a three-judge panel within 14 days of the challenge.

Attorney-General Jeff Sessions accompanied by Deputy Attorney-General Rod Rosenstein, left. Picture: APSource:AP
The bill would be retroactive to May 17, 2017 - the day Mr Mueller was appointed by Deputy Attorney-General Rod Rosenstein to investigate Russian meddling in the 2016 election and possible ties to Mr Trump's campaign.
"It is critical that special counsels have the independence and resources they need to lead investigations," Sen. Tillis said in a statement. "A back-end judicial review process to prevent unmerited removals of special counsels not only helps to ensure their investigatory independence, but also reaffirms our nation's system of check and balances."
Mr Mueller was appointed as special counsel following Mr Trump's abrupt firing of FBI Director James Comey.

Then Deputy Attorney-General James Comey (L) and then FBI Director Robert Mueller. Picture: AFPSource:AFP
Mr Mueller, who was Comey's predecessor as FBI director, has assembled a team of prosecutors and lawyers with experience in financial fraud, national security and organised crime to investigate contacts between Moscow and the Trump campaign.
Mr Trump has been critical of Mr Mueller since his appointment, and the president's legal team is looking into potential conflicts surrounding the team Mr Mueller has hired, including the backgrounds of members and political contributions by some members to Hillary Clinton.
He has also publicly warned Mr Mueller that he would be out of bounds if he dug into the Trump family's finances.

Senator Lindsey Graham is planning a bill that would prevent Donald Trump firing Special Counsel Robert Mueller. Picture: AFPSource:AFP
Mr Mueller has strong support on Capitol Hill. Senators in both parties have expressed concerns that Mr Trump may try to fire Mr Mueller and have warned him not to do so.
"Ensuring that the special counsel cannot be removed improperly is critical to the integrity of his investigation," Sen. Coons said.
Republican Sen. Lindsey Graham of South Carolina, another member of the Judiciary panel, said last week that he was working on a similar bill that would prevent the firing of a special counsel without judicial review.
Sen. Graham said then that firing Mr Mueller "would precipitate a firestorm that would be unprecedented in proportions."

Special Counsel Robert Mueller has the support of both Republicans and Democrats. Picture: AFPSource:AFP
The Tillis and Coons bill would allow review after the special counsel had been dismissed.
If the panel found there was no good cause for the counsel's removal, the person would be immediately reinstated.
n addition, only the Attorney-General or the most senior Justice Department official in charge of the matter could fire the special counsel.
In the case of the current investigation, Rosenstein is charged with Mr Mueller's fate because Attorney-General Jeff Sessions recused himself from all matters having to do with the Trump-Russia investigation.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUSSIA RELATIONS AT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Attorney General Rod Rosenstein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ty Cobb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Director Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tillis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Tillis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democratic Senator Chris Coons of Delaware</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Lindsey Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerous Low</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Virginia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Sen. Lindsey Graham of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOVE TO SAVE MUELLER FROM BEING FIRED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Director Jim Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counsel Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mueller</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Attorney-General James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFPSource</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mueller</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Jury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Senator Thom Tillis of North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20 Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Medvedev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special Counsel Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosenstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Presdient</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GettySource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFPNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinton of Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Judiciary Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamburg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump Jr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General Jeff Sessions</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Coons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton's 33,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capitol Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Director James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/Politics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HCare</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolinas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-friendly West Virginia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
