<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425847580376197</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/swoop/top-cricketers-become-the-highest-paid-athletes-in-australian-womens-sport-under-new-pay-deal/news-story/8119f0d66fa8716add9b39be068407d5</url>
  <title>Women big winners in cricket pay deal</title>
  <content>
MEG Lanning and Ellyse Perry are set to pocket up to $300,000 a season as part of a historic pay bonanza which cements cricket as the unrivalled leaders in women's sport.
Thursday's landmark announcement has made cricket fully professional, with state women's players who also play in the WBBL to now earn a minimum of around $50,000.
Jubilant and emotional scenes broke out at NSW Breakers training in Sydney on Thursday afternoon when one of the players, cheekily using a contraband phone, got word that the deal had been signed and announced the news to teammates.
Players who had gone without pay for more than a month, many seriously struggling to pay the bills, hi fived and celebrated mid-training and by Friday morning they were marching into NSW offices to sign their new contracts.
PAY DEAL:
In 2011-12 the average women's domestic wage was a lowly $2000 a season. This year, the average state player pulled in just $22,000.
Now the payment pool has expanded to an astonishing $55 million over the next five years, amid news that Channel 9 will broadcast key matches live in this summer's women's Ashes, with tickets to the bumper series to go on sale next week.
Cricket Australia has lost plenty in this bitter pay dispute, but they have undoubtedly spearheaded this rich deal for women in agreement with the ACA.
The average wage for an Australian international cricketer is now up to $94,000 and that's not including WBBL contracts or match payments which will push the top echelon of players up around $200,000 - the equivalent of what the top male domestic players earn.
For superstars such as Lanning and Perry, who have marketing contracts, they are comfortably the highest paid athletes in Australian women's team sport.
NSW coach Joanne Broadbent, a former top line player herself, says the announcement will go down as a momentous moment in women's cricket.
"There was a little bit of relief, but really good energy afterwards in and around when they read it out," she said.
"A few of them came into the office (yesterday) with big smiles on their faces, literally. I almost took a picture of one of them because it was just monumental. It was a moment you just want to capture. Really lovely to see.
"It's almost an unbelievable thing compared to where we were perhaps 20 years ago. When you see the magnitude of the money that's going into the game now, people do want to watch women play cricket."
Players have gone five weeks without pay and Broadbent has revealed the scope to which some of her players were battling - praising their resolve.
"They've really handled themselves really well. When you haven't got your financial backing or you've still got rent to pay and one of our players had moved from Bathurst to Sydney, left their job to do that, so I was more concerned with the ones who were more financially struggling.
"But the professionalism they showed throughout was unbelievable."
ACA manager and former Australian captain Jodie Fields says the beauty of the detail isn't just in the money.
"Alongside the remuneration obviously, the increased retainers and match fees, what's really been important has been the security of their workplace," said Fields.

Cricket: After 10 months of negotiations the cricket pay dispute is over. Fox Sports News reporter Tom Chadwick and foxsports.com.au's Tom Morris dissect what it all means.

Cricket pay war: Who wins?
"Things like the introduction of injury payments, prize money at domestic level, equal income protection and the introduction of a retirement fund the same as the guys get when they transition from the game.
"A marketing pool, and all those sorts of things that seemed like minute details but actually really mean a lot.
"Australian women can virtually train and play now a career."
Broadbent predicted that the standard of the women's game will continue to explode - with the announcement of a day-night Test match at North Sydney Oval against England in November another step in the women's game being put on a pedestal.
She is confident the fabric of passion that's always underpinned women's cricket will remain, despite the flood of money at long last coming into the game.
"You played for the love of it, and that's something I hope we don't lose," she said.
"The players still have that love for the game and want to improve themselves as players and people and I don't think the money will change that."
FACTBOX
Australian women base contracts:
Minimum wage: $72,000
Average: $94,000
With match payments and WBBL contracts factored in top players can earn between $200,000-$300,000
WBBL/WNCL State players base contracts:
Minimum wage: $36,000
Average: $46,000
Excludes match payments
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Factbox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellyse Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBBL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Chadwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Breakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBBL/WNCL State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Fields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg Lanning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbent</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
