<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426315731820845</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/rugby/melbourne-rebels-have-transferred-ownership-to-victorian-rugby-union/news-story/544b31e5d2f35b75df36dea997b9b6ae</url>
  <title>Rebels transfer ownership without telling ARU</title>
  <content>
THE Australian Rugby Union has asked for a please explain after the ownership of the Melbourne Rebels was transferred by the club's private owners to the Victorian Rugby Union without their knowledge.
Papers lodged with the Australian Security and Investments Commission on Friday showed Andrew Cox's Imperium Group had returned the Super Rugby licence for the Rebels to the VRU after months of negotiation.
Cox and fellow Imperium partner Peter Sidwell resigned from the Rebels' board, along with Michelle Williams, and they were replaced by VRU appointees Tim North, Owain Stone, Lyndsey Catermole and Rob Dalziel.
The transfer could make life awfully difficult for the ARU if they lose the arbitration ​case ​against Rugby WA and can't cut the ​Western ​Force. Any ​potential ​plan B to buy the Rebels licence back from Cox​ ​now appears off the table.
But the ownership change - which has the ​backing of the Victorian government - was questioned by the ARU, who have to sign off on any such transfer.
The ARU said in a statement they were not informed of the ownership change.
"The Australian Rugby Union (ARU) has tonight received confirmation from a third party that ownership of the Melbourne Rebels had transferred from Imperium Group to the Victorian Rugby Union (VRU)," the statement said.
"The Melbourne Rebels have an obligation under their Participation Deed to inform ARU of any change of ownership. To date, ARU has received no such communication from the Melbourne Rebels despite recent attempts to confirm their position. ARU is urgently seeking to confirm the terms on which this transfer occurred."

Rugby: The Wallabies have announced Michael Hooper will take over for Stephen Moore and Australian Captain.

Hooper to captain Wallabies
How the change of ownership changes the Super Rugby downsizing saga remains to be seen but Cox's departure would significantly reduce the chance of the Rebels being cut.
The ARU and Rugby WA engaged in arbitration hearing this week over the governing body's legal right to cut the Western Force from the competition next year. A decision is expected next week.
If Rugby WA win, the Rebels would no doubt come back into the reckoning as a possibility to be shut down.
But given Cox and Imperium have now transferred their shareholding to the VRU, the ARU can no longer enter any negotiation to buy back the Rebels licence with the private owners.
Whether the Imperium-VRU transfer requires ARU approval to be binding is another question, however, It is believed Victorian rugby advice is that the ARU can't withhold their approval unreasonably.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Captain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VRU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Dalziel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyndsey Catermole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Sidwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Rebels</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Participation Deed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperium-VRU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owain Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Cox's Imperium Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperium Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
