<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425370838997929</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/boxing/jeff-horn-v-manny-pacquiao-rematch-firming-for-november-in-brisbane/news-story/bfb0be43f67985d69579d786ed2b1070</url>
  <title>Jeff Horn v Manny Pacquiao rematch firming for November in Brisbane</title>
  <content>
Jeff Horn and Manny Pacquiao are likely to have a rematch in Brisbane in November.Picture: Dave Hunt

Jessica Marszalek, Anthony TempletonThe Courier-Mail

Share

A SOPHISTICATED ceiling of airconditioners could be installed over the boxing ring to counter the summer heat for the Brisbane rematch between world champ Jeff Horn and Manny Pacquiao.
The Courier-Mail understands the rematch is firming for November 12 at Suncorp Stadium, with plans being made to deal with the summer heat.
The Queensland Government is yet to sign on the dotted line, however, discussions are well advanced to hold the rematch in Brisbane.
Concerns had been raised about Brisbane's ability to host an outdoor fight in the later months of the year, given the heat and threat of storms.
But it's understood those factors are being taken into account, with the possibility of using airconditioners above the ring to keep the fighters cool.

Nicole Kidman says Horn v Pacquiao rematch should be in Sydney
1:26

Sunday Mail editor Peter Gleeson weighs in on Nicole Kidman wanting the Horn v Pacquiao rematch to be in Sydney, not Brisbane. Courtesy: Today Show

August 4th 2017
10 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Using an indoor venue such as the Brisbane Entertainment Centre - with a capacity of 14,500 - is a much less attractive option, given the pair's epic July 2 battle, which Horn won in a 12-round points decision, was fought in front of 51,000 people.
Australia's biggest-ever boxing event propelled the Brisbane schoolteacher to international stardom, but led to cries that a hometown advantage had applied. A re-score by the World Boxing Organisation confirmed Horn's welterweight title.

There are concerns weather could be a factor at Suncorp Stadium later in the year. Picture: Peter WallisSource:News Corp Australia
Pacquiao has a rematch clause in his contract for a return fight at Suncorp in November, however, Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk said negotiations to bring the Horn v Pacquiao rematch back to Brisbane were still ongoing.
"My understanding is that there are still discussions underway," she said.

The Courier-Mail understands the Pacquiao camp has not formally -accepted a rematch, but Tourism and Events Queensland is working with promoters to try to -secure the fight.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Events Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Marszalek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter WallisSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Kidman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Boxing Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony TempletonThe Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Today Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Gleeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacquiao</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Horn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November.Picture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manny Pacquiao</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Entertainment Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
