<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425843285408809</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4835366/murder-probe-after-farmers-death/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Murder probe after farmer's death</title>
  <content>
Deceased: Matthew Dunbar was found dead on Wednesday near Walcha. Photo: Walcha News

UPDATE: Death 'suspicious'

A murder investigation is underway after police confirmed a popular Walcha man's death is being treated as suspicious.
Oxley police are now treating Mathew Dunbar's death as a suspicious with homicide police called in.

Police won't be drawn on the nature of Mr Dunbar's death but confirmed it is suspicious.
Strike Force Ballin has been set-up by Oxley detectives and the State Crime Command's homicide squad to investigate how the 42-year-old died after his body was found on his Thunderbolts Way property outside Walcha in the early hours of Wednesday.

- Oxley Acting Superintendent Jeff Budd
"We are appealing for anyone in the Walcha community or wider public that has information that could assist investigators to please contact Oxley police or Crime Stoppers.

"Any information passed on or given to us will be treated as confidential."
Acting Superintendent Budd confirmed police had finished examining the crime scene where Mr Dunbar's body was found.
Investigations continue and anyone with information is urged to contact Oxley police on 6768 2999 or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.

Crime scene: Oxley police examine Mr Dunbar's home on Thunderbolts Way. Photo: Vanessa Arundale
EARLIER

A CRIME scene remained in place for a third straight day on Friday as specialist police continued their probe into the death of a popular farmer.
Mathew Dunbar's on Friday afternoon as Oxley detectives continued to investigate following the discovery of his body at 2am on Wednesday.
Detectives spent another day speaking with friends and neighbours of the well-known Walcha local.
Oxley police are remaining tight-lipped on much of the details surrounding the death but specialist resources have been deployed to assist Oxley detectives who are leading the probe.
Oxley Acting Superintendent Jeff Budd told Fairfax Media investigations are continuing.
"A crime scene remains in place and that is being processed by police," he said on Friday.
"A post-mortem on the body of the 42-year-old will take place in the coming days and police will prepare a report for the coroner."

Northern Daily Leader
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Daily Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dunbar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walcha</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Force Ballin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanessa Arundale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxley Acting Superintendent Jeff Budd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathew Dunbar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunderbolts Way</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Budd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walcha News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Dunbar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxley</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Crime Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
