<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425422378606392</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/world/abducted-berlin-asylumseeking-oil-executive-shows-up-on-vietnamese-tv-20170804-gxpd9k.html</url>
  <title>'Abducted' Berlin asylum-seeking oil executive shows up on Vietnamese TV</title>
  <content>
Hong Kong: Trinh Xuan Thanh, a high-powered executive in Vietnam, has become the subject of an unusual and mysterious diplomatic spat, with Germany publicly accusing Vietnamese officials of abducting and forcibly returning him to Vietnam.
Thanh, 51, fled the country last year amid accusations of economic mismanagement, ending up in Germany where he applied for asylum. Officials in Berlin were scheduled to hear his case July 24, but he didn't show up.

Up Next

'That' Scaramucci audio released

00:56

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Vietnamese 'Berlin kidnap victim' appears on TV

The possible abduction of Vietnamese businessman Trinh Xuan Thanh has sparked an international flare-up between Germany and Vietnam.

In Berlin on Wednesday, a spokesman for Germany's Foreign Office, Martin Schaefer, told reporters that there was "no longer any serious doubt" that Vietnamese diplomats and intelligence agents had participated in what he said was Thanh's kidnapping.
The Foreign Office said in a statement that the representative of Vietnam's intelligence agencies in Germany had been declared "persona non grata" and ordered to leave the country within 48 hours. Photo: Screengrab Reuters
On Thursday, Vietnamese officials offered a vague statement of regret, and in the evening, state-run television broadcast images of a haggard-looking Thanh.
"With encouragement from my family and friends, I came back to Vietnam and turned myself in to seek the forgiveness of the party, the government and the law," Thanh said in the broadcast, referring to the ruling Communist Party.

It was not clear if his statement was sincere or coerced.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The two countries have growing bilateral trade ties worth $13 billion over the past year, according to Germany's Foreign Office, but strong disagreements over Vietnam's approach to human rights. Critics say that the case illustrates how Vietnam's one-party government is apparently willing to pursue its domestic enemies overseas.
Thanh's lawyer, Victor Pfaff, told Reuters that he was abducted on July 23, outside a Sheraton Hotel in the Tiergarten district of Berlin and driven away in a car with Czech plates. Pfaff said Thanh arrived in Germany in August 2016, after a four-day journey through Laos, Thailand and Turkey, and that his wife and two children were in Berlin while another son stayed in Vietnam.
Rights activists have said for years that Vietnam imprisons many of its domestic critics under vague national security laws, and that Vietnamese plainclothes officers regularly intimidate and harass dissidents and their families.
Thanh's case has received widespread attention on Vietnamese-language social media this week. Many were sceptical that he had returned voluntarily; others applauded the government for arresting Thanh, saying it was an important step in a long battle against corruption.
Thanh was dismissed from Vietnam's National Assembly last year and accused of economic mismanagement that resulted in losses of about $147 million. He had been a senior official in the southern province of Hau Giang and the chairman of PetroVietnam Construction, a subsidiary of the state oil giant PetroVietnam.
He had been unpopular in Vietnam ever since local newspapers reported that he drove a luxury car and owned a large property.
"He could not buy them with the income of an SOE official," said Ngo Quy Nham, a senior lecturer in management at the Foreign Trade University in Hanoi, referring to state-owned enterprises.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnamese</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnamese TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ngo Quy Nham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Schaefer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Pfaff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiergarten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnamese-language</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pfaff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanoi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SOE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany's Foreign Office</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thanh, 51</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PetroVietnam Construction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hau Giang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Trade University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trinh Xuan Thanh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Czech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam's National Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thanh</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communist Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Screengrab Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheraton Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PetroVietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
