<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424898392586522</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/americna-import-laurin-nincy-completes-fire-roster/news-story/c1e9d89fa2d806e5e1e6a3accb5c0163</url>
  <title>Nincy completes Fire roster</title>
  <content>
THE Townsville Fire are putting the finishing touches on their star-studded roster for the upcoming WNBL season with the signing of WNBA draftee Laurin Mincy.
Renowned for being a defensive stopper, Mincy enjoyed a decorated college career at Maryland where she averaged a team-best 13.5 points, 4.0 rebounds and 3.4 assists in her senior campaign.
A third-round selection by New York in the 2015 WNBA draft, Mincy was signed by Seattle in 2016 before being waived by the Storm.
The six-foot guard has spent two years playing abroad in Israel, averaging 15.9 points, 4.3 rebounds and 3.3 assists during her debut campaign with Ramat Hasharon.
Mincy is the second import on Townsville's roster for this season - joining LA Sparks sharpshooter Sydney Wiese - and coach Claudia Brassard felt the 25-year-old brought a different dynamic to the guard position.
"She's long, athletic, and can get to the rim, but really we're after her defence with her athleticism that can really get up the floor and bother some people," Brassard said.
"I think we have a lot of great three-point shooters already so Mincy brings something a bit different where she can get to the rim quite easy and she'll just give us another weapon on the floor.
"We wanted was someone who we could say, 'here's Kelsey Griffin, go lock her down' or 'Steph Cumming's hurting us so you go spend five minutes on her and see what you can do'. I think she's that type of player.
"She's played overseas for a year or two as well so she's not a rookie by any means and she understands what the game is so it'll be good to have her on board.
"She almost cracked the Seattle roster two years ago so she's keen to try and get herself back in those line-ups. Hopefully we can assist in getting her where she wants to be and she can help us get that trophy back here."
Mincy will connect with the club before their first official day of preseason on September 2, but the Fire are likely to be without Melbourne-raised guard Marena Whittle.
The former college star injured her knee playing for the Nunawading Spectres in the SEABL which required surgery and she will miss the start of Townsville's WNBL campaign.
Brassard said the Fire were still considering their options to replace Whittle, but the coach was confident they have the playing depth to overcome any injury setbacks.
"It's a bit unknown if it's going to be three or four-month injury so we might look at bringing someone in for the season and have her as an 11th," Brassard said.
"I think we're covered in every position. We've got players who can play multiple positions as well so should someone go down then we've get every spot covered.
"I'm pretty comfortable there. For us, I think it'll be just about managing our bodies with all that travel and making sure we prepare the athletes as best we can with limited time on the floor."
Townsville Fire squad: Haylee Andrews (development player), Zitina Aokuso, Suzy Batkovic, Micaela Cocks, Darcee Garbin, Cayla George, Miela Goodchild (development player), Laurin Mincy (import), Mia Murray, Marena Whittle, Sydney Wiese (import), Kelly Wilson.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nincy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nunawading Spectres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurin Mincy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzy Batkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelsey Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brassard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Micaela Cocks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA Sparks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEABL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mincy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOWNSVILLE Fire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marena Whittle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claudia Brassard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cayla George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haylee Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramat Hasharon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mia Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcee Garbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Wiese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph Cumming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-raised</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville's WNBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miela Goodchild</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zitina Aokuso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
