<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425589882333776</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/spectator-out-a-war-on-frauds/news-story/88a0a9ad8bd5808122713f8e569fbbcd</url>
  <title>SPECTATOR OUT: A WAR ON FRAUDS</title>
  <content>
Great reading in the latest Spectator Australia.  
Rowan Dean:
Indeed, along with 'belief' in climate change, 'marriage equality' has become a critical battle field to be won or lost in the culture wars. This is a real shame, particularly for gays, who have become the latest 'useful idiots' in the Left's jackboot-stomping march through Australia's once-revered traditional institutions.
Sadly, the 'slippery slope' argument, once sneered at by the Left, has been borne out by events. In Adelaide's City of Marion council, for instance, councillors are wandering the streets investigating organisations seeking grants to determine whether or not they fly the rainbow flag to ensure, according to the Australian, 'that only gay and lesbian-friendly organisations could access funding.'
Andrew L. Urban on Bill Shorten's war on "inequality":
My cousin is a brain surgeon, one of the best in the world. I watched him operate one day, his steady, sure hands and eyes giving yet another patient a better quality of life. He does it every day.
He spent years studying, decades, and still studies. His private life is severely compromised by the incessant demands of his patients, day and indeed, nights. Evenings. Family dinners. Outings.
And he is not alone in the medical profession. A specialist I know takes calls and text messages from his patients 24/7, even on his holiday. These are dedicated, highly capable people, terribly important to society. There are few of them, in comparison to people like me, say (or even you Bill) whose inputs to society can easily be replaced. Not theirs. There are many more bakers and butchers than surgeons and medical specialists. If it were not so and there were many more brain surgeons than bakers, bread would be even more expensive than it is and the incomes of bakers would be higher, too. That's simple economics as you know. It is the 'natural inequality' of our world.
If you take, say, 70 per cent of my cousin's wages and give it to me, will you have 'tackled' inequality - or just created a new one?
Terry Barnes:
[Bill] Shorten has seized the political agenda with a vengeance. The talk suddenly is all about his issues: inequality, taxing the wealthy, the republic, gay marriage.In response, Malcolm Turnbull and the party of the forgotten people he leads have been caught leaden-footed, responding not leading, so far lost for any credible response...
It doesn't matter Shorten's solutions to the nation's ills are snake oil. He is running rampant, looking like a winner while his clueless opponents tear themselves apart. Even though Turnbull's budget move to the left sent Shorten further leftwards, Turnbull's gambit has served only to legitimise the opposition leader's class war rhetoric.
Mard Durie on Julia Baird's  :
A media fracas broke out this past week over Julia Baird's reports on the ABC about links between Christian teachings and domestic violence against women... This report was headlined by the ABC as: 'Research shows that the men most likely to abuse their wives are evangelical Christians who attend church sporadically.'
Andrew Bolt challenged Baird's use of the American research in the Herald Sun and on Sky News. He pointed out that the research she cited actually shows that the more people are involved in church, the less domestic violence they commit...
In this controversy, a careful examination of the chain of evidence reveals a 'Chinese whispers' effect in the way research findings have been distorted...
[Theologian] Steven Tracy was the weakest link. Baird had crucially relied on an article published by Tracy in 2008, and quoted Tracy's statement that 'It is widely accepted by abuse experts that... evangelical men who sporadically attend church are more likely than men of any other religious group (and more likely than secular men) to assault their wives'. This report Tracy referenced back to a footnote in one of his earlier articles, published in 2007, in which he had referenced five studies of domestic violence, four from North America, and one from New Zealand. All five studies reported an inverse association between church attendance and domestic violence. However only one report - Soft Patriarchs, New Men, by Wilcox- had reported that nominal conservative Protestant men were more abusive towards their wives than non-affiliated men. (Wilcox's research had also found that active conservative Protestant men were the least abusive of all the categories he investigated.)
Of the remaining four studies, one by Brinkerhoff, Grandin and Lupri found that religious denomination was not significant for predicting abuse,and that conservative Christian men do not abuse their partners more than other Christian men.
Furthermore, the New Zealand study reported that the worst abusers were not nominal Christians, but non-churchgoers.
In both his 2007 and 2008 articles, Tracy appears to have misrepresented evidence from his own referenced sources. Far from it being 'widely accepted' that nominal conservative Protestants are the worst abusers, only one of the five studies he himself referenced supported his conclusion, and two contradicted it...
Furthermore, since none of the American studies referenced by Tracy had made comparisons between Christianity and other faiths, it was misleading for Tracy to claim that evangelical men were more likely to assault their wives 'than men of any other religious group'....
Baird should have chased down Tracy's footnoted references and checked the primary findings rather than relying on Tracy's analysis.
Good stuff from Tom Quirk, too, on suspicious fiddling with the temperature record.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brinkerhoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Baird</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowan Dean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Men</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's City of Marion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grandin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Tracy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lupri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAR ON FRAUDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPECTATOR OUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Barnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mard Durie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christianity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Protestant</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spectator Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilcox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew L. Urban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracy</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soft Patriarchs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baird</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
