<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426229832473245</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/adelaide-twins-charlie-and-henry-support-different-afl-teams-one-follows-after-his-mum-and-loves-port-while-the-other-takes-after-dad-and-barracks-for-the-crows/news-story/9ad5962ee23ce475eed750f4dc7fe24a</url>
  <title>Twins prepare for their own Showdown</title>
  <content>
THEY share a birthday, live the same household and love their sport - but when it comes to football alliances, these twins couldn't be any more different.
Showdown day is always an interesting exercise for five-year-old brothers, Charlie and Henry Adams, who barrack for opposing South Australian AFL teams.
Charlie takes after his mother, Kimberley, and supports Port Adelaide, while Henry barracks for the Crows, just like father Ben.
While the twins - who aren't identical - won't make it to Adelaide Oval for this weekend's blockbuster Showdown 43, their dad will join the sellout crowd on Sunday afternoon.
More than 50,000 footy fans are expected at the match, a Crows home game.
Adelaide Oval management said supporters should arrive 20 minutes earlier than usual to allow for increased security measures, and limit the number of bags they bring.
Stadium Management Authority commercial operations general manager Darren Chandler said security also had the right to inspect and search patrons and their belongings using handheld or fixed wands, scanners, detectors or pat-downs.
"We have worked closely with all relevant authorities including SAPOL to increase our security measures in recent times," Mr Chandler said.
"This week's game will be one of the biggest of the year and we are preparing accordingly."
Among the thousands of AFL supporters will be the families and friends of footy players, some of whom have travelled interstate for the big game.
Power player Darcy Byrne-Jones's mother, Karen, who is travelling from Victoria for the match, said Showdowns were "nerve-racking".
"The Showdown was foreign to me until Darcy was drafted to Port Adelaide," she said.
"Over the years, I started to appreciate how big this game is - it is a significant game irrespective of the ladder positions of the teams.
"I think this week's game is going to be compelling with the stakes so high."
She said while she can't get to all of her son's Adelaide games, making it to the Showdowns was a priority.
Enthusiastic twins Charlie and Henry will instead watch the Showdown with their mother from their eastern suburbs home.
When asked what he thought of Port, Crows diehard Henry - whose favourite player is Eddie Betts - said "they're losers".
Port supporter Charlie - who likes Hamish Hartlett because he wears the number eight, his favourite number - went on to defend his team, saying the Crows were "bad".
But Henry wouldn't have a bar of it.
"They're not bad because they are first on the ladder," he rebutted.
Mrs Adams said Charlie took after her, while Henry was "identical to Ben".
"Henry is more one-eyed Crows than Charlie is for Port," she said.
When it comes to Showdowns, Mrs Adams said she preferred to watch from home.
"I can't go to Showdowns anymore - it is too stressful," she said.
"There is nothing worse than leaving a Showdown after your team has lost."
The gates open from 2pm for Sunday's Showdown at Adelaide Oval.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Hartlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Adams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday's Showdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAPOL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Chandler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Chandler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stadium Management Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Byrne-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
