<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426109573386480</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/the-preatures-new-album-girlhood-finding-new-confidence-on-home-soil-in-sydney-20170731-gxmcju.html</url>
  <title>The Preatures' new album Girlhood: finding new confidence on home soil in Sydney</title>
  <content>
There's a cracked egg on the doorstep of Hibernian House, a ragged tower on a street corner that Sydney band the Preatures call home. Singer Isabella Manfredi walks up a dim-lit, graffiti-ripped stairway to their recording studio on the first floor, apologising for the stink of stale tobacco. Sun glares through unopened windows, overlooking Central Station. She lights a stick of sandalwood incense and waves it about. "I just want to create a little bit of vibe."
This Surry Hills street houses cut-price fashion outlets, convenience stores and cafes. This building houses painters, poets and creative misfits. This room houses an unpeeled orange; bottle opener; toilet paper; headphones; overflowing ashtrays; electrical cords; curtains; black Chanel bag; deodorant; fake roses in empty beer bottles; coffee cups; piano; a sign saying "My love trumps fear"; a plastic tub of children's toys; posters of AC/DC, Neil Young and Star Wars; clocks; speakers; drums; a red couch; a brown couch; a sandwich-maker; sunglasses; a life preserver; way too many hats.Photo: Louie Douvis
It's like a university share house, without the passive-aggressive flatmates or excess of dhal. Guitarist Jack Moffitt offers to make tea but there's no milk. "It's not a smart idea to keep milk here," Manfredi says. The publicist pops out for supplies. Moffitt empties an ashtray. Manfredi holds a rollie while looking for a lighter.
She points to a red woolly jumper hanging high on the wall.GirlhoodPhoto: Max Mason-Hubers
"That was here when we got here, so we just left it."
"That's not entirely true," Moffitt says. "That's my jumper."

"That's your jumper? Oh my God," she says.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I definitely put it up there, but I don't know why," he says.Photo: Louie Douvis
This room was once a gallery and gig space dubbed the Doldrums. Punk bands performed for a $5 cover charge and there was a bucket of beer by the door. The Preatures took up the rent in late 2011, back when they were the five-piece former covers band the Preachers (they changed the name to avoid a legal stoush with another band), whose members met while studying at the Australian Institute of Music, located two streets away.
The rapid success of their own '70s and '80s-inspired pop songs meant they were going somewhere in a hurry. The 2013 single Is This How You Feel? - which was No.9 on the triple J Hottest 100 and won the $50,000 Vanda & Young Songwriting Competition - was followed by slots at overseas festivals, such as Coachella, Glastonbury and South by South West.
They stopped over in Austin, Texas, to record their 2014 debut album Blue Planet Eyes - which debuted at No.4 on the ARIA album chart - in a tick over three weeks. "We didn't sleep very much," Manfredi says.
Now they're back living in Sydney, ahead of the release of their second album, Girlhood, which they wrote and recorded in this unassuming inner-city room, with its comfortable couches and plastic flowers.
You can't be an artist if you don't upset anyone.
Isabella Manfredi

Manfredi says she needed to come home for the band's most personal songs to date. "I needed to come back to a space where I felt 100 per cent comfortable and safe, to see my friends, my mum, my nonna. That was really important to me, because for a few years I felt very isolated from everybody," she says.
"We wanted this record to sound like Sydney. We needed it to sound like this room, like our city. We couldn't really do it any other way."
Whispers and moans echo about the stairways and halls. Strange sounds rumble through the wall that the Preatures share with the studio of a stained-glass artist. "He used to have his whole shelf of glass on that wall but when we started rehearsing, the bass would vibrate the panes off the shelf," Manfredi says.
It's not a good room for recording music in, Moffitt says. "I think guitars sound OK in here but everything else you have to work a bit harder for."
He calls the studio and workspace their "den of iniquity". "You can be sort of depraved and spend a lot of time in here. Some days 16 hours have gone by and I haven't stepped outside once. It is a space where we all feel we can focus. And the things we need to stay focused are all here."
Construction works rattle the streets around Central Station. Some days, the building shakes with the heft of drills and power tools. "Sometimes, I would go to do vocals but there was too much noise, so we would go to the beach instead," Manfredi says.
She's 29, with brown eyes, blue jeans and a black faux fur coat. Moffitt is 27, with blue eyes, a thick black scarf and worn brown boots. They have matching lean frames and long wavy hair. They both look cold on this mild winter's day.
They started working on the new album in this makeshift studio in early 2016, with the ambition of wrapping it up in three months. But plans changed when guitarist and singer Gideon Bensen left the band in January. Then drummer Luke Davison slipped a disc in his back and was out of action for almost two months.
Manfredi,  Moffitt (who also produced the album) and bassist Tom Champion were forced to take their time. It was a change of pace from Blue Planet Eyes, which was written and recorded "on impulse", Moffitt says. "I sort of affectionately look back on that record as a soupy wonderland. Everything's ballsy and brash and somewhat lacking in a certain amount of perspective.
"But sometimes you have to live with something longer. With the kind of songs we had written for this record, they needed to have that time."
Their second album, which ended up taking about 12 months to finish, is more thoughtful - a little less pop, a whiff more country. The album is also more personal, especially for Manfredi. At its heart, Girlhood is about her own life and times as a woman in the male-dominated music world.
Each track tackles what she calls the "extreme f---ing confusion" facing modern women. "My experience of being a woman is a completely messy experience, completely contradictory," she says. "I was brought up to believe that you could do anything you want. And then I got into this situation where I was going 'I can do whatever I want, so what's stopping me? Is it me or is it other people? Is it because other people don't understand me or because I'm a woman?'."
The confusion started in her teens, when she started to get the impression that being "girlie" was considered frivolous or trivial. By her 20s, after years of touring with her male band members, she was losing touch with her feminine side. "Coming off the road, I realised that I had put a lot of myself to one side, to fit in with the group," she says.
"I love men, I love their stoicism and sense that life is just one big chance to rattle the cage ... But I was really missing female company and female energy."

Songs on the new album include Cherry Ripe, about the teenage Manfredi trying to be one of the boys who roamed in gangs around Sydney's beaches. Lip Balm explores female beauty regimens from a male perspective ("You say that I don't understand/The expectations, the demands/But you still wanna know what I think/It costs you $50 but it smells like shit.")
Something New is about the time she spent $7000 on clothes in Las Vegas, "in a streak of madness". The song also covers her cash-strapped gap year in Italy, surviving on a pauper's diet of dry Corn Flakes. One day, she dressed up nice and strutted into a major fashion house in Milan, pretending to be an actor in need of an outfit for an awards ceremony. "They took me into the big VIP change room and gave me food and sparkling water, and did all my measurements. And I said 'OK, my stylist will be in touch'," she says. "They were all so 'You're beautiful. Che bella!'."
She started dropping into different fashion houses on weekends, for a free feed and compliments. "It was the most epic fantasy world. I liked the performance, the thrill of it. It was all very Muriel's Wedding," she says. "But it's a hollow hit you get. One of the contradictions of the life of modern women is there are so many things we can buy to fulfil our fantasies and plug the hole of self-worth. There is that point when you cross a line from doing it for your own creative self-expression and falling into a pit of consumption."
Performing has always come easy to her. She feels most at home on stage, where she's a whipcrack of untamed energy - part Chrissie Hynde, part Chrissy Amphlett - jumping up and down and turning cartwheels.
Singing in the studio is a different story. As a child, she drove around with her father, Italian chef Stefano Manfredi, in an old Toyota station wagon that smelled of eggs and rotting meat, listening to the Smashing Pumpkins, Neil Young, Pink Floyd, Patti Smith and P.J. Harvey.
But she lacked the confidence to admit she wanted to be a singer - instead pretending she had plans to become a marine biologist, teacher or an ice skater. Even now, she sees herself more as a performer than musician. "On stage, I'm untouchable. But in the studio, I'm incredibly vulnerable, very fragile; like a little mouse," she says.
"I got asked a little while ago 'Why don't you think there are more women in the music industry?' I remember growing up, when the school system was very much 'You're a young woman, talented, intelligent, you can do whatever you want - but just make sure you tick all the boxes, follow all the rules and don't upset anybody.' But you can't be an artist if you don't upset anyone.
"I see it in my friends, in my family, all the time. We are always putting greater value on people's perception of us and opinion of us, above our own opinion of ourselves and what we want to do."
When recording Blue Planet Eyes in Austin, she struggled to put her voice front and centre. Coming home to their studio in Surry Hills helped her find the confidence to tell more personal stories. This is her safe space, a place to call her own. There's the couch she has slept on. There's the photograph of her as a 13-year-old on the wall. Manfredi comes and goes as she pleases. Some days she walks up the graffiti-lined stairs in the dark at 4am, to write or rehearse.
The end result of that homecoming is a new record with a strong, singular voice. Girlhood tells a story that is intimate, honest and inseparable from Sydney. "A lot of the songs on this record were so personal, I found it hard to get the words out," she says. "I had to be able to go home every night and see my friends and talk to them. I spent a lot of time being with the people who are close to me."
Moffitt, who lives in Bondi, says he only realised recently just how much he loves living in Sydney. "I am part of this city as much as it is part of me."
Manfredi, who lives in Kings Cross, loves the beaches, the bright light bouncing off the harbour, even the wretched sound of hammering from the constant construction works. "It's those little things that creep into whatever you are doing," she says. "With all the travel and everything, it gets quite lonely. I needed to come home."
Girlhood is out on August 11. The Preatures will perform at The Forum, Melbourne, on September 1, and Enmore Theatre, Sydney, on September 2.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corn Flakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Davison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lip Balm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hibernian House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P.J. Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry Ripe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J Hottest 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Champion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smashing Pumpkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Wars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manfredi</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabella Manfredi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glastonbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AC/DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chrissy Amphlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Station</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefano Manfredi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Moffitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moffitt</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enmore Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patti Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coachella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muriel's Wedding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chrissie Hynde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gideon Bensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GirlhoodPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Songwriting Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Planet Eyes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Young</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pink Floyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preatures</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
