<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651424894097619127</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/peter-kevin-kelliher-jailed-for-poisoning-neighbours-dog-with-lead-and-glassfilled-sausages/news-story/3f93927632347f44ae44db906a5e7175</url>
  <title>Jail for cruel man who poisoned neighbour's dog</title>
  <content>
AN Adelaide Hills man who whipped a neighbouring family's dog and fed her sausages laced with lead and glass shards has been jailed - but the owners believe the sentence is unfair.
Peter Kevin Kelliher, 64, was sentenced on Friday in the Mt Barker Magistrates Court to three months' imprisonment - two of which were suspended - for the ill-treatment of his neighbours' two-year-old golden retriever, Mia.
Magistrate Brian Nitschke ordered Kelliher to pay Mia's owners more than $12,000, banned him from having care or custody of animals for 12 months and ordered he serve a three-year good behaviour bond.
The court previously heard how the former mine worker entered his neighbour's 3000sq m Strathalbyn property on March 16 last year armed with a stock whip.
He then chased the dog, which his neighbours had bought in the wake of a family death, before striking it on the legs with the whip.
Over the next six months, he shaved filings from old fishing weights and added broken glass to cooked sausages before placing them over his neighbours' fence.
The Fabian family only found out about his poisoning campaign when Mia fell ill and they installed security cameras.
Mia's owner and mother-of-five Heidi Fabian, 45, felt the sentence was too light.
"I feel that the judge did the best he could within the parameters," she said.
"But I didn't think the sentence was fair, (the offence) was calculated and he (Kelliher) acknowledged it."
She said Mia is "happy and healthy as could be" but the lead had settled in her soft tissues and bones.
The family has yet to decide on a procedure to leach the lead out of Mia's system, which Ms Fabian likened to chemotherapy because it would compromise her quality of life.
RSPCA chief inspector Andrea Lewis said immediate imprisonment fitted the cruel act.
"This deliberate and deceptive act of cruelty has been met with shock by the community, and an immediate prison sentence sends a strong message that animal cruelty is a very serious matter that will not be tolerated," she said.
Kelliher in May plead guilty to 14 animal cruelty charges and asked the magistrate to serve his sentence on home detention.
But Mr Nitschke on Friday proceeded with sentencing and ordered Kelliher serve his one-month jail term immediately.
Kelliher was ordered to pay $10,885 in compensation to the Fabian family as well as $1258 in vet costs.
He was also banned from owning or caring for animals for a year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidi Fabian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Barker Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fabian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nitschke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Brian Nitschke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fabian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Kevin Kelliher, 64</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelliher</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathalbyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
