<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651425160385596689</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/two-qantas-long-haul-flights-forced-back-to-sydney-with-mechanical-problems-2017-8</url>
  <title>Two Qantas long haul flights have been forced back to Sydney with mechanical problems</title>
  <content>
Two Qantas planes had to abort their international flights and return to Sydney with mid-air mechanical issues.

Flight QF7 to Dallas turned around after wing flaps on the Airbus A380 failed to retract. The plane circled for 35 minutes, dumping fuel east of Wollongong before landing safely.

"As the Dallas flight is our longest on the network, the captain made the decision to return to Sydney," Qantas said in a statement on its website. The aircraft
"will be inspected by engineers."

Qantas A380 dumps fuel as it circles off Wollongong coast
- Illawarra Mercury (@illawarramerc)

A second flight, Qantas flight QF63 from Sydney to Johannesburg also needed to return due to cracked glass on the windscreen.

An aircraft windscreen is made up of three layers, and while the outer pane had cracked it did not compromise the integrity of the aircraft, Qantas said.

The Boeing 747-400 was safe to continue to Johannesburg but the captain made the decision to return as the windscreen will be replaced at Qantas' engineering base in Sydney.

Qantas said it was working to accommodate affected passengers or offer them transport home before replacement services are organised.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Mercury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbus A380</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas A380</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QF7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOHANNESBURG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QF63</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
