<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426706573852716</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/townsville/townsvilles-dream-rentals/news-story/2f6160092d3bf2eb7f9c172db63db1fc</url>
  <title>Townsville's dream rentals - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
21 Balmoral Drive, Castle Hill

RENTING in Townsville doesn't have to mean sacrificing living the high life with a plethora of luxury rentals on the market. We take a look at some of the best out there. Pools, wine cellars, media rooms and water views are just some of the luxurious features in these high-end rental properties. Take a walk through these properties and you'll feel like you've died and gone to real estate heaven.

21 Balmoral Drive, Castle Hill

This four-bedroom home in Townsville's most exclusive suburb could be yours for $1300 a week. There will be no fighting over the bathroom with four toilets including a bidet, three showers and two spa baths. Perched high on the hill this home has uninterrupted views of Cape Cleveland, Magnetic Island, Castle Hill and the CBD. There is also a cold room, media room, climate-controlled wine cellar, fire place and in-ground pool with ocean views.

19/18 High Vista Drive, Mount Louisa is for rent for $950 per week.

You'll have no shortage of room in this seven-bedroom, three bathroom home located in a gated community in Mount Louisa. It's $950 a week to rent but the property comes with one week's rent for free. The master suite has a walk-in-robe, own patio and ensuite with a spa bath. There is also a children's retreat, two large decks overlooking Townsville, pool with amazing views and theatre room fitted with a projector.

1588 Riverway Drive Kelso is for rent.

For the same price as a one studio apartment in Sydney you could be living in this four-bedroom house right on the river in Kelso. It's luxury at a bargain price of $595 per week which also includes pool service and gardener so you can kick back on the huge deck and enjoy the river views. The home also has a vacuum maid, ducted airconditioning, four bedrooms, three bathrooms, a purpose built children's room and spotted gum timber floors.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Vista Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Cleveland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balmoral Drive</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castle Hill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverway Drive Kelso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Louisa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
