<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426745228559493</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/accc-says-mergers-to-take-longer-under-documentheavy-approach-20170804-gxpj2r</url>
  <title>ACCC says mergers to take longer under document-heavy approach </title>
  <content>
The competition watchdog has warned it will take longer to consider contentious mergers and acquisitions under a new approach which will see a sharp increase in the amount of documentation and data companies will have to provide the regulator.
Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) chairman Rod Sims said the ACCC would introduce a "more intensive information-gathering approach" when reviewing contentious merger proposals.
The move was in response to mergers bypassing the ACCC for approval by the Australian Competition Tribunal and the Federal Court, which Mr Sims said had not blocked a case in the last 20 years.
"It is clear, however, that our current approach to merger review and litigation preparation is not resulting in adequately probative and persuasive evidence for the Tribunal or Federal Court. We have heard the message," Mr Sims said in a speech to the Law Council on Friday night.

The move will further inflame criticism by big business of the ACCC's approach to mergers. Thebetween Tabcorp and Tatts Group.

Mr Sims said two mergers which raised competition concerns were cleared with changes and eight were withdrawn in the last financial year. He said marginal cases were the biggest challenge for the ACCC.
"Criticisms directed to the ACCC's approach in these cases were that we were being too theoretical and lacking in commercial reality." In response, the ACCC would gather "substantially more evidence" for future tribunal applications or court proceedings.
This would involve an increase in section 155 notices, involving examinations under oath and "significant document requests".
Mr Sims said the changes would increase the burden on the ACCC and merger parties and the process would take longer.

"I think you will now see some lengthening of our timelines on contentious mergers, but we will continue to have regard to commercial timing pressures. By comparison with overseas regulators, the ACCC has traditionally been very quick to assess mergers. So even with an extension to our timelines arising from greater use of S155 notices ,it is unlikely that our timelines will approach those overseas," Mr Sims said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sim</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatts Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Sims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thebetween Tabcorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S155</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
