<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426195472734101</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/rate-rise-talk-has-homeowners-fixing-mortgage-interest-rates/news-story/32e4c82317f7b9c8b3cacf02c8a44485</url>
  <title>Homeowners fixing for a rate rise</title>
  <content>
HOMEOWNERS are rushing to fix their interest rates amid talk of an imminent rate rise, with the number of fixed-rate home loans jumping to the highest level in almost five years.
Mortgage Choice data released exclusively to The Courier-Mail shows fixed-rate loans accounted for 30 per cent of all mortgages in July as the big banks ignore the Reserve Bank and lift their own interest rates.
"We have seen a number of lenders adjust their pricing and policy which has encouraged more borrowers to seek out the perceived safety of a fixed-rate home loan," Mortgage Choice chief executive John Flavell said.
"July was the highest level of fixed-rate demand we have seen since December 2013."
Canstar chief finance commentator Steve Mickenbecker said borrowers should be "at least considering" fixing their home loan rates, but he warned a rate rise was still a few months off.
"I think people should be thinking about it," Mr Mickenbecker said.

Adam Posen Director of the Peterson Institute for International Economics Nell Henderson Global Central Banking Editor, The Wall Street Journal

What's Ahead Interest Rates and the Economy
First-home buyers Rachael Kennedy and Simon Armstrong decided to take out a variable interest rate loan on their New Farm property but are now considering fixing a portion of it "just in case rates do go up."
"We went variable to start with as I was keen to pay as much off as possible but now I'm considering fixing 50 per cent to secure the repayments," Mr Armstrong said.
"I like the certainty of a fixed rate so I can budget accordingly."
Although owner-occupiers are at risk if interest rates rise, Mr Mickenbecker said those on interest-only home loans were likely to feel the biggest pinch.
"One of the biggest issues is the rise in the number of interest-only home loans," he said.
"Because house prices have been going up, people have been saying I can't afford to pay principal and interest.
"Then the banks have added to the pain by bumping rates up.
"I think if the rates go up much more substantially, we will see a lot of people in stress."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachael Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Posen Director of the Peterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Armstrong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Armstrong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Mickenbecker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mickenbecker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Economics Nell Henderson Global Central Banking Editor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahead Interest Rates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Flavell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
