<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426710868820152</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/hospital-celebrates-delivering-its-100000th-baby/news-story/2c7b5350fbb7dd66b953ec250ce6b20d</url>
  <title>Whoa baby, you're a history maker</title>
  <content>
ONE-WEEK-OLD Taylor has helped the Angliss Hospital tick off a long-awaited milestone.
With 99,999 babies before her, Taylor was the 100,000th baby born at the hospital.
She was born at 10.25am last Monday, July 31.
Chirnside Park mother Elise Cox said it was special to be involved in a piece of history at the hospital, where she also gave birth to two other daughters.
Hospital staff had been counting down the days to number 100,000 but Mrs Cox said they were tight-lipped before making the official announcement.
"No one said anything until it was confirmed," she said.
"They were a bit hesitant in case they had missed any. After that everyone was getting excited, it was really nice."
Angliss Hospital program director of women and children Philippa Blencowe said there was a lot of anticipation in the lead-up to the milestone.
"Many of our staff were born here or had their children here. Some staff have also delivered babies of the babies they have delivered many years ago," she said.
The hospital first opened in 1939 as a 10-bed bush nursing hospital with one doctor and two
midwives.
Today their maternity services include a delivery suite, post-natal unit, antenatal clinic, foetal monitoring assessment clinic, special care nursery and paediatric service.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angliss Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WEEK-OLD Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elise Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chirnside Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippa Blencowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
