<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426745228559516</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/fnq-heat-eager-for-innisfail-welcome-for-npl-battle-with-brisbane-city/news-story/2df30b127eadb6c42f54ba0bf812d9ca</url>
  <title>Heat need Innisfail lift</title>
  <content>
INNISFAIL is abuzz for NPL action tonight and can count on FNQ Heat putting on a nailbiter - but it might not go the way the fans want.
The dying stages have proven a double-edged sword for the Heat in 2017, with four opposition goals from the 83rd minute onward costing the club six points and a top-four spot going into the final few rounds. In contrast, the FNQ club have gained seven points with goals beyond the 89th minute, which Crios O'Hare said was just a part of football and couldn't be blamed for the club's precarious position.
"At this point of the season, maybe it has come back to haunt us a little bit, but that's the way the game goes," O'Hare said.
"(Coach) Tim (Campbell) always talks to us about the importance of staying in the game for the full 90 minutes and not letting the game slip.
"It has happened to us a few times this season but at the same time we've done it to other teams in a few games."
Heat players know they have a mathematical chance of making the finals and although they have one eye on an FFA Cup showdown with Sydney United next week, a win against Brisbane City tonight is a must to keep those finals hopes alive.
O'Hare said playing in Innisfail in front of another raucous crowd at their home away from home could prove the difference against the John Kosmina-coached Azzuri.
It inspired the Heat to one of their best wins of the season against Redlands last year, which put them back on the path to the finals and eventually the grand final.
"I think having a good local crowd behind us makes a big difference," O'Hare said.
"Last year it was one of the main reasons we got a result down there and if we get another one we should be inspired to get a result."
The Heat will have their strongest possible squad available for tonight's match.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kosmina-coached Azzuri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innisfail</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FNQ Heat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crios O'Hare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Hare</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FNQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
