<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426719458754949</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/this-once-wildly-colourful-home-has-been-transformed-to-a-serene-retreat/news-story/e805ab7b61afc508700d31a88d56cf52</url>
  <title>This once wildly colourful home has been transformed to a serene retreat - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
89 Stuartholme Rd, Bardon

When Khylee Rodwell first laid eyes on her Bardon home, it exuded a Mexican look.
But the interior stylist with Omkara Interiors didn't take long to embark on a mission to revamp the home's orange and green walls.
"I completely changed the entire house," Mrs Rodwell said.
She has lived at the now three-level property for 10 years and said together with her partner, a tech and training captain with a major airline, they renovated the home inside and out.
With a professionally installed cricket pitch and practice net, and a 12 metre pool and poolside cabana, the home at 89 Stuartholme Rd, is impressive.

Khylee Rodwell at her Bardon home which is for sale. Picture: Mark Cranitch.

Mrs Rodwell has two sons, aged 19 and 16, who have enjoyed the comfort of the 1715sq m home.
"The 19-year-old is living and working out of home now and my other son is in Year 10 doing cricket training in the mornings, nights and weekends," she said. "So, the house is begging for another family to move in."
Mrs Rodwell said they installed the Keith Dudgeon cricket pitch for their sons, one who is in the Silver Rookies Squad and a fast bowler for Queensland Uni.
"It really is time to move on for us, the kids spend more time out than in," she said.
Mrs Rodwell said they expanded the three-bedroom home into a five-bedder, with all rooms having a breakout area.
"I don't like pokey bedrooms," she said.

89 Stuartholme Rd, Bardon

"The rooms are quite expansive and everyone has a private space between the large bedrooms and the large verandas."
Another standout feature of the home is a large concealed wine cellar.
"That was my idea," Mrs Rodwell laughed.

89 Stuartholme Rd, Bardon

"There was an area under the house for storage and it begged for a movie-beautiful wine cellar.
"You can go in and not come out for hours."
With the aim to give the house a southern charm, Mrs Rodwell added porches, verandas and elegance right through.
"You will see statues and fountains throughout that give it that look," she said.

89 Stuartholme Rd, Bardon

While the swimming pool has always been there, Mrs Rodwell said she gave it a new American-style look by building the cabana which comes off the dining area.
"It's one of my favourite places, just looking out to the gardens," she said.
"It's so elegant and relaxed."

89 Stuartholme Rd, Bardon.

The home which is a "great escape", is still close to the city, Mrs Rodwell said.
DETAILS:
89 Stuartholme Rd, Bardon
five bed
three car
2 bath
Agent: Drew Davies, McGrath Estate Agents - New Farm,
Auction: August 12, 2.30pm
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Dudgeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuartholme Rd</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khylee Rodwell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bardon</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Uni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12, 2.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silver Rookies Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Cranitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Rodwell</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath Estate Agents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omkara Interiors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
