<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426749523526933</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/jack-campagnolo-to-debut-in-northern-pride-reshuffle-for-intrust-super-cup-battle-with-souths-logan/news-story/8d4c6106f1df831680242fc75ab7a0d4</url>
  <title>Jack in his first crack at ISC bout</title>
  <content>
TULLY halfback Jack Campagnolo will make his Intrust Super Cup debut tonight against Souths Logan as Ty Williams looks to establish the future direction of the club.
The 19-year-old was the 2016 CDRL Rookie of the Year at the Tigers and has been touted for an ISC call-up since he captained the Pride's under-20s team earlier this season.
Williams said Campagnolo was a talent he expected to feature at the Pride for many years to come but he wanted to give him a chance this season without the pressure of trying to get them into finals.
"Obviously I want to see how he handles ISC, thinking about our future plans and where we want to go as a club," Williams said.
"His communication is good. I think he's just got to make sure he picks the right moments and opportunities and when to take them on.
"I've just said to him that the biggest thing I want him to do is keep doing what he's been doing at Tully ... and make sure of his one-on-one tackling.
"He doesn't shirk away from his defence and he knows how to put his body in front and that's part of the reason why he's getting an opportunity."
Campagnolo's inclusion at No.7 will force a shift in the spine and hooker rotation.
Connor Jones will play CDRL tonight for Mareeba, while Ben Hampton is expected to join the bench for his first ISC game at Barlow Park and his third Pride game for the season after missing the Cowboys' match against the Storm last night.
Patrick Mago is back after spending the past two weeks as a Cowboys reserve, offsetting the loss of Sheldon Powe-Hobbs, who has succumbed to a neck complaint.
The forecast of rain could dampen Williams's hopes of running the Magpies forward pack, who boast one of the best front row rotations in the competition, off their feet, but he said the 17 who took to the field would handle them.
Two underage women's fixtures, including an under-17 match between Kangaroos and a Cairns Combined team, will precede the Intrust Super Cup fixture and many of those players could feature in the club's plans to join a proposed statewide women's competition.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheldon Powe-Hobbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ty Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campagnolo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Combined</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Souths-Logan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tully</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CDRL Rookie of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Campagnolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mareeba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Mago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barlow Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CDRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
