<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426749523526893</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/gold-coast/amazing-floating-house-at-burleigh-heads-is-a-gold-coast-first/news-story/561fd41601d0680337459226f4b3a4ca</url>
  <title>Amazing floating house at Burleigh Heads is a Gold Coast first - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
The "floating" spaceship house at Burleigh Heads.

PINCH yourself - you're looking at the Gold Coast's first floating house.
Less than a year ago the 405sq m block at Burleigh Heads was home to a blue fibro shack.
Fast forward 12 months and neighbours are now reportedly starstruck by her jaw-dropping three-level house that now commands their quiet street.
Sitting on stilts, the latest timber design by architect Paul Uhlmann creates a floating illusion above Burleigh Heads which is comparable to a spaceship.

The magnificent house.

The house was built for Rosetta Naumoski, who described the finished product as her "dream home".
Ms Naumoksi bought the block on Hill Ave for $879,000 and teamed up with Gold Coast builder Nick Mcdonald from Mactech Constructions.
"I saw the block 18 months ago when I was hunting for a place to build my dream home," the mother-of-two said.
"The couple who had been living there had been there for the past 40 years but the home was falling to pieces."

Homeowner Rose Naumoski at her spectacular new Burleigh Heads home with builder Nick McDonald. Picture Glenn Hampson

According to Mr Uhlmann the house spans 8m wide and is the most dramatic floating design he has done.
"The colour of the home makes it appear as if its hanging off a cliff, the black bottom across the side of the house has given it that effect," he said.
Ms Naumoski said building the home was something she had planned to do for a long time but said the landscape of the block made it an almost impossible feat.
"It is my first build and I wanted it to be exactly what I had dreamt up," she said.

An aerial view of the house.

"I have done two renovations in the past but I got bored of that pretty quickly and wanted to make something from start to finish."
Ms Naumoski said architect Paul Uhlmann's design was altered a lot to fit her dream home requirements.
"Originally the design had a lot of iron but I love timber and light and bright spaces so we changed it a lot in that regard," she said.

The spectacular new Burleigh Heads home Picture Glenn Hampson

The home has ocean views from every level and has a special feature on each deck, including a firepit, outdoor tub and pool.
Builder Mr Mcdonald said the build took his team of nine just under eight months.
"We are very used to working with difficult aspect blocks but this block in particular was by far a challenge because it is the narrowest and the street was tight," he said.

The pool. Picture Glenn Hampson

Mr Mcdonald and his team build custom luxury homes on the southern end of the Gold Coast but said this was no ordinary build.
"There was a few obstacles and it wasn't built like a normal house from the bottom up," he said
"Getting the cranes in was the tricky part and once we finished a level there was no going back. It had to be spot on."

The balcony. Picture Glenn Hampson
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mactech Constructions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Naumoski</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Picture Glenn Hampson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Uhlmann</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh Heads</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Mcdonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Naumoksi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hampson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosetta Naumoski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Naumoski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Uhlmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
