<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426749523526910</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/university-hawks-focused-on-strong-finish-not-finals/news-story/3ecac6cc7e2c94b5096afbaf5f16ae7c</url>
  <title>Hawks focused on the here and now</title>
  <content>
UNIVERSITY Hawks coach Zammi Rohan insists his side hasn't started thinking about the AFL Townsville finals just yet as they prepare to take on defending premiers Thuringowa today.
The Hawks have been the competition's pacesetters this season, but they've slipped to second on the ladder following last weekend's 36-point loss to the Hermit Park Tigers.
That loss could have spoiled University's hopes of claiming the minor premiership, but Rohan said they were concerned more about how they're playing than their ladder position.
"We've just got our heads down and we're working hard. We don't want to get too carried with finals yet," he said.
"It's a bit of a funny time of year. We've got people all over the place at the moment, but I think we're fairly confident going into the game.
"We had a loss last week, but it's a good thing for us. We're not too concerned about the ladder.
"We've beaten the Tigers twice and they've beaten us twice and we've good record against the Bulldogs. We're really comfortable with we're where at.
"We're not concerned if we finish first or second. We still get a second chance in the finals so we're more focused on basic stuff, getting it together, and gaining some momentum."
Today's clash will be just the second time the Hawks have played at Tony Ireland Stadium this season and Rohan said it was important they feel comfortable at the venue which will host the finals series.
The Condon stadium is Thuringowa's home ground, but Rohan said every team enjoyed playing there and he expected his players to lift.
"The Bulldogs always a really tough opponent and it's good that we get another run on Tony Ireland Stadium before the finals," Rohan said.
"We've only played there once this year so that's something we're really looking forward to as well, trying to get our heads around what we need to do.
"It's one of best surfaces in Queensland and the facilities are great so the guys really step up to another level when we play there.
"But in saying that, it's the Bulldogs home ground and they play there a lot so that gives them a bit of an advantage knowing how to play on that ground."
In today's other clash, the Northern Beaches Suns will be looking to bounce back when they host the Hermit Park Tigers.
The Suns are coming off a shock loss to Curra last weekend and things won't get any easier against a Tigers outfit who have won nine of their past 10 games.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Ireland Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hermit Park Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNIVERSITY Hawks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Beaches Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Condon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zammi Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thuringowa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
