<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426487530516431</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/commonwealth-bank-safe-haven-for-criminal-activity-20170804-gxp54g</url>
  <title>Commonwealth Bank, safe haven for criminal activity</title>
  <content>
On the evening of Thursday May 21, 2015, NSW Police arrested Arlsan Shaffi, 25, and Salman Khan, 24, and .
After searching their respective residences in Auburn, in Sydney's western suburbs, the police found more than $3 million in banking receipts, some of which had been printed by Commonwealth Bank's deposit machines.
Over the previous 7 1/2 months, the authorities alleged the two men laundered $1,784,408, by making 255 separate deposits into 101 Commonwealth Bank accounts.
They had been part of a "cuckoo smurfing syndicate", a money laundering technique that involves using multiple people to make the deposits in different branches across a network, to attempt to avoid detection. It also involves piggybacking on legitimate international funds transfers being made by unwitting customers.

Cole Bennetts

The two men used dozens of CBA branches across Sydney to make deposits, many in amounts of $9900, or $9850 - just below the $10,000 threshold that requires banks to report them to AUSTRAC - in a process known as "structured deposits".

After the NSW Police's Strike Force A1 cracked their scheme, the game was up. Both men were arrested, refused bail, pleaded guilty in court, and, ultimately, were sentenced to jail terms.
But this week, it was time for their bank - CBA - to face the music.
In a case that which has senior criminal lawyers aghast at the scale of the alleged failures in Australia's largest bank, - either on time or at all - involving transactions totalling over $77 million. Suspicious transactions in the bank's "intelligent deposit machines" between 2012 and 2015 had a total value of $625 million.
All up, 11 CBA customers have been  for money laundering offences using the bank's accounts, involving at least four organised crime syndicates. One of them was of attempting to import methylamphetamine (ice) into the country.

Peter Braig

As well as providing details about the extent of the criminal enterprise,  filed in the Federal Court also illustrates how the authorities were frustrated at CBA's approach to various requests, which at times appeared lackadaisical, according to the pleadings.
After the NSW Police emailed CBA five days after the arrest of their customers, Mr Shaffi and Mr Khan, seeking its help to identify transactions, CBA took two weeks to respond. But "at no time has CommBank given the AUSTRAC CEO a [suspicious matter report] in respect of the matters", the pleadings say, a requirement of the law.
And it wasn't just . The regulator also alleges CBA should have been doing more to detect and report on the nefarious activity months before the mens' arrest.
For example, CBA's own anti-money laundering procedures triggered alerts on one of the accounts being used by Mr Shaffi and Mr Khan, on October 27, 2014. But it took more than two months before this was reviewed by the bank's Anti-Money Laundering Team, AUSTRAC alleges. And even though matters relating to other red flags on the accounts were referred to the CBA Intelligence Team on January 28, 2015, a review was not completed until May 4.

David Rowe

The court documents also show AUSTRAC believes CBA's systems should have identified multiple, large deposits being made on the same day into various suspicious accounts. "Of particular mention is that on several occasions the structuring is conducted in an intense manner whereby deposits consist of up to 26 structured deposits in a single day," the documents say.
The case also points to a breakdown in communication between different parts of CBA, as it appears some accounts were kept open even after the bank's security called for them to be closed. For example, on May 4, 2015, CBA's group security division forwarded an "Intelligence Bulletin" in respect of one of the suspicious companies being used by Mr Shaffi and Mr Khan to the bank's internal fraud team, noting it had been "flagged multiple times for structured payments under our transaction monitoring rules". It recommended the case be raised "with the Customer High Risk team, due to reputational and potential regulatory damage from suspected money laundering." But AUSTRAC alleges that notwithstanding the recommendations in the intelligence bulletin, "CommBank permitted the intense structured cash deposits to continue". The structuring only stopped when Mr Shaffi and Mr Khan were arrested.
CBA lawyers will be pouring over the claim and its 133-page appendix this weekend, after the bank said on Friday it would fight the claims and file a legal defence. Once this is filed, the bank will be able to say more about its position, CEO Ian Narev told staff in an email on Thursday night.
For now,. The legal documents suggest the failure of CBA to file 53,506 transaction reports on time could have been the result of a "system error", but why did this take so long to fix? And if the problem was isolated, did the cuckoo smurfers know about the weaknesses in the system?

Peter Braig

Questions have also been raised about whether the desire of CBA to be first to market with its fancy deposit machines and its broader focus on  might have been prioritised over its legal and regulatory obligations. As of October 2015, CBA had 507 of its "intelligent deposit machines" in the market, helping it corner the business for large, cash deposits and helping to boost fee income.
This case has therefore : the more life is made easier for customers, the higher is the risk of fraud. So has the focus on "the customer" resulted in CBA being overly accommodating to some customers who happened to be criminals that took advantage of the bank?
The  that Australia is behind world best practice when it comes to identifying money laundering.
Roger Wilkins, a former secretary of the commonwealth Attorney-General's department and former president of the Financial Action Task Force (FATF), the global body that oversees money laundering and terrorist financing threats to the financial system, said prevention and intelligence are the essence of modern law enforcement.

Austrac

"If you bring in new technology, part of FATF's guidance is that you need to run the ruler over it in terms of money laundering and counter-terrorism financing. You have to do due diligence on your systems. Then, within that, your have to do the basic bread-and-butter things, like reporting.
"Sometimes, compliance people can be seen as a pain, but culturally, we are moving into a world where we need to worry more about these issues. Compliance needs to be better integrated into making policy and business decisions and should not be seen as a tick-a-box exercise or some kind of add on."
CBA says all its staff are required to complete mandatory training on the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act. "Compliance with all our legal, regulatory and ethical obligations is a critical part of our vision and values. This is particularly important in relation to anti money-laundering and counter terrorism financing regulations," Mr Narev told staff in his email on Thursday night. He said CBA report over 4 million transactions to AUSTRAC each year.
But this is a reason why there will be so much soul-searching at CBA to work out what's gone wrong. Criminal law veterans say the scope of the apparent cultural failures are staggering.
"I don't know what culture they have that could have permitted this to happen," said Peter Faris, QC, a former chairman of the Australian Crime Commission.
"If you work as a teller, you are trained, and know why this is important. It is part of your daily business. To conduct themselves like this on a significant scale is a real problem for the government, and the bank's shareholders.
"To think the CBA, with its history and traditions, could be involved in what looks like systemic illegal transfers is truly shocking. It is very hard to believe. But I know how AUSTRAC works, and wouldn't have brought the case unless it has the evidence. This is what AUSTRAC is meant to do. The fact they have now made this matter public against the biggest bank in Australia indicates it is enormously serious."
Banking industry sources say protocols around handling large amounts of cash have been significantly tightened in recent years. At some banks, large deposits are made in depots rather than in machines and are monitored by specialist cash management teams. Technology systems are used constantly to monitor transaction activity that differs from normal activity.

Brendon Thorne

Anthony Quinn, the former head of Macquarie Bank's anti-money laundering program and now the CEO of Arctic Intelligence, which builds anti-money laundering technology systems, says the CBA case highlights the need for for mandated, regular independent reviews examining the design and operational effectiveness of operational controls.
"These should unearth major flaws in the anti-money laundering and counter terrorism financing programs, which should be reported to boards and senior management who need to prioritise fixing these issues," he said.
AUSTRAC acting CEO Peter Clark said on Thursday its goal "is to have a financial sector that is vigilant and capable of responding - including through innovation - to threats of criminal exploitation".

David Rowe

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Thorne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday May 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arlsan Shaffi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police's Strike Force A1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Khan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Crime Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Peter Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Action Task Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Faris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shaffi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Quinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA Intelligence Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Customer High Risk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Braig</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salman Khan, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 27, 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counter-Terrorism Financing Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Arctic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 4, 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FATF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>21</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cole Bennetts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommBank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
