<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426702278885361</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4797905/recalling-past-horror-as-we-celebrate-peace/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Recalling past horror as we celebrate peace</title>
  <content>
REMEMBERING: A march to mark Hiroshima day in Sydney in 1989. It is 72 years since the atomic bomb was dropped on the Japanese city, killing scores of people.

AUGUST 6 marks 72 years since the United States committed what is arguably the single gravest act of terrorism that the world has ever known. Terrorism means the deliberate targeting of innocent civilians and targeted they were.

The atomic bomb dropped on Hiroshima was at a location and when "nearly all the school children" were at out in the open, a perfect opportunity for mass incineration.
The Mayor of Hiroshima recalled at a memorial service in 2007: "A flash, an enormous blast, silence. The eyes of school children looking up were melted. Their faces became giant charred blisters. The skin of people seeking help dangled from their fingernails. Others died when their eyeballs and internal organs burst from their bodies; within the year, 140,000 had died." A similar number died, years after, from the insidious and lingering effects of atomic radiation.
It is therefore a matter for celebration that after extensive lobbying by peace-loving people throughout the world, that 122 countries at the United Nations approved on July 7 this year, a treaty to ban atomic weapons, their stockpiling, their use and their manufacture. The treaty will be open for UN member countries to sign in September.

Whilst it is not expected that the major nuclear armed countries will sign the treaty initially, the pressure of member nations and the world community will be focused on those who don't and hopefully shame them into taking a more positive stance in renouncing nuclear weapons and signing the treaty in the future.
On Sunday, August 7, the Hunter Peace Group will leave the Maritime Museum at 10am and march to Civic Park where a rally will be held to look back and look forward, to commemorate and to celebrate. All peace-loving people are welcome.

Bevan Ramsden, Lambton

Campaign 'misconceived'

THIS past week has seen an extraordinary campaign in the pages of the Newcastle Herald by the CFMEU to damage my political reputation. Full page advertisements appeared each day, suggesting I have somehow "failed" on jobs, especially jobs for apprentices on government building projects. The campaign is misinformed and misconceived. 
Nobody cares more about apprentices than me and the party I represent in the federal parliament. For 10 years as a teacher at TAFE and then at the University of Newcastle, I helped train hundreds of apprentices. At my first meeting with the Prime Minister following my election to the Senate, I raised the prospect of more apprentices. 
What the CFMEU is doing is revisiting my vote in the Senate for the government's Australian Building and Construction Commission Bill, a vote supported by other cross-benchers who want a return to the rule of law to building sites. The union says the ABCC's new building code somehow limits the employment of apprentices. 
Contrary to what the union says, the Code of Conduct does not prevent clauses in enterprise agreements that encourage the employment of apprentices. 
The code simply prevents union-imposed pattern agreements that require fixed numbers of apprentices without regard to the size of the building contractor or its ability to pay reasonable wages. 
Brian Burston, One Nation Senator

Blokes, behave

I DARE say I am not alone in being concerned that so many women are being harassed at the University of Newcastle. The problem, as I see it, is we men are driven by testosterone in our young adult years.
Testosterone is a major cause of our burning desire which overcomes all reason and respect.

This is no excuse but does help to explain inappropriate behaviour and lack of awareness of the impact we men have on women when we behave as Emma Elsworthy and others have described ('Sexual harassment no laughing matter', Herald, 2/8). 

We are having fun in our excitement and think that the woman should too think of our behaviour as acceptable. Appalling lack of insight and awareness, I know - and it doesn't justify the behaviour.
So come on men and boys, get your act together and realise that women do not want overtly sexualised behaviour unless they show clear indications of agreement in a private situation.
We are responsible for this problem and there is a golden rule of "do not touch".
Scott Bell-Ellercamp, Clarence Town

Vision for distant future

I AM nothing but impressed by Newcastle lord mayor Nuatali Nelmes' decision to back a light rail extension into Broadmeadow ('Council push for light rail in Broadmeadow', Herald, 1/8). It isn't that I support the idea, as - far from it - I am yet to be convinced of the guiding merits of the original light rail plan into Newcastle.

What enthralls me, however, is what this initiative reveals about the mayor's underlying character. She is being entirely true to the Labor Party's two final guiding principles - the only ones its members have left to speak of. The first of these is to maintain some sense of 'vision' and the second of which is their clearly applied readiness to spend money that does not exist. Nuatali's plan ably fulfills them both.

Thereby her visionary plan - good, bad, or indifferent - cannot begin to take shape for another 90-years plus. Only sometime after then could the prolonged lease for the Port of Newcastle be up for renewal, permitting any resultant funds to reappear for tendered works that may be entailed.

This is because of the iron-clad rule that no single politician dare breach. The coffers of Macquarie Street or Canberra will never be voluntarily, substantially or directly depleted for the sake of Newcastle. Nothing can happen without privatisation. All parties know this.

This rule has never historically been broken and to any cynics such as me, any attempt to do so would represent a veritable Sign of the Apocalypse.

Nobody realistically pretends that the present undertakings in the city have ever made any kind of a dent into the state's finances, current surpluses notwithstanding.

These shortcomings aside, I fulsomely praise the mayor in her ambitious endeavors, and I heartily wish her and her party good fortune in the upcoming local elections. If I were only in their municipality, they would certainly have earned my vote.
Steven Micevski, Dungog

Letter of the Week

The Herald pen goes to Bevan Ramsden for his letter about Hiroshima.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nuatali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Peace Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor of Hiroshima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JULY 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Museum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Bell-Ellercamp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sign of the Apocalypse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Elsworthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Burston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nuatali Nelmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dungog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hiroshima</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald, 1/8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Building</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Commission Bill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Code of Conduct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation Senator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald, 2/8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bevan Ramsden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarence Town</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Micevski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
