<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426839717841900</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/maggots-to-be-flown-to-patients-by-drone/news-story/1e79a8398d9635e8875003a3a39d94a2</url>
  <title>Maggots to be flown to patients by drone</title>
  <content>
MAGGOTS could be flown out by drones to remote communities for medical purposes, according to a research paper from Griffith University.
The larvae are among other medical supplies that could be taken by air to distant townships, according to doctoral candidate Frank Stadler.
Maggots are used for medicinal purposes such as treating wounds of diabetes patients as they eat only the infected skin.
"Wounds are becoming increasingly a problem due to the fact more and more people suffer from diabetes and the effects," he said.
"They are difficult to treat wounds and maggots do a good job of that."
The use of drones to transport medical maggots and other items would mean they would get to remote clinics quicker than by other transport options.
He said the cost of the drone would have to be weighed up against the need for medical supplies.
A long distance flying drone just 3m wide would be suitable for flying medical pieces could carry a payload of 5kg and would cost around $100,000.
Prof Stadler said it was particularly important as maggots had only a 48 hour window of use from production to application on to the patient.
"Also in that period of time maggots must not get hotter than 25C and must have ventilation," he said.
He said the use of drones would enable people to continue living in remote areas but have access to better medical services.
Griffith University Professor of humanitarian logistics Peter Tatham said the concept of using drones in humanitarian situations was not new, but it was yet to be used in a local situation.
"The short-range pizza delivery type drones have been used for a number of occasions in parts of the world. In PNG they were used in 2014 to deliver medicine to people who got a snake bite," he said.
The team have yet to complete a trial run but hope in the future they would be able to.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffith University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Stadler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Stadler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffith University Professor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Tatham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
