<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426616379537749</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/nrl/cowboys-coach-paul-green-lashes-referees-after-loss-to-storm/news-story/247e1f8af64b5102f777bc0c064ae457</url>
  <title>'Worst refereeing display I have ever seen'</title>
  <content>
COWBOYS coach Paul Green is facing a $10,000 fine by the NRL after launching a savage attack on the referees in North Queensland's 26-8 loss to the Storm.
Just a week after Dragons counterpart Paul McGregor was hit with a breach notice for blasting match officials, Green is sure to be the next coach in the sights of the NRL after his stunning post-match tirade.
The Cowboys coach lashed Ashley Klein and Alan Shortall, claiming fans were dudded by a refereeing performance he labelled the worst he had ever seen.
In one puzzling moment, Cowboys halfback Michael Morgan was denied an early try after he picked up the scraps from a high kick which appeared to go backwards after teammate Lachlan Coote soared high.

NRL: The Melbourne Storm have proven they are the team to beat after dismantling the North Queensland Cowboys.

Storm slice through Cowboys
INJURY CRISIS:
ANALYSIS:
The referees called Morgan back, ruling Coote knocked on to the dismay of North Queensland players.
Green said the Storm were clearly the better team but within seconds of praising the courage of his players, he changed tack to hammer the match officials.
"That was the worst refereeing display I have ever seen," he said.
"There were some calls," he added, shaking his head, "where they lacked consistency.
"I'm not one to shift the blame away from our performance, but the fans deserved more than that.
"There were two quality teams out there and I was left scratching my head at some of the calls.
"I said to the boys after the game I've never been involved in a game where so many things have gone against us ... it's just a shame the refs ruined the game."
Of Morgan's no-try, Green scoffed: "Backwards is backwards isn't it? Big calls in big games can swing possession."
Storm skipper Cameron Smith said he was surprised by the referees' application of the 10-metre rule.
"They were into us with the 10 metres and leaving (the line) early," he said.
"I don't know if they are cracking down on that, it wasn't something I felt I did differently to any other game this year.
"That was directed at me. But as far as the refereeing and the overall consistency, I didn't see any major issues."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Shortall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Klein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Cowboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Coote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
