<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426573429864033</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/technology/do-you-own-a-discontinued-ipod-nano-or-ipod-shuffle-you-can-now-flog-one-of-the-retro-gadgets-for-a-tidy-profit/news-story/b1d9e2d0ab40904e2761365dada4df90</url>
  <title>Apple products worth a mint</title>
  <content>
IT MIGHT make you feel very old to hear that Apple's iPod Shuffle and iPod Nano, which launched 12 years ago, have been killed off.
But if you were lucky enough to purchase one the first time around you might be able to make a tidy profit.
Smartphones are some of the most common products that sell for a high price online, with old models of iPhones and Samsung Galaxies regularly selling for hundreds of dollars.
But the Apple iPods which are gathering dust in your home could make you a bit richer too.
Some will get you little more than a twenty - but others might fetch up to hundreds or even thousands.
It's all down to the condition, the generation of the model and the amount of storage it holds. So collect up your old gadgets and cross-check them against this guide to see if you can rake it in.
HOW MUCH CAN YOU GET FOR YOUR IPOD SHUFFLE?
There were four generations of the iPod shuffle. The first launched in 2005 and is one of the most valuable models.
You could get around $340 for a boxed version, or around $140 for one in good condition with all the charging cables.
The second generation appears to go for the least amount on marketplaces like eBay. But you could get yourself up to $65 - almost half of its original cost.
• First generation: Sealed and with a high amount of storage (500MB and over) you could get $340 for the gadget.
• Second generation: Devices in good condition are selling for around between $25 and $140 on eBay although RED editions have been known to fetch up to $650.
• Third generation: The hard-to-find third version of the music players sell for around $240 and appear to be rarer than the other models.
• Fourth generation: Previous top bids reached $400 for the most recent version of the Shuffle, but you're more likely to get around $130 for one in perfect condition.
HOW MUCH CAN YOU GET FOR YOUR IPOD NANO?
We've seen six generations of iPod Nanos from Apple but they suffered the same fate as the Shuffle, with the last one rolling off the production line this month.
Again, some versions are worth more than others.
• First generation: Mint condition and packaged could get you $320.
• Second generation: Upwards of $35.
• Third generation: Upwards of $80 with new versions going for $330.
• Fourth generation: Red versions should get you at least $150 if they are in good condition.
• Fifth generation: Again, the limited edition Red versions fetch upwards of $240.
• Sixth generation: Top price is around $620 but others go for $210 to $240.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple's iPod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple's iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung's Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MUCH CAN YOU GET FOR YOUR IPOD SHUFFLE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MUCH CAN YOU GET FOR YOUR IPOD NANO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
