<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426728048689835</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:15</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/real-estate/queensland/townsville/townsvilles-rental-market-showing-signs-of-recovery/news-story/6667635c3e27c03924bd3fbe27042c34</url>
  <title>Townsville's rental market showing signs of recovery - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Generic image

TOWNSVILLE'S rental market is showing signs of recovery with vacancy rates falling to the lowest levels since December 2014.
The latest Real Estate Institute of Queensland figures show that as of the end of June, vacancy rates were 5 per cent.
It follows vacancy rates spiking in September 2016 at 7.1 per cent.
John Gribbin Realty principal John Gribbin said the rental market was slowly starting to turn around.
"There is definitely signs of improvement but it's not going to recover overnight," he said.
"We still need a lot of people to come back to Townsville because a lot of people actually left and that's been part of the problem.
"We're finding places like Annandale, Douglas and Idalia rent well and just generally suburbs that have houses that present well will always move, but the peripheral areas are a bit tougher."
Research commissioned by TP Human Capital and completed by regional economist Colin Dywer shows there has been a surge in demand for rental properties in Townsville in July and there are fewer than 1500 properties available.
"We have been collecting residential vacancy data from Realestate.com since July 8 and there has been a drop of 180 properties advertised; that's an 11 per cent absorption in just over three weeks," Mr Dwyer said. "Some of the absorption will be southerners taking up short term rentals to enjoy Townsville's climate but with all the current and proposed project activity and job creation a large proportion will be out-of-towners taking up jobs.
"As the NQ stadium project commences there is likely to be acceleration in demand for homes close to these projects."
Despite an improvement in vacancy rates Townsville's rental market is still classified by REIQ as being weak. In a statement, the REIQ said that the Government's focus on jobs and major infrastructure projects was staring to gain traction.
TP Human Capital managing director Clayton Cook said an increase in employment was likely to help improve Townsville's rental market.
"We have noticed a change in the Townsville jobs market recently, with a moderate to strong upswing in demand for construction workers, health and social assistance workers (NDIS), administration jobs and education positions," he said.
"There is evidence of skill shortages in some occupations such as labourers, riggers and hairdressers.
"If the jobs can't be filled locally then people from elsewhere will be recruited.
"This migration will impact the property market in a variety of ways; one impact is likely to be increased demand for rental properties."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realestate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Idalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TP Human Capital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Gribbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Gribbin Realty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate Institute of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Dywer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annandale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
