<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426478940581645</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/how-drug-syndicates-laundered-44-million-through-cba-20170804-gxpopu</url>
  <title>Drug syndicates laundered $44 million through CBA</title>
  <content>
Five people have been sentenced to prison in the past four months alone for money laundering schemes, including syndicates importing and manufacturing the drug ice, with two others awaiting sentence all related to the .
In total eleven people are in jail and dozens more have been arrested here and overseas including four criminal syndicates which laundered $44.8 million through CommBank's Intelligent Deposit Machines, which can take up to $20,000 in a single deposit.
The Australian Federal Police statement of claim says that $8.91 billion was deposited in CommBank's IDMs since 2012, before it conducted any assessment of the risk of money laundering and financing terrorism, which the bank was legally obliged to do.
With 507 IDMs operating during this time, each machine on average would have processed more than $17.6 million in deposits without any risk assessment of money laundering.

Two weeks ago two Malaysians, Yuen Hong Fung and Kha Weng Foong, who the AFP says were part of Syndicate 1, were jailed for six years, four months and five years, three months for money laundering after CommBank's Market Place branch in Leichhardt, Sydney, flagged suspicious deposits in the bank's IDM on August 20 2015, apparently by Foong.

The AFP statement , which did not process the Leichhardt alert until four days later, on August 24.
The AFP was already investigating and that same day arrested Foong at the Eastgardens branch at Bondi Junction, after he deposited $9950 into another account, which had been opened under a false name using a fake NSW driving licence.
The AFP pressured the bank to escalate their request for documents "to the highest priority at CBA" noting $21 million had been laundered by the syndicate and five people arrested, including three in Hong Kong.
The bank agreed to close the accounts, but wrote to the the account holders to give them 30 days notice. The chief account was not frozen until September 17 and a month later it was still pending closure.

Kean Wai Wong, a member of Syndicate 2, was sentenced on May 19 to three years for his part in laundering $2.2 million from an ice importation, with two others facing trial.
The AFP says CommBank ignored automated alerts from its system of suspicious transactions.
Jizhang Lu, a member of Syndicate 3, was sentenced to four years for money laundering connected to $17 million in proceeds from ice importation and manufacture in October 2015.
Syndicate 4 laundered $21 million from drug importation through 11 companies from February 2015 to February 2016.

Yeuk Tung Kong was sentenced to seven years, six months; Wai Ki Vicky Fung, Man Chun Mak and Yiu Pong Tang received between between three years and 10 months, while a fifth figure was fined.
Arlsan Shaffi, Salman Khan and Mandeep Singh were sentenced for "cuckoo smurfing", a means of money laundering that involves substituting funds in international money transfers by unwitting third parties.
"Evidence is now being collected so to charge Shaffi and Khan with offences under the Anti-Money Laundering/Counter Terrorism Financing Act," the AFP statement said.
at the poor light the case cast over the bank.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi Junction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kean Wai Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeuk Tung Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arlsan Shaffi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IDM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kha Weng Foong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommBank's Market Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaffi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man Chun Mak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering/Counter Terrorism Financing Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandeep Singh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wai Ki Vicky Fung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jizhang Lu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastgardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yiu Pong Tang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommBank's Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salman Khan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommBank's IDMs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syndicate 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syndicate 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syndicate 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syndicate 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leichhardt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yuen Hong Fung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommBank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
