<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426835422874544</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/opinion/its-time-to-talk-about-the-north/news-story/167c43a0e3cddfd3c9e74052ca36b8ff</url>
  <title>It's time to talk about the north</title>
  <content>
NEXT month's Northern Australia ministerial conference is a chance for Barnaby Joyce to prove his mettle as the north's number one man in Canberra.
Mr Joyce isn't from the north. His chilly electorate of New England couldn't be more different geographically to the tropical North.
But he does understand life in regional Australia and its challenges and rewards. That - and his position as Deputy Prime Minister - could make him an effective advocate for us at the very highest level.
How long Mr Joyce will stick around as Minister for Northern Australia is yet to be determined. Senator Matt Canavan's ministerial future is still up in the air. He may return to the role, or we might get yet another minister for Northern Australia.
But for the moment, Mr Joyce is the man who controls the cash and we want it here in the Territory.
It's promising that he has chosen Darwin to host the first meeting. For too long, the Developing the North agenda has been more like the Developing Queensland agenda. Money from the North Australia Infrastructure fund has overwhelmingly gone to Queensland - the NAIF's headquarters is in Cairns and the Co-operative Research Centre for Northern Australia is in Townsville.
It's time we got our fair share of the pie.
The NT is at a critical juncture.
We're facing a shaky economic outlook in the medium term as we stare down the Inpex cliff.
We need strong commitment from the Federal Government to get us through. We need investment - in roads, education, agriculture and innovation to help us ride out the rough times and get to the other side with a more diverse economy.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inpex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Joyce</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Australia Infrastructure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-operative Research Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Developing Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
