<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426448875809817</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/agriculture/melbourne-brewer-east-9th-leads-hemp-beer-charge-20170802-gxnldm</url>
  <title>A Melbourne craft brewer wants to be at forefront of Australia's first hemp beer</title>
  <content>
Melbourne craft beer company East 9th Brewing says it has perfected trial batches of what it claims is Australia's first hemp beer as it prepares to emulate North American brewers ahead of a legislative green light earmarked for November.
The company, which is owned by three entrepreneurs - Benjamin Cairns, Stephen Wools and Josh Lefers - along with four other smaller shareholders, has used kilograms of hemp seeds in the brewing process to come up with a unique flavour.
It has been fine-tuned after several prototypes.
"It really is distinctive. It's a unique nutty flavour, a bit smoky and a little bit creamy," Mr Lefers said.

The company, one of 400 craft brewers in a $740 million segment of the broader beer category, is eyeing a November start for the product. Federal and state ministers gave in-principle agreement in April for low-THC hemp seeds to be used in foods and the various states are in the process of making changes which are expected to be ratified by mid-November.

Mr Lefers said there were at least eight hemp ales selling in North America, with one of the leading brands being California's Humboldt Brewing Co's Brown Hemp Ale. "The US is really leading the charge on it," he said.
The company expects the first batch to sell out because of strong initial interest from customers.
It is currently illegal to consume hemp food products in Australia, even though many other countries allow it.
Mr Cairns said East 9th Brewing had a strong track record of innovation in its product line-up and has between 4000 and 5000 distribution points around the nation, including in Woolworths' Dan Murphy's superstores.

He said cutting-edge product development was part of the reason why craft beer was growing at a fast rate, while mainstream beer was sliding.
"We've had a good run of trial batches," he said. The company had been eyeing making a hemp ale since it was established seven years ago, but only now was the legislative environment about to change.
It aims to sell the hemp beer on tap in pubs and bars first up with an initial 50,000 litres planned. It has already chosen a name, Doss Blockos Hemp Lager.
A string of  trade on the ASX and it has become a major industry in the United States, with stockbroker Morgans outlining earlier this year that particular segment had become a US$7.4 billion industry. Hemp Foods Australia chief executive Paul Benhaim said hemp had many of the characteristics of a "super-food" and he expects strong demand to build after November because of the high levels of amino acids, proteins and omega-3 and omega-6 fatty acids.

Mr Cairns predicted that craft beer would continue to snare market share away from the big mainstream beer companies. "We just go after what we go after," Mr Cairns said.
East 9th Brewing has been able to quickly develop new products and labels in response to community issues, having brought out a series of products under its Fog City Activist Cider range on issues such as same-sex marriage and Australia's approach to immigration.
This brings its own set of dilemmas, which mirror those faced by hundreds of craft brewers with an anti-establishment and rebellious approach to upending the beer sector. Become too big and successful and you put at risk the very independent spirit which drove the company in the first place.
Mr Lefers said East 9th Brewing could fund its next leg of growth through traditional means and stay true to its original ideals. Elsewhere in the industry, those outside investors increasingly looking at the strong growth of the craft beer sector, and eyeing potential buyout opportunities, as has occurred in the US.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Wools</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$7.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hemp Foods Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fog City Activist Cider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths' Dan Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California's Humboldt Brewing Co's Brown Hemp Ale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East 9</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Lefers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cairns</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Benhaim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lefers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doss Blockos Hemp Lager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
