<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426745228559489</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/joel-selwood-racing-clock-to-be-fit-for-next-week-after-ankle-injury-in-loss-to-sydney/news-story/0d53d71a2dacb397f62ad9a59b84f11f</url>
  <title>Cats confident Selwood won't miss</title>
  <content>
GEELONG remains hopeful captain Joel Selwood can prove his fitness for next Saturday's clash with Richmond at Simonds Stadium after suffering an ankle injury in the 46-point loss to Sydney at Simonds Stadium.
On a night in which the Cats' top-two hopes took a dent, Selwood twice rolled his ankle before sitting out the final quarter of the match when the club put him in cotton wool.
MATCH REPORT:
SWANS WIN:
Cats coach Chris Scott said Selwood had been taken from the field when the game was beyond doubt in an effort to increase his chances of playing against the Tigers.
"They (the medical staff) are actually confident," Scott said. "I am actually confident enough to say now he will be fine."
"Clearly in the last quarter (the question) was around whether we should keep pushing him through, making his chance of playing next week lower."
Scott said Sydney's two-goal play at the start of the last quarter crushed the Cats' chances of staging a revival.
He said from the vision he had seen, he didn't agree with the umpire's decision to pay Tom Papley with a second shot at goal after Dan Hannebery had kicked the first one.
But he insisted Mitch Duncan had made a mistake in going back at Papley after there was a bit of niggle between the two of them.
"I have looked at it, and (you can) have an opinion on these things," Scott said. "I think that if the umpire that paid it has a look at the vision I have looked at, he will be disappointed that he paid it. That's OK, mistakes happen.
"The more accurate question and the one we are more focused on is why did Mitch do it in the first place.
"(He) gave them reason to pay a free kick and then gave them a 50 when he missed the shot.
"Clearly we had a chance at quarter-time and we handed it to them ... the mistakes were made by our players. If there was a subsequent mistake by the umpires, their coaches will pick it up on Monday when they get to work."
He expected Patrick Dangerfield, who resumes from his suspension next week, to come back fresher following his week off.
"I hope so," he said. "That was obviously one of the things that we considered in making that decision (not to challenge). It is hard to say definitively, (but) I don't think it will hurt him."

AFL: Geelong's Mitch Duncan punched Sydney's Tom Papley, giving away a shot for goal. Despite missing, the Cats gave away a 50-metre penalty, making the goal a certainty.

Cat's costly brain snap
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Hannebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SWANS WIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
