<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426234127440599</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/power-prices-must-fall-by-a-quarter-before-sa-can-market-itself-as-an-attractive-investment-destination-bhp-olympic-dam-boss-says/news-story/5557aafbc2aff80b1b449c95c8be788d</url>
  <title>BHP: Power prices 'must fall by 25 per cent'</title>
  <content>
POWER prices in South Australia need to drop by 25 per cent before the state can effectively market itself as an attractive investment destination, the boss of BHP's Olympic Dam mine says.
Jacqui McGill made the comments at an AmCham lunch in Adelaide on Friday, where
"We compete in a global market - I can't add a 25 per cent premium onto my copper price, because that's how much more expensive the power price is in SA," she said.
"(Power) pricing has to shift - you cannot have the power prices at the level we do and look to encourage investment into the state of SA.
"We need more action, both nationally and locally, to ensure pricing of power is improved."
Ms McGill has previously said that she was "very keen" to see power prices come down.
"You know our business is tied to the state. What I'm concerned about for the state is for those businesses who aren't tied here and what the potential impact of that higher pricing will mean for them," she said.
As well as price, Ms McGill said security of power supply was of vital importance.
Full production at Olympic Dam - which requires around 125MW of power to operate - didn't resume for more than a fortnight following last September's statewide blackout, ultimately costing the company $US105 million.
BHP had since "made investments to provide us with protection if there's ever a blackout of that duration again", Ms McGill said.
"We're very conscious that we're at the end of the Christmas tree lights where we're located in northern SA," she said.
"The removal of the Northern power station (in Port Augusta) from that area, that is a concern for us - the security of supply, price, and the reliability of the system.
"We've made investments over the past two decades that see us connected to the grid - that's a pretty normal expectation for someone in a first-world country to make ... that investment to build those powerlines should be sufficient to give you power.
"Now that's proven not to be the case, we've got a nationwide study underway to look at our options for power."
Business SA's executive director of industry and government engagement, Anthony Penney, said Ms McGill's remarks "make sense", particularly for energy-intensive businesses.
"If you look at future power prices as of today (Friday), SA is 30 per cent higher than NSW, 11 per cent higher than Victoria, and more than 50 per cent higher than Queensland," he said.
"So if you're a business owner looking to expand and you use a sizeable amount of energy, you're not going to go to the state with the highest prices."
A State Government spokesman conceded that power prices are too high nationally, not only in SA.
"The Federal Government knows the solution but still refuses to back the Finkel review recommendation for a market mechanism that drives new private sector investment in electricity generation," he said.
Opposition energy spokesman Dan van Holst Pellekaan said SA was "facing an investment drought due to sky-high electricity prices".
"The Weatherill Government's decision to close the Northern power station has resulted in the biggest economic blow since Labor's State Bank disaster," he said.
Asked what her advice to the major parties would be leading up to next year's state election, Ms McGill said: "Look at key infrastructure in the state and ensure it is ready and available at the right price - about 25 per cent lower than it is at the moment - to support business."
"We need to tackle some of the input costs, so that it's (SA) a good place to do business. Cheaper power is the key for me."
Ms McGill described the recent Finkel review into the national electricity retail market as "fantastic".
"For the government to adopt 49 out of the 50 recommendations was good. To adopt 50 would've been great," she said, referring to the failure to implement a clean energy target.
Mr Penney said Business SA "highly encouraged" the Federal Government to adopt the CET.
luke.griffiths@news.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$105</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Penney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP's Olympic Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Penney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AmCham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weatherill Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui McGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's State Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Augusta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McGill</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holst Pellekaan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
