<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426466055679429</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/world/china-airbrushes-north-korean-missile-tests-20170803-gxoyj2</url>
  <title>China is not the answer on North Korea</title>
  <content>
After North Korea tested an  that, for the first time, appeared capable of reaching as far as the United States west coast and into Australia, it made headline news around the world.
The launch came just three-and-a-half weeks after an earlier test which had also dominated newspaper front pages, forcing defence experts to slash estimates for how long it would take Pyongyang to deliver nuclear weapons to distant targets.
But, in China, which shares a 1400-kilometre border with North Korea, both missile tests barely rated a mention. News coverage in the tightly controlled state-owned media was limited to the foreign ministry's bland comments reiterating Beijing's "commitment to the denuclearisation of the Korean peninsula".
The Communist Party's official newspaper, The People's Daily, ran a short story on the July 4 missile launch on page 22.

Bloomberg

This news placement does not accurately reflect the potential consequences for China should North Korea's temperamental dictator Kim Jong-un realise his nuclear ambitions. Putting aside China's proximity to North Korea's nuclear facilities, Beijing is Pyongyang's only major ally and is being held responsible by the likes of Donald Trump and Malcolm Turnbull for reining in Kim's ambitions.

The lack of coverage in China is indicative of Beijing's priorities. Ding Xueliang, a social science professor at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology says despite mounting pressure from world leaders, "it's very clear China does not want to do too much on North Korea."
US President Donald Trump, frustrated by what he sees as Beijing's inaction, is threatening an investigation into China's trade practices. Australia and the United Kingdom have piled on the pressure, urging the Chinese government to do more to solve the problem. And with each missile test, public calls for Beijing's intervention grow louder.
However, there are a growing number of experts who believe these calls . China's diplomatic sway in North Korea is not what it used to be and Beijing is reluctant to use its economic leverage in any significant way for fear of triggering a humanitarian crisis on its doorstep.
"China really doesn't want the regime to collapse because they would get a flood of refugees across the border," says Bruce Bennett, a senior defense researcher at the Rand Corporation.

AP

"North-eastern China is not the Manchuria of World War II. It's a rust belt. It's got the worst economic conditions in China and they can't afford a whole lot of refugees coming in."
Andrew O'Neil, a professor of political science at Griffith University, agrees China is unlikely to cut off fuel exports or impose dramatic trade sanctions.
"They have zero inclination to put any real pressure on the border," he says. "While they are concerned about missiles reaching deep into China and they are concerned about the US choosing a military option, I don't think they will respond to the pressure from the US."
O'Neil says the public urgings for China to do more to resolve the issue are "just an alibi for the White House not having a coherent policy."

AP

With China's economic leverage seemingly off the table, that leaves diplomatic influence. However, relations between China and North Korea have deteriorated since Kim came to power in 2011.
"The bilateral relationship between China and North Korea is at a historical low," says Lu Chao, a director of the Border Studies Institute at the Liaoning Academy of Social Sciences in northeast China.
"China's influence over Pyongyang is way less than US expectations."
Unlike his father and grandfather, Kim Jong-il and Kim Il-sung, the current leader has not visited China since taking over the reins and is said to have purged pro-Beijing factions from within the political elite.

The assassination in February of Kim's estranged older brother, Kim Jong-nam, who had been living in Macau and Beijing and was widely regarded to be under the protection of Chinese authorities, added further strain to the relationship.
"From what I have been told from very high level defectors from North Korea, Kim Jong-un when he was declared the successor started killing all of the elites who knew his older brother," says Bennett.
"I think he was worried that as he increasingly infuriates the Chinese, some day they could come in and remove him and put his older brother in place."
Even without these strains in the relationship, the focus of China's leadership is very much on domestic issues in the lead up to the Party Congress later this year, at which new appointments will be made to the top decision-making body.

This week, Chinese President Xi Jinping and other Communist Party power brokers retreated to the beach resort of Beidaihe, east of Beijing, to negotiate over candidates for leadership positions.
Xi is almost certain to remain General Secretary for a second five-year term but at least five of the top seven positions are potentially up for grabs, with the appointments crucial to the long-term viability of the Party.
"This is Xi's priority right now," says Ding.
"He is focused on his own political security and that of the Party."
Given Beijing's domestic focus, its diminished political influence over Pyongyang and its resistance to meting out economic punishment, analysts are debating what else can be done to halt North Korea's nuclear program.
US Secretary of State Rex Tillerson said this week the Trump administration was willing to hold talks with North Korea but only if it agreed to give up its nuclear program, which is a deal breaker for Pyongyang.
"Kim Jong-un is much less receptive than his father or grandfather to sitting down at the table with the Americans," says O'Neil. "He is very hardcore in the way he approaches the outside world and less schooled in the merits of bargaining and compromise."
China has urged South Korea and the US to halt joint military exercises in exchange for a suspension of North Korea's nuclear program but there are fears this would leave Seoul vulnerable to an attack.

The US has also said it is preparing military responses should diplomatic efforts fail.
"A lot of people talk about surgical military strikes," says Bennett. "The problem is there's not one facility or two facilities in North Korea supporting these programs, there are dozens.
"Even if you were to do a symbolic strike that took out a couple of facilities, North Korea has been very clear it would retaliate in the most severe of manners.
"With any kind of attack against North Korea there is the possibility of a big war and that would probably be a nuclear war. Nobody wants to take the chance of that at this stage."
Bennett says there are other military options like sending a carrier battle group into the Yellow Sea off the coast near Pyongyang, which would infuriate both North Korea and China. However, these are "symbolic" and wouldn't "stop North Korea from building more missiles", he says.
He says political rather than military pressure should be applied to force Kim to the negotiating table.
"We have pretty good evidence to suggest that a fair number of the elite in North Korea are unhappy with Kim Jong-un," he says.
"He runs what is generously called a third-world economy. Why aren't we doing more to advertise to North Koreans what South Korea looks like?"

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffith University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North-eastern China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Neil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchuria of World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beidaihe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February of Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Studies Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong Il</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Party Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew O'Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong University of Science</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Secretary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lu Chao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese President Xi Jinping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ding Xueliang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seoul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Il Sung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rand Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communist Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong Nam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yellow Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liaoning Academy of Social</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
