<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426715163787629</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/how-the-jury-found-dane-andrew-pilcher-guilty-of-corinne-hendersons-murder/news-story/fd8a3f8953381e6cff8ec6d0713b4f88</url>
  <title>Murder: Corinne was trying to start afresh</title>
  <content>
CORINNE Henderson was on the cusp of a new life.
The Townsville fly-in, fly-out mine worker had been offered a promotion, her romance with colleague Dwayne Wickham was blossoming and construction on her dream home was starting within days.
On September 26, 2015, she spent the day with her parents, Mr Wickham and his mother at the Townsville Cup.
An hour after she went to bed at her Idalia unit, she heard the kitchen window smash - it was her ex-partner, Dane Andrew Pilcher.
Pilcher, 38, was yesterday found guilty of the murder of Ms Henderson, 32, by stabbing her 21 times with a kitchen knife.
He mutilated her body - slashing her face, neck, hands and back - before phoning triple-zero.

Pilcher had pleaded not guilty to murder, raising the defences of self-defence, provocation and accident.
But a Townsville Supreme Court jury reached a unanimous guilty verdict at 3.50pm yesterday, deliberating for two-and-a-half hours.
Pilcher did not react or show any emotion as the verdict was handed down.
One of his supporters gasped loudly, and his father Norm Pilcher walked out of the courtroom before the matter was set down for sentencing on Thursday.
The court heard Pilcher had been in custody since September 26, 2015, the night he murdered Ms Henderson.
Crown prosecutor Michael Cowen QC said when Pilcher's home was searched police found a rifle, ammunition and illegal steroids.
He tendered documents for Justice David North's consideration, including victim impact statements written by Ms Henderson's parents and brothers.
Ms Henderson's friend Sally Jupp said the Henderson family travelled from Tasmania for the trial, but did not attend court until the verdict was handed down.
She said the family, who did not wish to speak to media, would be affected for the rest of their lives.
"(It would have been hard) having to relive all of the details of how horrific it was - if it was one stab, that fatal stab wound and that was it, as opposed to the brutality of the attack," Ms Jupp said outside court.
"Their daughter was their world and I don't think that they'll ever be the same, ever again."
Pilcher was convicted yesterday after a nine-day trial, in which Mr Cowen called nearly 40 witnesses.
Pilcher chose to take the witness box, and gave what Mr Cowen described to the court as a "nonsense" account of being stabbed first by Ms Henderson.
Mr Cowen said Ms Henderson and Pilcher had been in a relationship for about two years when she broke things off in July 2015.
Pilcher moved out and Ms Henderson had been forced to change her locks.
"Text messages off his phone, off various other people's phones, document what he thought of the breakup of the relationship, that he couldn't seem to let it go with Corinne," Mr Cowen said.
Pilcher's sentence hearing will be held on Thursday.
Under Queensland legislation he will be sentenced to a mandatory term of life in jail.
Killer's past life revealed
CONVICTED murderer Dane Pilcher stands at six foot three.
He is a lean, fit fighter, trained in knife combat from his time in the Army and has practised martial arts.
Pilcher, 38, has criminal records in Queensland and Western Australia.
During his two-week murder trial, Pilcher took the stand and revealed his past life to the jury.
He finished his studies at Thuringowa State High School before starting work in the mining industry at 20.
Pilcher had a brief stint in the Army and was deployed to Iraq for two months. In 2007, he went absent without leave and returned to mining, taking a job as a machine operator at Cannington mine, near Mount Isa.
At one stage, as a temporary supervisor, he was making $190,000 a year.
Pilcher married his sweetheart of four years, Katherine Pilcher, in 2010 and she gave birth to their son in 2012.
They purchased a family home at Rupertswood in 2013.
Corinne Henderson started working at Cannington mine in July that year, and by September she and Pilcher were having an affair.
"When Corinne and my relationship was exposed, there were people at the workplace who took exception to our relationship, we had a certain supervisor claiming that it was affecting our work," Pilcher told the Supreme Court during his murder trial.
He said he and Ms Henderson were put on different shifts, and he was sacked about April 2013 when he showed up late to work.
Pilcher said he was compensated $12,500 for unfair dismissal through Fair Work. At the time he killed Ms Henderson, Pilcher was working at a coal mine near Moranbah.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cowen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corinne Henderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwayne Wickham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Idalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Henderson</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine Pilcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Andrew Pilcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 26, 2015</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilcher</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corinne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Isa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wickham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norm Pilcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moranbah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cowen QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cannington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilcher, 38</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jupp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice David North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Jupp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Pilcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thuringowa State High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupertswood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
