<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426483235549021</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/visa-restrictions-to-hit-property-demand-ubs-20170801-gxniqv</url>
  <title>457 Visa restrictions to hit property demand: UBS</title>
  <content>
Australian housing demand could fall by as much as 10 per cent if new rules on 457 visas resulted in a halving of future approvals, according to scenario studies by investment bank UBS.
The demand for housing could fall as much as 30 per cent if student visa approvals fell by a third.
The analysts, Grant McCasker, James Druce and George Tharenou, said they spoke to a number of industry contacts, drew upon surveys and analysed visa data to examine the latest changes to the 457 visa regime (renamed Temporary Skill Shortage or TSS visa). The changes are to be fully implemented by March 2018.
Whilst the analysts don't anticipate such a sharp fall in demand they do say housing demand will drop because of the new visa restrictions.

"We see risks on the horizon. The impact of the new TSS visa to housing demand is likely under appreciated by the market."

include such things as restricting the pathway to permanent residency for occupations on the Short-term Skilled Occupations List, alongside other requirements such as higher  and longer Australian work experience.
While the new visa rules will likely slow the rate of growth of skilled visas it is also likely to have effects on other visas applications because of the interdependency between student, graduate, 457 and permanent visas.
"Tighter eligibility requirements and the interdependency between visa categories, particularly student visas, means net overseas migration will likely fall and net overseas migration comprises around half of underlying demand," the analysts said.
In fiscal 2015, about 400,000 student and 457 visas were granted. The analysts say that demand for land is more at risk than apartments due to the demographics.

They say Indians are the largest 457 visa users and the fastest growing migrants, while Chinese are a bigger student category but small 457 users.
"The [Indian] demographic is the largest user of the 457 visa and are more reliant on the path from student to permanent resident based on the data. Anecdotally this demographic is over represented in Sydney and Melbourne land projects."
The analysts expect that developers of land, such as the largest listed group Stockland, will face pressure while developers of apartments, such as Mirvac, will escape the changes largely unscathed.
The National Property Research Company's Matthew Gross, who is a business liaison to the Reserve Bank of Australia on real estate, said net migration is one of the most important drivers of the property market.

"When you start taking out migration numbers then you might find yourself in a situation where you have more product than end users," Mr Gross said.
"Without an end user your product slows - its like the mining towns when the miners moved out - vacancy rates rose and asset prices declined."
In June 2016 overseas migration for NSW showed a net increase of 76,000 while Victoria recorded 68,000 and Queensland third largest with a net increase of 21,000.
"Australia's property market would be so much worse off if it did not have the level of immigration we have had in the last 4 to 5 years."

Over the last five years house prices in Sydney have risen more than 75 per cent.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Druce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TSS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirvac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Property Research Company's Matthew Gross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant McCasker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Short-term Skilled Occupations List</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Tharenou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temporary Skill Shortage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
