<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426719458755015</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/entertainment/in-the-zone/news-story/5dbad7568fd720d5a20387da6d60ecd2</url>
  <title>In the zone</title>
  <content>
He's been embedded in the Free Syria Army, crossed Afghani war zones, crawled through the Indonesian jungle to find orang-utans, and on an African safari on the trail of rhino poachers.
But today, Sabour Bradley's locked in an editing suite in Melbourne - the side to being a documentary film maker that requires probably the least adrenaline.
What he's working on is (mostly) top secret, although he tells Townsville Eye it's a pilot for a series on a digital platform in the US which he's written and directed, featuring a presenter with worldwide appeal.
"I can't say too much about it, but it's really cool and really exciting. It's hard to talk about it without giving anything away," he says, almost bursting. We're intrigued.
Despite all his globetrotting, Townsville is still one of three places Bradley considers "home" (the others are Cooktown and Kununurra in Western Australia).
He loves Magnetic Island despite the lack of surf, and it was the first place he took his British wife upon arriving in Australia. (Apparently it was also the place where he first saw a woman's breasts, but we're not sure if those stories are connected).
Most importantly though, it was here in Townsville where he discovered the love for storytelling that would see him venture into some of the world's most dangerous locations making documentaries for Al Jazeera, National Geographic and the ABC.
"I was in Year 12 at Kirwan High and I wrote this story for the Townsville Bulletin as a student journalist and it went in the paper and people from all over would come up to me and talk about it," he said.
"That was the first time I realised you could sit down and write something, and it could have all these wide-ranging effects that you never saw.
"I realised that what I wanted to do for the rest of my life was travel the world, find amazing people and tell their stories."
Bradley's big break in the documentary making world came almost by accident during a trip to Afghanistan.
"I went there chasing a girl and I was going to ask her to marry me. About three weeks after I arrived in Afghanistan we broke up," he said.
"I had a job there for three months so while I was there they asked me to make a series, and that became Extreme Tourist.
"I got to traipse all over Afghanistan and it sold around the world on National Geographic."
It was on the back of that experience in Afghanistan that he caught the attention of the ABC, who later gave him a gig telling Australian stories for his series Head First.
For his latest project, Bradley's stepped away from the camera, teaming up to write and direct Iranian-born American comedian Bobby Aazami (pictured top left) in his autobiographical one-man show The Six Million Dollar Kid, which premieres at the Townsville Cultural Festival next week.
"It's a superhero story about a guy growing up in Iran who was completely obsessed with the American TV show The Six Million Dollar Man. So much so that he believed it was his destiny to become the Six Million Dollar Man," he said.
"His family had to escape from Iran because of the Islamic revolution.
"Arriving in America was a complete cultural clash. He doesn't speak English, he doesn't have any friends.
"Then a tragedy happens in his family that they ask him to cover up, so he's living with this dark secret as a kid and the one thing that gets him through this whole time is his belief in superheroes and this belief he's going to become a superhero."
The show has been an 18-month labour of love for the pair who met while Bradley was in Portland. Upon hearing Aazami's amazing life story, Bradley became fixated on the idea of bringing it to life on the stage.
"When I become obsessed by a story, I just cannot stop. I would be out shooting a documentary, crawling through the mud in Indonesia looking for orang-utans, and in my head this story was just going over and over," he said.
Finishing the show in time for the premiere has been a race against the clock.
The pair locked themselves away for 10 days in a house at Torquay a few weeks ago for some intense workshopping to get it just right. But the experience proved to be far more transformational and emotional than either of them could have expected.
"Halfway through workshopping, [Bobby] had this profound moment he finished the scene about his mother and he came and sat down at the table and said 'I realise after 35 years, I'm now ready to forgive my mother'," Bradley said.
"That happened because he was in a scene playing his mother and himself so he was able to see things from her perspective and from his own. That was a profoundly moving moment but also incredibly happy.
"Wherever the show goes around the world, the fact that doing it has been this incredible healing process for Bobby is probably the more important part of it."
As projects go, the collaboration with Aazami definitely ranks as one of the safest.
Gathering stories from all corners of the globe has seen him in some pretty dicey situations including being shot at by the Turkish military while searching for a missing Australian in Syria.
But Bradley says he has a simple criterion for deciding whether or not the risk is worth it, and it doesn't involve checking in with his mum to gauge her reaction.
"My mum is a very different kind of mum. She spent 18 months travelling through the Middle East with my older sister as a baby on her back. She went through Iran, Afghanistan, Egypt, and all these kind of places back when there was no internet and no safety net," he said.
"So when I rang up and said, 'Hey, Mum, I'm going to be going to Afghanistan,' there was a silence on the other end of the line and she goes, 'Oh, and I suppose you want me to pay for that, do you?'
"There was no, 'Don't go! It's too dangerous!' She completely accepted it. She's pretty hardy - it really takes a lot to scare her."
For Bradley, diving in head first on a dangerous story comes down to one simple question: Is this story worth dying for?
"If you're going to go into places like Syria or Afghanistan or the Congo and there's a potential for you dying, you have to ask if it's worth your life to tell their story? If you say 'yes' then you just go for it," he said.
"Often I'll get to a point in a story and I'll think, 'Wow, I'm really blessed to be making this and to be with these people and for them to be sharing their story with me' - like being in Afghanistan in some of the most dangerous parts of the country and meeting these people who were so brave and doing incredible things and willing to laugh about it.
"For me, I think it's not so much about the act of sitting down and writing, but more about people. That's why I love interviewing and conversation and pushing people.
"That's why I gravitated towards documentary making and asking questions because I've always been curious. If I'm at a party or anywhere I'm probably the guy asking the awkward questions for the story.
"I think as journalists and storytellers, we're always asking awkward questions to get to the heart of the matter or get to the conflict, which is drama and which is where the interesting stuff lies."
The Six Million Dollar Kidis on at the Townsville Cultural Fest on August 11 at 12pm and August 13 at 4pm. More info at bobbyaazami.com or culturalfest.org
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooktown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian-born American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Free Syria Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Jazeera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Eye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Egypt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Cultural Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Congo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Six Million Dollar Kidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnetic Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sabour Bradley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Cultural Fest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Extreme Tourist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirwan High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kununurra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobby Aazami</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torquay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Head First</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Six Million Dollar Kid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Six Million Dollar Man</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aazami</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
