<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426706573852760</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/real-estate/queensland/townsville/house-on-the-hill-to-go-to-auction/news-story/ab44050426badc4c5695c458cd799157</url>
  <title>House on the hill to go to auction - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
ONE of Townsville's most iconic homes is about to go under the hammer after receiving huge interest from potential buyers.
is instantly recognisable as the white house on the hill admired by many as they walked along The Strand.
Now the three-bedroom, two-bathroom Californian bungalow will go to auction on site on Thursday.
Listing agent Julie Mahoney from Harcourts Kingsberry Townsville said 250 groups of people had been shown through the property in the past three weeks and 100 people turned up to the first open home.

"We've had everyone from gardeners who used to work at the property over the years to people looking for an investment or to live in, so we've had quite an array," she said.
"Some significant people have lived there that have contributed to the history of Townsville.
"It's such an elegant property and it's been very well maintained.
"While it hasn't got a theatre room it has a stately elegance and it will never lose its value.
"I think it's going to be a local buyer that will live in it and just cherish it because they don't make them like this anymore and they can't be re-created."
It's the first time the home has been on the market in 44 years after being bought by co-founding director of the North Queensland Cowboys Max Short in 1973, who died last year, aged 89.
Many a social gathering has been held on the vast lawns of the property with prominent identities in attendance while everyone from the home's cleaner to politicians have eaten in the home's grand dining room.
The house is positioned on a huge parcel of land over two allotments with sweeping views of Pallarenda, Magnetic Island and Castle Hill.
While the home has been immaculately maintained, the character details such as classic timber framing, casement windows, traditional light fittings, and crown moulding have been retained.
The open plan timber kitchen has a separate causal dining area while there is also a formal dining room, two separate living areas and a master suite with walk-through wardrobe to ensuite.
A covered outdoor patio leads out to the lawn while there is also double car accommodation with a separate workshop.
Ms Mahoney said the auction will be held at the home by REIQ's 2016 auctioneer of the year Justin Nickerson.
"The family has requested it on-site and I think it's deserving of an on-site auction because the house is what it's all about and I just think it honours the property to have it on site," she said.
"There has been a lot of boardroom talk about the price and everyone from bank managers to real estate enthusiasts all have an opinion but its true market value will be found on auction day."
9 Cleveland Terrace will be open for inspection on Sunday from 3pm to 3.30pm before going to Auction on site on Thursday, August 10 at 5.30pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pallarenda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Terrace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harcourts Kingsberry Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castle Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mahoney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Nickerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Mahoney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Cowboys Max Short</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ's 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
