<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426749523526901</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/world/possible-new-banksy-graffiti-surfaces-on-israels-west-bank-barrier/news-story/f05efc27f20aa713a3819a8827231b2b</url>
  <title>Has Banksy struck again?</title>
  <content>
HAS Banksy struck again in familiar territory?
Two murals showing an over-size President Donald Trump appeared on Friday on Israel's West Bank separation barrier, just metres from where the elusive artist decorated a hotel earlier this year.
The new drawings that resemble Banksy's earlier art popped up on the edge of Bethlehem, the Palestinian city where the barrier largely consists of a wall of towering slabs of concrete.
In one scene, Trump is shown hugging and kissing a real Israeli army watchtower built into the wall, as his left arm reaches around the tower. In another drawing, Trump is depicted wearing a Jewish skullcap and placing a hand a wall - a scene taken from the US president's May visit to Jerusalem's Western Wall, the holiest site where Jews can pray.
A cartoon thought bubble next to him says: "I'm going to build you a brother" - a possible reference to Trump's plans to build a wall between the US and Mexico.
It is not clear if the new murals are indeed the work of Banksy. The new graffiti is just a few metres from The Walled Off Hotel, a Palestinian- run guesthouse opened this year that bills itself as having the "worst view in the world".
The nine-room hotel was decorated with Banksy's trademark political murals, including one in "Banksy's Room" that shows a masked Palestinian and a helmeted Israeli soldier in a pillow fight.
Banksy has made previous forays into the Palestinian territories, including drawing a painting of a girl pulled upward by balloons on the barrier facing the hotel.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jewish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walled Off Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banksy's Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bethlehem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestinians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel's West Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerusalem's Western Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banksy</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
