<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426483235549061</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/economy/higher-electricity-gas-prices-to-help-push-inflation-back-into-rbas-target-range-20170804-gxpkk8</url>
  <title>Higher electricity, gas prices to help push inflation back into RBA's target range</title>
  <content>
Higher electricity and gas bills for households will help push headline inflation back within its target range, while the economy should be able to largely withstand the drag caused by a stronger Australian dollar, according to the Reserve Bank.
In its August Statement on Monetary Policy, the Reserve Bank repeated its expectation that the Australian economy will "grow at an annual rate of about 3 per cent over the next couple of years", which it notes is slightly higher than estimates of potential growth.
But, (by half a percentage point for this year to 2-3 per cent and by a quarter-point in the first half of next to 2.5-3.5 per cent), saying the  "had a modest dampening effect" on GDP growth.
According to the latest statement, underlying inflation is "expected to reach around 2 per cent over the second half of 2017 and increase a little thereafter."

However, the forecast for headline inflation has been pushed higher, largely reflecting the larger-than-expected increases in over the coming years. As a result, headline inflation "is forecast to rise gradually and be between 2 and 3 per cent over much of the forecast statement."

The statement notes that "inflation in prices of utilities has picked up considerably in recent quarters", as wholesale gas and electricity prices have surged following the closure of coal-powered fire stations and as industry investment has fallen due to uncertainty over electricity and environmental policies. At the same time, the production of LNG for export has lifted demand for gas.
And . "The announcement of price increases by a number of electricity and gas providers points to significant pick-up in utilities inflation in both the September quarter 2017 and the March quarter 2018", the statement says.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has tried to cushion some of the impact of rising power bills on consumers by summoning electricity bosses to Canberra next week to demand they provide more information on how to reduce energy costs.
It's not only consumers who are affected. The statement notes that higher electricity and gas prices could also boost inflation indirectly, because they will push business input costs higher. Because utilities make up only a small fraction of overall business costs, these indirect effects are likely to be fairly small.

But, the statement says, "this will vary by industry and there is uncertainty around the extent of the pass-through of higher costs to final prices."
The entry of major foreign retailers - including the  is also expected to dampen inflationary pressures.
According to the statement, "the arrival of further new foreign retailers will be an important influence on consumer durable prices over the next few years."
The Reserve Bank, however, concedes that its forecasts for both inflation and growth could be disrupted by the rising Australian dollar, which is now trading close to the highest level of the past few years against the US dollar

On a trade-weighted basis (which measures the Australian dollar against a basket of currencies of our major trading partners), the statement notes that "the Australian dollar has risen to levels last seen in late 2014".
This ascent in the currency has been built into the Reserve Bank's latest forecasts. But, the statement notes, that a further rise in the Aussie dollar, if sustained, "would be expected to result in a slower pick-up in economic activity and inflation than currently forecast."
Based on the past, a 10 per cent rise in the local currency's value on a TWI basis unrelated to higher commodity prices "would be expected to cut inflation by just under 0.5 per cent over each of the next two years, and to leave output 0.5 to 1 per cent lower in around two years' time.
The future trajectory of house prices could also dampen the outlook for growth and inflation. The Reserve Bank is expecting consumer spending to pick up in the period ahead, supported by strong jobs growth and low interest rates.

But it warns that  and high debt levels could cause consumers to tighten their purse strings.
A major worry is that consumer spending growth has been strongest in Sydney and Melbourne, where
The Reserve Bank warns that large unexpected falls in housing prices could cause highly indebted households to try to pay down their debt at a faster pace, which could crimp spending.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TWI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
