<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426444580842417</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/lincoln-lewis-to-appear-on-hells-kitchen/news-story/d5fb89a66f7274373efb7b504d52f46b</url>
  <title>Lincoln out to prove he's not a 's**t' cook</title>
  <content>
LINCOLN Lewis says there are two good reasons he snapped up the opportunity to appear on Hell's Kitchen - his cooking skills could use some serious work and so could he.
Speaking ahead of the show's premiere on Seven on Sunday night, the Queenslander, 29, told The Courier-Mail: "I just want to work".
"I always talk every job over with my mum (Jacqueline) and dad (NRL legend Wally Lewis) and my family as they are all smarter than me and they said 'you can't cook for s**t anyway so you might as well learn," he said.
"But on a more serious note, I wanted to work and be busy and be back on a set again.
"I've been auditioning and whatnot and have knocked back jobs over the past two years to focus on what I was doing but, at that moment, I was ready."
The former Home and Away star, whose other credits include popular shows such as House Husbands and Gallipoli as well as last year's Aussie feature film Spin Out, admitted he did have some concerns about venturing into reality television.
"As an actor, you're used to playing a role, whereas with a reality show you're yourself so it's raw and a bit nerve-racking as you're not sure how you'll be portrayed," he said.
"I think anyone would be a bit worried but, as cliche as it sounds, I just thought 'stuff it, I'm going to go into it knowing who I am and I'm going to have fun doing it."
Lewis will appear on the new show alongside the likes of The Chase Australia supernerd Issa Schultz, One Nation founder David Oldfield, Real Housewives of Melbourne's Pettifleur Berrenger and reality television darling Sam Frost.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lincoln Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housewives of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslander, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lincoln</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spin Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqueline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallipoli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Issa Schultz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hell's Kitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pettifleur Berrenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chase Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Husbands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
