<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426844012809252</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/prawn-stars-to-delight-territorian-fishermen-and-foodies/news-story/217ef28a69cc9c7be2001324eb2787ef</url>
  <title>Prawn stars to delight Territorian fishermen and foodies</title>
  <content>
DARWIN seafood enthusiasts have been rejoicing this week, amid the beginning of the tiger prawn season.
Mr Barra retail manager Amon Hesketh said there were two main types of prawns in the Territory.
"Tiger prawns only happen once a year - it's a wonderful time of year," she said.
"Tiger prawns are a quality prawn, a stronger, meatier prawn - it's got it's own unique flavour."
She said tiger prawns, the local bestsellers, were clearly very popular with consumers.
"It's great to support the local industry," she said.
The Northern Prawn Fishery supplies Darwinites with tiger prawns.
Australian Fisheries Management Authority chief executive James Findlay said that if you are hooking into wild caught prawns from the Commonwealth's NPF, not only will your tastebuds be onto a winner but you can be assured that the product you are eating is from a well-managed, sustainable fishery.
He said by continuously looking to the latest in innovation and science, fishing operations had significantly improved their operations, which was great news for hungry Territorians.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amon Hesketh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Fisheries Management Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth's NPF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Findlay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwinites</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Barra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Prawn Fishery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
