<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426401631168621</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/mounting-urgency-for-australia-to-get-a-national-space-agency-according-to-the-state-government/news-story/bf6a0ed49009ffcee759b3b751983033</url>
  <title>State Govt: Australia needs a NASA now</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIA needs a National Space Agency announcement by the time Adelaide hosts the "Space Olympics", the State Government says.
Their urgency is backed by the Australian Strategic Policy Institute.
ASPI space expert and senior analyst Dr Malcolm Davis says "often" countries want to work with us on space projects but without a "NASA equivalent", there's no easy point of contact.
Adelaide will host the International Astronautical Congress in September.
Dr Davis said there was "no time for delay" and that an announcement at the Congress would be critical.
It would show Australia was engaging with space for the first time since the dawn of the Space Age, he said.

In honor of 'Space Exploration Day' we're taking a look at the modern day Space Race between billionaire entrepreneurs Elon Musk and Jeff Bezos. SpaceX and Blue Origin are private aerospace companies racing to make interplanetary travel possible for the world's population. Unlike the Cold War era Space Race, which was a competition between nations, their billionaire backers believe they are on a global mission to save humanity. SpaceX and Blue Origin are built on the belief that Earth has an expiry date. With that looming threat in mind, they are working to facilitate a space-faring civilization for the future. Elon Musk, founder of SpaceX, believes, "catastrophic global warming or some as-yet-unknown technology could spell the end of us," and has publicly revealed his ambitions to colonize Mars within the next 50 to 100 years. Jeff Bezos' Blue Origin predicts to have their first interplanetary commercial flight by 2018. This is the first step to his long-term vision of millions of people living and working in space. Credit: Various via Storyful

The Modern Space Race: SpaceX v. Blue Origin
The Space Age began when the Russians launched the Sputnik satellite 60 years ago on October 4, 1957.
"When you go to the US ,if you want to talk space, you go to NASA," Dr Davis said.
"There's a face, a point of contact - the Congress is coming up on us fast, there's not a lot of time."
Billionaire entrepreneur Elon Musk is set to announce details of a proposed mission to Mars at the Congress, which is the world's biggest gathering of astronauts and space experts.
Highlights will include Australia's role in the development of space tugs for inter-orbit transfers, the search for space junk, and the possibility of outer space settlements, Defence Industries Minister Martin Hamilton-Smith told The Advertiser.
"All eyes" would be on SA for the Congress, with SA "eyeing a larger share of the space economy", he said.
At Friday's Council of Australian Government's Industry Council meeting, the State Government and the ACT Government teamed up to push for a space agency headquartered in Canberra, with an operational base in South Australia.
Assistant Minister to the Treasurer Chris Picton told The Advertiser they were pushing for a quick decision so the Congress becomes a chance to tell the world about our space industry.
"The statistics are pretty telling," he said.
"Of the massive $400 billion space industry, on the basis of our economy we should be getting about 1.8 per cent of that in Australia but we're only getting 0.8 per cent."
Mr Picton said the lack of an agency was a barrier to working with other countries.
"We don't have a space industry to talk to their space industry," he said.

The Federal Government will consult on its review of the space industry until mid September - the Congress begins on the 25th.
Science Minister Arthur Sinodinos says the review will consider the pros and cons of a national space agency.
The review is not scheduled to finish until March, but it is understood there will be an update at the Congress.
The Advertiser revealed on Friday that the $100 million Advanced Manufacturing Fund - earmarked to help South Australia and Victoria after car makers close - could help businesses transition to space.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Govt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Astronautical Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mars</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Space Exploration Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Science Minister Arthur Sinodinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advanced Manufacturing Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Origin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Bezos' Blue Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Industries Minister Martin Hamilton-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Space Race</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday's Council of Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Bezos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modern Space Race</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Chris Picton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Space Age</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Malcolm Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SpaceX</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Picton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government's Industry Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Space Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sputnik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Strategic Policy Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Davis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
