<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426191177766590</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/billy-slater-stars-as-storm-crush-cowboys-268-to-curtail-finals-charge/news-story/a51c494f746339cc1960997dd81db347</url>
  <title>Crushed Cowboys in finals fight after Storm surge</title>
  <content>
NORTH Queensland have been plunged into a desperate fight for a finals berth after an injury crisis and a brilliant Billy Slater combined to crush the Cowboys in Townsville.
The ladder-leading Storm again flexed their premiership muscle as Melbourne's talismanic Big Three Slater, Cameron Smith and Cooper Cronk engineered a 26-8 victory at 1300 Smiles Stadium.
But there was pain on several fronts for the Cowboys, whose fifth consecutive loss to Melbourne was compounded by injuries to key trio Gavin Cooper (calf), Antonio Winterstein (groin) and prop Scott Bolton (elbow).
The Cowboys' injury toll was so acute hulking forward Coen Hess was forced to defend at left centre - and the clinical Storm went for the jugular, scoring three tries down the Origin rookie's edge.
Returning from concussion, Slater was sublime, the Storm champion posting three try assists, three tackle busts, two line-break assists and one line break as he tormented the Cowboys.
Now North Queensland are walking the top-eight tightrope. They are likely to finish the weekend in sixth spot, just two wins ahead of the ninth-placed team. And with a daunting road trip to face fast-finishing Penrith next Saturday night, the depleted Cowboys face a nervous run to the playoffs.
Amid the carnage, the Cowboys showed immense courage.
The hosts trailed 16-8 with 16 minutes to play before they ran out of petrol as Storm wingers Suliasi Vunivalu and Josh Addo-Carr finished with doubles to break the Cowboys' spirit.
As if Melbourne's all-star cast wasn't formidable enough, North Queensland had to battle with another unwanted foe - fresh injuries.
The momentum generated by the hosts' energetic start was gradually eroded by a slew of setbacks as three Cowboys top-liners left the field inside 26 minutes.
The game was just 60 seconds old when Origin back-rower and skipper Cooper limped up the tunnel with a suspected calf injury.
Winger Winterstein was the second victim, straining his groin in a futile attempt to stop Storm flyer Addo-Carr stepping through for his fourth-minute try.
And when hardworking prop Bolton trudged off holding his arm, the Storm could smell blood as North Queensland's bench looked as skinny as a Kenyan marathon runner.
The Cowboys did well to hold their nerve. Few hookers possess Jake Granville's incisive edge and when he sliced through in the 13th minute, the Cowboys were hanging tough at 6-4.
But Melbourne are the masters of exploiting a rival's deficiency. With Cowboys coach Paul Green forced to deploy forward Hess at left centre to cover for Winterstein, Storm masterminds Smith and Cronk went for the jugular.
Melbourne's one-two try-scoring punch at the back end of the first half was landed on the Cowboys' left edge as Hess struggled to shut down the quicker Will Chambers.
The Storm weren't at their imperious best. But with Slater setting the standard, they moved a step closer to the minor premiership.
MELBOURNE 26 (J Addo-Carr 2 S Vunivalu 2 W Chambers tries C Smith 3 goals) bt NORTH  QUEENSLAND 8 (J Granville try E Lowe 2 goals) at 1300SMILES Stadium. Referee: Alan Shortall, Ashley Klein. Crowd: 21,380.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMILES Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hess</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addo-Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Shortall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Winterstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J Granville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slater</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Granville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C. Smith 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suliasi Vunivalu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterstein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUEENSLAND 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Three Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Chambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Klein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E Lowe 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMILES Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Addo-Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coen Hess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenyans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J Addo-Carr 2 S Vunivalu 2 W Chambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
