<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426844012809308</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/residents-dark-on-gardens-oval-plans/news-story/5f82ef1472d6c0834c637a2c102c361b</url>
  <title>Residents dark on Gardens Oval plans</title>
  <content>
RESIDENTS are dark on the Darwin council about plans for lighting up Gardens Oval and have warned mayoral candidates it is going to be a local government election issue.
The residents have formed a protest group and started a campaign to head off the construction of four 32m towers around the main oval, which they say will destroy their living conditions.
AFLNT boss Michael Solomon has told council the light towers would house state-of-the-art LED lighting and cost in the vicinity of $450,000 to $500,000. Mr Solomon has previously said his organisation had bipartisan support to fund the project on Darwin's oldest sporting arena.
Protest group spokesman Dan Leather has also warned Chief Minister Michael Gunner and his Labor Member for Port Darwin Paul Kirby that they cannot hide from the glare of the lights battle.
"There are around 800 rate-paying residents that will be affected if the Darwin City Council and the Territory Government allows this project to go ahead," Mr Leather said.
"The oval is in Chief Minister Michael Gunner's electorate and the bulk of the 800 residents live in Paul Kirby's electorates. They have an important role to play in making sure that they properly represent the people who voted for them and also to protect this precious greenbelt.
"The plan is to light up Gardens Oval six days a week until after 9pm with four towers at a height equivalent to an 11-storey building with between 100 to 600 lux lighting capacity.
"Many of us are long-term residents who bought here because of the quality of life offered. Our lives are going to be turned upside down by these light towers shining into our homes. We don't have anything against sport, but we do have a problem with our homes being lit up like daylight by these towers. "
He said there were great community ovals at Nightcliff, Moil, Anula and Alawa that can be used instead.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Darwin Paul Kirby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nightcliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gardens Oval</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Minister Michael Gunner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territory Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Leather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Leather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Kirby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
