<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426397336201280</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/a-gifted-boy-left-singapore-to-enrol-in-this-public-school-20170803-gxoger.html</url>
  <title>To learn digital money-making secrets, eight-year-old Seth swaps Singapore for Dandenong school</title>
  <content>
Eight-year-old computer prodigy Seth Yee has swapped his home in Singapore for Dandenong North, drawn by a program at a local primary school where students are learning how to build the next Bitcoin.
In what is believed to be a Victorian first, students at Wooranna Park Primary School are being taught how to use the software behind Bitcoin to create their own security-encrypted digital currency.Photo: Paul Jeffers
Seth's father, Ray, said the family had searched far and wide to find a school such as Wooranna Park which would stimulate their son, who was building virtual spaceships on a NASA program when he was six.
"I think it is opening up a lot for him," said Mr Yee.
Under the supervision of Kieran Nolan, a network engineer turned teacher Seth's fellow students, most of them in grade five and six, spend three weeks programming the new currency called "WoorannaCoin"
WoorannaCoin has no dollar value - it is set up on a platform allowing people to create mock alternatives to Bitcoin - but Mr Nolan said the priority is to teach students the software behind Bitcoin, called Blockchain.

"I think it is going to be as important as coding in schools in the coming years," he said.
"It's a way of teaching financial literacy, digital literacy ... it teaches students how networks talk to each other.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"If students don't have these skills now, schools are doing them a disservice.
"If you only look at numeracy and literacy, that won't get someone a job in the future, they need to have these skills."
Bitcoin has stolen headlines for revolutionising digital financial transactions, but the market has been subject to booms and busts.
Blockchain however, which allows users to make anonymous, secure payments that cannot be forged, reversed or stolen, is now being trialled for other uses - elections, health record storage and property transactions.
Mr Nolan's students are using Blockchain to build a transparent and secure voting system.
Using the technology has also empowered students to control their online data, said Mr Nolan, as Blockchain uses a peer-to-peer network, which means it is not regulated by a centralised authority.
This means that the student's data cannot be stored and exploited by a third party.
"I think it's important for them to learn about trusted third parties, whether that be Facebook, Google or YouTube, that their data doesn't belong to them."
Impressed by the scale of innovation, a US-based software developer and funder Andrew Kwon donated 21 Bitcoins (the equivalent of $30,000 at the time) to the school during a visit six months ago.
It is believed this is the first time an Australian school has received Bitcoin donations.
Half of the fund - controlled by Mr Kwon - has paid for computer hardware for a new high-tech centre, equipped with virtual reality goggles, 3D printers, networking equipment, a Microsoft HoloLens, a programmable robot and drones.
The other half will be spent on computer hardware that the students will vote on.
This new centre, to be called the "Blockchain Headquarters" is where students will learn about the process of raising funds for new currencies and run their own mock kickstarter campaign.
As well as learning what he can, Seth Yee is running a weekly session teaching students how to code and use the Blockchain.
"He is being more creative about the things he can do," his father says.
"He is also helping to teach some teachers how to set up computers and use programs."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Yee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wooranna Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nolan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wooranna Park Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kwon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Kwon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WoorannaCoin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seth Yee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft's Hololens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blockchain Headquarters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
