<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427020106471912</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:23</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/hr-mcmaster-steve-bannon-russia-trolls-2017-8</url>
  <title>The knives are coming out for H.R. McMaster</title>
  <content>
Allies of White House chief strategist Steve Bannon intensified their battle against national security adviser H.R. McMaster this week as McMaster began asserting more control over the National Security Council , Michael Flynn.

The dismissals of NSC officials Ezra Cohen-Watnick, Rich Higgins, and Derek Harvey have exacerbated friction between McMaster and the more nationalist wing of the White House, which is led by Bannon and has President Donald Trump's ear.

"There is a split in the White House between the Bannon camp of ideologues and the McMaster-Mattis-Tillerson camp of more centrist intellectuals," , a retired Army colonel who worked closely with McMaster, . "And this conflict is playing out in real time as the Trump administration tries to flesh out its foreign policy and national security policy."

The recent ascendance of retired Gen. John Kelly from Homeland Security secretary to White House chief of staff should ensure  his independence and control over the NSC - for now. 

But the nationalists may have a competitive advantage: Trump, who already thinks McMaster is a "pain" who talks too much and has complained to aides that he wants Flynn back at the White House, is  sending McMaster to replace Gen. John Nicholson as the top commander of American and NATO troops in Afghanistan.

"What the nationalists are saying about McMaster: 'He wants to send more troops to Afghanistan, so we're going to send him,'"  reported Thursday.

Whether McMaster is ousted or not, efforts to undermine him both inside and outside the West Wing seem to be well underway.

McMaster has gone to bat for Trump in the past. He  to reporters after he disclosed Israeli intelligence to Russian diplomats in the Oval Office. And he said he "" if Trump's son-in-law, White House senior adviser Jared Kushner, had asked to set up a secret back-channel method of communicating with Moscow during the transition period.

But right-wing media outlets like Breitbart have long harbored suspicions about McMaster,  to stay away from the term "radical Islamic terrorism" in a speech to Middle Eastern leaders in Saudi Arabia earlier this year.

As Weekly Standard writer Michael Warren told CNN on Friday, Bannon and his allies see McMaster's sudden purge of Flynn appointees as an even more overt attempt to sabotage Trump's agenda.

"Obama holdovers at NSC or State Dept who are leaking [should] do real time for these leaks," tweeted conservative political commentator and Trump ally Laura Ingraham. "Why has McMaster fired actual Trump supporters?"

Since the firings, administration officials speaking anonymously to conservative-leaning news outlets  of being "anti-Israel" and  "everything the president wants to do."

One former National Security Council official speaking to  called McMaster a "sycophant" of retired Gen. David Petraeus and seemed to try to appeal directly to the president's ego.

"I don't understand why [Trump's] allowing a guy who is subverting his foreign policy at every turn to remain in place," the official said.

On Thursday,  to his predecessor, Susan Rice, allowing her to keep her security clearance was leaked to Circa - an outlet seen as friendly to Trump. Circa paired the letter, which immediately stirred outrage in far-right circles, with quotes from anonymous West Wing officials claiming it undermined the president's judgment.

"What is this? Does H.R. McMaster need to go? Susan Rice? Omg," tweeted Trump ally and Fox News host Sean Hannity, who  last week.

"H.R. McMaster is a Deep State Plant who Opposes the Trump Agenda," tweeted Mike Cernovich, a prominent far-right provocateur who describes himself as an "American nationalist." 

Cernovich set up a website this week , on which he alleged the general has "been leaking information to David Petraeus and has had direct contact with George Soros" - a billionaire, left-leaning philanthropist and frequent bogeyman of the far-right.

"America needs Rich Higgins in office, not HR McMaster,"  Frank Gaffney, the president of the Center for Security Policy, a far-right think tank. "If HR McMaster is not fired for sabotaging the  agenda, it will be the McMaster administration."

"Why is Gen. McMaster making decisions without even informing Gen Kelly?"  Jack Posobiec, an alt-right internet activist and pro-Trump conspiracy theorist. "Is this proper chain of command?"

Twitter accounts that have been linked to Russian influence operations have jumped on the anti-McMaster bandwagon, too, using hashtags like #FireMcMaster and #deepstate, according to a  that aims to  efforts in real time. 

On Friday, the top and trending websites being shared by the accounts was the Circa story about McMaster letting Rice keep her security clearance. Shares of a Breitbart story titled "NSC Purge: McMaster 'Deeply Hostile to Israel and to Trump'" have increased by 2300% since Wednesday, according to the site, and "clearance," "McMaster," and "Susan Rice" were among the top and trending topics.  

- Rosie Grey (@RosieGray)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSC Purge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derek Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Petraeus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OMG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeland Security</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Hannity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Posobiec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rich Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deeply Hostile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMaster-Mattis-Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Ingraham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen. John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR McMaster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosie Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Gaffney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMaster</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flynn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FireMcMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen. David Petraeus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does H.R. McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cernovich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen. John Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Rice</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ezra Cohen-Watnick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Dept</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRUMP AGENDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekly Standard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bannon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deep State Plant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Security Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breitbart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RosieGray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen. McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Cernovich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Soros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H.R. McMaster</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
