<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427088825949997</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/2673766/try-this-inner-city-wine-bar-wins-big/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Try this: Inner city wine bar wins big</title>
  <content>
SCRUMPTIOUS: Moroccan lamb skewers with fragrant couscous and minted yoghurt and watercress, left; duck, pork and shiitake dumplings with ponzu and porcini dusted vermicelli, right.  Picture: Marina Neil

RESERVE WINE BAR
Address:  102 Hunter Street, Newcastle
Open: Wednesday, Thursday, Friday from noon, Saturday from 3pm, Sunday noon to 6pm
Phone: 49293393
Website: reservewinebar.com.au, facebook.com/ReserveWineBar
Owned by: Tim Bohlsen, Patrick Haddock and Justin Oliver
Chef: Wayne Isaac
IT'S been open a little over a year and Newcastle's Reserve Wine Bar has already emerged as the top small bar in the country.
The bar was opened last year in a former bank building on the corner of Hunter and Bolton streets in Newcastle's central business district by Tim Bohlsen, Patrick Haddock and Justin Oliver. Last week, it took out the top gong for small bars in the National Savour Australia Restaurant & Catering HOSTPLUS Awards for Excellence 2014, and picked up the Best Regional Wine List Featuring NSW Wines at the NSW Wine List Awards.

Reserve Wine Bar chef Wayne Isaac.
The  bar's extensive wine list has also gained national recognition, awarded the maximum  three-glass rating by Gourmet Traveller Wine Magazine.
The list draws on Hunter Region treasures as well as wines from the team's travels across the country and the globe, with an attitude towards encouraging punters to   try wines they have not encountered before because ''life is too short to drink the same wine or, even worse, bad wine''.
Here is a selection of what Reserve has dubbed their grazing menu, which features small plates and share-friendly dishes to complement the wine selection. Produce is sourced from within 100kilometres of Newcastle from artisan cheesemakers, small-goods provedores and more.

Grazing: Oysters: natural, shucked to order $3, kilpatrick $4; grilled sourdough, dukkah $7; grilled chorizo sausage with lemon $7; crispy tortilla, house-made dips $12; roasted local olives and nuts $9; hand-cut potato chips, truffle salt $8; spicy Cajun chicken with raita $10; cos, pear and candied walnut salad with parmesan cheese $14; five-spiced squid, braised wombok, bean sprouts and sweet chilli $16; leek arancini, chilli and pea puree, parsnip chips $16; prawn ravioli with sage brown butter, parmesan and rocket $18; seared scallops, sweet potato and cumin puree, tomato coriander salsa and crisp pancetta $18; potato gnocchi, gorgonzola dolce latte, pine nuts, spinach and chorizo $21; duck sliders, red cabbage and apple slaw, aioli $21; crispy skin pork belly, parsnip puree, caramelised apple $21; braised beef cheek, potato and artichoke gratin with a bitter chocolate jus $25; house-made duck liver pate and terrine, cornichons, sourdough $20; cheese: selection of imported and Australian cheeses $26; dark chocolate brulee, brandy tuille $15; lemon curd tart, vanilla ice-cream, lavender toffee $15; nougat semifreddo, peanut brittle $15; dessert assiette: trio of desserts $40.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle's Reserve Wine Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gourmet Traveller Wine Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catering HOSTPLUS Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ReserveWineBar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Savour Australia Restaurant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Isaac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Regional Wine List Featuring NSW Wines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moroccan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Bohlsen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oyster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Haddock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Oliver</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RESERVE WINE BAR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Excellence 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cajun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Wine List Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Region</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
