<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426964271896093</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/football/speech-from-coach-alen-stajcic-about-les-murrays-impact-on-football-gives-matildas-inspiration-to-thrash-brazil/news-story/631a57ed946591467f5876aa2258d56c</url>
  <title>Les's legacy brings inspiration for Matildas</title>
  <content>
MATILDAS veteran Lisa De Vanna has revealed how an emotional pre-game speech from coach Alen Stajcic drawing on the late Les Murray's legacy to football was the inspiration behind their 6-1 demolition of Brazil.
The Australian women's football claimed their first trophy in seven years by winning the Tournament of Nations in Carson, USA with Stajcic heralding the team's performance as the perfect start to their 2019 world Cup preparation.
The Matildas team wore black armbands during the game against Brazil in memory of the beloved broadcaster, who passed away on Monday after a long battle with illness.
GIANT KILLERS:
De Vanna, who scored a brace against Brazil to become the Matildas' all time leading goal scorer, says Matildas coach Stajcic spoke about Murray before the game and the players took his words to heart.
"Staj usually puts different things in team meetings and today it was all about Les," De Vanna said.
"For obviously Polks (Clare Polkinghorne) and Lydia (Williams) who are senior players, we obviously knew all about his legacy and what this man fought for. Just like we are fighting to be the best team, to be recognised and to lift the game and the women's game in Australia.
"Les was a pioneer. Staj laid out how he was like us women, fighting to show what we can do. And for Australia.
"A lot of the girls took that advice onto the field and it showed. To go out and score six goals, it was a bit of a dedication to Les."
After beating world champions the USA for the first time and registering a 4-2 win over Asian rivals Japan, the Matildas needed just a draw against Brazil to claim the trophy. But in keeping with how they progressed during the tournament, Stajcic was delighted with how they dominated in the final game and believes it stands them in good stead for the ultimate goal - the 2019 World Cup.
"The best part was that we got better and better as the tournament went on and certainly showed that we can back up game after game," Stajcic said.
"Moving forward it's certainly something we're striving to achieve until we've achieved the ultimate goal, which is to be competitive at the World Cup."
But the biggest stepping stone to the World Cup is next year's AFC Asian Cup in Jordan, a tournament the Matildas last won in 2010, and Stajcic says the team has evolved enough to believe they can match it with the best on any given day.
"All four teams experimented a bit, but we certainly showed that we can match it with the best teams and even dominate large parts of contests," he said. "Really pleasing to see how much we've evolved and matured and developed that sense of belief that we can dominate some of these teams on the world stage."

Football: Re-live all six goals scored by the Matildas in their Cup Of Nations match against Brazil.

All six Matildas goals
While Stajcic didn't want to single out any players, he did say that Sam Kerr was as influential a presence in the dressing room as she was on the field.
Kerr scored four goals during the tournament and, on current form, is right up there as one of the very best players in the world.
"She's added an extra sense of confidence to the team," Stajcic said.
"Just to know you've got a person like that in your team gives everyone else a lot more belief and confidence. A lot of people thrived off that."
The Matildas will receive a heroes welcome when they return home and Stajcic hopes they continue to receive support when they take on Brazil in two friendlies next month.
"We're playing Brazil in Penrith on September 16 and in Newcastle on the 19th. It would be great for the Australian public to come out and watch these girls," he said. "And vice versa - it would be great for the girls to feel that support from all around the country as we try and build our team and make our code as popular as we can."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alen Stajcic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stajcic</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Polkinghorne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFC Asian Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cup Of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Re-live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staj</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa De Vanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lydia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
