<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426397336201285</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/riverland-growers-receive-less-than-1-million-to-help-recover-from-november-hailstorm-which-destroyed-74-million-in-crops/news-story/e319e03ca11e05ae476d49cd5ab93711</url>
  <title>Growers frozen out of hailstorm recovery grants</title>
  <content>
RIVERLAND growers have received just $717,000 in storm recovery grants after last year's catastrophic hailstorm caused $74 million in damage to the region.
The State Government allocated $3.1 million to help with the clean-up of 260 storm-affected properties, but it was this week revealed that $2.2 million had gone back into government coffers.
Agricultural Minister Leon Bignell told an estimates committee that 84 of 117 grant applications had been approved, worth $717,000 - about $8500 each.
He said a further $110,000 was spent on grants administration and the remaining $2.2 million was returned to Treasury.
Berri farmer Steve Brauer was shocked at the revelations after he was deemed ineligible for the clean-up grants, despite nearly all his stone fruit crop being wiped out by the golf-ball sized hail - which equated to a loss of $60,000.
Mr Brauer told The Advertiser initial damage estimates from the storm had since increased and he had lost about $100,000 worth of dates and was now living "day to day".
"It seems to me they (the Government) made themselves look good by offering the grants, but they were Clayton's grants, that's just how I feel," Mr Brauer said.
"I think there should have been a low interest loan instead. We didn't need a handout, we just needed a loan."
Mr Brauer said he sought information on the grants at the Loxton Research Centre, but was told he was ineligible because the grants did not cover loss of produce.
The grants, up to $10,000 each, were available under the Natural Disaster Relief and Recovery Arrangement, where the Commonwealth provided assistance to the state for disaster relief.
The funding was only allowed to be used for clean-up costs, removal of debris and repairs to infrastructure not covered by insurance.
Chaffey MP Tim Whetstone said growers in his Riverland electorate, especially those who lost their yearly income, should be "rightly frustrated" that grant money had gone unspent.
"With $74 million in confirmed crop losses, the storm will have long-term impacts, particularly post-harvest cashflow and economic hardship ... in years to come," Mr Whetstone said.
"Many of the primary producers were ineligible to access the storm clean-up fund and received no financial assistance for recovery efforts.
"My hope was for a form of a concessional loan to assist these growers and the local economy, but what we see now is $2.2 million allocated to the recovery returned to Treasury."
The latest figures come as a Freedom of Information document revealed primary producers would face economic hardship for up to five years after the storm, which had a revised damage bill of $74 million, not the estimated $71.5 million.
The FOI documents revealed three Mallee properties reported damage of $4 million, while the wine industry had an estimated a loss of 50,000 tonnes of grapes - a farmgate value of $15 million.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverlands</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedom of Information</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brauer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chaffey MP Tim Whetstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Leon Bignell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whetstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Brauer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natural Disaster Relief</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recovery Arrangement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mallee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loxton Research Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
