<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426272782146993</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/nrl/fans-are-loving-the-return-of-graeme-hughes/news-story/fa24a3326e04ba58467ee8133c676e64</url>
  <title>Fans are loving the return of Graeme Hughes</title>
  <content>
Bunnies stun Dragons
2:11

NRL: The South Sydney Rabbitohs have taken the St George Illawarra Dragons right to the wire and seriously dented their finals hopes

August 4th 2017
2 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/NRL News/

Former player and candidate for football club board Graeme Hughes.

Adam Santarossa

Share

RETRO Round returned to the NRL this weekend, and it's safe to say, given the crowds, fans decided to stay at home.
But those that did watch on the box certainly enjoyed what they heard on Fox Sports' coverage of the St George Illawarra Dragons clash with South Sydney.
The broadcaster is celebrating "Retro Round" this weekend, embracing everything from the 1980s. As part of their coverage, former commentator Graeme Hughes was given an opportunity by Fox Sports to return to the broadcast booth.
The former Canterbury Bulldogs' premiership winner, and current host of 2SM's "Talkin Sport" program was certainly a hit.
'Graeme Hughes' trended on social media throughout the night and several rugby league fans were calling on network bosses to make him a permanent member of their broadcast team.
I would gladly sacrifice my left nut to have Graeme Hughes commentate on   instead of Ray Hadley
And to think that Ch 9 have Ray Hadley & Matt Thompson as commentators & the class & professionalism of Graeme Hughes calls one match a year
How good it is listening to Graeme Hughes calling the  match on
Graeme Hughes showing he's lost nothing as a commentator. Best in the business.  Bring him back full time  !
Graeme Hughes putting on a clinic in how to commentate a game ... bring him back full time
Hughes became a commentator after his retirement and was the voice of Channel 10s rugby league coverage, before Channel Nine took the rights in 1991.
'Retro Round' has given fans the opportunity to revel in a bit of nostalgia and harks back to an era where entertainment was the name of the game.
In recent years, wrestling tactics, slowing down the ball and robotic game plans have seen fans criticise the quality of the NRL.

Graeme Hughes, rugby league commentator (middle).Source:News Corp Australia
Hughes spoke to Triple M Grill Team Sydney before his return to the broadcast booth at the SCG, and agrees with that perception.

"People often say to me, you see a lot of teams run out there and it wouldn't matter what colour jumpers they have got on - they all play the same," Hughes said.
"Let's have two or three (plays) up the middle and then put a kick to the corner and see if someone can jump up for a try."
The broadcaster has a ready-made plan to combat that and help change the game for the better.
"Our game starts at the play the ball," Hughes explained.
"With today's game, all I want to see them do is make a serious attempt to play the ball.
"We've now got guys who are tackled, they place the ball when they're lying on the ground and then get up and play it - which is a penalty.
"That rule hasn't changed. So if Tony Archer got off his backside and really did coach them the right way, you want to talk about slowing down the play the ball, getting people on-side, make them play the ball properly. I'm happy if they just do that."

Graeme Hughes is back in the box.Source:News Corp Australia
Hughes was fortunate to be the voice of some classic Grand Finals in the end of the 1980s and start of the 1990s. The commentator says they remain the highlight of his commentary career.
"I always say it 1989, 1990, 1991- anyone that hasn't seen those Grand Finals, go and find a copy somewhere. They were spectacular Grand Finals," Hughes said.
"Play went from one end to the other. Again it was an old fashioned style, players stood deep and backed each other up. That's why we got football."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Santarossa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Hughes</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M Grill Team Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Hadley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retro Round</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Archer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra Dragons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ch 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
