<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426848307776646</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:43</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/when-sandflies-are-worse-than-the-crocs/news-story/6caceb0d8a8d762faf17692373433dda</url>
  <title>When sandflies are worse than the crocs</title>
  <content>
TOO many tinnies could have been the reason these budding fishos got their own tinnie stuck in the mud.
The hopeful crabbers were allegedly stuck on the banks of Reichardt Creek behind Winnellie, trying to catch crabs but got caught by a low tide. They stayed stuck until Tom Waddell and his mates came past in their own boat fishing for live bait about 3pm.
"We were just cruising along Reichardt Creek, just getting some lives and we (saw) these guys in the bush," he said.
"We went closer and pulled up and a couple of them were jumping out of the tree and were excited to see us.
"I think they'd had a few cans already and the old she'll be right attitude got the better of them."
Mr Waddell said the crabbers had lost their phones and used his to contact friends to come get them at high tide.
"They were looking up Facebook to try and find mate's phone numbers and then when they got a hold of one, they were like 'mate we need the essentials - B & H smooth rum cans, smokes, and some Bushman's," he said.
"I reckon they had been sitting there for hours before we got down the creek.
"I was trying not to laugh, they'd been mauled by that many sandflies that they were ready to get eaten by a croc - they were that over it.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winnellie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Waddell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Waddell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bushman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reichardt Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
