<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426745228559588</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-lucky-to-still-have-laurie-oakes-as-a-local-resident-20170804-gxpptt.html</url>
  <title>Canberra lucky to still have Laurie Oakes as a local resident</title>
  <content>
Laurie Oakes is truly one of nature's gentleman.
The legend of Australian political reporting was inundated with wellwishes on Friday as news of his impending . But he still had time to answer a few questions about his attachment to Canberra, the city; not the byword for parliament.Photo:
Laurie's last night on air for Channel Nine will be August 18. He confirmed to us that afterwards he had no plans to leave Canberra, a long-time resident of Red Hill.
"I'll be staying in Canberra,' he said.Photo: Peter Morris
"I like that it's within striking distance of Sydney and the coast and I think it's the most liveable city in Australia.
"The facilities are good and when you get to my age, you do look at the health facilities.

"I know a lot of people retire to the coast but then they spend a lot of time on a bus coming back to Canberra to see a doctor.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Canberra is a good place to live and a good place to retire."Photo: Andrew Meares
The 73-year-old  is expecting to spend at least part of his retirement "gently travelling around Australia".
"See a bit more of the place and take it all very easy and relaxed," he said.
Well-deserved, no doubt. And there was much goodwill for Oakes on Friday as the parliamentary press gallery prepared to lose one of its icons.
"Twitter's been amazing. The papers' have been amazing. It's all been very overwhelming," he said.
And while Oakes has dabbled in local planning issues as an ordinary Canberra citizen concerned about past housing proposals in Red Hill, he doesn't see himself writing furious letters-to-the-editor or becoming a local agitator in retirement.
"I don't think so," he said, definitely.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
