<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426835422874540</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4834655/parramatta-light-rail-falls-1-billion-short/?cs=7</url>
  <title>Parramatta light rail falls $1 billion short</title>
  <content>
At least $1 billion in funding still needs to be found to complete the Parramatta light rail project, leaked internal documents show, meaning the Berejiklian government could be forced to double the money it has reserved in infrastructure funds.

A cabinet-in-confidence document dated March 2017 obtained by the opposition reveals the total cost of the project at $3.41 billion - $2.41 billion more than the $1 billion set aside from the Restart NSW and Rebuilding NSW funds.
Separate documents from May last year, obtained by Fairfax Media, reveal Transport for NSW estimates $1.3 billion will be raised from "value capture" - a levy on property development along the rail line previously put at $200 per square metre of gross floor area.
The Transport for NSW Finance and Investment committee document states: "Balance of funding to be sought from other funding sources including Federal."
This leaves no determined funding source for $1.1 billion required to complete the project, with stage one from Westmead to Carlingford via Parramatta CBD due to open in 2023.
Planning work is under way for stage two, from Camellia to Strathfield via Sydney Olympic Park.
Labor's transport spokeswoman Jodi McKay called on the government to release the business case - which the documents show was due to be completed by May - to show how the project will be funded.
Last year .
"This is a government that's constantly boasting about how good they are at infrastructure when the exact opposite is true - they are still short more than $1 billion and that's after they have slapped a $1.3 billion tax on Western Sydney," she said.
"The people of Western Sydney are already being slugged with unfair and unaffordable tolls and now they have to pay an extra tax for their light rail while the people of the Eastern Suburbs get theirs for free. It's a tale of two cities."
However, transport minister Andrew Constance said: "There can't be a funding gap when we haven't finalised the total project costs".
"We have already put aside $1 billion to get this project under way and have always been upfront that the project cost will be more than this," Mr Constance said.
"We will confirm a delivery model and investment decision in the coming months, after consideration of the final business sase."
A Transport for NSW spokesman said the government was looking at "a range of funding sources to meet the capital cost of the project" including the development levy, which will also fund new schools and road upgrades.
He said $3.41 billion was "an early estimate made well before the program was broken into two stages, and is a total cost estimate for the entire network extending more than 20 kilometres from Westmead to Strathfield via Olympic Park".

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebuilding NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westmead</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Restart NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Suburbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodi McKay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Finance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlingford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camellia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
