<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426311436853517</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-04/dubai-residential-tower-fire-extinguished/8776690</url>
  <title>Dubai fire: Streets reopened around Torch Tower as fire extinguished and no deaths reported</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Police in Dubai have reopened the streets around one of the world's tallest residential skyscrapers after firefighters put out a blaze that erupted early on Friday in the high-rise, forcing residents to evacuate in the middle of the night and sending chunks of debris plummeting below.

Key points:

Firefighters battled the blaze for more than two hours
No casualties have been reported
Highly flammable cladding similar to that on London's Grenfell Tower may be to blame

No major injuries had been reported but a few people were treated for smoke inhalation, according to Dubai's Gulf News website.
Several residents said  - a more than 335 metre-tall residential building in Dubai's popular waterfront Marina district.
The same building had also caught fire just two-and-a-half years earlier.
The cause of the fire was not immediately known but in the past, such infernos in Dubai have been linked to highly flammable building cladding - as was  that killed at least 80 people.
More than 40 floors of the building on one side were engulfed in flames as residents looked on from below, many in tears.
The firefighters battled the blaze for more than two hours.
Dubai's Civil Defence announced at about 3:30 am that firefighters had brought the blaze under control and said cooling operations were underway.
Authorities shared video of the building from the outside later on Friday, showing the entire length of the tower charred on one side.

By midday on Friday, a few police cars could be seen in the area, but the streets had been wiped clean of the debris, some of which had fallen on cars parked below.
However, the skyscraper remained closed to residents, some of whom were moved to a nearby and even taller residential tower while others decided to stay with friends.
Officials said they were working on providing shelter for those affected and assessing the damage.
The Torch Tower also caught fire in February 2015 with no casualties reported.

External Link:

Tweet from Ismail Mostafa: "Im also so happy that everyone we were with and everyone in the building came out safe and sound. scary for all of us"
Parts of the building were still undergoing restoration work when the second fire broke out early on Friday.
In both incidents, fire alarms alerted residents and building staff knocked on doors to ensure evacuation.
Tower resident Alireza Aletomeh, who is now staying with friends, said towers like the Torch should have sprinklers.
He wondered why Civil Defence crews did not deploy helicopters to try and extinguish the fire quicker.
"Putting out the fire was the most important thing, which took them so long," he said.

Simon Bach, a New Zealander who lives in a high-rise across the street, said he saw a few policemen as well as Emiratis in traditional white robes helping people get out.
About 10 to 12 firetrucks arrived quickly on the scene, he said.
He said just as the firefighters had seemed to bring the blaze under control, falling debris ignited a part of the building further down.
"It seemed really out of control," he said.
"People were streaming out of the car parks of the building."
Several skyscrapers in the United Arab Emirates have caught fire in recent years, including a towering inferno that engulfed a 63-story luxury hotel in Dubai on New Year's Eve in 2016.
In that blaze, as in others in Dubai in recent years, residents escaped without major injury.

External Link:

Tweet from Farzan.: "Just waking up now to find about Torchtowerfire. Not comforting to know that I slept through a very bad fire just a few buildings away..."
Earlier this year, Dubai passed new fire safety rules requiring buildings with quick-burning side panelling to replace it with more fire-resistant siding.
Authorities have previously acknowledged that at least 30,000 buildings across the UAE have cladding or panelling that safety experts have said accelerates the rapid spread of fires.
While the new regulations are now in place for construction in Dubai and other cities, it's unclear how authorities will force owners to replace flammable siding with better material.
The tragic June inferno in London .
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Bach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torch Tower</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farzan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Arab Emirates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UAE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai's Gulf News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alireza Aletomeh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civil Defense</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emirati</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai Civil Defense</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Grenfell Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Year's Eve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torchtowerfire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ismail Mostafa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
