<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427140365558357</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/hyperkin-smartboy-game-boy-games-android-2017-8</url>
  <title>This $50 accessory lets you play your old Game Boy games on your Android phone</title>
  <content>
It might be time to blow the dust out of your old Game Boy cartridges, because Hyperkin is looking to give them a new lease on life. 

Two years ago, the mobile phone peripheral manufacturer released an ad on  for the SmartBoy, an accessory that would clasp onto your phone and allows you to play Game Boy and Game Boy Colour games on it.

The reception was so positive that the product then went into development. 

Now that we're only a few weeks away from its official launch on August 21, it appears the SmartBoy was worth the wait. 

The SmartBoy was designed for the Samsung S8 family of devices, but works on most Android phones that have a USB Type-C port. To use it, you will need to download the , as well as an emulator - Hyperkin recommends My Oldboy!, which is available for free online. 

The look and feel of the peripheral is similar to the original 1989 Game Boy, down to the colour of the buttons. It can play all Game Boy and Game Boy Colour games, as well as Game Boy Advance games, though  that they don't advertise that feature because they take too long to load. 

The case snaps onto your phone, covering the bottom half of the screen with the controls, and displaying the Game Boy games in their original aspect ratios. 

The Hyperkin can be  and will retail for $US50. Watch it in action below. 

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SmartBoy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game Boy Advance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game Boys</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyperkin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game Boy Color</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USB Type-C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oldboy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung S8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
