<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426719458755040</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/townsville/welcome-to-elegance-personified/news-story/1d400272e522dec89a3a24f2ac7022b5</url>
  <title>Welcome to elegance personified - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
WALKING into feels like stepping back in time to when men dipped their hats to ladies, music was listened to on a gramophone and films were black and white.

Once entering the elegance of yesteryear takes over, and upon ascending the grand timber staircase, stunning views of Castle Hill, including the iconic Saint, make for a jaw-dropping view.
Nestled at the base of Castle Hill this grand home has no shortage of street appeal with its wide verandas and classic Queenslander look.
From the second-storey deck the views extend to the water and out to Cleveland Bay with the high vantage point also capturing cool breezes.
This house has clearly been well looked after with the walls adorned with artwork and both the interior and exterior kept to immaculate standards.

Listing agent Sally Elliott from Smith & Elliott said there was nothing even close to the standard of this home currently available on the market.
"The best way to describe this home is the absolute epitome of everything an elegant Queenslander should be," she said. "It would suit a professional couple with children because Alexandra St is still very much a family-owned street.
"Where the house misses out on backyard what there is underneath is a huge, legal height games room which is covered and you could put a soccer net or netball hoop down there."
The home is on a 730sq m hillside block in an exclusive enclave near Townsville Grammar School, Gregory Street and Queens Gardens.
Five bedrooms, three bathrooms plus a sophisticated home office and library mean there is no shortage of space in this large home.
The master suite includes a dressing room and flows to the veranda while the formal lounge also leads to the veranda and ocean views.
The entertainer's kitchen has stone bench tops with island bench and scullery while the
bi-fold doors open out to a
large rear deck and inground lap pool.
Ms Elliott said the owners originally bought the home to house their vast art collection but were reluctantly letting
go of the property to downsize.
"They bought this house because apart from the fact that it was very beautiful, it had a lot of wall space and because they had a lot of art, they needed to find it a home," she said.
"Their children have now left home and it's a big house for two people."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queens Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregory Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Grammar School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castle Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
