<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427045876276276</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/1542208/rock-stars-launch-mental-health-service-headspace/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Rock stars launch mental health service headspace </title>
  <content>
Rock stars launch mental health service headspace 

YOUTH SUPPORT: Grinspoon frontman Phil Jamieson, MTV's Kate Peck, headspace Youth Reference Group's Brittany Szlezak and Silverchair's Chris Joannou at the headspace opening yesterday. Picture: Marina Neil

YOUTH SUPPORT: Grinspoon frontman Phil Jamieson, MTV's Kate Peck, headspace Youth Reference Group's Brittany Szlezak and Silverchair's Chris Joannou at the headspace opening yesterday. Picture: Marina Neil

exit

YOUNG people in Newcastle can get help for problems ranging from bullying to anxiety now that the mental health headspace centre in Hunter Street has opened.
Silverchair's Chris Joannou, Grinspoon's Phil Jamieson and MTV's Kate Peck, Paul Mac and Blue Juice's Jake Stone came together as the Rock N Ride Crew on Friday to mark the opening.
The centre, at 582 Hunter Street, is the second headspace to open in the region and follows the success of the Maitland office.
It was opened under a $200 million federal government program to open 90 new headspace centres around the country.
Newcastle manager Andrew Steele said there had been a growing demand for youth mental health services in Newcastle.
"Newcastle is fairly typical, many young people are presenting with mental health needs around anxiety and depression."
"Certainly things like bullying have an impact on young people," he said.
Newcastle headspace will offer services for an estimated 80,000 young people aged between 12 and 25 in the area.
Its work will include counselling, health and sexual health advice, education and employment information, and alcohol and other drug services.
The staff will include an occupational therapist, psychologists, social and youth workers, youth charity representatives and a general practitioner.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grinspoon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silverchair's Chris Joannou</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YOUTH SUPPORT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grinspoon's Phil Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Reference Group's Brittany Szlezak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Juice's Jake Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Jamieson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rock N Ride Crew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTV's Kate Peck</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
