<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426917027254936</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4833499/tassals-antibiotics-use-in-salmon-quadruples/?cs=7</url>
  <title>Tassal's antibiotics use in salmon quadruples</title>
  <content>
Only one salmon producer in Australia - Tassal - has increased its use of antibiotics, new figures show, as calls grow for farmers to limit their use of the drugs to stop the rise of superbugs.

Tassal, Australia's biggest salmon company, quadrupled its use of antibiotics between 2012-13 and 2015-16, despite promising to phase them out and its rivals dramatically reducing their reliance on the medicines over the same period.
According to its latest sustainability report, it fed 301 kilograms of antibiotics in total, up by 443 per cent, or 9.8 grams per tonne of fish, up by 353 per cent, on the figures three years prior.
"Over the past 15 years, antibiotic use has fallen dramatically in salmon farming worldwide and in Tasmania," a Tassal spokesman said. "Antibiotic use now may fluctuate from year to year depending if fish require treatment."
In 2008-09, Tassal pumped an astonishing 4.1 tonnes into its salmon, before heeding calls from authorities to cut down its use.
The World Health Organisation has raised alarm over the overuse of antibiotics in humans and animals (including farmed fish) that it said was leading to the rise of drug-resistant superbugs - "the greatest and most urgent global risk".
Tassal confirmed it mainly used oxytetracycline - which WHO has classified as a "highly important antimicrobial" for human medicine - to treat a Yersinia infection in 2016.
"Tassal only administers antibiotics requiring minor use permit for regulatory and consumer confidence following comprehensive veterinary due diligence," a spokesman said.
Official data from Tasmania's Department of Primary Industries shows total antibiotic use by all salmon producers plunged in 2012 (to 48.4kg) and 2015 (to 32.3kg) before escalating in 2016 to hit 800kg.
Most of it was oxytetracycline. A tiny amount (less than 1 per cent) was trimethoprim, also considered a "highly important antimicrobial".
Health and environmental experts have previously raised concerns about birds and wild fish eating the medicated fish meal and the contamination of the ocean.
Professor John Turnidge, senior medical adviser at the Australian Commission on Safety and Quality in Health Care, said while Tassal's figures were disappointing, he believed commercial pressures would see it try to eliminate antibiotic use.
He said overall, the salmon industry was doing well in developing vaccines to avoid antibiotics.
"Oxytetracyline is rated 'low' in Australia ... and I am pretty sure the company is aware of Australia's list and has chosen carefully to deal with an outbreak," he said.
He said surveillance in food animals was just starting and so far no clear evidence had emerged that humans were at risk of catching resistant bacteria from meat.

Unlike Tassal, Huon Aquaculture has managed to reduce antibiotic use by 95 per cent to 5.45 kilograms since 2013-14. It's important to note the dosage rate for trimethoprim is much lower.
Huon's general manager of fish performance, Steve Percival, said while it used oxytetracycline, it preferred trimethoprim, as it was "very aware of the importance of oxytetracycline for use in human health".
He said the drugs were an option of last resort.
"If our vet feels there is a need to treat the fish with antibiotics for an illness, it is supervised, reported, strictly regulated by government, and the antibiotics are allowed to pass through the fish long before it is harvested," he said.
Another competitor, Petuna, claims it has eliminated antibiotic use, in part, by developing vaccines.
"If we need to treat our fish for their health and wellbeing, we will," a spokeswoman said. "If antibiotics are administered, treated fish are not harvested until enough time has passed to allow no residual trace to be detected."
Tassal said its "2017 class" of salmon has been vaccinated and it doesn't expect to use any antibiotics.
It said that each farm uses different sections of water, for example, salt water, or fresh and salt water, meaning the disease, types of antibiotics and practices can be different.
The ASX-listed company produces more than 25,000 tonnes of salmon each year.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor John Turnidge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Health Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxytetracyline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health-care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania's Department of Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huon Aquaculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yersinia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petuna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Percival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
