<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426715163787636</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/arts/review/andy-griffiths-and-terry-denton-take-treehouse-to-a-new-level/news-story/0a4e65da77ac99cacc2063ad45046107</url>
  <title>Storey tellers</title>
  <content>
They are the men behind books about intelligent but psychopathic bums, killer koalas from deep space, zombie kittens, an exploding cow, a gas-eous Banquo, Ninja snails, obtuse owls, Frankenpotatoes and a never-ending treehouse that includes a man-eating shark tank and a chainsaw juggling arena. Yet if you didn't know any of this, sitting down with Andy Griffiths and Terry Denton might feel a bit like meeting two serious professionals from a conservative profession. Accountants, say. Or publishers.
Well, that is a bit of an exaggeration, one that would be right at home in The 91-Storey Treehouse, the new book in the duo's manically minded and manically selling children's series.
Illustrator Denton, 66, does look a bit like a bean-counter in weekend mufti. He's tall (he loved playing Aussie rules as a kid), grey-haired, bespectacled and wearing dark trousers and a blue flannelette shirt. It's the decade younger writer, Griffiths, who lets the cat out of the bag, especially when he takes off his black jacket.

His left forearm is dominated by a tattoo of two cats shooting red laser beams from their eyes. His other arm is populated by characters created by some of his heroes, including Dr Seuss and Lewis Carroll. That's all the eye can see, so who knows what lurks beneath the T-shirt? Its slogan is provocative enough on its own: You've Got Foetus on Your Breath.
OK, so former dissatisfied schoolteacher Griffiths and architecture degree dropout Denton are not working for KPMG. The point, though, is that like a lot of people who make a living through comedy, this pair is not obviously comical. They are not bouncing around on their heads and dealing with inflatable underpants like their 10-year-old alter egos, writer Andy and illustrator Terry, in the Treehouse books. Their chaotic comedy is internal. It's a mind-hand-page dynamic.
They talk about their 20-year partnership, which started with Just Tricking! in 1997, with seriousness. It's jovial, amicable, respectful seriousness, but seriousness nevertheless.
"The 20-year marriage?" Denton says. "Well, I am always surprised we have got this far. We have learned to work with each other. Sometimes it takes diplomacy and patience." "Yes," Griffiths agrees. "We had to figure out a way not to step on each other's toes. There has been fireworks in every book, but it's fun."

There's something of a paradox here. Before he became a full-time author Griffiths was the vocalist in a couple of 1980s alternative rock bands. (You've Got Foetus on Your Breath, by the way, is one of the names of Australian singer JG Thirlwell's unusual musical outfit.) He looks up to authors such as Roald Dahl but he wants to be Alice Cooper. He quit teaching because he disliked the fact kids were bored by the books they were forced to read. He agreed with them. Books should make children - and their parents - laugh.
Today when he's not writing he visits schools and pulls madcap faces as part of his commitment to children's literacy. He's a narrow but deep reader of adult fiction, as in when he likes a book, he reads it often. JD Salinger's The Catcher in the Rye, the one he'd take to a desert island, he's read 25 or so times. Ditto with films. He's seen Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey 30 times. His bookshelves have copies of graphic novels such as Watchmen, comic collections like The Far Side, Dr Seuss books, Winnie the Pooh, Pinocchio and several volumes of his biggest influence, EW Cole's Funny Picture Book, alongside works by JD Salinger, Kurt Vonnegut, Ray Bradbury and Franz Kafka.
He is fond of Kafka's The Metamorphosis, about the young man transformed into a giant bug. Griffiths is an introvert, someone uncomfortable with crowds. He needs a lot of alone time, which is fine by his wife and editor, Jill, because she is introverted too.
When I ask them over dinner how two introverts get along, Jill says, "Wonderfully! We know about letting each other have quiet time.'' Her desert island book is George Eliot's Middlemarch. They have a 16-year-old-daughter, Sarah, and Griffiths has a 23-year-old daughter, Jasmine, from his first marriage.
Denton is a rogue branch in his family tree. His father was a chemist, his mother a nurse. He has four brothers, three of whom are doctors, the other a lawyer. "And then there is me,'' Denton says. He and his wife, Kirsten, have been together for 36 years. Their two adult daughters are doctors and their son is a history major at university.
The six Treehouse books have sold 2.8 million copies. The new one will take them past three million. Yet their creators admit, perhaps with more humour now than at the time, that their own children have not been rusted-on fans. Griffiths remembers the wording of a letter Jasmine wrote, when she was a kid, to Harry Potter author JK Rowling. "I like your books. They are much better than my dad's."
"But she has come to appreciate it [his work] as an adult, especially how it helps kids discover reading," Griffiths says. The teen Sarah isn't quite there yet. She prefers books about relationship dramas to ones about "anarchy and body parts".
Denton makes his own Rowling joke, which makes me think they've worked on this gag. Yet his conclusion is lovely. He talks about receiving letters from grateful parents.
"They say [their child has] read his first chapter book because of us ... and then gone on to the good stuff like Harry Potter," he says. "I think it has kind of snuck up on us a bit, this feeling that we are helping kids to read, and it brings you to the point of tears at times."
As for his own children, Denton says "they have always enjoyed being dismissive of my work". But, he adds, "I think they are proud of me now." His siblings "were dismissive for a long time", though have become more appreciative in -recent years.
Of course, the success of the Treehouse books generates both a public profile and cash. You don't need to be an accountant to work out that three million books at around $15 each is good for the bank balance. The inevitable corollary is that the books, produced annually in August or September, are now a full-time job. That means Griffiths's adult novel, started a lifetime ago, curls in a desk drawer. When I ask him about it, he says he finished only one chapter ... and he talks about it at length. As for Denton, a painter and sculptor, his ambition to enter the Archibald Prize remains wishful thinking.

"Five years ago I had an exhibition and I thought I'd have another," he says. "But the Treehouse is so dominant there is just no time - and yes, there is a degree of frustration in that, I admit."
He's quick to make it clear this is a First World problem. "We earn a lot of money from them," he says of the Treehouse books, "so I don't need to do other books to make a living any more."
Denton lives on Victoria's Mornington Peninsula, which is almost visible from Griffiths's living-room window. He arrives at the writer's elegant, idiosyncratically decorated house at bayside Williamstown in an ordinary car, which is nowhere near as adaptable as the sandwich submarine he draws in the new book. We go to Griffiths's study to talk. Once again, there are signs we're not in a conventional office.
The Australian Book Industry Awards plaques are on the wall, yes, but so are drawings of the homicidal koalas. Griffiths activates a robotic singing and dancing cat that Jill helped design. But he's most proud of a recent acquisition, a colour poster promoting the Australian illusionist Leslie George Vante Cole, aka The Great Levante. I'm drawn, however, to the full-size human skeleton standing in a corner, cloaked in an academic gown and topped by a mortar board hat.
This goes to my favourite chapter in the new book, "Warning''. In it, Andy's brain becomes infected and he turns into Andrew, a mortar board hat-wearing intellectual proud of his "multisyllabic narrative powers". His "Treehouse Chronicles" collaborator, Terrence, understands not a word.
"I think we've made him too smart for his own good," says Jill, the permanently sensible character in the stories. Terry agrees, and fixes the problem with a giant mallet.
Griffiths plans to don the academic gear - and assume the Andrew persona - at the launch of the new book next week.
This tension between author and illustrator is a running joke in the books. It's Terry who is celebrated. His name is etched on most of the trophies in the Treehouse, much to Andy's irritation. It's a bit different in the real world. Griffiths is the public star. His name is on the top of every book; Denton's is at the bottom. The illustrator says that's OK, as long as the royalty cheques are equal.
Funnily enough, it started the other way around. When Griffiths wrote his first book, Swinging on the Clothesline, in 1993, a work that was aimed at helping teachers assist kids in learning to read, it became publishable only when Denton was hired to do the illustrations. "He's got a great sense of humour," Griffiths remembers being told.
The two bumped into each other a bit later at an arts festival. "Terry said I should publish a book of fiction," Griffiths says, "but I said no one would want to publish it, because it's too crazy."
Denton, an established children's book illustrator who had worked with authors such as Mem Fox, was not so sure about that. "I'd been in the game for 10 years," he says.
"Yes," Griffiths adds, "so with Terry on board I went to publishers ... who tended to say, 'With Terry involved at least we'll sell out our print run.' "
Griffiths says that when looking at Denton's drawings he experienced "the sort of hilarity I hadn't had since Year 8 maths". As they got to know each other, Denton realised he was with a kindred spirit.
"I had never found anyone who was writing stuff like this, and I thought, 'This is where my brain is'," he says. "I was constantly trying to wind it back before we met, and now I didn't have to do that."
Well, not quite. That 1997 debut, Just Tricking!, included a drawing of a boy standing outside his classroom, covered head to toe in a (large) condom. The publisher didn't like that. "Jill and I took it out," Griffiths says. "It's hilarious!" Denton maintains.
That book was followed by Just Annoying!, Just Stupid!, Just Crazy!, Just Disgusting!, Just Shocking!, Just Macbeth! ("Twas not me,'' Banquo says after farting, "Twas the haggis!") and Just Doomed! In between came The Bad Book, full of nursery rhyme reinterpretations such as "The Old Lady Who Swallowed a Poo", and The Very Bad Book, which did more of the same.
And there was also the trilogy that caught attention in the US, even if the titles had to be changed: The Day My Bum Went Psycho, Zombie Bums from Uranus and Bumageddon: The Final Pongflict. Stateside, the bums became butts to avoid any risk of stores shelving the books alongside other works about homeless people.
It was The Bad Book, published in 2004, that forced Griffiths and Denton to think more carefully about the limits they liked to push. In one of the stories a boy lights a match and sets fire first to his bottom and then to his head. No trouble there, but it's the next bit that generated the most complaints the two have received: "Little Willy took a match / And set fire to the cat / Said Little Willy as it burnt / 'I bet the cat hates that'."
"We got into a lot of trouble," Denton says. "Not because the boy set himself on fire, but because of the innocent victim, the cat." Griffiths doesn't joke about this. "We violated a moral code of storytelling, and we learned from that."
Indeed, despite all their craziness, the Griffiths-Denton books, especially the Treehouse series, are about friendship, loyalty and the kindness of others. In the latest book, the main new characters are the grandchildren of Andy and Terry's publisher, Mr Big Nose (who reminds me and my 12-year-old of a bellicose version of Frank Dickens's comic strip buying clerk Bristow).
When I mention that it's interesting the little Noses are nice, Griffiths says, "Yes, at first I thought they were going to be more bratty. Tie up Andy and Terry and cook them maybe ..." Denton jumps in. "That's a nice idea!"
It'd be no surprise if Griffiths agreed. It's clear that the brake on their riot act is Jill, an experienced book editor. When I ask if he and Denton ever disagree on whether something is funny, they both say hardly ever.
"It's more between me and Jill," Griffiths says. "She prefers verbal jousting while I prefer more physical violence. Whenever Terry and I venture into sheer chaotic madness, it's Jill who pulls us back. 'You're just entertaining yourselves now,', she says. 'Remember the reader.' "
The Treehouse, then a humble 13 storeys, grew out of Griffiths's plan to write The Very, Very, Very Bad Book. He met Denton and asked him what he had in mind for that.
"All Terry had was a drawing of a tiny bird holding a large gun," Griffiths says. He pauses and goes to a drawer to pull out the drawing. The gun is an automatic pistol.
"I said, 'What else have you got?' "
Denton delivers the answer he delivered back then. "Not much."
This put them in a difficult position. Could they do a whole book about a bluebird with a Glock? Maybe. But Griffiths had another idea: "Let's write a bad book about trying to write a book."
And so The 13-Storey Treehouse took root. It's the home of Andy and Terry, who write children's books for the impatient Mr Big Nose. Their animal-loving friend Jill lives nearby. Denton's early sketches were from ground level, looking up into a treehouse, and Griffiths loved them. The book was published in 2011. The Treehouse back then was practically a shack compared with what it is now, with 13 storeys added year in, year out. The recent instalments have also been adapted into stage plays.
Griffiths and Denton say their artistic relationship has developed along with their friendship. Early on, Denton's illustrations were confined to the wide margins of the pages. "I had Terry under control then," Griffiths says.
But the drawings soon took over more space. "A lot of my work is removing words, as I realise Terry's telling the story," Griffiths says, an observation that has Denton's complete agreement. "Yes, it takes the pressure off the words a bit."
Words still intervene, though. "Yes, sometimes I have to redraw," Denton says. He looks away for a bit. "Andy will often write new lines 1 1/2 minutes from the printing machine being switched on."
"I used to," Griffiths says in his defence. Then he adds, "And sometimes when Terry's drawn the wrong thing Jill and I say, 'Fantastic! Let's write around that.' " Denton raises his voice ever so slightly. "Rarely!"
Next year, the Treehouse will reach a level its builders never imagined, entering the three-digit address domain at 104 storeys. They are at work on it now, and showed me some early illustrations. It looks like there'll be a refrigerator-throwing range ("The internet has made the research a lot easier," says Griffiths, flipping through online shots of men and fridges in athletic abandon), and a $2 shop next door to a $2 million shop.
What comes after that? Well, 117 storeys, of course. Disregard what the author says next.
"We have used up every idea for a Treehouse book! We have painted ourselves into a corner with our feet nailed to the floor!"
And, he concludes, "I love that artistic -challenge."
The 91-Storey Treehouse, by Andy Griffiths and Terry Denton, is published next week (Pan Macmillan, 362pp, $14.99). Griffiths and Denton will appear at a Sydney Writers Festival event in Sydney on Thursday evening. swf.org.au

Literary Editor
Sydney
Stephen Romei is The Australian's literary editor. He blogs at A Pair of Ragged Claws and can also be found on Twitter and Facebook. When pressed, he nominates Dostoyevsky's Crime and Punishment as his favourite book, though sometimes it's Moby Dick.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninjas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williamstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Griffiths</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bumageddon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uranus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pan Macmillan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bad Book</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths-Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Bradbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Macbeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ditto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinocchio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Tricking</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Vonnegut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Crazy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winnie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banquo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denton, 66</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JG Thirlwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie George Vante Cole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roald Dahl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Got Foetus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Shocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moby-Dick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Writers Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths</name>
    <count>31</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pair of Ragged</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day My Bum Went Psycho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirsten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Seuss</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Space Odyssey 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EW Cole's Funny Picture Book</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Levante</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JK Rowling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Big Nose</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treehouse Chronicles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watchmen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Disgusting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pooh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bristow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Book Industry Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Eliot's Middlemarch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Denton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Dickens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kafka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far Side</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storey Treehouse</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Potter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archibald Prize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanley Kubrick's 2001</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasmine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Lady Who Swallowed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mem Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franz Kafka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Final Pongflict</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dostoyevsky's Crime</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denton</name>
    <count>27</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Romei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>storEy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First-World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Doomed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankenpotatoes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Annoying</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Said Little Willy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JD Salinger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
