<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426474645614301</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/gambling/tabcorp-could-exit-sun-bets-in-two-years-if-struggles-continue-20170804-gxpicr</url>
  <title>Tabcorp could exit Sun Bets in two years if struggles continue</title>
  <content>
Tabcorp's struggling Sun Bets joint venture with News Corporation could be closed unless the business records steep revenue increases in the next two years.
The wagering giant revealed on Friday that it would have to pay News £11.1 million ($18.3 million) in 2018 and £16.5 million the following year, or about $46 million in total, for the British business run with News' The Sun newspaper.
But if revenue does not reach those respective payment figures and future targets are not agreed to, Tabcorp would be able to terminate the business at the cost of £1.5 million ($2.5 million) plus winding down costs.
Those figures mean Sun Bets would need to dramatically improve its financial performance to meet those targets. It made $4.6 million revenue from $203.6 million turnover in 2017 for earnings before interest, tax, depreciation and amortisation loss of $46.2 million.

But Tabcorp chief executive David Attenborough told AFR Weekend the company was still committed to Sun Bets and was confident recent management changes would help boost its performance.

"We are locked and loaded with Sun Bets. We've made management changes and we've looked at the mix of products and have the English Premier League starting and the soccer World Cup coming up [next year]. So we are committed to the business and believe it can definitely improve."
Tabcorp results within guidance

Tabcorp on Friday released its 2017 financial results, revealing earnings, before interest, tax, depreciation and amortisation of $504.1 million, down 2.3 per cent from the previous year but within guidance given to the market in June.
Tabcorp recorded underlying net profit of $178.9 per cent, down 3.8 per cent from 2016 but fell to a statutory loss of $20.8 million due to $199.7 million of significant items after tax.

That figure included $61.8 million related to Austrac money laundering investigations, $53.9 million of costs associated with the pending Tatts merger and an operating loss of $47.6 million and impairment of $20.7 million for
Mr Attenborough said the main plan for the company in the 2018 financial centred on completing the Tatts deal.
"At the same time, we have a clear set of priorities to drive performance in our core businesses and benefit from the strategic initiatives we delivered in 2017. We will continue to focus on maintaining a disciplined approach to operating expenses and capital expenditure and delivering sustainable returns."
Mr Attenborough was particularly pleased with the signing of 13,400 digital accounts for Tabcorp's social lottery Keno business and a 9.7 per cent increase in active TAB digital betting customers to 475,000.

Merger vote delay

A shareholder vote on the $11 billion merger between wagering giant Tabcorp and Tatts Group has been delayed until October.
A scheme booklet for the proposed merger is now expected to be provided to Tatts' shareholders in September and the meeting of Tatts' shareholders to vote on the deal in October, the companies revealed on Friday.
The deal is subject to an appeal by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission and rival corporate bookmaker CrownBet,

A full bench of the Federal Court will hear both the ACCC's and CrownBet's applications on August 28 and 29.
Tabcorp will pay a final dividend 12.5¢ per share, fully franked, taking the full year ordinary dividend to 25¢ per share.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR Weekend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Attenborough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatts Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun Bets</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrownBet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News £11.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Attenborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
