<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426277077114304</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/eagle-farm-racecourse-to-be-out-of-action-until-april-as-track-makeover-announced/news-story/44afb7a1246d4655cc9d1a45703adbb7</url>
  <title>Racetrack to be ripped up and replaced</title>
  <content>
RACING Queensland is set to embark on a $1.5 million renovation of Eagle Farm Racecourse that will retain the track's much-maligned sand profile and deliver a scheduled return to racing next April.
The renovation follows a review ordered by Racing Minister Grace Grace as to why the new track failed so badly and the best way to resurrect it.
The review was conducted by former Victoria Racing Club chief executive Dale Monteith, who this week tabled a 71-page report in conjunction with Sports Turf Consultants, who carried out more than 170 tests on the maligned surface.
Eagle Farm was closed in September 2014 and after a $10 million redevelopment, was re-opened in June 2016 but was plagued by problems from the outset.
Only a handful of meetings even remotely lived up to expectations and after the at the Group 1 Kingsford Smith Cup meeting on May 27, RQ shifted the remainder of this year's carnival to Doomben and Ms Grace ordered the review.
"We can't afford to waste time with finger-pointing and blame-shifting - my absolute priority is to ensure the track is operating at its optimum level," Ms Grace said yesterday.
"Dale Monteith's thorough and exhaustive report sets out a clear path to remediating the track, and Racing Queensland and the Brisbane Racing Club have reached in-principle agreement to implement his recommendations."
It had been feared the reconstruction would cost many millions of dollars but Monteith's recommendations have been estimated to fall between $1 million and $1.5million, with only the turf and a percentage of sand to be replaced.
It will be funded out of RQ's Racing Infrastructure Fund, which was established after the control body struck a 30-year deal with wagering provider UBET in 2014.
Mr Monteith and STC have recommended the kikuyu grass be replaced with couch and that new "angular" sand be introduced to provide a more stable profile than the one offered by the existing "rounded" sand.
It is also recommended Eagle Farm be given a reduced racing program in the first three years to allow the new turf time to mature.
Mr Monteith was critical of some of the maintenance procedures recommended by track constructor Evergreen and of some "maintenance control failings" of the Brisbane Racing Club.
He described some of the methods as "outdated" by comparison with Melbourne courses like Flemington and Caulfield.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RQ's Racing Infrastructure Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Monteith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle Farm Racecourse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Monteith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doomben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing Minister Grace Grace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EAGLE Farm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Grace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1 Kingsford Smith Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evergreen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Racing Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monteith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Turf Consultants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Racing Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
