<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426964271896117</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4782033/ninja-parc-giving-more-people-active-options/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Ninja Parc giving more people active options</title>
  <content>
FUN: Rafferty Davis, left, and Ollie Daniels, both seven, negotiate one of the obstacles in the Ninja Parc during a school holidays kids' session.

I watched intrigued as some downstairs indoor courts were transformed into a Ninja Parc at The Parc - Indoor Activite Zone, formerly known as Howzat Indoor Sports.

It was last summer and I was playing indoor soccer and each week I would turn up to see a new addition to the obstacle course.

It looked a bit like UFC meets Tough Mudder but when I sat down last week with The Parc director John Pirlo, who conceptualised the idea for the Ninja Parc, he told me the appeal of it was that people of all ages and abilities could gain benefit from a session there.
"I did Tough Mudder six or seven years ago and I saw so many people who weren't into exercise just doing it for fun and the camaraderie of it," he told me.

"Our philosophy has always been we just want people to do something, we just want to encourage more people to be active, including kids."

CHALLENGING: Ninja Master Matt Hunter, left, watches on as The Parc club manager Lisa Spencer and The Parc director John Pirlo hang about.
The Ninja Parc comprises a number of obstacles, some more challenging than others.
But John said everyone who goes in for a session comes out feeling some kind of benefit.
"The first thing is it's fun, moving is a by-product," he said.

"Another benefit is you are doing movements you don't typically do, such as hanging, balancing and agility as you go through the course.

"There's also a lot of hand-eye coordination involved and anyone can do it."
There are rope climbs, bouldering challenges, vertical and horizontal doors, a sea of poles and a newly added warped wall.
The venue hosted some of the country's elite ninjas when "Ninja Warrior" obstacle racing made its Newcastle debut in February.
John said members of the public can test themselves once a month at Ninja Parc's race night. The focus is time trials but it is not just about being the fastest around the course - it is for individuals to improve their own previous times in an encouraging and supportive environment. 
It is also for the whole family.
Ninja sessions start from Little Ninja Gymnastics (three to six-year-olds) and range up to Ninja Fit classes for adults. 
There are free play sessions and after the holidays The Parc will launch after-school sessions, where kids take part in a Ninja session followed by designated time for homework.
The day I was there, there were a dozen kids running, scaling, jumping and balancing their way around the Ninja Parc and having a ball doing it.

You can find out more at .
National Diabetes Week

This week is National Diabetes Week and Diabetes Australia has launched campaign It's About Time  to raise awareness of the seriousness of the type 2 diabetes and is urging 500,000 Australians who could have undiagnosed type 2 diabetes to get checked.
Find out more at .
Winter Warmer Workout

If you are time poor or just can't get up in the cold and dark, stay active this season by squeezing in some quick workouts when you can.
This is my go-to, snappy session while cooking dinner and wrangling kids:

20 squats with alternating single-armed shoulder press;
20 shoulder throws (straight punches with light dumbbells in hand);
20 bent-over rows;
10 lunges with bicep curl;
10 lunges with tricep extension.
Repeat 2-4 times between slicing, dicing and sauteing.
Make it harder: by adding in squats jumps, mountain climbers and burpees.
Upcoming fitness events

Winery Running Festival, July 16, Hunter Valley: Offering 42.2km, 21.1km, 10km, 6km and 2km for kids. .
Lake Macquarie Running, August 27, Warners Bay: Raising money for the John Hunter Children's Hospital Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU), there are 21.1km and 10.5km options plus a 4km kids scamper. .
Tomaree Trail Run Festival, September 17, Fingal Bay: A newly launched event which traverses along beaches, national park and rugged coastlines. Distances on offer include 21.1km, 11.5km, 6km and a kids event. .

Renee Valentine is a writer, qualified personal trainer and mother of three. r.valentine@fairfaxmedia.com.au.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninjas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parc</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NICUs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tough Mudder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Offering 42.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninja Fit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninja Parc</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rafferty Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Valentine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie Running</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howzat Indoor Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warmer Workout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ollie Daniels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Ninja Gymnastics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninja Master Matt Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomaree Trail Run Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Diabetes Week</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winery Running Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fingal Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter Children's Hospital Neonatal Intensive Care Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indoor Activite Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diabetes Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Pirlo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
