<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426702278885356</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/stuff-your-face-with-doughnuts-at-the-third-dandee-donut-eating-competition/news-story/271d8be131f87571c178761ea4c4943d</url>
  <title>Comp winner nabs dough - and dough</title>
  <content>
STUFF your face with delicious free doughnuts for a chance to win $500 - dreams really do come true at Dandenong Market.
For the third year, the market is partnering with  for the 2017 Dandee Donut Eating Competition.
To be crowned the ultimate Dandee Donut Champion, the winner will have to eat at least 30 doughnuts - going home with a full stomach, $500 and a trophy.
Competitive eaters hoping to take the crown include Riley 'Chompamatic' Murphy, Nathan 'The Immortal' Imber and Wayne 'Wayne's Burgers' Barker.

A select number of volunteers from the crowd are expected to be given a chance to gauge their guts against the pros.
The first stage will include five rounds with five participants each; in each round, contestants will compete to eat the most doughnuts in two minutes or the first to eat 10 doughnuts, whichever comes first.
The winner in each round will continue to the finals where the first to finish 20 doughnuts wins.

Dandenong Market's Briony Walker said Dandee Donuts had remained one of the market's most popular and well-known traders, drawing people from all over Melbourne with a strong and loyal following.
"People often tell us they can eat bags and bags of these deliciously warm jam doughnuts - so we're putting them to the test.
"The winner will have to devour up to 30 Dandee Donuts, which is quite the challenge, even for a doughnut aficionado."
The Dandee Donut Eating Competition will be held at Dandenong Market on Sunday August 13 from 12pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Market</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chompamatic' Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandee Donut Champion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandee Donuts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne's Burgers' Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Market's Briony Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandee Donut Eating Competition</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immortal' Imber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
