<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426453170777237</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/chanticleer-cbas-unfortunate-pattern-of-poor-cultural-behaviour-20170804-gxprk9</url>
  <title>Once again CBA hit by issues that it was slow to deal with</title>
  <content>
When Commonwealth Bank of Australia chief executive Ian Narev  there were four things that really worried him.
The culture and leadership were not consistent across the group, there was a risk that employees were not caring for the CBA culture, people did not feel safe to speak up and there were some examples of cultural issues not being addressed.
These issues were openly raised and discussed at a leadership forum held at the Sydney Hilton ballroom in October 2014. The stated objective of that full-day event was to "motivate and inspire our senior leaders to work together to lead and shape our culture for the future".
It is obviously no coincidence that  at the same time that .

David Rowe

Civil proceedings launched this week by the country's financial intelligence and regulatory agency, .

The are six separate prongs to the AUSTRAC allegations, the worst of which is the claim that even after it became aware of suspected money laundering or structuring on CBA accounts it did not monitor its customers to mitigate and manage the risks of money laundering and terrorism financing.
CBA blame coding error

CBA is yet to respond in depth to the allegations but its initial message was that the 53,506 contraventions of the law for failing to notify AUSTRAC of cash transactions in excess of $10,000 were because of a .
The AUSTRAC court documents released on Friday  but it only served to.

CBA told AUSTRAC it had uncovered a "systems error" on June 16, 2014. It tried to resolve the error on September 18, 2014.
But AUSTRAC said this did not resolve the systems error on all affected accounts until more than a year later on November 30, 2015.
The AUSTRAC case has highlighted an issue that appears to have been a feature of Narev's tenure as CEO. When problematic issues have been identified by regulators or the media, Narev and his leadership team have been slow to respond.
Major issues that have followed this pattern include the that has taken about three years to remediate.

The  was another example of a problematic cultural issue that was dealt with too slowly by the leadership team.
Serial offender

Another lesser known cultural problem was inside CommSec, which is the country's largest online broking platform with more than 1 million customers.
In  by the Australian Securities and Investments Commission because of two infringement notices handed out by the Markets Disciplinary Panel (MDP).

The infringement notice issued with the fine revealed that CommSec was a serial offender. It lifted the lid on a culture of non-compliance going back almost eight years.
It was the fifth occasion on which the MDP had found that CommSec had not complied with the market integrity rules. Since 2008 it has also been sanctioned three times by the ASX Disciplinary Tribunal, once by the ASX Compliance Committee and entered into an enforceable undertaking that related to concerns it may not have complied with its obligations in relation to handling client money.
When Narev announces a record $9.7 billion 2017 profit next Wednesday he will once again face a barrage of questions about apparent weaknesses in the bank's culture.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommSec</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Hilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MDP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markets Disciplinary Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 16, 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX Compliance Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX Disciplinary Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
