<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426470350646857</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/rebel-liberal-dean-smith-determined-to-push-ahead-with-gay-marriage-vote-20170804-gxpf0t</url>
  <title>Rebel Liberal Dean Smith determined to push ahead with gay marriage vote</title>
  <content>
 Efforts by the Coalition to find a consensus on the way forward for same-sex marriage are on shaky ground, with a key dissident signalling he will push ahead to hold a parliamentary vote even if the party room restates the current policy for a plebiscite.
As the Nationals party room met in Rockhampton on Friday to reaffirm to holding a plebiscite, WA Liberal Senator Dean Smith indicated he would defy his colleagues and introduce his private member's bill.
"One of the cherished principles indeed of the parliamentary Liberal Party is that individual members and senators are able to listen, involve themselves in the debate, put their best case forward but if, in all good conscience, they can't support a decision of the party room, they are free to uphold their own conscience on issues," he told Sky News.
"That's an important distinction between ourselves and Labor. It's a distinction that I will use on this particular issue at this particular point in time."

Trevor Collens

to try to resolve an increasingly damaging internal fight between a small group of pro-gay marriage MPs demanding an immediate parliamentary conscience vote and those who want a public vote of the people before changing the law can be contemplated.

Options being canvassed include a secret ballot to gauge MPs' views. It is likely the Liberals will resolve to try again to win Senate support for the plebiscite, and if it fails, hold a .
While Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull is personally supportive of same-sex marriage, he is holding the line against a free vote to placate conservatives.
Senior frontbencher Christopher Pyne, who raised conservatives' ire in late June after , said on Friday the overwhelming view of the party room was to support the current policy.
"The first step is a national vote to bring the Australian public with us - that is the policy that has been reaffirmed by Malcolm Turnbull, by the cabinet and by me here today," he said.

Plebiscites corrosive

But Senator Smith, who is gay, said past experiments of plebiscites like the World War I conscription votes, had been acrimonious.
He said the plebiscite was a delaying tactic by those opposed to change despite the majority of the public supporting same-sex marriage.
"I've been on the public record ever since we first announced the plebiscite proposal that I did not support the plebiscite and that I would work to develop my own bill or would work to support a bill that would give same-sex relationships equal status before the law in Australia," he said

"I have made it very, very clear that I cannot support and will not support a plebiscite nor a postal plebiscite.
"They are corrosive, they are divisive, I think they will stain our parliamentary democracy and not improve it."
Senator Smith said when the party adopted the plebiscite policy in August 2015 in the dying weeks of Tony Abbott's prime ministership, it was "conceptual" with no one aware it would cost $160 million to conduct and some Coalition MPs refusing to be bound by the result.
Senator Smith said a postal plebiscite had a number of "dangerous elements" with questions over its cost, how long it would take to conduct, the risk of young people being disenfranchised and the "real" chance it would be challenged in the courts.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Collens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
