<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426362976462056</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/mp-greg-hunt-orders-sport-integrity-review/news-story/46512c63c20f7ddc50fe7c74a4fdff37</url>
  <title>Tribunal to put sports stars under microscope</title>
  <content>
RATBAG sport stars and elite athletes face being investigated and penalised by a powerful new corruption and integrity sports tribunal that could have the powers of a standing royal commission.
Sports Minister Greg Hunt will today reveal he has ordered an authoritative review of the integrity of Australian sport, including the merits of a new national sports integrity tribunal.
There is a similar tribunal in the UK and NZ.
It was predicted the tribunal could become the "Independent Commission Against Corruption (ICAC)" for sport.
A review panel, headed by former NSW Supreme Court Judge James Wood, will consult with the administrators of the NRL, AFL, ARU, Football Federation of Australia and Australian Olympic Committee.
As doping, match-fixing, illegal gambling and integrity scandals continue to overshadow and plague big-spending, big-earning sports teams and stars, Mr Hunt's move signals individual administrators may lose the power to discipline their own.
There have been criticisms in the past of codes applying different penalties to the same types of serious infringements or crimes.
Mr Hunt told The Courier-Mail the review team was expected to finalise its recommendations by the end of the year.
"Sport is part of our DNA, bringing with it so many physical, social, cultural and economic benefits, so it's vital the integrity of all sports are protected,'' Mr Hunt said.
"At the moment we have some of the world's strongest integrity measures but we need to ensure it always remains this way.
"The review will examine national and international integrity threats and future challenges, including the rise of illegal offshore wagering, match-fixing and doping in sport.
"They will also consider the merits of establishing a dedicated national sports integrity commission."
The terms of reference require Mr Wood to examine the adequacy and capability of the Australian Sports Anti-Doping Authority, including its anti-doping rules.
The process can be lengthy and time-consuming. Changes aim to ensure alleged doping infractions are dealt with in an effective, fair and timely way.
It comes as fears of match-fixing are exacerbated by the rise in illegal online offshore wagering, particularly in Asia.
Australia's national policy on match-fixing was agreed to in 2011 but there are questions about whether it needs to be updated.
It will also be considered whether Australia should formally join international efforts on countering match-fixing by becoming a signatory to the Council of Europe Convention on the Manipulation of Sporting Competitions.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Olympic Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council of Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sports Anti-Doping Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court Judge James Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Greg Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commission Against Corruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manipulation of Sporting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hunt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
