<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426788178233424</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/basketball/muo-comes-up-big-in-late-stages-to-lift-chargers-over-hot-favourite-mt-gambier/news-story/0c7fe988bf7fc0617061bec44edc737f</url>
  <title>Muo's heroics save Chargers</title>
  <content>
a SPRINKLE of Mathiang Muo magic in the dying minutes helped deliver the Hobart Chargers their most important win of the SEABL season when they downed premiership favourite Mt Gambier 88-80 at the Derwent Entertainment Centre last night.
Watched by almost 2000 fans, the hometown heroes climbed to second on the table and now have the chance to advance further with a win over Frankston on the road tonight.
"We'll have the opportunity to host the grand final if we can get them," said Chargers coach Anthony Stewart.
"A top-two spot is what you always want and we need to beat Frankston to finish either first or second."
The Chargers were constantly under pressure from Mt Gambier but controlled the game for most of the night until an 11th hour charge by the Pioneers.
With 3min 44sec left to play, Mt Gambier had moved from nine points down at the third change to trail by one and coming home with a wet sail.
At that moment, Muo was watching from the bench.
That's when Stewart unleashed his rangy forward to great effect.
In a tense last two minutes, Muo hit two critical three pointers and inside the last 30 seconds drew two fouls and both times converted his shots.
"He wasn't real happy with me dragging him with four minutes to go," Stewart said.
"He was only out for 30sec but I think it got him thinking a bit and he's gone back on and hit two threes. That's what he's capable of, and if it's not him it's Rob Heyer, or it's Chris Whitehead and Tiri Masunda stepping up."
Mt Gambier came to town expecting the Chargers' offence to be its superpower but the home team's heroics on the defensive boards got the job done.
In what might have been a preview to the national championship final, the Chargers outgunned the same team that humbled them on the road exactly one week earlier. The win lifted the Chargers over Ballarat to second on the table.
Whitehead finished with 22 points.
The Hobart women lost their game to the Centre of Excellence 77-72 in Canberra.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOBART Chargers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPRINKLE of Mathiang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Whitehead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derwent Entertainment Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballarat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiri Masunda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEABL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Gambier</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Heyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
