<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427346523992937</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/2507915/knights-ballboy-the-coolest-job-in-the-world/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Knights ballboy: the coolest job in the world</title>
  <content>
Newcastle Herald's  Mick  Maher who was a ball boy at the 1997 NRL grand Final between the Knights and Manly. Picture: Max Mason-Hubers

CORNERPOSTS bend, stadium pies smell better than they taste, and rugby league ballboys do the spiral ball-toss.
Performed between fence and sideline, this involves funnelling a football into the air and catching it. Then repeating. It has an hypnotic effect on the kids in the crowd, who imagine themselves plucked from the stands, perhaps by their favourite player, mid-sausage roll, to join the ballboy ranks.
Last Friday under lights at Homebush, it was a ballboy's gentle lob that rocked the Parramatta Eels' season.
Down by two points, Eels halfback Chris Sandow reefed a 40-20 kick into the corner to get his team the ball back. But his subsequent slide-over try was ruled out because, with a grandstand baying for him to get a move on, an 11-year-old volunteer had thrown the ball to Eels winger Vai Toutai - who'd called for it - instead of placing it on the sideline. Of all the ways the Eels could miss the finals.
Parramatta coach Brad Arthur seethed at the ruling but spoke up for the boy, especially when News Corp published a photo of NRL ground manager Bruce Richards seemingly scolding him (which Richards denies).
Former Knights ballboy Mick Maher didn't like it either. "Hopefully he has been able to shake it off," says Maher, 30, who now works in marketing for Newcastle Newspapers.
"It's been good that the Eels have defended him the way they have. There are so many d---heads involved in the NRL that would've said the same thing to us back in the day."
Maher says most adults in the game are nice to kids. The ones who aren't mostly don't mean it; they're just invested in the players.

Knights after winning 1997 grand final
But he also recalls an official telling he and some other boys before a finals game not to "f--- anything up". And they hadn't even had a chance to f--- up. So it's not hard to imagine a post-match spray.
In professional sport, young volunteers often find themselves at the pinch-point of pressure moments. The kid who's slow with the sweat towel at Wimbledon is more likely to cop it on break point. When Chelsea's Eden Hazard kicked a ballboy for not releasing the pill, his team's hopes were fading in a cup semi-final.
For Maher, becoming a ballboy felt like a dream. Still does. Without a parent on the board or support staff, he'd recognised Paul Harragon in a park, worked up the guts and asked for the job. The Chief set it up.
"You were a Knights ballboy, the coolest job in the world," says Maher.
"You'd remember that when you were copping it from the crowd, or when the players went nuts at you."
For some in the sport, the boys (and they're all boys, though there are rumours of a girl at the Brisbane Broncos) merit as much consideration as the Gatorade or the goalposts.
They're meant to just work and what's more, work smart. Long before the rules made it black and white, Maher and every other ballboy knew that you threw the ball to your team, but never to the opposition. Their ball got placed on the sideline.
The inconsistency flared in 1998 when North Sydney Bears ballboy Mark Sorrenti threw the ball to the home team's Wade Horder, resulting in a try against the New Zealand Warriors.
"If the players were calling for the ball you're going to pass it," Sorrenti told Fairfax this week, in defence of the Eels ballboy.
Seven years after the Sorrenti controversy, Manly's John Hopoate had to apologise for calling Warriors ballboy Jamel Thompson a "little s--t" when the 14-year-old refused to throw him the ball. Thompson had correctly placed it on the line.
In Maher's two years with the Knights - culminating with the 1997 grand final - no one went easy. Not players, fans or cameramen. He recalls a "death stare" from Andrew Johns after the great halfback had demanded the ball for a quick restart. Unable to throw the distance, Maher kicked it over his head.
One cameraman, who Maher collided with during a game in Wollongong, looked him in the eye and said, "f--- you, you little ----". He felt gutted, and completely in the wrong. These were grown men whose careers depended on a game. Is it fair to put that pressure on a kid?
Brett Finch speaks warmly of his sideline upbringing.
Before he was a 250-game player with four clubs, Finch was a six-year-old fetching buckets of sand at Knights home games. He started in 1988, the team's first year, while his dad Robert coached the lower grades.
"We'd get there nice and early and the crowd would start to build up," he told the Herald.
"To run out as the ballboy in front of 25,000 screaming fans, you'd run over to the hill side of the field and those fans were as passionate as any in the game."
Like the footage of Novak Djokovic joking around with a ballboy at Wimbledon, the interplay between the Cowboys' Johnathan Thurston and the kids who fetch his kicking tees are some of the game's warmest pictures. Thurston lets them keep the tees.
Give or take the odd tumble in front of thousands of people, Maher wouldn't change "99.9 per cent" of his time as ballboy.
"I can't remember feeling any hardcore pressure," he says.

"There are times when you got pretty embarrassed - like you might slip over when chasing a kick or spray the ball terribly when kicking it to Joey - but the excitement of what you're doing overrides the embarrassment."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novak Djokovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Sorrenti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vai Toutai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Newspapers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly's John Hopoate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sorrenti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CORNERPOSTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wimbledon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maher, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Finch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowboys' Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Eels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Harragon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Sandow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wade Horder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamel Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homebush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maher</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatorade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Maher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney Bears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea's Eden Hazard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
