<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426530480190165</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/world-travel/asia/new-photos-reveal-exactly-how-north-koreans-spend-a-day-at-the-beach/news-story/5deb46f8a5afb4022fe107217f1d7638</url>
  <title>New photos reveal exactly how North Koreans spend a day at the beach</title>
  <content>
Undercover in North Korea
0:44

Journalist Suki Kim spent a year undercover in North Korea. She posed as an English teacher, then bravely wrote a book about her insights into North Korean society.

June 23rd 2017
a month ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

Men looking towards the West Sea Barrage beach outside the coastal city of Nampo, southwest of Pyongyang. The West Sea Barrage beach features as a stopping point for foreign tourists, and is a destination for North Korean work groups from the neighbouring area. The beach lies at the end of an eight-kilometre-long barrage that separates the sea from the Taedong River, which runs through Pyongyang. / AFP PHOTO / Ed JONES

Share

A LOT of people might forget that North Korea, our neighbour in the Pacific, boasts a pretty long coastline.
Meaning that, just like us, they partake in the occasional fun day at the beach to spend time with friends and soak up some rays.
But as pictures taken by the AFP's chief photographer for North and South Korea Ed Jones have revealed, they don't necessarily enjoy the same sort of beach activities we do in Australia.
From roasting clams with lighter fluid to singing karaoke and forming weird conga lines on the sand, here's how North Koreans enjoy a day at the beach.

North Koreans dance on West Sea Barrage beach outside of Nampo. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP

A North Korean woman dances on the beach. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP

North Koreans getting down on the beach. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP
Most North Koreans head to Nampo for their summer getaway, a coastal city that lies to the south west of the country's capital city Pyongyang.
As you can see in the below photo, the seaport is extremely popular with North Korean tourists.

The streetview of Nampo. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP
Pictures also reveal how tourists not only love a dance on the beach, they also love a bit of coastal karaoke.

Two boys carry a karaoke box along the West Sea Barrage beach. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP

A boy poses with his karaoke machine. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP
The spot is also becoming increasingly popular with foreign tourists, who can head to the coastal destination to indulge in some clams cooked with lighter fluid.

A hostess cooking clams using lighter fluid. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP
Pictures also showed workers repairing part of the road.

North Koreans repair a section of the West Sea Barrage. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP
Locals were also pictured forming peculiar conga lines on the beach, while other beachgoers enjoy the calm water in doughnuts.

A group of women play a game on the beach. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP

Beachgoers enjoy the water in Nampo. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP
The West Sea Barrage itself is an eight kilometre long barrage used to separate the sea from the Taedong River. The beach in Nampo lies at the end of the barrage.

A man walks along a section of the West Sea Barrage. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP

A woman carries her baby to the water as dozens of North Koreans hide from the sun. Picture: Ed JonesSource:AFP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suki Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP PHOTO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea Ed Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nampo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taedong River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed JonesSource</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Sea Barrage</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
