<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426277077114337</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/neymar-denies-he-left-barcelona-because-he-wasnt-the-main-star-says-he-wants-trophies-at-psg/news-story/699421145da30fe61420bd01ce8e6b2c</url>
  <title>'I want to dream bigger': Neymar speaks!</title>
  <content>
NEYMAR has spoken for the first time as a Paris Saint-Germain player - and he's dismissed a persistent theory about his Barcelona exit while outlining his title dreams in Paris.
His press conference was packed, and PSG president Nasser Al-Khelaifi opened it by saying Neymar is a "worldwide idol" and "the best player in the world."
Al Khelaifi was then asked if there was a release clause in Neymar's contract.
"We have put one in," he said, but then declined to say how much it was.
It was then Neymar's turn to speak and he didn't disappoint.
"I'm very, very happy - thank you very much Mr Chairman for those kind words," Neymar said.
"Thanks for this new challenge - I'm really happy to come to Paris, to PSG, which is a great club in a wonderful city.
"I really can't describe what I'm feeling in my heart.
"I'm really looking forward to practice with my new teammates, to play games and achieve the objectives I have.
"This is for ambition, they have a similar ambition to mine. I want something bigger, a bigger challenge and my heart made that decision and made me follow. That is why I am here. I want to give my best to help the club win trophies.
"I wanted to come to Paris and it was only linked to finding a new challenge. It is not because I was not THE star at Barcelona, I fitted in very well there. This is not what I am looking for here. PSG deserve trophies and I will have new trophies, this is what motivates me, I want to dream bigger."
"It's not as simple as saying the challenge was not big enough [for me to sign last year].
"I felt in my heart this is the time to sign for PSG and I did it.
"The challenge might be similar or even bigger this year.
"I just want to start, train with my teammates play games and be happy at the club."
Neymar was then asked who he talked to that made him sign for PSG.
"It was one of the most difficult decisions I have ever taken," he said. "I was at a great club at Barcelona, I have friends there and it was not easy to leave at all. It was very tense moments, I had to think and rethink about what I wanted to do in my life, I leave very good friends behind, but that is football. Things go fast in football.
"I want to thank all my friends at Barca, they welcomed me so well but it was the right time to leave. I spoke with the Brazilian players here and they were happy for me to come here."
Neymar was asked if the Brazilian influence at PSG was a determining factor in him joining.
"To be really honest, that wouldn't have changed my approach," Neymar said.
"Of course I have friends here, but I arrive here because the global environment is very positive.
"It was not easy - I had to think a lot, I had to think what I wanted to do with my life.
"A lot of people wanted me to talk about it but it's difficult to communicate when you're not 100% sure what you want to do.
"But as soon as I made up my mind, I started communicating.

Football: Insane queues outside the Paris Saint-Germain store in Paris as fans try to get first Neymar jerseys.

Crazy queue for Neymar shirt
"This is what my heart told me to do. I always ask my heart every day and my heart told me, 'Go to PSG.'"
Neymar was then asked if he cared that some people thought his move was all about money.
"What I say to these people is they don't know anything about my personal life, I was never motivated by money," he said.
"What I think about is my happiness and together with my family, I want them to be happy.
"If I was following the money, I would be somewhere else, with other clubs in other countries.
"I'm really sad that people still think that way and I'm glad that PSG believe in me.
"I have done nothing bad. I am sad about the fact that the fans think that. I hope it is only a minority. I never lacked respect to the fans and I think every player should be allowed to stay or leave a club.
"You are not obligated to remain at a club, if you wish to leave then the player has that right.
"Once again, I want to thank the fans, the club, the players.
"I want to write history at PSG, this is the only reason. There are new challenges and I want to help write history. Our biggest challenge is the Champions League, but want all the trophies."
LIVE stream every round of La Liga on beIN SPORTS with the Foxtel Sports Pack. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.

Football: Neymar Jr. Releases a video saying goodbye and thankyou to Barcelona and their fans after four years at the Spanish giants

Neymar says goodbye to Barca

Football: Neymar has agreed to a five-year contract with French club PSG.

Neymar agrees to PSG deal
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al-Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasser Al-Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Sports Pack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chairman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BeIN Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
