<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427256329678008</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/the-queens-interests-are-not-ours-three-reasons-why-the-republic-will-get-up-one-day-20170803-gxos68.html</url>
  <title>The Queen has four drinks a day, and who could blame her? </title>
  <content>
It may be seditious to even pose the question, but here goes: is it possible the Queen goes about her regal business permanently tipsy? A report from Food and Wine this week revealed  - opening with a gin and Dubonnet before lunch (that's gin with a fortified wine: her Maj doesn't mess about with mixers), and ending with a glass of champagne before bed.
This classifies our monarch as a risky drinker, according to health guidelines, but then, those guidelines probably also stipulate one shouldn't eat cake every day, and yet, one does - a slice of one's favourite chocolate biscuit cake. If the Queen is travelling, she pops a piece of it in her handbag.Photo: AP
Such entirely self-pleasing consumption habits can only command respect for the Queen, but they're also a reminder of how tedious it must be to be royal. The endless engagements, the intimacy-killing sycophancy of all those curtseyed meetings, the sea of small talk, the constant pressure to look right and stay awake. Who wouldn't need a stiffener to endure it? And that's before you even get to the many occasions on which her own family must have driven Liz to drink.
The 20th anniversary of Diana's death has done much to remind us of the misery of the Windsors - for years the Princess of Wales was trapped in her marriage, starved of love and even ordinary kindness. She was a sacrificial virgin and little more than a child bride when she married at 20.
To re-watch the footage of Diana's two children walking behind her coffin at her funeral, eyes glued ahead, gawped at by millions and yet never once cuddled, is to realise this family is colder than iced Dubbonet. Prince Harry said the unsayable in an interview in June: "Is there any one of the royal family who wants to be king or queen? I don't think so."
Embarrassment is not a reason to enact constitutional change, and yet, isn't it getting a bit sad how clingily Australia hangs off the skirts of an institution its own members are, at best, ambivalent towards?

They are born to it and trapped in it. Australians, as Opposition Leader Bill Shorten reminded us last week, are not. Shorten promised Labor, if elected,  on the Republic issue. He was criticised by constitutional monarchists, notably Tony Abbott, who pointed out the lack of detail on the constitutional arrangements.
It is true Shorten offered no detail, but several things have happened recently to give his renewed Republic proposal a push.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The first was the visit, last week, by British Foreign Minister Boris Johnson. He was the  dinner, and the crowd loved him - his jokes about Stubbies shorts, his claim to be like Sir Les Patterson, his recitation of Land Downunder.
But all of his references were at least 30 years old. The image he mirrored back at his Australian audience was of the nation slumped in a cultural cringe, decades out of date. It was embarrassing, but more so for him than us. Johnson also conducted a verbal hypothetical, exploring what would have happened if Australia had joined the European Union.
It was a logically distorted attempt to reverse-engineer a political excuse for Brexit, made to the wrong audience.
Johnson's central message was deeply patronising: Australia had never joined the European common market and yet, even you people, Swiftian barbarians that you are, have managed to flourish economically. How humiliating that Britain was now seeking to do independently (of the EU) what Australia had accomplished years ago, all by its itty self.
It was bizarre, and made me wonder why we still revere and tolerate such post-colonial condescension.
Then, this week, came reports of the High Court case, argued by Anthony Whitlam QC (how ironic), son of Gough,  of correspondence between the Queen and former Governor-General Sir John Kerr about the dismissal.
The 1975 constitutional crisis is one of the defining historical events of modern Australia, it happened 42 years ago, and yet historians are unable to access important documents from two of the main players.
The letters are embargoed for another decade, and after that the Queen holds veto over their release. Any Australian who cares about history or national identity should find it outrageous that we are not allowed to know all the facts about our own story.
And come 2027, why would the Queen release those papers? Her interests are not aligned with Australia's. Her duty is to uphold the House of Windsor.
Finally, we have the relentless talk of citizenship - both the dual citizenship tragi-farce played out in parliament, and the government's touted changes to citizenship laws, meant to ensure new Australians want it badly enough before we hand it over.
How any politician can seek to score the Australian-ness or otherwise of any person, while themselves supporting a foreign head of state, is puzzling.
The momentum for a Republic will slowly rebuild, and like same-sex marriage, it is only a matter of time before it happens.
When it does, we can toast it with a gin Dubbonet cocktail, or four.

Twitter:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubbonet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Land Downunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiftian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Les Patterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-ness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor General Sir John Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubonnet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Foreign Minister Boris Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess of Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Whitlam QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Windsor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
