<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426315731820832</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/woman-allegedly-set-on-fire-may-lose-use-of-arms-and-hands/news-story/57fc9ce26617adc75113126ad0c011dc</url>
  <title>Battle not over for burns victim</title>
  <content>
A WOMAN who was allegedly set alight in her bed last week by a man she had met two weeks earlier may lose the use of her arms and hands, rendering her unable to work.
Sigourney Leigh Coles, 28, was allegedly doused in petrol and burnt by Matt James Nolan, 27, in her north Brisbane home.
On fire and screaming in agony, her two housemates pulled her into the bathroom and showered her third and second-degree burns, before paramedics rushed her to hospital.
Nolan was later arrested by police in another suburb.
He has been charged with attempted murder and entering a dwelling with intent.
Sigourney was put in an induced coma and underwent surgery earlier this week.
Ninety per cent of her burns have needed skin grafts, but her battle is far from over.
"At the moment it is also unclear if she will have full mobility of her hands and arms," lifelong friend Kate Munro wrote online.
"Along with the physical damage, there is going to be a lot of mental anguish and stress. Sigourney will need psychiatric counselling to deal with the situation that has been dealt to her.
"It is extremely unlikely she will be able to sustain a job or any kind of paid work for a prolonged period of time."
Sigourney suffered burns to the left side of her face, ear and neck and the top her chest.
Her hair has been burnt and she has third-degree burns to her hands and fingers.
Sigourney's mother Paula Coles plans to build an extra room at their family home, so she can become her daughter's full-time carer.
Sigourney will likely spend the next few months in the Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital's Critical Burns Unit undergoing skin grafts.
"Sigourney had surgery (earlier this week) to treat her burns and had to have 90 per cent of the burns skin graft," Ms Munro said.
"Paula will be moving Sigourney into her place when she is released from hospital, which is expected to be within a month or two. Paula will need to build an additional room to accommodate Sigourney and (Sigourney's brother) Jacob."
A fundraiser has been set-up to assist Sigourney in her recovery.
Already more than $16,000 has been raised.
Ms Munro believes $25,000 will get the Coles family back on its feet.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sigourney</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sigourney Leigh Coles, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt James Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Munro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Munro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Hospital's Critical Burns Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paula Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
