<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426191177766693</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/channel-9-sport-reporter-sam-squiers-celebrates-as-premature-baby-imogen-comes-home/news-story/10a4e7bc97b3d457dc5734eff8f34865</url>
  <title>Sam's baby 'Immi' shows fighting spirit</title>
  <content>
TODAY marks baby Imogen's official due date, but the daughter of Channel 9 sports reporter Sam Squiers has already spent almost eight weeks on earth, proving herself every bit the little fighter.
Sam and "Immi" were left fighting for their lives after pregnancy complications led to a dangerous placental abruption, forcing doctors to perform an emergency caesarean at 32 weeks.
Imogen was 1.3kg when born and was rushed to the Mater Hospital's Neonatal Critical Care Unit. She spent 44 days in hospital before Sam and her firefighter husband Ben could finally take her home last week.
"We are just so relieved to have her home and she's been amazing," she said.
"She's a gorgeous little thing. She has a little bit of sass, which is great for a girl. She's a little fighter and very feisty."
Imogen is still on home oxygen and needs regular hospital check-ups, but she breastfeeds well and continues to put on weight. She last weighed in at 2.3kg.
"We're on to the next challenge now, which is caring for a newborn," Squiers said.
"We don't really go anywhere public or crowded because we are extra protective over her and her immunity.

"But she breastfeeds like a little champion and for me that was a great feeling.
"I felt a bit vulnerable that I couldn't take her to full term and if I couldn't have breastfed as well it would have broken me."
Squires had severe pre-eclampsia during her pregnancy, which caused the placenta to separate from the uterus wall, leading to loss of vision and kidney failure, and putting Imogen at risk of being stillborn.
Her symptoms came on without warning and, with Ben interstate for work, the 34-year-old was rushed to hospital in an Uber in agony.
She said the weeks that followed were "emotionally draining".
"It was numbing even being called a mum in those first few weeks when I couldn't hold or pick up my baby whenever I wanted. When I could only hold her once a day and spend the rest of the day staring at her through a Perspex box," she said.
Looking back on the experience with Immi now at home, Squires said she could not have got through it without the support of staff and other parents who had experienced the NCCU.
"People knew exactly what to say at the right time and it helped me through such difficult times," she said.
"I'm just so lucky that the end result is that me and Immi are here today and feeding on a cushion; it could have been so different."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Squiers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mater Hospital's Neonatal Critical Care Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imogen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Squiers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Squire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCCU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
