<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426229832473273</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/adelaide-parents-turning-to-psychologists-for-advice-about-teen-netflix-movie-to-the-bone/news-story/9c694dc290357afa6a909c0fa84e8def</url>
  <title>Experts warn new teen movie cuts too close</title>
  <content>
WORRIED Adelaide parents and educators are turning to psychologists for advice about a "graphic" new Netflix movie about anorexia that is aimed at teenagers.
The film To The Bone tells the "confronting" story of a young woman with anorexia nervosa, and should have carried a "trigger warning" according to the national voice on eating disorders, The Butterfly Foundation.
There are fears the film - which stars a waif-thin Lily Collins alongside Hollywood star Keanu Reeves - glamorises the potentially dire eating disorder.
Butterfly Foundation chief executive Christine Morgan says: "My concern is, that while this film might cast a spotlight on the reality of eating disorders, it needs to come with clear warnings at the start.
"There are two groups who are particularly vulnerable - those who already have an eating disorder as well as those in 'pre-stage' who are really concerned about their own body image."
Internationally, there have been calls to ban the film because experts are worried it might incite eating disorders.
The Butterfly Foundation has created a "fact sheet" that schools can use to provide as a guide for parents and staff that includes safe viewing tips.
Local psychologists and eating disorder specialists also say they are being contacted for advice by parents as well as schools.
Some teachers are concerned about conversations they're hearing in the schoolyard.
The film's release comes less than two months after the controversial series on suicide 13 Reasons Why, also created for Netflix.
Researchers from the San Diego State University found there was a spike in internet searches about suicide, including phrases such as "how to kill yourself", in the wake of that show.

AN anorexic teenager was just hours from death after eating no food and water for a WEEK in a desperate bid to become popular at school. Ellen Lietzow, then 17, had refused to let even a drop of water touch her lips in the worst of her struggle with anorexia, where her weight plunged to under five and a half stone. After a week of fasting she collapsed with a seizure and was rushed to hospital. She was in such poor condition doctors and nurses were astonished she was still alive. Shockingly, Elle admitted to losing weight because she thought that being skinny would make her popular amongst her peers. She's now bounced back to health after embarking on a strict vegan and fruitarian diet. Videographer / Director: Thomas Baricevic, Tristan McLachlan Producer: Rebecca Lewis, Chloe Browne Editor: Chris Bardy

Anorexia sufferer's incredible recovery
Adelaide clinical psychologist Kirrilie Smout says while the film has some positives as a "conversation starter", it contains "unhelpful messages" and parents need to be wary.
"(It) underestimates the suffering involved in eating disorders, doesn't accurately portray treatment and may make eating disorders seem attractive or interesting," the director of Developing Minds Psychology and Education said.
"I believe that for some kids and teens who either have, or who are at risk of developing an eating disorder, it could quite feasibly trigger jealousy, anxiety about current weight, desire for weight loss and disordered eating behaviour."
Ms Smout, who has written a blog on the issue, says the movie isn't suitable for young children.
"It is entirely appropriate to say to a 13-year-old 'no, you are not watching this', and to provide the reasons why and suggest another film to watch instead.
"If you have an older child (16-plus) who wants to watch it and won't be distracted by another suggestion, ask them if you can watch it together so you can talk about it afterwards ... then monitor and watch what's going on later."
If a young person has a negative body image:
1. NEVER ignore and dismiss concerns as, "this is just a phase"
2. DON'T forget the importance of role-modelling (be careful about your own language and how you refer to yourself)
3. DECOUPLE size and shape with value as a person (remind young people while it is important to be healthy, a body is there to help live life, it doesn't define them)
- tips from Butterfly Foundation CEO Christine Morgan
Butterfly Foundation National Helpline, 1800 33 4673, thebutterflyfoundation.org.au
Lifeline, 13 11 14, lifeline.org.au
Kids Helpline, 1800 55 1800, www.kidshelpline.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirrilie Smout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helpline (1800 55 1800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellen Lietzow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego State University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Browne Editor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lily Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tristan McLachlan Producer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reasons Why</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keanu Reeves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Developing Minds Psychology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Baricevic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butterfly Foundation CEO Christine Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butterfly Foundation National Helpline 1800 33 4673</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butterfly Foundation</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
