<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426491825483765</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/trump-tweets-july-jobs-report-2017-8</url>
  <title>Trump on jobs report: 'I have only just begun'</title>
  <content>
President Donald Trump took to Twitter on Friday morning to celebrate the release of  and promised more jobs gains to come.

"Excellent Jobs Numbers just released - and I have only just begun," Trump said. "Many job stifling regulations continue to fall. Movement back to USA!"

The Bureau of Labour Statistics reported that the US economy added 209,000 jobs last month, higher than the 180,000 expected by economists. The unemployment rate also ticked down to 4.3%, tying the lowest level in the past 16 years.

Job gains were solid in Friday's report, but wages remained lacklustre, with average hourly earnings increasing only 2.5% from the same month a year ago, remaining below pre-recession levels.

The job gains were roughly in line with the average pace of increases over the past few years of the recovery. The average monthly job gains for the first seven months of 2017 was 184,000, just below the 194,000 average monthly job gains through the first even months of 2016.

Trump has had a coloured history with the Bureau of Labour Statistics' report, frequently casting doubt on their numbers before he became president.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Labor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobs Numbers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
