<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426702278885354</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/editorial-sorells-voice-ready-to-be-heard/news-story/0b02a7baa4d602d49bde573efaca5f46</url>
  <title>Sorell's voice ready to be heard</title>
  <content>
THE ongoing discussion about council mergers appears another case of much ado about nothing.
All in all, very little progress has been made.
Councils have commissioned consultants' reports, several of which have identified significant savings, and many have agreed to further investigate resource sharing with neighbouring municipalities.
But at the heart of it, not much has happened.
Some have barely started the process.
Others have already put it in the too-hard basket.
There are those in the community, the Mercury among them, who believe that amalgamations are necessary to reduce the 29 councils which serve our communities - easily the highest per capita ratio in the land.
That does not mean that all councils must merge, nor that the more effective ones not be able to carry on as normal.
It is merely a serious acknowledgment that 29 is, on any scale, too high and leads to unnecessary bureaucracy and over-government.
But for every vote in favour, there is opposition. Groups and councils say amalgamations won't increase efficiency or ensure lower rates and lead to better services. Others see little point in disrupting the status quo.
And many are understandably very protective of their own little patch.
The State Government has pursued a course of encouraging voluntary amalgamations.
The logic is twofold.
Firstly, it went to an election promising not to make such unions compulsory.
Secondly, it knows full well that it would be electoral poison if it did.
It needs look no further than the fallout from similar attempts by the likes of Campbell Newman or Mike Baird.
But the truth is that, unless it is compulsory, self-interest will prevail more often than not, and talking a good game will win out over actually doing something.
So we are largely stuck in a holding pattern.
In some areas, a merger just makes sense.
A greater Hobart council would appear to have considerable benefits, given the billions of dollars worth of significant projects in the wings, the traffic problems affecting the city and surrounding municipalities, concerns over a critical lack of housing and a like-mindedness among existing civic leaders to improve education outcomes and cope with increasing tourism numbers.
But this seems highly unlikely in the short term.
At a time when the city and surrounding regions desperately need an umbrella strategy and vision for the future, none exists.
At the very least, we will continue calls for a City Act to join together key pieces of the puzzle.
So in this climate, it was interesting to see the community of Sorell coming out strongly in support of amalgamations, with 84 per cent per cent of those surveyed supporting the concept.
If all else fails, it may be left for the community to push the case, to take action and force change.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sorell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
