<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426710868820176</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/hilton-hotels-means-business-in-townsville/news-story/55a97b08dddd03e887f8aeee3ad7ebf7</url>
  <title>Hilton means business</title>
  <content>
HILTON Hotels is promising to bring a level of luxury to Townsville that the city hasn't experienced since the 1980s.
Townsville City Council has .
The renowned brand has proposed a 4.5-star, 175-bed hotel - to be run by the Hilton subsidiary DoubleTree - be built in the Townsville CBD Stadium precinct.
Townsville-born Focus Pacific chief executive officer Michael Grahamaid said the brand was all about growth and identified Townsville as a worthwhile investment.
"Townsville is both a big city and a big leisure community," Mr Grahamaid said.
"The timing is right."
Concept designs for the hotel show restaurants and cafes on the ground level, with Mr Grahamaid stating the new facility could also offer commercial "outcomes".
"This will grow another leg in the market," he said.
"Can you make it more than a Hilton? Absolutely."
He said the business plan for the hotel would see it accommodating visitors for more than 50 years.
Townsville Enterprise tourism and events director Bridget Woods said the tourism industry was excited to have a global brand wanting to establish itself in Townsville.
"We still need to focus on building visitation numbers in the region and look at our local business," she said.
Ms Woods said Hilton's proposal was an example of how the stadium had become a catalyst for investment.
The council and Hilton Hotels will work together until November when a final decision is expected to be made.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DoubleTree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Enterprise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville-born Focus Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilton Hotel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Grahamaid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Grahamaid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville CBD Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridget Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
