<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426788178233452</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/social-service-organisations-call-on-will-hodgman-to-fix-issues-that-affect-childrens-commissioner-role/news-story/5804ff651166f278638ecfb9de46acd1</url>
  <title>Plea to support children's advocate</title>
  <content>
Tasmania's social services have come together in a call to arms to end political infighting and interference over vulnerable children.
It follows the shock resignation of Children's Commissioner Mark Morrissey who was only part way into a five-year appointment.
In a move designed to strengthen the commissioner's role, the Tasmanian Council of Social Service has written to Premier Will Hodgman "imploring" him to fix the issues that have plagued a string of commissioners.
Mr Morrissey was the fourth commissioner since 2010 and the third to leave prematurely.
TasCOSS chief executive Kym Goodes said in the wake of the latest resignation: "We must ask ourselves why we are not legislating to ensure the strongest powers possible to protect Tasmania children".
"We want a commissioner that is not constrained by politics ... that can independently investigate cases and report to Parliament," she said.
"We want a commissioner that hold the government of the day to accountable."
In her letter, Ms Goodes called for reforms including:
THE commissionerhave the authority to require reports from relevant state authorities about action taken on recommendations.
THE commissioner have powers equivalent to the Ombudsman when conducting inquiries and investigations.
The recommendations flow from the South Australian royal commission into the state's child protection system.
Relationships Australia chief executive Matt Rowell called for tripartisan support on the issue.
"We've seen the three leaders for the three parties in Tasmania come together on family violence," he said. "It seems like a no brainer to us that they could do the same for vulnerable children."
Former Children's Commissioner Aileen Ashford, who quit in frustration six months before her term expired, echoed the need for more independence. "There is a theme around the lack of independence of that office," she said.
Ms Ashford is the second past children's commissioner to speak out since Mr Morrissey's resignation.
Former commissioner Paul Mason said on Thursday the role needed greater separation from "executive government".
Human Services Minister Jacquie Petrusma said the Government was happy to consider TasCOSS's proposal.
"It should, however, be noted that [we] strengthened the powers of the children's commissioner and the position's independence in 2015," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Minister Jacquie Petrusma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kym Goodes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrissey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ombudsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goodes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasCOSS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Council of Social</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Children's Commissioner Mark Morrissey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ashford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Children's Commissioner Aileen Ashford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Mason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Rowell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
