<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426401631168608</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/south-australian-catholic-schools-in-lost-1000-enrolments-in-2016-blame-economy-and-lack-of-funding/news-story/2f2cbd9b77c08506bf82bf33bcb452e5</url>
  <title>Catholic school enrolments plummet</title>
  <content>
MORE than 1000 students left the state's Catholic school system last year - with the sector blaming the economy for parents' financial struggles and a lack of State Government funding.
Enrolments peaked in 2013 at 48,557 but plunged 3.8 per cent to 46,806 by 2016, with the losses growing in each of the past three years.
By contrast, student numbers in public and independent schools are on the rise.
The independent sector overtook the Catholic system in enrolments last year.
"Our independent research shows that the decline in enrolments is largely attributed to financial pressure on parents and carers," Catholic Education SA director Bruno Vieceli said.
"This is understandable in the current economic climate."
Mr Vieceli said SA Catholic schools received the least state government funding per student in the country, so many had to charge higher fees than schools over the border.
CESA pointed to 2015 figures from the National Catholic Education Commission showing per student state funding was $2061 in SA.
Excluding the territories, the next lowest was Victoria on $2177, ranging up to $3127 in WA.
Mr Vieceli said other states provided more capital works funding to Catholic schools, while the SA Government delivered STEM funding and utility cost relief to state schools but not private ones.
Loreto College's enrolments dropped from almost 1000 in 2008 to below 650 last year.
Rostrevor College declined from more than 1100 students to about 750 over the same period. By contrast, Cabra Dominican College gained about 130 students to reach 1175 last year.
Catholic Education SA is pinning revival hopes on initiatives such as expanding early years services and shifting Year 7s into high school, aimed at creating "smooth pathways" for children from birth to Year 12.
Education Minister Susan Close said the State Government, unlike the Federal Government, would deliver its share of the of the original Gonski needs-based funding deal to all school sectors.
That would deliver a boost to Catholic schools of $20 million over the next two years.
The state was also offering $250 million in low-interest loans to private schools for science and maths-related upgrades, she said.
After the public system lost 500 students in 2014, it lifted enrolments over the next two years by almost 4600, or 2.8 per cent, to 170,773 last year.
And over the same three years that Catholic schools shed enrolments, independent schools grew 2.5 per cent, or 1166 students, to 47,212.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Catholic Education Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Susan Close</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno Vieceli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic Education SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gonski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loreto College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Vieceli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabra Dominican College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CESA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rostrevor College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
