<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426702278885396</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/entertainment/grins-all-round/news-story/0c7fc48e99d3eb9fe5098517dffdf912</url>
  <title>Grins all round</title>
  <content>
GRINSPOON ARE BACK ON THE ROAD AND HEADING OUR WAY ON THEIR HUGE NATIONAL TOUR CELEBRATING THE 20TH ANNIVERSARY OF THEIR HIT DEBUT ALBUM GUIDE TO BETTER LIVING. WE CAUGHT UP WITH GUITARIST PAT DEVERN TO TALK ABOUT THE ALBUM'S LEGACY AND BRINGING THE BAND BACK TOGETHER AFTER A LONG HIATUS.
-
HOW HAS THE TOUR BEEN GOING SO FAR?
I can't ask for more really. All the shows have been sold out and the crowds have been great. The band has been pretty much on fire I reckon. We've just had a little bit of a break over the Splendour in the Grass period so we're looking forward to getting back on the road for the next leg.
YOU'VE BEEN ON A HIATUS FOR A COUPLE OF YEARS NOW. WHY DID YOU DECIDE TO GET BACK TOGETHER FOR THIS TOUR PARTICULARLY?
To be honest with you, it was our management's idea. We had stopped touring in 2013. We got together for a short period of time at the end of 2015 and management kind of came to us and asked what we wanted to do, and we honestly weren't sure. We were kind of happy having a break. But they said 'How would you feel about having a party for the birthday of Guide to Better Living?' We all thought it was a good idea. It'd been five years since we'd been on the road which was long enough for us to have a break. It came together pretty naturally. It was just something that had come up and we'd all agreed on, which is often hard.
WHAT WAS THE FEELING LIKE WHEN YOU ALL GOT ON THE STAGE TOGETHER AGAIN FOR THE FIRST SHOW OF THE TOUR?
Our first show at Traralgon was a little bit rough and ready. We did a couple of warm-up shows before we did Margaret Court Arena which was the first of the really big shows. But the first time we got back on stage it was a little bit rusty, I've got to be honest with you. Well it was for me. Maybe the others didn't, but I felt a bit rusty. But it was only one gig that was kind of rusty. From the second gig onwards I think we clicked back into gear.
HAVE YOU NOTICED ANY PARTICULAR SONGS GETTING THE BIGGEST REACTIONS FROM THE CROWD?
The good thing about this tour is that we're doing Guide to Better Living from beginning to end, so everyone kind of knows what to expect when we take the stage. We do the show and then we have a short break and then we come back and do all the hits off the following four albums. We don't really delve into later albums. After we do Guide to Better Living we kind of keep it to Easy, Thrills [Kills & Sunday Pills], and New Detention. Those songs get a big reaction. I think the show really flows well. It's a tried and true concept doing an album tour, but this one really seems to work. We had five singles off Guide to Better Living so a lot of the songs get really good reactions.
DO YOU THINK THE CROWD FAVOURITES HAVE CHANGED OVER THE COURSE OF YOUR CAREER?
Well, it's funny because when you talk about the "course of our career", I'd probably divide our career into two parts. There's the first four albums and then the next three albums. With the first four albums I think it was really our sweet spot as far as Grinspoon was concerned. We were getting a lot of radio airplay, and we were selling a lot of records et cetera. So each time we released a record we'd have another hit single off that record which would become more popular as time went on. So it's changed in that way. But people like the staples: Champion and More Than You Are off our early albums and the stuff from Guide to Better Living. They're the songs that people really dig.
IN YOUR EYES, HOW IMPORTANT WAS GUIDE TO BETTER LIVING TO YOUR CAREER?
It was our first record. We'd done EPs before then and got signed to Universal Records, so it was our first record on a major label. We sold a lot of copies of that record. It charted at number 12 and stayed in the top 50 for about 60 weeks I think. It took us all around the world and got us signed to Universal out of New York. We moved to LA and did the whole America thing for a number of years. It was a huge point in our career. But, it was different times back then. Music was a lot harder to access for people, so you really had to get out there and play. You had to tour to be heard because people couldn't just stream you from Spotify.
WHAT ARE SOME OF THE HIGHLIGHTS THAT STICK OUT FOR YOU OF THAT TIME?
I remember when the gigs started to sell out. I remember that being a really exciting time. We were still playing small to medium venues but those venues started to sell out really quickly and crowds started to get wilder, and we'd have to bring more people around us to keep touring. I really remember that momentum building. And I have good memories of the early festivals, and walking out on stage and people actually wanting to see us - we were getting big crowds. We might have been playing early on but we were getting night time crowds. They're definitely the memories that stick out in my mind.
HOW DO YOU THINK YOU'VE CHANGED AS A BAND SINCE THEN?
Not a great deal, really. We're still the same group of four people, and individually we're the same people. As a band it's hard to say because we haven't released any original music in a while. As we progressed through seven albums I think our music might have become a bit more mature - that's probably the best way to put it. We weren't as raucous as we were on our early couple of albums. But now we're a bit more of a heritage act I guess.
HAS SPENDING SO MUCH TIME TOGETHER AGAIN BROUGHT UP ANY DISCUSSIONS OF MAKING NEW MUSIC?
We haven't even really talked about doing any new music. I don't know if there's even an appetite out there for people to hear new Grinspoon music. But we haven't even really been on the road in such a long time and all we were really planning on doing was doing this tour. But who knows what's going to happen afterwards. I guess we'll all take stock of everything and when it gets towards Christmas time when the tour finishes we'll see what we want to do.
IF YOU WERE WRITING NEW MUSIC NOW, DO YOU THINK IT WOULD STILL HAVE THAT DISTINCT GRINSPOON SOUND OR DO YOU THINK IT WOULD BE A BIT DIFFERENT BECAUSE YOU'VE BEEN OFF DOING YOUR OWN THINGS FOR A WHILE?
I don't know. I think it would probably have to sound like us, because it is the same four people and a band's often about the sound rather than the song. We're probably a bit more of a "sound" kind of a band. But it would be interesting to see.

Grinspoon is playing at the Dalrymple Hotel on Friday August 11 from 8pm. Tickets: moshtix.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMPORTANT WAS GUIDE TO BETTER LIVING TO YOUR CAREER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIATUS FOR A COUPLE OF YEARS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grinspoon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalrymple Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIGHLIGHTS THAT STICK OUT FOR YOU OF THAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAND SINCE THEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WRITING NEW MUSIC NOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotify</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THINK IT WOULD STILL HAVE THAT DISTINCT GRINSPOON SOUND OR DO YOU THINK IT WOULD BE A BIT DIFFERENT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Pills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TH ANNIVERSARY OF THEIR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOTICED ANY PARTICULAR SONGS GETTING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FEELING LIKE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIRST SHOW OF THE TOUR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THINGS FOR A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BIGGEST REACTIONS FROM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Traralgon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOUR BEEN GOING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAUGHT UP WITH GUITARIST PAT DEVERN TO TALK ABOUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Detention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COURSE OF YOUR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DECIDE TO GET BACK TOGETHER FOR THIS TOUR PARTICULARLY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPENDING SO MUCH TIME TOGETHER AGAIN BROUGHT UP ANY DISCUSSIONS OF MAKING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAND BACK TOGETHER AFTER A LONG HIATUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Court Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GRINSPOON ARE BACK ON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALL GOT ON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALBUM'S LEGACY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWD FAVOURITES HAVE CHANGED OVER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Better Living</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIT DEBUT ALBUM GUIDE TO BETTER LIVING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HEADING OUR WAY ON THEIR HUGE NATIONAL TOUR CELEBRATING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universal Records</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Think You</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STAGE TOGETHER AGAIN FOR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
