<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427260624645352</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/dont-laugh-too-hard-at-donald-trumps-spin-doctors--ours-are-just-as-bad-20170803-gxonjs.html</url>
  <title>Don't laugh too hard at Donald Trump's spin doctors - ours are just as bad</title>
  <content>
Let me share with you a time I was so full of self-loathing I could barely look at myself in the mirror. A period when I would wake each day in fright and wonder how much I would have to betray my principles, to contradict my conscience, and how much pressure there would be on me to outright lie.
You see - and this isn't easy for me to say - for a year, I was a publicist.

Up Next

Much of South Asia could be unlivable by 2100

01:24

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

'That' Scaramucci audio released

The New Yorker released portions of the phone call between its Washington correspondent, Ryan Lizza and former White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci.

Now, to all who share this title, please don't be upset. I'm sure you will agree that the key to doing your job without doing your nut is to represent admirable clients and products. To like and respect what you flog. I didn't do that. I took the pieces of silver and paid for them with my dignity and self-respect.
I have been thinking about this horrible period of my life a lot lately. I even managed a laugh. I mean, who couldn't, watching Sean Spicer trying to spin turds (same as trying to polish, only with an added level of difficulty)?Photo: AP
I then marvelled as Anthony Scaramucci - the so-smooth-he's-slippery model of PR, which doesn't so much break the mould but create it - slid on up to the podium only to be kicked off his pedestal and slither back down some 10 days later.
Now, while Scaramucci and Spicer might be licking the boot prints off their bespoke Saville Row suits as I type, I have some words of consolation: "You blokes have dodged a bullet. Because although you may not come from a place called Principle, you were destined to land in a place called Hell. This is because the product you were pedalling is called hate and insanity, and while the USA may have bought it last election, it's left a very nasty taste the world over that is plain toxic. I know I am physically gagging every damn day."

Spinning for Trump has to be one of the worst imaginable jobs on this planet and reminds me of a movie I couldn't stop watching after I escaped my own moral morass (it was way too close for comfort while I was still there). In 2005's excellent Thank You For Smoking, Aaron Eckhart plays Nick Naylor, the vice-president of the Academy of Tobacco Studies, a lobby group masquerading as research organisation funded by big tobacco, with the aim of debunking the health risks of tobacco use.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

He regularly meets with colleagues Polly Bailey, mouthpiece for the Moderation Council, funded by the alcohol business, and Bobby Jay Bliss of the NRA-backed gun advisory group SAFETY, who refer to their triumvirate as the MOD Squad (Merchants of Death). MOD's gatherings entail them competitively debating just who kills more each year, each boasting their toll greater.Photo: AP
Nick, a likeable and smooth talker, has a quandary - declining youth smoking rates - and devises a campaign to re-glamourise cigarettes in movies. However, he faces adversaries who push even his skilfully honed talents for twisting the truth, all the while trying to be a role model for his 12-year-old son, a salient voice of reason.
As appalling as the premise is, it remains true to this day. In fact, it's possibly worse. Lobbyists are still out there defending such atrocities as the church's systematic and sanctioned sexual abuse of children, anti-abortion organisations, white supremacy hate groups, climate change deniers, the whaling industry, anti-immigration, Islamophobia ... the list goes on.
If you think about it, there isn't much difference between being a MOD and a politician. It is all about spinning bull, following the party line, allowing policy to override conscience, majority opinion over the individual.
My own views were muted when I was a PR. I had words placed in my mouth that I was expected to repeat, and appear convincing as I did it. I may as well have just joined the Libs.
Because, just as Scaramucci had no hope of making Donald Trump appear anything other than the unhinged, xenophobic, narcissistic, bigoted bully and buffoon he is (even by making himself out to be similarly smarmy and sinister), Malcolm Turnbull too is having his strings pulled by those behind him and words placed in his mouth. He is spinning bull and it is pathetic to watch.
Just listen this week, when he said he still believed in a plebiscite on gay marriage, despite polls saying Australians want it legalised - like yesterday! And despite being openly pro-equal rights for all regardless of their sexual preference.
He's speaking for the conservatives to whom he sold his soul to get his precarious gig - his enemy Tony Abbott and his hardcore Catholic mates. Watching Turnbull trying to say everything is just tickety-boo in his party is akin to watching Spicer trying to defend the megalomaniacal menace currently running (in to the ground) the USA - and it's excruciating not just for him, but for an already disillusioned public.
It makes me recoil and cringe at his sanctioning of the cruel conservative collective he fronts, actively imprisoning innocents in UN-law-breaking concentration camps; stifling renewable and sustainable energy initiatives in favour of the big business coal; stalling on vital childcare reform; stripping the budgets of hospitals, schools and women's shelters; prohibiting the education of children on gender differences; perpetuating the atrocious death rates of our Indigenous population (including children tortured in custody); giving tax cuts to the rich and little or no hope to our youth ... the list goes on. And on.
Yep, if Scaramucci and Spicer are looking at alternate gigs, I strongly suggest they stop spinning for politicians and become one themselves. They have the skill set - an ability to lie, to have no conscience or morals, and to kowtow to those with the most money. Turnbull can show them the way.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobby Jay Bliss of the NRA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moderation Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polly Bailey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spicer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thank You For Smoking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy of Tobacco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Lizza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saville Row</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamophobia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merchants of Death</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Naylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mod Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Eckhart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
