<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427071646080417</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:35</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/megan-rapinoe-uswnt-goal-2017-8</url>
  <title>Megan Rapinoe puts defender on skates to lead the way in US Women's National Team victory over Japan</title>
  <content>
It's been an up-and-down run at the Tournament of Nations for the U.S. Women's National Team.

In the opening game of the tournament they found themselves out of sorts, falling to Australia for the first time in team history. They bounced back after a shaky start to their second game, falling behind 3-1 to Brazil before rattling off three goals in ten minutes to steal victory from the jaws of defeat.

On Thursday night, the U.S. were back to looking like the best team in the world with a 3-0 win over Japan in the final game of the tournament.

Megan Rapinoe, who kickstarted the team's comeback against Brazil, was again first to break through against Japan, completely turning her defender and waiting with a professional patience before finding the back of the net.

Watch video of the goal below, courtesy of ESPN.

Mallory Pugh and Alex Morgan would add goals in the second half to send the home team fans home happy.

While the U.S. Women weren't able to win the inaugural Tournament of Nations, the return to form was a welcome one for a team that looked like it might be falling from its spot atop the world of women's soccer.

Rapinoe and company will be back in action in September with a pair of upcoming friendlies against New Zealand.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S. Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Rapinoe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mallory Pugh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Women's National Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rapinoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S. Women's National Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
