<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426745228559584</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/good-weekend/two-of-us/after-lavinia-codd-had-a-stroke-she-did-a-phd--and-inspired-her-daughter-20170726-gxj25f.html</url>
  <title>After Lavinia Codd had a stroke, she did a PhD - and inspired her daughter</title>
  <content>
Photo: Paul Harris
After suffering a stroke in 2001, Lavinia Codd, 47, went on to do a PhD in neurogenesis and work at the Queensland Brain Institute. Her achievements have been a powerful inspiration for her daughter, student Zoe McDonald, 18.
ZOE: My first memory is of playing with the IV drip in Mum's hand at the hospital. Mum was just 31 when she had the stroke. She came home a different person, angry. She wasn't a smoker, a drinker or overweight - so why had this happened to her?
She'd been at one of Dad's work functions when she felt a sizzle in her brain, like a match going out. Her left field of vision went and she became confused. They took her to hospital but she was sent home with migraine medication. It's understandable - you wouldn't look at a healthy young woman in a gorgeous red ball gown and think she'd had a stroke. They didn't give her an MRI or the clot-busting drug that can help if given within a few hours.
Grandma was the main caretaker of me and my brother Sam for a while. One time when Sam fell over, cut his knee and started crying, Mum held her arms out, but he ran to Grandma. That was really hard for Mum.
She'd get lost around the house and had problems recognising faces. She'd dress me in red shorts and a blue top, in order to find me easily at kindy pick-up. She didn't have any movement or speech deficits, it was invisible things like memory, so people didn't really understand.
She improved so much that in about a year she got her driver's licence back. She continued to have navigational issues, though; at shopping centres I'd have to direct her back to the car.

When the stroke happened, she'd been studying science part-time at uni, wanting a career change from accountancy, and was planning to do plant biology. The doctor said, "Sit back and watch TV for a while. Your recovery will plateau after a year or two anyway." That frustrated Mum. She refused to accept it and was back at uni within the year. Her interest shifted to neuroscience; she wanted to know how and why her stroke had happened, and how she could fix herself and other people.
She went on to do a PhD in neurogenesis, which looks at the regeneration of brain cells. She now works at the Queensland Brain Institute at the University of Queensland, where she has helped set up the Stroke Advisory Board (SAB).
I get my strength from Mum. She taught me you have to work hard to be successful. It was tempting to give up in year 12 when study got overwhelming. But thinking of her struggle to find motivation after her stroke helped me push on. She's an incredible woman with a really great mind, even though it's been damaged.
No one knows what caused the stroke.Doctors said she'd plateau, but she drove herself to recover. I've watched her improve on a daily basis. Mum's stroke has made me who I am today.
LAVINIA: There are more than 50,000 strokes in Australia annually. It's not just an old person's disease; a third of all stroke survivors are actually under the age of 65.
It's weird but when I had the stroke I thought, "Oh, finally I'm being tested." I'd had a charmed life: three siblings I love, great parents, a good education. I was smart and things weren't that hard. I met [my husband] Scott, had a great relationship and two perfect kids. Nothing had gone wrong in my life. Ever. The neuropsychologist said I had no coping mechanism, as I'd never had to cope [with setbacks]. I was angry after the stroke and still am. That will never go away.
Every mother will say she's close to her daughter but Zoe and I are particularly close. Her depth comes from the intense, honest conversations we'd have as she grew up about everything: politics, religion, sex, drugs, alcohol. We don't have arguments, we'll have discussions on differing views. From primary school on, I'd say to the kids, "Tell me if you disagree with any rule and I'll listen and take what you say seriously. But I'll decide because I'm the mum."
Zoe's gentle but forceful. She's happy to stand up for herself but doesn't like conflict. She writes a lot and does slam poetry. I never would have picked her for a performance person but she takes on a persona and is good at it, winning competitions. Right from the start, even in her childhood short stories, I'd come across a sentence or a paragraph where she'd totally nail something, capture the scene or emotion. You could always see a spark of brilliance.
Recently we watched the Amy Adams sci-fi movie Arrival together. It deals with complex issues and, while I lay in bed afterwards thinking about it, I knew exactly what Zoe would be up to. Sure enough, she was expressing her thoughts on it by writing poetry. Her shining quality is her ability to see and then express emotions, connections and relationships.
We may have mother/daughter times together, like shopping or having a facial, but Zoe's comfortable in herself and her appearance and is conscious of not having to wear make-up or dress in a certain way to impress the opposite sex. She'd rather be who she is and doesn't want to change for anyone.
We text a lot. "Why don't you just ring each other?" Scott asks. "Because it's fun," I reply.
I've always been driven. I went back to my life and challenged the very parts of my brain that were damaged. I think my recovery is evidence of neuroplasticity. Zoe, who is now studying arts/journalism, has written about me and the importance of philanthropy in funding scientific research that can change lives. She's become an advocate and attends SAB meetings.
I'm not going to say I'm Zoe's best friend. I'm her mum and think she's the world's best daughter. But I like her as well as love her. If I'd been her age, we'd have been friends at high school.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stroke Advisory Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe McDonald, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PhD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Brain Institute</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lavinia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lavinia Codd, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lavinia Codd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
