<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426530480190173</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/the-trip-to-spain-with-justin-hemmes-20170803-gxp3w1</url>
  <title>The Trip to Spain, with Justin Hemmes</title>
  <content>
Each January, I promise myself that in the ensuing year, I'll go somewhere in the world I've never been. Last year's destination was Japan, where in the April I  my little brother for 10 days but then abruptly found myself again in November . This year's was Spain, and again, despite taking nearly 34 years to visit,  on Barcelona in March, here I am in San Sebastian not five months later.
Over lunch last month at Uccello, its proprietor Justin Hemmes foreshadowed his coming sweep through Europe's culinary Mecca, the restaurateur understandably curious to learn what exactly these basques do with the fruits of the sea that we antipodeans do not.
Deep within my already massive guts, FOMO stirred. And stirred, and stirred. Hey, with 72 Sydney shingles on the go, Justin feeds more uninvited stragglers every week than Jesus did (just the once) at the Sea of Galilee, I told myself. I called him (Jus, not Jesus) as the date approached to claim a spare room at his Airbnb on the Bay of Biscay.
After two hours on an Iberia bug smasher from ghastly Luton and a stroll through the Kubo-kutxa's Balerdi retrospective, I link up with Jus and his trusty lieutenants Frank and Jordan. We traipse through the old town's famed pintxos bars, grazing on blistered Padron peppers and lashings of jamon at La Cepa, local cheeses at A Fuego Negro, foie gras at the Michelin-starred and heaving La Cuchara De San Telmo, Russian salad at Bodega Donostiarra and transcendental marinated anchovies on baguette slices at Bar Bergara. Standing at Bar Nestor, we murder two enormous slabs of local beef on the bone, served rare and blanketed in rock salt, and plates of ludicrously flavourful fresh tomatoes.

Alamy

The boys sample the local ciders; I stick to the house reds - at most places, €1.20 a glass. "With these prices and my drinking, if I stay here a year I'll save enough to make an offer on The Hermitage." Going off his expression, Justin is not a seller.

The next morning when I cantilever myself out of bed, I find Jus sprawled, sleepless, on the sofa. "The street lights blazed through my window all night," he laments, as Jordan pads into the living room, walks straight to Justin's bedroom door and presses a button. Black-out blinds descend with a hum. We all fall about laughing.
After a swim in the Atlantic (La Concha Beach's pontoon even sports two, blue slippery dips), and a virtual sprint around and through the Guggenheim in Bilbao, we roll up at Asador Etxebarri, housed in the small church square of Atxondio.
As it would happen, Steve Coogan and Rob Brydon lunched here in the second episode of The Trip to Spain (premiered in April on Sky Atlantic; nowhere to be seen on Foxtel), immortalising its "life-affirming butter" with the initialism "L.A.B." and observing that "there are few things worse in this life than a tomato with no flavour. This is the antithesis of that."
"Well, er, bombing in Syria? That might pip it at the post."

"You think?"
Tripe, mussels, prawn, octopus, squid; red bream, lobster. Cow's milk ice cream with beetroot sauce. We are a quartet of Augustus Gloops in our very own chocolate factory.
Groaning all the way home, and after another swim, we all retire without dinner. "I'm not eating until 5pm tomorrow," Frank vows as solemnly as if his hand clutches the Bible rather than his ribs.
This time we all lie down in darkness, but Justin is again first on his feet as the sun (also) rises. He bounds in to my room. "OK we've seen enough here. Frank is leaving from Athens and I can get a slot this morning out of Biarritz. Let's go."

We are soon back in the tour bus, across the French border and in the centre of the town. Were it up to me, Biarritz's market, Les Halles, would be one of the seven wonders. Every butcher, monger or grocer's daughter is straight out of The Blue Lagoon, yet still not nearly as Elysian as their produce. "Even the boy at the bread stand was handsome. And so polite!" Justin marvels.
"You'd turn?"
A dreamy pause. "No, but I think I'll come back as him."

We load up with cheeses, terrine, salumi, radishes, strawberries, cherries, apricot tart and, of course, rose. And forty minutes later, 40,000 feet up, we are throwing the most glorious picnic as we bear down on the Aegean. As he prepares our epic spread like a boss, Jordan turns across the narrow aisle to his colleague. "Still not eating, Frank?"

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asador Etxebarri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALAMY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iberia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Cepa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bible</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bar Nestor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bodega Donostiarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Cuchara De San Telmo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atxondio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuego Negro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biarritz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black-out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uccello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Augustus Gloop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Hemmes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelin-starred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea of Galilee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hermitage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aegean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Padron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Atlantic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay of Biscay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlantic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bilbao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Concha Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elysian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kubo-kutxa's Balerdi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mecca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bar Bergara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Halles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Sebastian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Lagoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOMO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Coogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L.A.B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Brydon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guggenheim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
