<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427015811504581</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/blackstone-taps-ex-ge-exec-to-lead-massive-new-infrastructure-fund-2017-8</url>
  <title>Blackstone named a leader for its massive new infrastructure fund</title>
  <content>
The Blackstone Group has hired ex-General Electric exec Steve Bolze to help run its massive new , the firm .

Bolze, who worked at GE for 25 years and previously served as CEO of its $US28 billion power business, joins Blackstone as the head of portfolio operations and asset management for the new business, where he'll help global head Sean Klimczak manage as much as $US100 billion in investing firepower for infrastructure projects.

The new unit raised an eye-popping  from Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund in May and expects to attract another $US20 billion from other investors. The remainder would come from additional debt financing, Blackstone said.

Blackstone teased Bolze's hiring during its 2nd-quarter earnings call in July.

When asked about hiring for the new business, Steve Schwarzman, founder and CEO of the $US371 billion asset manager, said the firm would be adding some outside hires, including "a world-class operating partner that I think will just knock the people's socks off."

At GE, Bolze managed global infrastructure investments, helping boost overall revenues 70% from $US16.5 billion to $US28 billion over the course of a decade, Blackstone said in a statement.

"We are delighted to welcome Steve to Blackstone as we build out our team of best-in-class infrastructure professionals," Schwarzman, who is an adviser to President Donald Trump, said in the statement. He added, "We believe that these investments will play a vital role in helping the United States rebuild its ageing infrastructure and know Steve's extensive expertise will contribute greatly to that effort."

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bolze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Klimczak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Schwarzman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolze</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schwarzman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of the US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackstone</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Electric</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackstone Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US16.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$28</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
