<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426715163787585</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/yarra-ranges-ratepayers-who-pay-rates-early-in-running-to-win-hotel-stay-dinner-hot-air-balloon-ride/news-story/6c048b11568ee7cdc3e3bec6c6c5c96f</url>
  <title>Pay rates early and you could win big</title>
  <content>
A COMPETITION with prizes including hot-air balloon rides to encourage residents to pay their rates early helped Yarra Ranges Council boost its cash flow by $5 million last year.
The council estimates it saved $250,000 in interest due to the early repayments and is planning to run the competition again this year.
But despite the incentives, the council is taking action to recover $1.5 million from 350 people who did not pay their rates last year.
Ratepayers had until September 30 last year to pay their 2016-17 rates in full for the chance to win one of five prizes.
Prizes included accommodation and dinner in the Yarra Valley, lunch and a ride on Puffing Billy and a "magic moment" at Healesville Sanctuary.
The council's corporate services director Troy Edwards said 4308 ratepayers paid early and were eligible for the competition.

Mr Edwards said that was almost 700 more people than the previous year.
He said it was a "successful low-cost initiative" which boosted the council's cash flow by about $5.1 million and meant the council did not have to make significant borrowings for capital works projects. He said ratepayers have to pay in full by October 2 to be eligible for this year's competition.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puffing Billy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Ranges Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Healesville Sanctuary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
