<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651426573429864061</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/national/labor-senator-begins-push-to-turn-australia-post-into-bank-20170803-gxoro0</url>
  <title>Labor senator Sam Dastyari begins push to turn Australia Post into bank</title>
  <content>
Prominent Labor senator Sam Dastyari says he plans to spend much of the year pushing for Australia Post to be granted a banking licence, bringing his  to an issue he hopes will rebuild his political credibility.
The 34-year-old senator resigned from the shadow ministry last year after .
In an interview with AFR Weekend, Senator Dastyari said he had been cleared by the Labor Party leadership to try to turn public support in favour of the government-owned postal company being turned into an authorised deposit-taking institution.
The change would allow Australia Post, which is looking for new business to replace , to operate deposit accounts and issue credit cards.

"To drive down prices we start by giving Australia Post an ADI," he said. "We'll start with credit cards. If you really believe the government should get involved in banking then you need to win the case with the arguments."
Senator Dastyari, who is a close supporter of leader Bill Shorten, has a history of being ahead of Labor Party policy. He says he advocated a royal commission into banks a year before it became the party's official position.
The idea has been around several years, although has never been taken up by either main party. In the 2014 the Communication Workers Union urged the Abbott government to turn Australia Post into a "one-stop shop" providing banking and insurance services, and everything else, for rural and regional communities.
Critics argue that the government shouldn't seek to increase banking competition by turning one of its own companies into a bank.

The organisation, which has a new chief executive, isn't pursuing the idea. "Australia Post has no plans to obtain a banking license," a spokeswoman said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR Weekend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communications Workers' Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastyari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dastyari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
