<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428025128836973</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/nambour-was-a-boom-town/3207575/</url>
  <title>Nambour was a boom town</title>
  <content>
HELEN Turner and I both joined the Ray White office in Nambour in 1993 and bought the franchise in 1996.
Within a few months, we bought an independent office and moved the business to the centre of town. This proved to be successful as in those days, Nambour was a thriving town.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s as people opted away from the more expensive coastal areas in a post-GST search for cheaper housing.
Nambour had the lower price end of the market cornered as the average home could be purchased for between $120,000 and $140,000, whereas a similar home averaged about $170,000 at Maroochydore.
Buyers also liked the fact that Nambour was home to the hospital, excellent schools, TAFE and a good train service.
The business grew rapidly and before long, Helen was managing 360 rentals: quite a large rent roll for a country town. I was busy with five sales staff and Helen and I watched the area go from strength to strength.
In those days, the internet was just a fledgling tool and access to council records was by microfiche, with minimum sales history. Properties were advertised for sale on window cards in the office, each Saturday in the Sunshine Coast Daily real estate section and through the Ray White monthly property booklet.
This meant that there was much more interaction than now with buyers going into the office and actually being taken out to view properties in the salesperson's car.
Helen and I always felt that we led the way in introducing new ideas to real estate in Nambour. For instance, we used to hire a mini-bus each Saturday and take people out to the properties open for inspection. We were also the first office in town to purchase a car strictly for property management and had it badged in the Ray White colours.
We were both active in the community, joining the chamber of commerce and I became the chamber president. Helen was also the first female member of the Rotary Club of Nambour 76.
We sold the business at the end of 2004 to a staff member, bringing to an end our proud association with the real estate industry in the Nambour district.
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
FAMILY holiday was catalyst for a change of scenery and lifestyle.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotary Club of Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HELEN Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
