<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427904869750677</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/world/asia/shinzo-abes-era-may-be-over-as-japan-braces-for-instability-20170804-gxp7el</url>
  <title>The Abe era may be over as Japan braces for instability </title>
  <content>
Japanese politics returned to a familiar place on Thursday when a Prime Minister under pressure from scandals and falling approval ratings  in a bid to boost a flagging government.
The only surprise was that the Prime Minister in question was Shinzo Abe.
Until relatively recently Abe has presided over Japanese politics and his ruling Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) with an authority not seen since the days of the telegenic, Elvis-loving Junichiro Koizumi, who retired as prime minister in 2006.
Abe, who took on the role in December 2012, has brought stability to a chaotic polity and was being talked about as a new regional strongman as he pushed for a more assertive Japan to play a larger global role.

Alamy

But that narrative has changed after an unhappy summer of scandals, in which Abe's approval ratings have plunged to their lowest level since he returned as Prime Minister.

Now pundits are openly talking about the era of Abe being over. That might be a little premature, but he is certainly a weakened leader and that has major consequences for Australia and the region.
In an attempt to resurrect his standing and reset the agenda Abe reshuffled his cabinet on Thursday, taking what most pundits described as the "safe" option.
"These are people who are serious, know the brief and are not going to embarrass the Prime Minister," said Tobias Harris, a fellow at the Sasakawa Peace Foundation, via phone.
The boldest change is the appointment of the outspoken moderate, Taro Kono, as Foreign Minister. He has a degree from Georgetown University, is a vocal critic of nuclear power and is seen as having strong connections in Washington after working as an aide for several US politicians.

Bloomberg

His predecessor Fumio Kishida, considered a rival to Abe, was not given a role in the new cabinet, and instead appointed chairman of the LDP's Policy Research Council.
Abe made two other changes and in announcing the reshuffle said the government's focus would return to the economy and indicated controversial attempts to amend Japan's pacifist constitution would be put on hold.
Growth problem

"The economy remains our top priority," Abe told a news conference after the reshuffle.

YOSHIKAZU TSUNO

This should bring a new push on the so-called "third arrow" of Abenomics, which focuses on structural reform, but has largely failed to have a noticeable impact on growth.
will be welcomed, according to Harris, but he notes Abe's plummeting approval  simply due to a renewed focus on policy.
"There has been a real erosion of trust in Abe ... and his reputation as a trustworthy figure over the last six months," he said.
According to a poll of polls compiled by Harris and his Sasakawa Peace Foundation, Abe has an approval rating of just 33 per cent and his negatives are closing on 50 per cent.

Yoshinobu Shimizu

That has led to speculation about his tenure.
The key date is September next year when Abe is scheduled to seek a third term as LDP leader. He could remain in power until 2021 and become the nation's longest serving leader.
Just six months ago that seemed highly likely, but unless his poll numbers improve by early next year he might not even make it to the LDP meeting as leader.
"Not that Abe will go easily," said Harris.

"Things will have to get much worse before he does that."
The spectre of a weakened Abe clinging to power and political instability in Tokyo has consequences for the region, where Japan has sought to play a bigger role in recent years.
"The stability of Japan's domestic politics has allowed it to play a more meaningful role in supporting regional stability," said Yoichi Funabashi, a high-profile author and foreign policy observer during a visit to Australia earlier this year.
Abe has joined forces with Narendra Modi of India to challenge China's dominance in Africa, and worked with Australia to counter Beijing's influence in the Pacific.
Under Abe, Japan has also become a key player in an informal web of interlocking regional arrangements designed as a counter-measure to China and its growing influence.
Any departure of Abe could jeopardise these new regional arrangements, which have stood as a warning to China but not overly antagonised Beijing nor hurt trade relations.
According to Funabashi another worry is right-wing populism taking hold after Abe.
"Traditionally whenever Japan has had a long-tenured government we've seen political turmoil follow. That might be the case again," he told the Australian Strategic Policy Institute during his visit to Australia.

"I'm particularly concerned about the possibility of right-wing populist sentiments being unleashed more visibly."
Despite being seen as Japan's most conservative leader in 70 years, Abe has kept the far right in check during his tenure and he continued this trend on Thursday with his promotion of moderates tasked with focusing on the economy.
"I want to unite and move forward by returning to the early spirit we had when we took back the government in 2012," Abe said in reference to the economy.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALAMY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LDP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abenomics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harris</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yoshinobu Shimizu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YOSHIKAZU TSUNO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yoichi Funabashi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobias Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Democratic Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taro Kono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis-loving Junichiro Koizumi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgetown University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fumio Kishida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narendra Modi of India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LDP Policy Research Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shinzo Abe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Funabashi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abe</name>
    <count>21</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Strategic Policy Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasakawa Peace Foundation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
