<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427432423340345</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4833489/open-homes-to-see-this-weekend-in-sydney/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Open homes to see this weekend in Sydney</title>
  <content>
An elegant redesign in , a 1920s heritage home in Newtown and a sunny north-facing apartment in  all make Domain's property wish-list this week.

Ryde

An elegant redesign has transformed this cottage into a modern classic.
A stone island is the hero of the kitchen-living area, which opens to a covered deck and lawn. The main bedroom plus study alcove take up the whole second storey.
Meadowbank Public School is 100 metres away; ferry and train services are also close by.
Agents  and  of  will take the property to auction on August 19 with a guide of $1.85 million.

The Ryde property has had an extensive renovation.  Photo: Supplied

Newtown

8 Hawken Street, Newtown. Photo: Supplied
Between two train stations and with a primary school at the end of the street, this freestanding cottage is designed thoughtfully for rest and recreation.
The cherished hallmarks of its pre-1920s heritage shine through a sleek renovation with indoor-outdoor living and designer touches.

The open-plan living space leads to a paved outdoor area.
Photo: Supplied
and  of  will take the property to auction on August 19.

Darlinghurst

509/50 Burton Street, Darlinghurst. Photo: Supplied
The iconic Republic II building by architects  is known for its edgy urban design, walk-to-anywhere location and hipster-magnet properties.
This north-facing apartment has a two-storey glass wall to soak in the city atmosphere and a balcony overlooking the pool and the city skyline.
A guide of $1.7 million has been set for the August 12 auction.  of  has the listing.

The communal outdoor area has a water feature and looks out to Sydney's CBD.  Photo: Supplied

Download the Domain app to search for properties open for inspection this Saturday near you

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darlinghurst</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newtown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawken Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burton Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republic II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meadowbank Public School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
