<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428042308706349</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sc2067-sekisuis-vision-for-beachfront-development/3209001/</url>
  <title>SC2067: Sekisui's vision for beachfront development</title>
  <content>
YAROOMBA will feature "a fantastic coastal village" in 50 years according to the man driving five-star hotel plans on the Coast's last undeveloped beachfront site.

Evan Aldridge is Yaroomba Beach project director for Sekisui House's proposed 220-room The Westin Coolum Resort and Spa as well as 148 serviced apartments development.

The plans are before Sunshine Coast Council for consideration, with a decision expected later this year.

Sekisui House bought the site from Lendlease in 2010 with an existing development approval for a gated apartment and housing estate, similar to what is south of there already.

Mr Aldridge said construction of that project could start immediately.

"But it doesn't generate the public benefits of the proposal that we're applying for now," Mr Aldridge said.

"We have done substantial engagement to get that feedback from the community as well as looking at the visions for the Sunshine Coast.

"We think that we've got the right balance in terms of the offering that we've got right now."

It is an offering Mr Aldridge says fits in with his hopes for the wider region.

"I think the important thing is, the Sunshine Coast is already an awesome place.

"It's got such great attributes, particularly all of the landscape and beauty that actually is quite scenic in terms of its appeal.

"It's important that is both retained and protected."

He has lived on the Coast for eight years.

His wife Amy has lived on the Coast for most of her life and together they have two boys Kaiden, 5 and Tate, 2.

"Its a fantastic place to bring up kids.

"I've got a personal interest in wanting to see the Sunshine Coast grow and develop and have those opportunities there but also to make sure the culture that's here on the Sunshine Coast keeps developing.

"It's been established for a long time now and its been growing.

"It's at a point now where there is an opportunity to bring in some of those extra amenities to make sure there is that great sort of growth in the different destinations around here.

He said Sekisui House's plot of land would look like a "fantastic coastal village" in 50 years.

"It'll be a great destination to come down, if you're local, to... have a bite to eat or go to the beach or come down and experience one of the cultural events we will have there.

"It will also be a really big draw card for tourists coming into the area.

"We really do see it as a new age of sustainable coastal village.

"It will be a key place on the map of the Sunshine Coast."

from  on .

Mr Aldridge said if approved, The Westin Resort and Spa and serviced apartments would be included in the first stage of development.

"That provides the great economic boost to the region.

"It automatically establishes a new luxury accommodation precinct which is really needed on the Sunshine Coast as well as having integrated conference facilities.

"It is the last beach-side tourism focus area to be developed on the Coast and therefore we think it deserves a proper outcome on that."

But he said the existing approval was the company's fallback position.

He said it was still valid for about four or five years.

"That is the plan B."

Moving forward, he said he hoped his children still lived on the Coast in 50 years.

"With all of us, we like to go out and explore other areas but I really hope that there's the diversity in the economy to draw people back and want to establish a lifestyle here for themselves.

"That's the challenge... to make sure that we can change some of the thinking... particularly things like having more connected villages and making sure that we can provide the amenities within close distance for everybody rather than having things too spread out."

Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westin Coolum Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sekisui House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC2067</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sekisui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evan Aldridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaiden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tate, 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Aldridge</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lendlease</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westin Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
