<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428033718771653</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/tom-has-memories-of-elation-at-his-first-sale/3207545/</url>
  <title>Tom has memories of elation at his first sale</title>
  <content>
HAVING moved to Noosa from Brisbane just 20 years after the Sunshine Coast was named, I've witnessed 31 years of continuing change in the real estate industry.
Back in the mid-'80s you could buy a house in Noosa for around $50,000 and there were plenty of blocks for sale around $10,000. That sounds cheap now, but it's all relative. It was a lot to pay back then when other areas on the Coast were offering properties for a lot less.
Going back 50 years when the Sunshine Coast's name was first coined, a beachfront block could be bought from developer and former Brisbane lord mayor Clem Jones for around $1000. They are in the multi-millions now.
There was just timber buildings in Hastings St and places like Noosa Sound, Noosa Waters and Noosa Springs did not exist.
There were 14 real estate offices in Hastings St in 1986 - now just four survive.
Nobody had exclusive agencies then, auctions were unheard of, there was no internet or mobile phones, advertising was basically classifieds in the local paper, office window displays and property signs which sometimes numbered more than 10 per property.
Agents controlled all real estate information, so buyers and sellers had to come into their offices. Photos were on Kodak paper. In fact, a photo lab subleased space in our office.
We had one typewriter and in 1987 our office bought a fax machine, but initially we couldn't use it much because people at the other end didn't have one.
Relying on postal communications meant it was all running at a snail's pace compared to now. Any response that came back in under two weeks was prompt.
My first sale was to a Tasmanian couple who I met while they were looking at properties in the office window display. Because agents all had the same listings and same properties in the window, you had to be quick; if you missed them they would walk 20 metres further to another agency.
Once you had them in the car you tried to cover all bases by showing them everything in town in fear of them buying one of the properties you missed through another agent.
We would often spend many days, literally, just showing one buyer around. Your heart would sink when you saw them coming into the office with a bottle of wine, because that was invariably a consolation price for chauffeuring them around for a week.
After two months in the industry, and more than a week of inspections and a few lunches with the Tasmanian couple, they bought a unit for $33,570.
Thirty years later, I can still clearly remember the elation of that first sale. It earned me about $600.
There have been thousands since which still always give me a buzz. I think it's the same for all career agents.
So much has changed and it happened right in front of our eyes. It's still happening now and change will continue at an accelerating pace, so anyone lamenting they had not bought or bought enough real estate back then should think about buying now because even more change lies ahead.
The next big game-changer will be when the Sunshine Coast Airport expansion in 2020 caters for direct international flights. Currently the Gold Coast attracts 30 times as many international travellers due to the ease of access.
Technology is the other big game-changer which we are highly focussed on.
We are celebrating 50 glorious years for the Sunshine Coast, but imagine just what it will look like when celebrating its centenary.
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastings St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clem Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Sound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kodak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
