<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428033718771689</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/organ-donation-mums-final-gift/8774292</url>
  <title>Organ donation: Mum's final gift saved two lives and reminds us she's never far away</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

"Julie's organs could save many lives."
The hours leading to this moment had raced by. It began with a horror phone call, moved to disbelief, before all emotions were shut down for a desperate airport dash. Then, a baggage carousel reunion where reality was inescapable: "Catastrophic. Unsurvivable."
On that same day, two other families received phone calls that also changed everything. They were strangers, but had one thing in common: they each loved a child who may not live to see Christmas. I don't know their names, but I do know they couldn't live a normal school kid life.
Days were spent surrounded by white hospital walls and the dreaded hospital food. These little kids were in serious kidney failure and on dialysis. But that evening in 2014, in the cool of early autumn, the phone call finally came. There was a match. These kids were getting a new kidney.
"Julie's organs could save many lives."
But to get to this moment for two young lives, a family had to deal with the loss of one. It was an agonising 12 hours, where wild thoughts and despair and agony washed over. Every conceivable thought rushed through their minds in those endless minutes. But donating organs wasn't one of them.
They were still trying to digest the day's events. An emergency helicopter ride, life support machines and now, the helplessness of a "catastrophic, unsurvivable" injury. It was all coming in fast. But they had a decision to make, one the clock wouldn't wait for. Julie's vital organs could give many a second chance at life. Fewer than 400 people had donated organs the previous year. It sounded like a low number, yet was somehow an Australian record.
Those little kids got their second chance that day because they received a rare gift: life. And that gift came from my Mum.
'The world as we knew it ended'

At just 53, an aneurysm ruptured in Mum's brain just over three years ago. It was extremely sudden and unexpected.
As the world as we knew it ended, my Dad, three younger siblings and I were asked by intensive care doctors if we would consider donating Mum's organs. We knew immediately Mum would want to help wherever she could.
The paperwork was daunting, the compulsory questions confronting. But we were guided gently by medical staff and supported by a social worker and nurses from Donate Life. We learnt quickly Donate Life staff were a special group of people, who never pushed our family into any decision, although they were acutely aware of just how urgently Mum's organs were needed.
We ticked the boxes to donate Mum's major organs, including her heart, the biggest piece of her we miss.
Mum had the most wonderful heart. It was protective, brave, immensely proud and full of love.
She would walk into a room and make each person feel special, like nothing else mattered but the conversation the two of you were having.
We also agreed to skin donation and were told a small patch of skin would be used to grow more for burns victims. I loved my Mum's skin - it felt like velvet. As a child, I would run my hands up and down her arms and over her face.
Now, her beautiful skin has been shared with those who've gone through awful trauma. They will face enormous challenges for the rest of their lives and Mum is helping make that a little easier.
And it's fitting that Mum is living on through young people. You could never say a bad word about a young person around Mum - she simply wouldn't believe you. She saw things in them many others couldn't - or wouldn't. Perhaps the most wonderful news we received as a family was that Mum had helped get those two little kids out of hospital, back home and to school.
We wish for her return every day, desperate to rewind the clock to "before".
Both are impossible asks. So we share stories of Mum's final gifts, which remind us she's never far away.
This week is DonateLife Week for the .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DonateLife Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donate Life</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
