<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428003654000019</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/beachside-house-hospital-claim-master-builders-glo/3209055/</url>
  <title>Beachside house, hospital claim Master Builders glory</title>
  <content>
DEMONSTRATING the health of the Sunshine Coast building industry, a stunning beachside house and the largest hospital to be built in Queensland in 20 years are the big winners in the 2017 Master Builders regional housing and construction awards.
The striking Sunrise Beach home of exceptional standard and style by Kern- ohan Construction has taken out the 2017 Master Builders Sunshine Coast House of the Year.
The $1.8 billion Sunshine Coast University Hospital by the Exemplar Health consor- tium has won 2017 Sunshine Coast Project of the Year.
The awards, held at Lake Kawana Community Centre last night, recognise the talent on offer in the region.
Master Builders' CEO Grant Galvin commended Sunshine Coast builders on 30 years of awards, noting they were highly sought- after by the state's top builders and tradespeople.
"The standard we have seen this year is incredible,'' he said, "and demonstrates the impeccable talent and expertise of our industry."
Designed by Aboda Design Group and with furnishings by Zooi, the Sunrise Beach house also took out Best Residential Swimming Pool and Individual Home $1.26m-$2m.
The 2017 President's Award went to PJ Burns for a Hamptons-style house that won Individual Home $251,000-$350,000.
The Commercial Trade Contractor award went to Regson Fabrications for their work on the Sunshine Coast University Hospital.
The hospital, the biggest project seen on the Sunshine Coast, completed by Exemplar Health consortium used cutting-edge design and building techniques to deliver the best health facilities available.
In a great test of thought, planning, collaboration and quality control, the consortium comprising Lendlease, Siemens and Capella Capital, with partners Spotless Facil- ities Services, has provided the community with the latest in facilities and technology.
Live modelling allowed the latest innovations to be included in the build. Every- thing had to be thought through and tested so services would be ready on opening day.
Design changes, modifications and the rapid advances in technology meant everyone had to keep ahead of the build.
The new tertiary facility was delivered through a public private partnership  contract to design, build, finance and maintain the hospital for 25 years.
The SCUH project comp- rises 150,000sqm main hosp- ital building, the Sunshine Coast Health Institute and Mental Health Facility.
There are 3500 car parks including two multi-level above-ground car parks, a 100-place child day-care facil- ity, retail facilities and park- lands on the 19.5ha site -the same footprint as Brisbane CBD. Supporting infrastruc- ture such as roads and utilities were also included in the project.
Although it was one devel- opment, all teams involved had their own programs, which needed a massive co-ordination effort. In addition, everyone had to be pro-active on work place health and safety.
The communication pro- cess  required planning of the work sites that included 1800 workers, as well as the co-ordination of stake- holders.
The Sunrise Beach house sits in the eastern side of a steep sand dune.
Elevated above David Low Way and with 180-degree views of the ocean, it is built over two levels carved three metres into the edge of the dune. It features a suspended infinity-edge swimming pool to make the most of the coastal outlook.
Builder Darren Kernohan loved the collaboration on the project that was instrumental in such a stunning outcome.
Particular challenges in the construction were to contain the 500sqm  volume of the home on a tapering 752sqm site while protecting and maximising the finished floor levels to capture the views, especially across the swimming pool. This was done while retain- ing the coastal and native vegetation and remaining under the eight-metre height limit.
The lower level offers four bedrooms, bathroom, kitchenette and snug. By suspending the concrete pool on block blade walls, all spaces enjoy a view of the beach.
The upper floor features a main bedroom suite with dramatic views right up to the dune on Sunrise Beach and the ocean beyond. A home office has been com- bined behind the bedroom.
Again, the ocean views dominate and have been enhanced by clever, thought- ful design and skilful execution.
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
Hopes children of 2067 will enjoy the same natural attractions
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Individual Home $1.26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regson Fabrications</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President's Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunrise Beach</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commercial Trade Contractor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siemens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mental Health Facility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboda Design Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Project of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Facil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Individual Home $251,000-$350,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Residential Swimming Pool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builders' CEO Grant Galvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Low Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Kernohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builders Sunshine Coast House of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamptons-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exemplar Health</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Kawana Community Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PJ Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lendlease</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capella Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zooi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Health Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
