<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428016538902169</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/my-noosa-love-affair-since-1976/3207570/</url>
  <title>My Noosa love affair since 1976</title>
  <content>
MY WIFE Gail and I first came to Noosa in 1976 and driving over the hill after 24 hours with kids in the back, past the Reef Hotel and looking at Laguna Bay for the first time, we were absolutely gobsmacked.
We ended up putting up two little tents in Thatchers Caravan Park, on the corner of Noosa Pde and Hastings St.
The next morning, surfboard in hand, walking around to Tea-Tree with the kids, we spotted some beautiful waves in one of the most beautiful places in the world.
We were visiting our friends, Peter and Christine Dowling.
Peter had opened a real estate office in Hasting St in 1976. I was in residential real estate in Melbourne.
We both loved the surf and had a lot in common, holidaying and surfing at Torquay.
We kept coming for a few years and I can still remember walking Hasting St with the concrete brick paving, sand between the toes and going to Dooley's restaurant next to the Noosa Woods Caravan Park.
Peter offered me a position as a real estate salesperson, so in February 1981, Gail and I migrated up. She drove the old Peugeot with trailer, the two small children in the back, the air-conditioner thumping away while I was in the old Valiant with the dog and another trailer.
Reaching Toowoomba suddenly there was flash flooding around Esk so after doubling back via Brisbane we finally arrive at our rented sight unseen, old Queenslander in Tewantin.
I thought I'd retire for a few weeks to surf everyday but I was bored after about a week and knocked on Peter's door and started work.
In those days, we didn't have a coffee machine and I didn't have a desk or a listing book and I thought "it's fairly hard to get going in these circumstances"., so I would go down to Harvest Foods for morning coffee and a Betty's Burger for lunch. Being optimistic, I was determined to make a success of things. I ended up taking the old listing books home every night, writing the listing sheets out by hand and ringing the owners the next day. In 30 days, I knew a lot about the listings and the owners' motivation. From that point on, I could turn things around, working under Peter's business umbrella.
In late 1981 there was just an absolute sales drought. Standing in front of the office one day, I noticed a blue Cadillac and caravan drive down Hasting St. "These people have obviously got money" I thought as they parked the caravan at the Noosa Woods caravan park.
I had nothing to lose so I knocked on their door the next day and after about a week and 20 cups of tea and lots of biscuits we ended up driving around, looking at real estate and I sold them a vacant block in Moorindil St, Tewantin, where they have lived happily ever since. Unfortunately he is now deceased but she still waves every time she passes the office.
That sale really broke the drought.
In those days, I'd go down to Harvest Foods for morning coffee and a Betty's Burger for lunch. I'd check the surf from Tingarana Arcade and at 4pm hop in the old car with board in back and call into Noosa Kitchen, which was a milk bar next to the surf club.
David Allen the developer of the First Point units asked me to call in to discuss the marketing of his oceanfront townhouse. He knew what I was up to, so suggested I call in after my surf.
Running around to Tea-Tree and surfing some of the best uncrowded waves, I was walking back, looked up and saw a koala as the sun was going down on the north shore and the bay was a shimmering red. By the time I reached National's carpark I was smelling the sausages and onions being barbecued and five minutes later was talking to David, drink in hand sitting in what was and still is one of Australia's signature waterfront properties. There would not have been a day similar anywhere in the world.
In December 1986, Gail and I bought established real estate business Walker & Co, on Noosa-Cooroy Rd, where the Golden Breed Surf shop is today. We borrowed all of the money to buy the business, which was really run down from a sales point of view although the rent roll of holiday properties had potential.We had a ledger machine, two-line incoming switchboard and not a computer, fax machine or mobile phone in sight.
We'd lost most of our accounting system and information on the landlords and it was almost the start of the Christmas holidays. We had 60 holiday properties which we were going to be managing and people were coming from all over Australia to holiday in them.
About December 17, the office was broken into and ransacked. They stole the fire-proof safe with all our ledger cards. We had 60 holiday properties which we were going to be managing and people were coming from all over Australia to holiday in them. So we had no idea where we were starting, who was arriving and whether they had paid. It certainly wasn't a good start.
An old bloke rang in the afternoon and he said he'd seen this safe at the back of his paddock in Tewantin, with brown ledger cards blowing all over the place. So I went over and picked them up in the old Valiant and bought them back.
As I sorted them I realised we finally had a handle on the business.
We were under the Christmas pressure as Gail and I really didn't know where we were going. Soon after a woman knocked on the door and said she had all the computer skills to operate a rent roll and stayed with us for about 20 years as our initial holiday property manager and accountant.
In the first few months I received a call from a Melbourne solicitor wanting to market Lion Head - a small beachfront acreage in Seaview Tce which I had sold him the year before. His wife didn't like it being oceanfront next to the national park and believed there was just too much land. We took it to market and the auctioneer did his stuff, selling to a local couple for a record price of $680,000 in 1987.
It sold for $5.4 million in 2013 and there's a magnificent home currently being built on it.
We ended up employing 25 staff and in 1987, I bought another office in Tewantin. We used to sell 20 properties a month and it was just a terrific office back in late 1980s and '90s and right through up until the time I sold eight years ago.
It's now the Laguna Tewantin Real Estate office where I work and once again it's a market leader.
A commercial operator knocked on the door of the Noosa office 15 years ago, wanting to purchase the business. The sale was just at the right time and I thought I would retire over to the Tewantin office. But I never ended up retiring and consequently at 70 years of age, I'm still working and loving the environment and the work. I treasure the relationships forged with people over the years and the negotiations of the listing and selling processes.
I had the fortunate situation of selling properties on Sunshine Beach and Noosa Sound showing some capital growth from the early 1980s up until recently for some of the properties, compounding at 17% per annum, showing capital appreciation of $1000/day from the early 1980s to around 2007. So it's been fantastic growth.
I can remember dealing with the local developers and saying you have got to move across the bridge into the Noosaville area. We started selling, through Peter Dowling's office, Hideaway Island which was really the third stage to Noosa Sound. We had a little portable office and planted a few trees which are still on the corner of Dolphin Dr and Noosa Pde. I was the first person on duty and we had the brochures and everything ready to sell.
A couple pulled in at 8.30am Sunday in a cloud of dust and said "We would like to buy a block. Don't worry about trying to sell the island to us and all the advantages of living there, we want this particular block." He got out of the car and said "this is the one where we fish from" then they had this little ding-dong as they couldn't make up their minds which block it was. They ended up buying the one and I think, from memory, they paid about $85,000. It's been sold several times since and there is a magnificent home recently been built across two blocks after removing the original home.
Many are saying it is just getting too busy. There is too much traffic. The river is not as good as it used to be fishing-wise. I just say you just have to get out and about and enjoy Noosa for what it is.       
I particularly love surfing and enjoy the early morning sun rises from First Point, the river mouth, and Tea-Tree Bay especially as it is just so beautiful in the mornings and those sunsets are in many cases the best. Noosa National Park is one of our most used and loved national parks in Australia, along with the Noosa River with its natural vegetation, pathways and boat sheds - also just absolutely magnificent.
The walks down Hastings St, buying an ice cream, going to a restaurant, the surf club looking over Laguna Bay and just utilising the benefits and the advantages of our well provided infrastructure of what we've got here is just magnificent. You don't need to be a millionaire.
The spread of the development that has come right along the river, it's taken years for it to move in this direction, people love it for what it is.
The introduction of the River Light Ferry has brought a new wave of people that would not have come to the Tewantin area and wouldn't have driven this far. Many from Hastings St have hopped on the ferry and plied their way along past the yacht and rowing club ending up at Harbour Town, buying a glass of wine and then gone for a walk along our main street and looking in real estate agents' windows. There are many that just basically fall in love with Tewantin because of their initial trip on that ferry.
They have invested wisely, retired here and their children are now coming and buying real estate from me, which is just terrific to see.
It's amazing to look out the window and see people walking past the office who I've sold property to back in the early '80s.
They have all aged and some are on motorised scooters and walking frames, but they all still loving it here.
I am very optimistic about the future of the area, especially with the infrastructure that we have. Our council have so much empathy with the area, the environment, the people and the tourist industry that is very vibrant.
Noosa is one of the greatest tourist, living and lifestyle destinations in the world. Those who do their world trips always come back saying "There's no place like home and we really haven't found a place as good".
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dolphin Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laguna Tewantin Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dowling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peugeot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastings St</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laguna Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Kitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty's Burgers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tingarana Arcade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Dowling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Breed Surf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 1981</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa-Cooroy Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Pde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cadillac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harbour Town</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hideaway Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thatchers Caravan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIFE Gail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dooley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torquay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorindil St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Light Ferry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1986</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Woods Caravan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tea-Tree</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tea-Tree Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Sound</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seaview Tce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvest Foods</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
