<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428038013739009</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sc2067-mayors-50-year-vision-for-the-sunshine-coas/3208974/</url>
  <title>SC2067: Mayor's 50-year vision for the Sunshine Coast</title>
  <content>
ABOLITION of state governments, creation of super shires and a network of transportation tunnels are some of the massive changes Sunshine Coast Mayor Mark Jamieson envisages 50 years from now.

"We will only have two levels of government," Cr Jamieson said.

"I think we will have national government and then we will have major regional governments.

"We are going to be a vastly different place."

He predicted if not all, at least part of Moreton Bay as well as the Sunshine Coast, Noosa, Gympie, Fraser Coast, North Burnett, South Burnett and Somerset regions would be cast as a regional government.

"There will still be very important local priorities around waste, around water management, around important community facilities.

"But I think beyond that we need to be focused on 'how do we cut the cost of government, without limiting the services and indeed enhancing the services'.

"The opportunities around economic development, enhanced infrastructure... we would position ourselves at that point as a population well in excess of two million people."

from  on .

Cr Jamieson referenced Australia's first people when explaining why he thought it a good idea.

"The Jinibara, the Kabi Kabi and the Butchulla largely lived within that area.

"Add to that the Waka Waka and the Goreng Goreng and you are pretty much covering an area that our original inhabits saw as a natural area to be in."

But he wasn't sure how the new super shire would be governed.

"That's where there is a lot more thought needs to go into it.

"How those regions then collaborate, particularly in State of Origin time, would be pretty important.

"I think that will still be important to us."

He was confident Noosa, the shire that in 2013 broke free from the Sunshine Coast just five years after amalgamation, would be a part of the major regional government.

"In the end I think you'll want communities to recognise that there is going to be major change in federation- 'we have got to participate or get left behind'.

"I think people also need to recognise that if you're planning for a much bigger area, you have got a lot more options."

Cr Jamieson said taking on huge tracts of agricultural land as well as a port at Bundaberg would be incredibly important.

He said there would be mining opportunities in the Burnett regions as well as more coastline and Fraser Island to manage.

"It'd be fair to say that Sunshine Coast is probably further advanced but we'd just keep moving that advancement north in appropriate ways."

He wondered how much better a regional government would be if taxation was split 70-30 between it and the national government, rather than the three per cent local governments currently received.

"How much more of that decision making could be made at regional levels about what was important to them?

"They are quite far-reaching changes and many people would say 'why change, we have got a great place and we'll just keep rolling along'.

"That's a fair comment, a fair opinion.

"My sense is that, if you look at history, we as a race, as a species, want to continue to progress."

He said people were always looking for easier, faster and more productive ways to do things.

"People are driven by a whole range of motives and that isn't going to change.

"My sense is, even though we think things are just perfect, we've got to be ready for change and be prepared to embrace that."

LIFESTYLE

Cr Jamieson said automation would have a major impact on the way society and communities operated.

"I think if we are going to be fair dinkum about what we will look like in 50 years, we have probably got to go back 150 years because the pace of change in that last 150 years has been pretty steady by comparison with what we have seen in the last 10 and what we will see certainly in the next 50."

He said the kitchen was the focus of households in generations past.

"Everybody had a kitchen with a kitchen table where you sat and ate your meals.

"Well that has changed dramatically."

He said he could see a point in the future where apartments didn't have kitchens.

"People will live there and they will just go downstairs and eat at any number of different opportunities, whether they are focused on breakfast, lunch or dinner.

"That will be people's socialisation outside of the workplace."

He expected work habits would also change.

"The way in which society is sliced and diced and the automation of the workforce may well see a very wealthy society where the wealth is perhaps owned by fewer people.

"But because of the way government manages the taxation system, there are structures put in place that enable those people to be more focused on their community; more focused on environmental work; more focused on their own wellbeing; more focused on a sense of enlightenment, if you like, from an artistic perspective.

"In China, of a century ago, that was very much how a lot of people lived.

"They didn't actually work, they were more focused on personal fulfilment- and that means a lot of different things to a lot of different people."

Cr Jamieson expected health and food would also change.

"Will we see science providing demonstrated opportunities where food production and the way in which it's processed creates healthier outcomes? I suspect we will.

"Technology will help people monitor their own well-being far more easily.

"You won't need to go and see a doctor necessarily.

"You will be able to check your vital signs by, who knows, some computer chip that may be inserted into your body."

COMMUNICATION

A submarine broadband cable connecting the Sunshine Coast with the rest of the world is a major feature of Cr Jamieson's future predictions.

"It is a piece of kit that is relatively inexpensive but is as rare as hen's teeth in terms of the eastern seaboard of Australia.

"Here we are saying we can be a communications hub and that will spin-off a whole range of industry that will create opportunities for people into the future.

He was very confident it wouldn't take 50 years to have the international link.

"I struggle to understand why it has taken as long as it has now."

He said the region's hospitals and universities could be connected to the best in Asia and United States.

"It is hard to imagine, but I think it is important we largely embrace the future and where those opportunities exist."

He said rejection of change could limit the region's ability to achieve communication milestones.

"People are very focused on nostalgia and there is something in that, don't get me wrong.

"We've got a rich history, certainly from our original inhabitants.

"It's a very exciting time to be anticipating what is coming next."

DEVELOPMENT and TRANSPORT

"In 50 years, the Sunshine Coast itself could be in excess of a million people," Cr Jamieson said.

"In that regional sense, it could be two and a half million people.

"We just can't allow sprawl to accommodate those people because we are going to impact those important agricultural areas where we need to be growing food.

"The cost of providing infrastructure around roads, water, sewage, police, ambulance, fire, all of those things, are just incredibly expensive."

He said that would bring a "very real" debate about higher-density living.

"It will come faster than people think."

"As the Premier said when she assisted in turning the sod on the new city in Maroochydore, we won't get a more effective public transport system until we've got a level of density that can support it.

"So a duplicated rail network to Nambour, which we need now, logically it would be all the way to Bundaberg by then."

He said there would also be a complete public transport network of light rail and buses serving the Sunshine Coast and other points north.

"That would certainly make it easier for people to get around."

Cr Jamieson said dealing with some of the existing legacies of Coast transport would be challenging.

"It is going to be bloody hard to widen the Nicklin Way to eight lanes.

"Hard and expensive."

He said an underground approach could alleviate congested areas.

"What about a tunnel straight underneath Buderim?

"What about a tunnel underneath the Bluff?

"What about a tunnel that consumes part of Caloundra Rd?

"They're the sorts of things we need to consider and as we increase density and not sprawl, they will become even more important."

ENVIRONMENT

There could be a lot more solar farms in Cr Jamieson's 50-year future like the one the council has built at Valdora.

"In appropriate locations," Cr Jamieson said.

"We have got a lot of floodplain, we have got a lot of sunshine, why wouldn't we want to use that in as a productive of a way as we possibly can?"

He said they could be privately owned.

"They may well be owned by citizens who can see an opportunity to invest their own private money into a solar farm because they believe in renewable energy, but because they also believe that they can long term make savings from it and enjoy the dividends that come from that."

He said the Coast needed to deal with issues like climate change.

"If we look after our environment, unlike everything else in the world, it will be like it is today in 50 year's time.

He said the need for investment in development could not be ignored.

"One of the greatest challenges we as a council have got at the moment is working with our neighbours in Moreton Bay to convince the State Government that there should be legislation that protects the inter-urban break.

He said the 690-hectare tract of land that ran between Bribie Island and the Pumicestone Passage to the Glass House Mountains could prove to be a tourism attraction.

"Into the future, I can only imagine the potential around authentic, Indigenous experience for international tourists coming here and wanting to see the oldest civilisation in the world in action.

"In the shadows of the Glass House Mountains talking about Dream Time, culture, art, bush tucker.

"What an opportunity for our Indigenous residents and what an opportunity for internationals to come and enjoy that."

He said the Glass House Mountains would not change in 50 years.

"But we want people to have so much more enjoyment."

HOTEL DEVELOPMENT

Cr Jamieson believes Sekisui House will have realised hotel plans at its Yaroomba site by the time 2067 arrives.

"It's hard to imagine not- without identifying what the form of that might be," Cr Jamieson said.

He said he could only think of two parcels of beach front land on the Coast available for development.

"One is the land at Yaroomba and the other is land at Bokarina, which currently has development starting.

"That isn't going to change.

He said the Coast would need six new international hotels in six year's time.

"In 50 year's time, gee, that might be 50 hotels- if people are still using hotels as the means for accommodation.

"I think they will and I think they will be very focused around high-end branded hotels that they have a real relationship or brand hotels generally that they have a relationship with.

"That might be at a three-star level, a four-star level or a seven-star level but that's the sort of appeal we want to have.

"There are currently tourism markets that we don't enjoy the patronage of because we don't have the facilities they demand.

He didn't think having those facilities would change Coast residents' lifestyles.

"We can't lose sight of what drives human nature to go and do the things they do.

"There'd be a lot of people who have not come to the Sunshine Coast in the past for a holiday because they couldn't get a Qantas flight, because they are a Qantas club member,

"We don't have the sort of hotel, high-end hotel option they were after and there may be a range of other things that they would expect.

"You could say the same for the other end, that we don't have enough backpacker-type accommodation or enough three-start hotels for business accommodation, so people would come here and do business and stay in those sort of properties.

"That is what we are going to need to have."

ARTS and CULTURE

"This is an area we have not been strong in," Cr Jamieson said.

However, he said that could be changed with the digital revolution.

He wondered what the world's best digital art gallery would look like.

"Why couldn't we have that here- because we have got the cable.

"So we can do a whole lot of things that other people can't do."

COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

Cr Jamieson acknowledged the rapid growth of the Coast didn't encourage involvement in community organisations.

"There is only one reason why people leave the Sunshine Coast- they can't get a job," Cr Jamieson said.

"That's been its drawback forever.

"We are changing that.

He said work being done to create jobs was bringing more people to the region.

"That transience doesn't encourage people to get involved in the communities so we have got to make it stickier for them to want to be involved.

"That's why transitioning the economy is so important.

"We just can't rely in the future on tourism, construction and retail.

"Health, medical and well-being, aviation and aerospace, education and research, agribusiness, the clean-tech sector, knowledge industries and professional services, that's really where our focus is.

Cr Jamieson said those jobs would reduce the need for Sunshine Coast residents to commute to Brisbane or work in a fly-in, fly-out capacity.

"If their job opportunity was here, how could we convince them that the hour a day they were saving , or maybe four hours a day they were saving, could be reinvested in the community?

"Maybe it's Neighbourhood Watch, maybe it's a chamber of commerce, maybe its getting involved in an artistic group.

"I think that's part of it."

He said it could be a part of a changing work and life balance.

"We are pushing people to the limit and we will start to need to see a regression of that.

"I think that will come from advanced technology and then people will think 'oh, I've got a bit more time on my hands- I will involve myself in something'."

IN SUMMATION

"I've probably taken a more futuristic view and tried to think 'well, 50 years of massive change... and how could we have something that was actually much, much better.

"Or at least somewhere between much, much better or no worse than we've got now.

"I think the reality is, as levels of government, we've got to find ways to enliven our community about 'what are the steps we take to be better, or indeed, much, much better'.

"People just don't want more of the same."

Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glass House Mountains</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundaberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kabi Kabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicklin Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waka Waka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bribie Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sekisui House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC2067</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Mayor Mark Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neighbourhood Watch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOTEL DEVELOPMENT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dream Time</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Burnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jinibara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jamieson</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goreng Goreng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pumicestone Passage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butchulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somerset</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valdora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Burnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bokarina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
