<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427818970403525</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/movies/robert-pattinson-asked-to-perform-sex-act-on-dog-for-new-movie-good-time/news-story/621c937bf7eb1daa5109598b88e106ef</url>
  <title>Pattinson told to do rude thing to dog</title>
  <content>
MOVIE star Robert Pattinson gave new meaning to faking it on the set of his new film, Good Time.
During an appearance on US talk show Jimmy Kimmel Live on Thursday the 31-year-old actor recalled an experience involving his canine co-star, in which he was instructed to get up close and perhaps too personal with his furry friend,
"Oh God, I don't know if I can say this," Pattinson began. "There's a lot of things in this movie which really cross the line of reality. It's not even on the line, it's way beyond the line. There was initially this scene - I don't think I should say this - but it's like, my character, Connie, has this affinity with dogs. He thinks he is a dog in a previous life and he thinks he has control over animals and stuff."
The star of the Twilight franchise continued to giggle through his explanation of a particular scene, which ultimately landed on the cutting room floor.
Robert Pattinson Reveals Crazy Story from New Movie Good Time

"There's this one scene, which we shot, which basically, there's a drug dealer who busts into the room and I was sleeping with the dog and basically giving the dog a h**d job," Pattinson revealed.
Though Pattinson also said it was "a character thing," he approached the trainer in preparation for the take.
"I asked the trainer, 'cause the director was like, 'Just do it for real, man! Don't be a p***y!' And then the dog's owner was like, 'Well, he's a breeder, I mean, you can.' He's like, 'You gotta massage the inside of his thighs.'"
Pattinson decided not to go through with it.
"I didn't agree to do the real one, we made a fake red rocket," he said. "It was fun. It'll be on the DVD extras."
This story was originally published in the and is reproduced here with their permission
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Movie Good Time</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Pattinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Pattinson Reveals Crazy Story</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Kimmel Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pattinson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
