<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427999359032620</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/united-petroleums-second-store-opening-could-mark-dawn-of-a-new-era-for-cairns-motorists/news-story/9706e21611aa9233f7bf80b15c544323</url>
  <title>New outlet throws out challenge on pricing</title>
  <content>
A COLOSSAL fuel price shake-up could rattle the Far North market and spark a fresh era for fed-up motorists when a new retailer releases its bowsers in Cairns North today.
Independent Australian retailer United Petroleum has drawn the battle lines and committed to putting an end to exorbitant fuel prices in the region with the opening of their second store on Sheridan St.
The State Government and RACQ have thrown their support behind the new site, saying it should "spook rival servos" into driving down prices to realistic market levels.
It comes after an Australian Competition and Consumer Commission report found service stations have been ripping off Cairns' motorists for years.
About 1500 vehicles have been filling up at United's Woree site daily since it started selling unleaded fuel at 126.9 cpl two weeks ago.
United Petroleum marketing manager Andrew English said the company had set a new benchmark for fuel prices in Cairns.
"If competitors do move we will make sure we have the best priced fuel in town. That is how competitive environments should work," he said.
"Eventually they will have to move or they will go out of business."
United's emergence is on the back of an ACCC report that found since 2012-13, prices in Cairns have been about 11 cents per litre more than in Australia's five largest cities.
In the past two weeks major retailers in Cairns have sold unleaded fuel at 137.9 cpl. The city's petrol stations have been making 38 per cent more profit on fuel sales than the average across Australia because of the lack of competition.
The United Sheridan St site, which the company has identified as its "flagship store", has replaced the BP on the southbound side of the road.
Prices are expected to be listed at 109.9 cpl for unleaded and 108.9 cpl for diesel for two weeks. A similar offer drew about 2000 cars through the Woree site daily for two weeks.
Mr English said trade "exceeded expectations". "We knew the people in Cairns had been doing it hard for a long time and paying exorbitant prices for fuel, but we have been a bit overwhelmed with the response," he said.
Queensland Treasurer Curtis Pitt will officially open the store at 11am today. He urged motorists to reward the company for a "bold business strategy" that successfully disrupted the market in other areas.
"Locals know the market has failed and we have been paying far too much for far too long," he said.
"I think there's real potential that this kind of market disruption will bring down the benchmark price in Cairns, just as we've seen United Petroleum successfully drive down prices in other markets around the country."
RACQ spokeswoman Renee Smith said Cairns motorists should send a strong message to major retailers who were "overcharging and have been for far too long".
"We need to vote with our wheels and wallets and let the expensive service stations around town know that they will need to drop their prices if they want our business," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Petroleum</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United's Woree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheridan St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Sheridan St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Treasurer Curtis Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
