<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428012243934729</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/adcock-booting-bombers-in-right-direction-as-final/3208896/</url>
  <title>Adcock booting Bombers in right direction as finals loom</title>
  <content>
WHEN it comes to the best new signing in the Ipswich A Grade competition look no further than Fassifern five-eighth Aaron Adcock.
Adcock has just broken through the 200 points barrier for the Bombers, already stamping his authority in his first year.
The silky skilled five-eighth has a rugby union background as a fly-half, and you can tell.
Adcock has the passing skills of a union number 10 and is also a goal kicker, and a good one too.
Like all successful rugby union kickers he has a crisp and balanced strike of the ball and doesn't miss many.
He already has a large lead in the top point-scoring stakes in the competition with 204 points from 15 games, including seven tries and 88 goals.
With Adcock being a country lad at heart, it is no surprise he is enjoying his first year at Fassifern with the competition leaders.
"I grew up in Charleville and went to boarding school at Ipswich Grammar and played rugby union there," he said.
"I played a bit of league on the side for Norths in the 16s, rugby union for the First XV (at Grammar) and then union for Souths in the Brisbane comp' in colts.
"I had two years there and then had a couple of years off.
"This season with Fassifern is my first year back playing footy in a couple of years.
"It is awesome.
"They are a good bunch of boys and a good group of country people. Everyone is friendly and easy to get on with."
Adcock has been working for former Ipswich Jets captain and club legend Steve Parcell at Mutdapilly.
"One of the Fassifern boys, Mick Hayes, got me to come to a Fassifern training session,'' Adcock said.
"I was going to play one trial initially and go from there, but I hung around and I love it now."
The brilliant players he is surrounded by make Adcock's job easier.
On his side of the field is robust centre Marika Kuriyalavou. On the other side is lightning fast Leveni Kurimalawai.
"Either way we go we've got weapons either side of the field," Adcock said.
"Having big David Fa'alogo on one side is great and having either one of Aleki (Falepaini) or Adam (Korave) on my edge is good too.
"I can sit back and play off the back of them. It is pretty easy. It is one of the best forward packs, and certainly best teams, I have played with.''
Adcock was humble when asked about his extraordinary goal kicking record.
"I don't get too many tough ones in games because the boys are always scoring long range tries and putting it down under the posts," he grinned. "They look after me."
Coach Daniel Roos said Adcock was an integral part of the side. "He kicks goals at around 80 per cent most games and even higher sometimes so he is really handy to have," Roos said.
"Aaron is really easy to get on with, he listens and always tries his hardest.
"He is a really good communicator on the field and he takes his opportunities when they are there for him to run."
The Bombers host Eastern Cobras at Harrisville on Sunday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charleville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrisville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leveni Kurimalawai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aleki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Grammar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Adcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fassifern</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Cobras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First XV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adcock</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mutdapilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marika Kuriyalavou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Fa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich A Grade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falepaini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Parcell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
