<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427256329677997</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/world/sessions-vows-crackdown-on-culture-of-leaks-in-washington/news-story/57f94cd5ab3d726dd36c6d2542a27718</url>
  <title>Sessions vows crackdown on leaks</title>
  <content>
Attorney-General Jeff Sessions has vowed to come down hard on government employees who leak classified information to the press - saying that "this nation must end this culture of leaks."
"We will not allow rogue anonymous sources with security clearance to sell out our country," Sessions said at a news conference at the Department of Justice, promising to hunt down leaders and then throw the book at them.
President Trump has been enraged by the continual leaks coming out of the White House and intelligence community, and complained on Twitter last week that his Attorney-General was "weak" when it came to going after leaders,
Sessions said that the FBI had beefed up staff devoted to investigating leaks, and that those caught in his crackdown would be prosecuted to the full extent of the law.
"We are taking a stand, this leaking must stop," he said.
Sessions said that Justice has launched more investigations into leaks in the past six months than during the preceding three years.
Without citing any specific examples, he said, "leaks are incredibly damaging. Leaks hurt our country."
He also said that the press must balance the public's right to know with national security concerns, but wouldn't answer when a reporter asked later if that meant journalists would be prosecuted.
The Attorney-General said four people are already being prosecuted to allegedly leaking, though he did not provide any details.
Team Trump has been stung repeatedly by a series of embarrassing leaks, including that first son Donald Trump Jr. and son-in-law Jared Kushner had met with a Kremlin-linked Russian lawyer who wanted to dish dirt on Hillary Clinton.
The most recent leak came this week when The Washington Post printed transcripts of contentious phone calls Trump had with Mexico's president and Australia's prime minister.
Also on Friday, a presidential adviser raised the possibility of lie detector tests for the small number of people in the West Wing and elsewhere with access to the transcripts of Trump's phone calls.
Trump counsellor Kellyanne Conway told "Fox & Friends" that "it's easier to figure out who's leaking than the leaders may realise."
Asked if lie detectors might be used, she answered, "Well, they may, they may not."
A recent book, "Devil's Bargain," about the rise of Trump adviser Steve Bannon, pointed the finger at Conway herself as an insider who had repeatedly leaked to the press during Trump's campaign.
This article was
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devil's Bargain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellyanne Conway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General Jeff Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin-linked Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
