<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428007948967421</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/how-to-nail-that-job-interview/3208880/</url>
  <title>How to nail that job interview</title>
  <content>
YOU'VE applied for the job and you've been called in for an interview - congratulations.

They are obviously impressed with your experience and skills and now it's time to back it up with a stellar interview performance.

Here are some ways you will smash it and impress your interviewers.

Get a good night's sleep: This might seem obvious, but nerves definitely can keep us awake all night. You do not want to turn up tired and yawn throughout the interview.

Plus you want to be on your A-game when answering questions, and tiredness can interfere with that.

Be well presented: Find out what the company's dress code is before going to your interview. Although you want to match the recommended attire of the company, if in doubt, go more formal than casual.

Don't forget to take a shower, wear deodorant, but skip the strong perfume or cologne. If you wear make-up, keep it natural.

Practise your handshake: A good handshake is firm, but not too strong. Try and match the person whose hand you are shaking as a good guide. Make sure your nails are clean and tidy.

Be punctual: Aim to arrive at least 15 minutes before your interview time.

If you are driving, know exactly where you can park your car, or if you are taking public transport, know how long it takes from the station/stop to where you will be interviewed.

Being a little early gives a good impression and shows that you respect your interviewer's time.

Research the company: You need to know a little about the company before you go in for an interview. Having no idea about what the company does shows a lack of interest and initiative.

A quick read of the company's website, a Google search and social media search is easy to do.

Be prepared: Before the interview, review the job outline and identify any areas where your skills may be weaker.

This will give you the opportunity to plan how to answer any tricky questions and turn your weaknesses around into strengths. It is so important to know your resume/CV back to front.

Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
