<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428003653999981</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/passion-for-bath-and-body-products-grows-from-nece/3207935/</url>
  <title>Passion for bath and body products grows from necessity</title>
  <content>
WHAT started out as a medical necessity has become a passion for Terry and Melek Fahey. They have turned their range of soaps into a fully fledged business to help others.
With a daughter suffering from eczema and nothing on the market that appeared to help, Terry and Melek took it into their own hands to create a good, natural, chemical-free product.
"We could only find things that were harsh on the skin long-term," Melek said.
"They were masking the problem and not fixing it."
Through extensive research and years of trial and error, they finally created a product using coconut milk and goats milk, as they are both nourishing, moisturising and soothing for the skin.
The Faheys soon had soap overflowing their home, so they decided to trial the product at market stalls, leading to the birth of their business Oska and Willow - Artisan Bath and Body.
Now with a full studio at their home, they are regulars at markets around the region and soon able to supply direct to customers online. The couple soon realised customers wanted more natural product lines, so they expanded their range, introducing their body and bath products which included hand and body wash, lip balms, bath bombs, bath milks, essential oil room sprays and organic hand-rolled beeswax candles.
Now a new range released shortly will consist of body lotions, coffee body scrubs and even their own range of organic perfumes.
Terry and Melek use the traditional cold-process method to create their soap, colouring each batch individually to match the fragrance, ensuring that each bar is unique.
"After five years, I realised it didn't have to look boring, it could be pretty, too, so I used it as my form of art," Melek said. "I love it. I will smell a fragrance and the design will come to me."
Oska and Willow is a business that tries to use as many locally sourced products as possible, allowing Terry and Melek to give back to the community.
"It highlights what's available in our region," Melek said. "We are supporting the community and other companies - keeping each other strong."
Their ultimate goal is to open their own shopfront within the Sunshine Coast, allowing them to consistently engage with customers throughout the week, creating a more personalised experience. To view their full range, find them at the Cotton Tree Markets, The Original Eumundi Markets and soon at Caloundra Street Fair and www.oskaandwillow.com
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Artisan Bath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Original Eumundi Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willows</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Street Fair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oska</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
