<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428025128836941</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/internet-has-changed-the-real-estate-game/3207582/</url>
  <title>Internet has changed the real estate game</title>
  <content>
IT'S interesting for someone like me who was born and raised here, to be celebrating the 50th anniversary of the naming of the Sunshine Coast.
I've only ever known it to be called the Sunshine Coast or the Sunny Coast, as many now affectionately refer to it.
I began my real estate career in 2000, on the cusp of the new millennium, and over these past 17 years, have witnessed some significant changes to the property landscape.
I have been fortunate to have worked through some very buoyant years during this time - the Global Financial Crisis being the most challenging period - but all in all the health of the Sunshine Coast property market has been glowing.
One of the biggest changes in this time has been the prominence of online marketing, which has really transformed the way we sell and has increased the "reach" of the marketing message to a global audience.
Other changes in technology, such as text messaging, social media, electronic newsletters and increasingly sophisticated databases have made it so much easier for agents to communicate quickly, easily and effectively.
What hasn't changed is the thirst and demand for quality customer service; this is often the key point of difference between a successful agency and a mediocre one.
The smart operators dedicate and drive their business with a customer service philosophy/orientation, as opposed to a transaction-based one. If you deliver the best service with the right intentions, the transactions will follow.
The way we live is changing. As an increasing number of people are enjoying longer, healthier lives, downsizing is a huge trend, especially in "lifestyle" regions such as the Sunshine Coast.
Empty-nesters and Baby Boomers are relocating here, attracted to the climate and laid-back lifestyle, while appreciating our close proximity to Brisbane.
Along with downsizing, people are also looking for low- maintenance living. House block sizes are generally getting smaller, partly due to land shortage but also a lifestyle-driven phenomenon where busy working families want quality leisure time on weekends and are no longer seeking big yards that require ongoing maintenance.
Waterfront properties are still always in high demand and attract strong capital gain while properties within walking distance to the beach are also ever-popular.
School catchment zones and access to other amenities also continue to drive people's decision-making when buying.
With the massive public and private infrastructure investment across the region, the Sunshine Coast is booming and last year was Queensland's best performing market.
There is a lot of confidence in this region, which is driving huge levels of investment. This is then creating employment opportunities which, in turn, creates increased demand for housing.
It's an exciting time to live and invest here.
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
FAMILY holiday was catalyst for a change of scenery and lifestyle.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Financial Crisis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baby Boomers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunny Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Internet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
