<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428231287269721</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:05</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/slack-ceo-stewart-butterfield-fan-universal-basic-income-2017-8</url>
  <title>It's not just Zuckerberg  --  Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield is a big fan of universal basic income</title>
  <content>
Booming tech salaries and the resulting wage gap have put the greater San Francisco area at the  about income inequality in the United States. It's even become a central issue for a certain not-running-for-president billionaire, Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg.

In particular, Zuckerberg is an  for a universal basic income, which would guarantee all citizens a monthly stipend to cover basic expenses like food and rent. 

Advocates say the system is one of the surest ways to lift people from existing poverty, and it also happens to be a societal safeguard for when automation and AI take over more and more jobs. 

Turns out, Zuckerberg isn't the only CEO who thinks it's a good idea.

Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield took to Twitter on Friday to further a discussion on the role that family money has played in some of the most successful businesses. 

"Doesn't have to be much, but giving people even a very small safety net would unlock a huge amount of entrepreneurialism," Butterfield Tweeted.

Butterfield, who is from Canada, went on to say that he thinks free healthcare is more vital than a free college education.

"Plenty of people are happy and successful without any college, whereas all dead people are just dead," he wrote.

Doesn't have to be much, but giving people even a very small safety net would unlock a huge amount of entrepreneurialism.
- Stewart Butterfield (@stewart)

Who said instead? ???? (Though, of the three, free college seems the least important by a factor of 10.)
- Stewart Butterfield (@stewart)

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart Butterfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butterfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butterfield Tweeted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zuckerberg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
