<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428377316160344</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/latest-news/uk-man-who-tried-to-join-is-gets-six-years/news-story/25bb581cb17d6626859c6073e74d9fec</url>
  <title>UK man who tried to join IS gets six years</title>
  <content>
A father of two who told an undercover British police officer he intended to join Islamic State fight in Syria has been jailed for six years.
Ghulam Hussain, 31, bought plane tickets with the intention of travelling to Syria and said he would rather die than return to the UK.
He gave the officer STG160 ($A263) to pay for his accommodation on his journey to join IS and made plans to meet him in Turkey.
Hussain earlier admitted engaging in conduct in preparation for committing an act of terrorism and engaging in conduct with the intention of assisting another person to commit an act of terrorism.
Judge Peter Collier QC, said: "It was your intention to go abroad, it was your intention to take up arms and to kill and you did encourage the undercover officer to do the same as you.
"You did have a commitment to travel to Syria, to join Daesh (IS), to fight and give your life."
The court heard that Hussain spent STG390 ($A641) on tickets to Pakistan via Istanbul.
The defendant, who is of Pakistani origin, claimed he was visiting family and stopping in Turkey for dental treatment, but intended to "disappear" in Istanbul and travel to Syria.
He met the undercover officer at a retail park in the East Midlands on October 6 last year and audio and video recordings were made of their conversations.
Simon Davis, prosecuting, told the court that Hussain told the officer he'd been making plans to travel to Syria for the past 12 months and would give a pledge of allegiance to IS when he arrived.
The prosecutor said Hussain told the officer they would get to handle a weapon when they got there and would fight the non-believers.
The court heard that he gave the officer advice about social media, where to book accommodation in Istanbul, travel times to the Syrian border and clothing needed for the journey.
Hussain, who showed no emotion as he was jailed, would serve half his sentence before being released on licence.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hussain</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISTANBUL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STG160</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ghulam Hussain, 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STG390</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Peter Collier QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Midlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
