<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428007948967397</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/nev-was-there-for-name-change-debate/3207533/</url>
  <title>Nev was there for name-change debate</title>
  <content>
NEV Kane holds the rare honour of being able to claim he was personally involved in discussions that led to the Sunshine Coast getting its name.
In 1967, Nev was an active member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch which supported other organisations in the change of name from Near North Coast to Sunshine Coast.
Now aged 85 and still an active real estate agent, he recalls that the renaming issue was discussed at numerous REIQ branch meetings - not just one - and other service organisations also pushing for a name change were always in close contact with the branch.
He said memorable active REIQ members on this issue were auctioneer Doug Biggs (Day & Grimes), Cotton Tree valuer Harold Richards and Jim Carolan - initiator of the first Coast radio station called 4NA and also principal of Nambour real estate agencies.
All three have since passed away.
You don't stay in real estate game on the Sunshine Coast for long without being a trusted name.
Nev Kane's name has been synonymous with our local industry ever since he bought Graham Shaw's Yandina Commission Agency in 1953, at the tender age of 21.
That made him the youngest provisional commission agent working in Queensland at that time.
Nev was granted a full commission agent licence in 1955 after intense scrutiny due to the fact that no one so young (he was 23 at the time) had ever been granted a licence in Queensland to that point.
In 1956, he was invited by local active agents to become a provisional member of the Near North Coast branch of the Real Estate Institute of Queensland (REIQ) and became a full member on May 19, 1959.
It's not just the name of the Sunshine Coast which has changed considerably over the past five decades and Nev has been in the thick of things to a large degree.
He can recall marketing Coolum subdivisions in the 1950s, including the naming of many well-known streets in the area.
For example, William St, Hewitt St, and Birtwill St (one of the main retail areas of Coolum) were named after William Thompson who developed the subdivision and Birt Hewitt, who had a house next to the subdivision.
Birtwill St was a combination of their names.
Nev's personal achievements within the region in general and real estate in particular are worth noting because it shows he has never left time to rest on his laurels.
During his career he:
Became the first multi-list agency award-winner on the Sunshine Coast.
Was a Sunshine Coast REIQ branch executive committee member, vice-president 1968-69; president 1969-70; treasurer 1992-94, secretary 1994.
Went into partnership with Eric Marsh in 1970 to establish Marsh and Kane Real Estate in Noosaville (for over 40 years).
Was made an REIQ Fellow in 1996 for his long-running contribution to the real estate industry.
Was principal of three real estate agencies at one time - Nev Kane Cooroy, Nev Kane Yandina and Marsh and Kane Noosaville (this was sold in 2009).
Has served as a Justice of the Peace since 1976.
Is still an active member of the Yandina Chamber of Commerce, Maroochy Land Care, Noosaville branch of the Queensland Justice's Association and a current member of the REIQ Sunshine Coast Zone.
After 64 years of continual business in real estate, Nev Kane is considered the longest-operating real estate agent in Queensland today.
Still a sole trader, he enjoys heading into the office in Yandina, beside the BP Service Centre, each day and ensuring everything is still running smoothly.
And because he has always put his name to his business, many local families continue to be among his loyal clients, dating back decades and generations.
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
Coast researchers welcome govt inspection of white spot studies
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
I HAVE worked through some very buoyant years.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
FAMILY holiday was catalyst for a change of scenery and lifestyle.
YOU learnt by driving around with the boss.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Carolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grimes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birt Hewitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hewitt St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev Kane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doug Biggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Shaw's Yandina Commission Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev Kane Cooroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Land Care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice of the Peace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birtwill St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Fellow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Sunshine Coast Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marsh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harold Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate Institute of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Justice's Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BP Service Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev Kane Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Near North Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
