<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428351546356013</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:33</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/gleaming-rigs-strut-their-stuff/3209010/</url>
  <title>Gleaming rigs strut their stuff</title>
  <content>
MORE than 100 gleaming highway beasts will cruise through the middle of Casino from 10am today for the 2017 North Coast Petroleum Casino Truck Show.

The annual event draws both local and interstate trucking companies to show off their best 'blinged up' rigs in their full glory.

For the first time this year the trucks will also be competing for cash prizes, with the ultimate title "Rig of the Show" winning $1000.

There is also $100 each to be awarded to the the top five "elite" ranked rigs, and another $600 combined for the first, second, and third best fleets.

The family fun also includes live music, kids' rides, a raffle draw, industry displays, and a free mini train.

President of the truck show Stuart George said the event gave visitors the chance to see Casino's main streets "alive with wall to wall trucks".

"It's an opportunity to experience the heart of the event right up close," he said.

The event kicks off this morning with the main parade at 10am down Johnston St and Centre St.

The prize presentation and raffle draw will take place at 2pm.

'Next 50 years will be really focused around health and well being'
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Coast Petroleum Casino Truck Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rig of the Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centre St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnston St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
