<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428257057073873</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/private-sydney/ps-nabil-gazal-jnr-takes-different-view-on-split-with-roxy-jacenko-20170801-gxn8gv.html</url>
  <title>Nabil Gazal jnr takes different view on split with Roxy Jacenko</title>
  <content>
 
It has been one of this town's more intriguing love triangles of recent times, but millionaire property developer Nabil Gazal jnr has a slightly different version of events that led to his break-up with (someone else's) wife Roxy Jacenko.

Up Next
Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

01:28

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Private Sydney: Roxy Jacenko chapter #3452

Things move fast on Planet Roxy. The troubles with her marriage, second weddings and diamond rings. Andrew Hornery investigates

Gazal, who PS hears is currently in London and has been making the most of his single status with the local ladies, has told friends it was he who broke it off with Jacenko, much to the relief of his loved ones, not in the least his mother.
"It was too much for him, he felt like he was suffocating ... he wanted out," PS was told by a source close to Gazal.
His friends claim the decision to end it with Jacenko came just weeks before her husband Oliver Curtis was due to be released from Cooma jail following his 12-month sentence for insider trading.
But in the months before, both he and Jacenko had intended to build a new life together. PS understands there were plans for Jacenko and her two children to Curtis to move into Gazal's Darling Point apartment once renovations by society decorator and Jacenko's friend, Blainey North, had been completed.

But it was not to be, with Jacenko handing back the $50,000 eternity ring PS revealed she had fashioned from a diamond pendant Gazal had given her.

You will now receive updates from

Daily Life Newsletter

Daily Life Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

However, Jacenko's girlfriends, some of whom attempted to convince Gazal to reconsider, have been offering a slightly different version. According to Team Roxy it was she who broke up with Gazal.

Oliver Curtis and Roxy Jacenko, in an Instagram photo from Bali, are planning a second wedding.  Photo: Instagram

Jacenko politely declined to comment to PS this week, but not before voicing her objections to her description in this column as a "publicity-seeking missile".
And yet on Thursday she was in a much more chatty mood with the Murdoch press.
While spruiking a range of mops, Jacenko managed to drop a bombshell: she had considered divorcing her jailed husband months ago.
"I'd spoken to a lawyer about divorce, and he knew that, I'd told him," Jacenko said.
"I told him I wasn't sure what was going to happen in the future ... it was without question the worst 12 months of my life."
It was PS who revealed Jacenko had been spending time with Gazal last year, culminating in April when a series of steamy photographs of the pair kissing during a late-night party at Gazal's Darling Point home became public, just weeks before Curtis was due for release.
"You can read a lot into three seconds of pictures," Jacenko claimed this week, having refused to comment on the images for the past three months.
"We were stupid ... that's where it starts and that's where it stops. My marriage in my eyes had come to an end ... it had been a seriously tough 12 months ... [we were] drunk and stupid and mucking around."
Drunk? Stupid? Mucking around?
Meanwhile Jacenko has yet another card up her sleeve in the publicity stakes, teasing details on social media of her upcoming second wedding to her husband, from her new diamond engagement ring to fabric samples of her custom-made wedding gown.
Gazal is not expected to feature on the guest list.
Delta torn over designer tag

Australia's sweetheart, Delta Goodrem, has been ruffling feathers of late, with a few sequins in the count too.
While the leggy chanteuse copped a drudging recently after she starred in a television commercial appearing to not be wearing a seat belt with her head hanging out the window of a moving car and her long mane blowing in the wind, a little closer to home her name has left a bad taste with emerging Sydney fashion designer Yousef Akbar.

Fashion designer Yousef Akbar has been left baffled by the lack of an endorsement from Delta Goodrem after she wore one of his gowns. Photo: Dallas Kilponen

PS has learned that Akbar has been waiting for Goodrem to come good on an endorsement for his label after she wore one of his sparkling sequined gowns on Channel Nine's Footy Show during a performance.
However Goodrem's spokeswoman told PS the singer had uploaded video of her wearing the gown, which Akbar said he was aware of. Goodrem's spokeswoman told PS: "It was not intentional to not directly tag the designer. Delta endeavours to support and cross promote as many fashion moments as possible"

Delta Goodrem is said to have specifically sought an outfit from Yousef Akbar for her Footy Show appearance.

Akbar confirmed to PS his design was specifically sought by Goodrem's stylist Fleur Egan because it was "perfect" for the stage set up being planned for the singer's high-profile appearance.
It is common for designers to provide gowns, gratis, for celebrities to wear during major events. Usually the deal is that those stars provide details of the label on their social media feeds as a payback for the designer's generosity, as has been the case with both Mauboy and The Veronicas.
Akbar confirmed to PS the gowns were not gifts, but rather on loan, in return for a social media plug.
Heiress Grace Forrest denies being a philanthropist

No airs and graces with this young go-getter
They just don't make heiresses like they used to, or at least they don't when they come from the billionaire Forrest clan.

Grace Forrest, daughter of billionaire Andrew Twiggy Forrest, as seen in Harpers Bazaar Australia. Photo: Liz Looker

No extravagant birthday parties, no social debuts in Paris, no front row fashion show appearances, no glitzy weddings, no $20,000 handbags and no string of handsome boyfriends filling up gossip columns.
Instead for 24-year-old Grace Forrest and her actor sister Sophia, 22, it's all work, work, work.
The daughters of mining mogul and philanthropist Andrew Twiggy Forrest have been on something of a publicity campaign in recent months, Sophia making her first major outing in Sunday Life magazine last month, while next monday it is big sister Grace's turn, with a revealing interview in the glossy pages of Harper's Bazaar Australia.
"I'm actually working as a researcher with a think tank called the Legatum Institute," she tells the magazine from her new London home. "Their aim is to understand and tackle the great challenges that face humanity."

Sophia Forrest, the daughter of Nicola and Andrew Forrest, is on track to becoming one of the country's leading actors thanks to her break-out role on Love Child. Photo: Hugh Stewart

Clearly the University of Notre Dame Australia graduate, who is now completing a master's degree in strategic communications, is not one to shy away from seemingly huge challenges. She and her father organised for faith leaders from around the world, including the Pope, to meet at the Vatican and sign a collective pledge to end slavery by 2020.
She is also a founding director of the Walk Free Foundation, which seeks to eliminate modern slavery and is funded by the Forrest family's Minderoo Foundation.
In May her parents announced they would be donating $400 million of their personal $5 billion plus fortune to charity, $75 million of which was pledged to end modern slavery.
But don't label her a "philanthropist".
"Well, technically I'm not one," she says. "I also don't really like the separation in - dare I say it - class, which means when someone very wealthy gives away a small percentage of their fortune they are a philanthropist, but when a young family must manage their budget but they buy fair-trade tea or coffee or support a child's education in another country, that's not considered philanthropy. Often that family is giving up a lot more of their income, percentage-wise, and is also making a conscious decision to make positive change.
"Generosity is generosity; sharing one's wealth to help others less fortunate is powerful no matter what the number is or what you call it."
In the magazine spread, Grace also takes on the role of fashion model, though PS understands she was very specific in the labels she would wear for Harper's, ensuring that only "ethical" brands were included. No doubt that $32,300 Cartier watch fit the bill nicely given Cartier's extensive corporate responsibility policy.
Spotlight on a former first lady of David Jones

We can only imagine what the late doyenne of Sydney society Lady Lloyd Jones would make of today's South African owners and their bags of "spiralised" zucchini in the gleaming new David Jones Food Hall unveiled at her old family store in Bondi Junction on Wednesday night.
It has been some time since Sydney's Lloyd Jones family had any connection with the department store empire their forebear David Jones established nearly two centuries ago. Today, PS's Spotlight shines on one of the golden eras of retailing in this city, a time when shopkeepers were among the leading names on the social ladder, with vast fortunes and stately homes.
The names Lloyd Jones, Grace, Hordern, Foy, Walton and Myer were afforded an almost regal air in Sydney's society pages of the day.

Lady Lloyd Jones ( left) and Mrs Anthony Hordern in the late 1930s. Photo: Fairfax Media

But none were more formidable than Lady Hannah Benyon Lloyd Jones, the second wife of Sir Charles Lloyd Jones, the chairman of David Jones Ltd from 1920 until his death in 1958.
Until her death in 1982, she had been a familiar face around the retailing floors of David Jones, her immaculate, chauffeur-driven Rolls-Royce conspicuously parked outside the flagship Elizabeth Street store
She hosted a young Queen Elizabeth at a state banquet in 1954 at the David Jones Ballroom and once filled a helicopter, which had landed on the roof of DJ's soon to be defunct men's store, with lollies before dispatching the pilot to share the sugary booty at a children's hospital.

Lady Lloyd Jones ( left) and Mrs Anthony Hordern in the late 1930s.

Lady Lloyd Jones was awarded an OBE for her charity work in 1955, and something called the Coupe d'Or du Bon Gout Francais, or rather the Gold Cup of Good Taste from France in 1961.
For half a century she controlled Sydney society from the drawing room of Rosemont, which remains Woollahra's grandest house.
As Herald journalist Valerie Lawson recalled in her account of the era, Connie Sweetheart, Hannah was "Lady Bracknell played by Edith Evans".

Charles Lloyd Jones farewells his mother Lady Lloyd Jones at Kingsford Smith Airport as she prepares to go to Paris to receive the Coupe d'Or du Bon Gout Francais. Photo: Noel Harold Stubbs/Fairfax Media

"With eyes closed and arms outstretched, she greeted guests such as the Menzies and the Caseys; Danny Kaye and Cecil Beaton; Pucci and Gucci; Elizabeth Arden and Helena Rubinstein."
She also presided over one of the great society feuds of Sydney.
When Ursula Mary Hordern, wife of rival retailing scion Sir Anthony Hordern, was working for her brother-in-law Sir Frank Packer as the fashion editor of The Australian Women's Weekly throughout the 1940s and 1950s, she hatched an audacious plan to bring Paris fashion shows to Australia, and over three years brought out glamorous gowns and models from the leading houses. Only one label was absent: Christian Dior.
Instead Dior had already signed up its post-war collections with David Jones. Lady Lloyd Jones, a Dior loyalist, hosted her own grand parade in 1948 in the store's ballroom. Sydney became the first city outside Paris to see the designer's famous "new look".
The competing fashion ambitions created a social schism between Lady Hordern and Lady Lloyd Jones, but by the summer of 1953 they made a public reconciliation as "joint hostesses" of a grand ball, irreverently referred to as "The Draper's Ball".
In from the cold

Anthony Bell and his estranged wife Kelly Landry appear to have reached some sort of common ground following their bitter and very public bust-up. PS understands the former couple, who have both endured a rough few months, are "committed" to creating a happier environment for their young daughters, with talk of a family skiing trip in the not too distant future.
Mountain goes to Murdoch

It's usually at this time of year when things heat up around Rupert Murdoch's Holt Street bunker with the octogenarian media mogul famous for his annual mid-winter pilgrimage Down Under to keep an eye on the local troops.

Rupert Murdoch, pictured here with son Lachlan, has seen daughter Elisabeth marry artist Keith Tyson in England. Photo: Bloomberg

But with his daughter Elisabeth's third wedding last weekend in England (she married artist Keith Tyson in her shed, which had been filled with flowers and $1200 bottles of champagne) and his own new bride Jerry Hall to keep busy, it is no wonder that this year the "mountain" is going to Rupert.
PS hears Daily Telegraph editor Chris Dore is among those summoned to Los Angeles next week to meet with Rupe. Dore certainly gets around, with much chatter about his recent visit aboard James Packer's Arctic P in Bora Bora.
PS looks forward to that, ahem, "scoop". Meanwhile, recently it has been Lachlan Murdoch, News Corp co-chairman, who has been walking the shop floor. He and wife Sarah have been in town for an extended trip, though they will be returning soon to the US, as both are on the guest list of Erica Packer's Aspen 40th next month.
Well-heeled dining

Sydney's dining scene is in for a shake-up. At the power end, it is wall-to-wall Ferragamo suits at the new District Dining under Chifley Tower. If ever there was a husband-hunting ground in this town, it is here, with tables laden with young men in flash suits and expensive watches. But ladies, you will have to be quick.
The one-hour business lunch offer is strictly adhered to (OK, the Herald's Terry Durack got out in 1 hour, 15 minutes, but really, who has pudding at a business lunch?).
Meanwhile over at David Jones' new Bondi Junction Food Hall on Tuesday night, PS hit the fab new sushi bar with former Westpac boss Gail Kelly, who was recently installed as a director of South Africa's shopping giant Woolworths, the owners of DJs.
Dressed in an eye-catching pink and baby blue ensemble (with matching pink shoes and scarf) Kelly, who has just donated $1 million to the University of NSW for a scholarship program, will no doubt soon embrace DJs' Australian fashion offerings. She told PS she was deeply interested in the "customer experience" when asked about moving from banking to retail.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Bracknell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Curtis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bon Gout Francais</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupert Murdoch's Holt Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PS</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Harold Stubbs/Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi Junction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Arden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones Food Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Charles Lloyd Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Veronica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer's Arctic P</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OBE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footy Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Cup of Good</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Roxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosemont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Dore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJs' Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vatican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hordern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald's Terry Durack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blainey North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ursula Mary Hordern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Lloyd Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferragamo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi Junction Food Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elisabeth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edith Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helena Rubinstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Hordern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rolls-Royce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones Ballroom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Anthony Hordern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mauboy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Notre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walk Free Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophia Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper's Bazaar Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupert Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yousef Akbar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Dining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Anthony Hordern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planet Roxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murdoch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grace Forrest</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cecil Beaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Tyson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Twiggy Forrest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bora Bora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUPERT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacenko</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minderoo Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gazal's Darling Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Kaye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Draper's Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Akbar</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erica Packer's Aspen 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Dior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legatum Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerry Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hornery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PS's Spotlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodrem</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy Jacenko</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine's Footy Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Lloyd Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fleur Egan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woollahra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dior</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Frank Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cartier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsford Smith Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Women's Weekly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Kilponen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chifley Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connie Sweetheart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Hannah Benyon Lloyd Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harpers Bazaar Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Landry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gazal</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valerie Lawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Lloyd Jones</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forrest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Love Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nabil Gazal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta Goodrem</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz Looker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
