<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427256329678004</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/game-of-thrones-episode-four-leaked-and-posted-online-20170804-gxpx2y.html</url>
  <title>Game of Thrones episode four leaked and posted online</title>
  <content>
Los Angeles: The next episode of Game of Thrones has been stolen and posted on the internet, but the leak isn't believed to be related to the .
Links to the fourth episode in season seven, set to premiere on August 6, appeared on a discussion board on Reddit.

Up Next
Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

01:28

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

HBO hacked, programming stolen

The script for an unaired episode of Game of Thrones has been stolen by hackers according to Entertainment Weekly. HBO has confirmed the hack but not the content taken.

The pirated copy of the episode, titled The Spoils of War, was available via Google Drive, according to the report.
However, shortly after the episode link was posted on Reddit on Friday morning, the post was updated with this message: "The file has been taken down for violating GoogleDrive's [terms of service]. You can no longer view it."

It's not the first time Game of Thrones - believed to be the most-pirated TV show of all time - has been hit with pre-release piracy.
In 2015 the first four episodes of season five landed on piracy networks after being copied from review screeners, nearly a full day before the season premiere.

During last year's season six run, an episode leaked ahead of its premiere date after it was accidentally made available on HBO Nordic.
The latest leak came from pay-TV distribution partner Star India, a subsidiary of 21st Century Fox, whose logo appears as a watermark in the pirated copy with the text "for internal viewing only", the Verge reported.Photo: HBO
"We take this breach very seriously and have immediately initiated forensic investigations at our and the technology partner's end to swiftly determine the cause," a representative of Star India said in a statement.
"This is a grave issue and we are taking appropriate legal remedial action."Photo: HBO
Mumbai-based Star India operates more than 40 channels in eight different languages.
HBO did not respond to a request for comment.
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Weekly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spoils of War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO Nordic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumbai-based Star India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoogleDrive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Century Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
