<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428334366486605</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/boxing-mma/british-boxer-amir-khan-announces-split-from-wife-in-ugly-twitter-row/news-story/c948bac8305fcc88585ff6d906b0d0b0</url>
  <title>Boxer and wife in insane Twitter fight</title>
  <content>
BRITISH boxer Amir Khan has split from wife Faryal Makhdoom and accused her of cheating on him with heavyweight champion Anthony Joshua, according to a string of explosive Twitter posts.
the social media spat started after the boxer announced their separation on his Twitter account.
"So me and the wife Faryal have agreed to split," Khan wrote. "I'm currently in Dubai. Wish her all the best."
The breakup feud turned ugly when Khan, a former unified light-welterweight world champion, started making sensational claims that Makhdoom had moved on with Joshua in subsequent tweets.
"Faryal moved on quick," another of Khan's tweets read. "Always mentioned to me how much she wanted to be with another guy, from all people another boxer."
Makhdoom, a 26-year-old model, fired back at Khan's claims, branding her husband a "cheater" himself and a "bad role model, always around women and alcohol" in tweets that have since been deleted.
"Accusing other boxers just because your boxing career is finished. Man up amir," she wrote in a tweet now removed from Twitter.

So me and the wife Faryal have agreed to split. I'm currently in Dubai. Wish her all the best.

Lol moved up in the weight classes lol. Trust me I ain't the jealous type. No need to send me pictures of the men your talking to

Mans like Joshua can have my left overs!

"After all these years. I've always defending a cheat, always stuck around for him, always had his back. And I'm called a gold digger?" she continued. "LOL! He's given me jack s*** - I pay house bills and bills for my daughter myself! It's like I'm a single mother while he's out messing around.
"And he has the nerve to blast me like that? The amount of evidence I have on you. It can destroy you. But since I loved you at one point in my life. I'll just let it go.
"I'm not the one who's been in the papers every month with my pants down Cheater!"
Joshua, a fellow Brit and the current holder of three world heavyweight titles, also got involved in the action on Friday morning, going so far as to deny he had ever met Makhdoom.

Bantz aside, I hope you guys can resolve your situation or this is a hack as we have never even met! Plus I like my women BBW

Khan and Makhdoom, who wed in 2013, have a history of publicly accusing each other of various wrongdoings. Makhdoom went on a long social media rant last December, alleging Khan's family had bullied her and demanded she wear more conservative clothes.
While Khan supported his wife in the family feud, the couple appeared on British TV in January after a sex tape involving Khan was leaked online and brought more attention to his past cheating scandals. Khan, 30, has been accused of affairs with a handful of models while he and Makdhoom were together.
"At the end of the day I can hold my head high knowing I've given this marriage my 100% while amir clearly hasn't," Makdhoom wrote in another since-deleted tweet. "Bad company."
She added: "I think he just needs some attention because boxing hasn't been going well for him so he's just been acting up."
This story was originally published in  and is reproduced here with their permission
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joshua</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amir Khan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faryal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faryal Makhdoom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khan, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makhdooms</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Joshua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makdhoom</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
