<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428214107400300</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/private-sydney/delta-goodrem-keeps-fashion-designer-yousef-akbar-hanging-on-20170803-gxov8v.html</url>
  <title>Delta Goodrem keeps fashion designer Yousef Akbar hanging on</title>
  <content>
Australia's sweetheart, Delta Goodrem, has been ruffling feathers of late, with a few sequins in the count too.
While the leggy chanteuse copped a drudging recently after she appeared in a television commercial appearing to not be wearing a seat belt with her head hanging out the window of a moving car and her long mane blowing in the wind, a little closer to home her name has left a bad taste with emerging Sydney fashion designer Yousef Akbar.Photo: Dallas Kilponen
PS has learned that Akbar has been waiting for Goodrem to come good on an endorsement for his label after she wore one of his sparkling sequined gowns on Channel Nine's Footy Show during a performance.
The problem is, it has been 10 months since she wore the frock, and Akbar, who has also dressed the likes of Jessica Mauboy and The Veronicas, did not want to discuss the matter with PS this week. However, it did make it clear he was getting a little tired of waiting for "Delts" to come good.Footy Show
Goodrem's stylist Fleur Egan had requested the gown, which Akbar confirmed to PS was specifically sought because it was "perfect" for the stage set up being planned for the singer's high-profile appearance.
It is common for designers to provide gowns, gratis, for celebrities to wear during major events. Usually the deal is that those stars provide details of the label on their social media feeds as a payback for the designer's generosity, as has been the case with both Mauboy and The Veronicas.
The gowns are not gifts, but rather on loan.
"She refused to do it, and he has absolutely no idea why ... even when he tried to follow it up, he hit a blank wall. He did everything they asked in good faith," PS's mole explained.
Goodrem's spokeswoman did not respond to PS's queries this week.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Veronica</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footy Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Mauboy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mauboy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yousef Akbar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yousef Akbar.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Akbar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodrem</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine's Footy Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fleur Egan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Kilponen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta Goodrem</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
