<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428033718771701</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/expo-88-sparked-the-sales-boom/3207549/</url>
  <title>Expo '88 sparked the sales boom</title>
  <content>
I STARTED in real estate in 1989. It was a great time to start as Expo 88 had just happened and as Brisbane and the Gold Coast were fully booked, people were forced to come north.
The response was "how long has this place been here?". We had people walking in just wanting to buy property.
Mind you, back then you could buy a block of land in Oceanic Dr, right on the beach, for just $80,000. Now if you could find a vacant block, you would be looking at $800,000!
You could also buy a waterfront unit in the heart of Mooloolaba for just $150,000. Now you would need $750,000.
High quality homes in Mountain Creek were selling for $275,000. Now you cannot buy a block of land for that!
One of the things that I remember from those days, as the mother of three sons who attended Stella Maris Primary and then Immanuel Lutheran High, was that while they were both great schools, there was little choice in schools.
We had people choose not to buy here for that reason but now we have the absolute opposite, with people relocating here because of the incredible educational facilities.
We have the best private schools you could find; the best and very highly regarded state schools and of course, the incredible University of the Sunshine Coast.
What a game changer that has been.
The biggest change in the real estate industry over the past 29 years has without doubt been technology.
When I first started there we no mobile phones but we had two-way radios back to the office.
I was one of those people who thought the internet would never work for selling homes, as people had to "feel it - touch it". Boy have I been proven wrong!
But not all technology is great, with the sites all over the place now where people can value their homes, or the homes they want to buy, it can prove a nightmare as they often do get it very, very wrong. A good, professional agent is still required.
Another of the biggest changes I have seen is the standard for real estate agents. We are, at the end of the day, entrusted with the greatest responsibility.
Everyone in my team is in awe of the fact that people give us the key to their home - what greater honour and responsibility is there than that?
Back when I started, you did a five-day course and were then let loose on the public. Now, with the higher standards of training and the REIQ working hard on compliance, if you are dealing with an accredited REIQ agent, you should feel confident that they are professional.
Keeping in mind that we are dealing with people's lives, it is always so exciting to assist a young couple buy their first home. That is such a buzz.
And at the other end of the scale, when you reach the stage of your life that you are selling the ' family ' home, to move to a retirement village - and how far have they come in the past 30 years?  A lot of them a more like resorts now, and that does make the transition easier, but it is massive to hold their hands and dare I say their hearts, while they make that transmission, as quite often, they are also, at the stage of losing the ability to drive, losing hard fought independence, you are a real shoulder for them at that stage.
I am very proud to say that although I got dragged kicking and screaming into the 21st century of real estate and the internet, when I realised it was "a thing", I looked at how bad many of the photos were and decided that if my properties were going on the internet, they were going to stand out.
So I was the one of the first agents, if not the very first, to use professional photography. We have sold many properties sight unseen because of the good stories that go with the great photos.
One of the biggest "highs" is selling a home under the hammer. I recall one on the river in Maroochydore. We thought we would sell it to a developer but our buyers was a lovely family that had a son with a disability. They outbid everyone else and bought the home because he was happiest when playing in the sand and with the sand on the very doorstep of this beach house, it was a dream to them.
Those things stay with you.
I started in real estate because I was suddenly a single mum with three boys and needed a "family friendly" job so that I could take the boys to school each day and get to the rugby games and other activities. I never imagined it would be something that I would still be doing 29 years later.
Something that was very good to me in regard to financial rewards, allowing me to raise my boys and travel, never imaged the people I would meet, I should write a book one day.
Real estate is the best job in the world as it allows you the freedom to prioritise your family. As a single mum of three boys, that was essential to me.
You are mobile and you meet the most amazing people. Some become life-long friends.
No two days are the same.
I have had the pleasure of working with some incredible people and am now very happy to be in the position of giving back in that regard, being blessed with the chance to mentor some of the young guns and future leaders of the industry.
That is a great privilege.
Vicki Stewart is the principal of Stewart Property in Mooloolaba.
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oceanic Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart Properties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expo 88</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immanuel Lutheran High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stella Maris Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountain Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
