<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428304301714954</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:22</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/coalmine-worker-gets-payout-for-horrific-burns/3208936/</url>
  <title>Coalmine worker gets payout for horrific burns</title>
  <content>
A FORMER coalmine worker who received burns to a quarter of his body hopes a penalty handed down to a mining firm will make the industry safer.
Ben Nelson used to love working in coal mines, Brisbane Magistrates Court heard on Friday.
But after he was engulfed in flames in a 2012 Collinsville accident, it was "physically and mentally impossible" for him to go back.
After years of legal wrangling, Mr Nelson was awarded $50,000 on Friday.
Queensland mining services company Thiess pleaded guilty to one charge of failing to discharge health and safety obligations in an incident causing grievous bodily harm.
Mr Nelson was hospitalised and needed skin grafts and multiple operations after a problem with a drill and pressure build-up blew off an inlet pipe.
The Department of Natural Resources and Mines, which took Thiess to court, was awarded $150,000 in costs.
Mr Nelson told NewsRegional he had no idea what to expect when turning up to court but was happy afterwards.
"In the beginning I had some issues with the way that the investigation was being handled," he said.
"I didn't think it was done to the best of their ability but they've certainly made up for it by getting a good outcome."
Thiess was fined $90,000, from which Mr Nelson's gratuity must be paid.
Mr Nelson now lives in Lawrence near Grafton in New South Wales. He hoped Magistrate Jane Bentley's ruling would improve life for miners and contractors.
"Hopefully it's going to make the mining industry a safer place to work," he said.
Ben Nelson received burns to his body after an explosion at the Collinsville Coalmine in October 2012.Jacob Miley
Mr Nelson believed Thiess, the managing contractor at Collinsville, was "sincere" when it voiced regret on Friday for what happened.
Thiess's guilty plea was neither early nor timely, prosecutor Dearne Firth said.
The risk to Mr Nelson, who received third-degree burns, and a colleague with him, would have been greatly reduced if the men had received adequate training, she said.
But Ms Firth acknowledged Thiess had no previous convictions and was mostly a good "corporate citizen".
It would have been nice for Thiess to have shown some "generosity" to Mr Nelson sooner, Ms Firth said.
She said Thiess could move on but Mr Nelson had to live with "the adverse impact of these injuries for the rest of his life".
Defence lawyer Paul Hardman said Thiess wanted to express "regret and contrition" and had taken steps to ensure an accident like the Collinsville one was not repeated.
"It did have a very comprehensive safety management system. It was one aspect of the system that failed."
A contractor at the time of the incident, Mr Nelson was responsible for his own workers compensation.
Some issues around the incident were the subject of separate litigation. - NewsRegional
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Firth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collinsville Coalmine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thiess</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Nelson</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Hardman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Natural</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collinsville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NewsRegional</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Nelson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dearne Firth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Jane Bentley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2012.Jacob Miley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
