<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427608517002668</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/03/27/acid-tanker-explosion-damages-m1</url>
  <title>Acid tanker explosion damages M1</title>
  <content>
Traffic problems could continue on the M1 motorway in southeast Queensland during the weekend after a tanker hauling 15,000 litres of hydrochloric acid exploded into flames.
Authorities say it is a miracle no one was harmed when the truck caught fire on the motorway at Loganholme about 8.30am on Friday, shutting down the major Brisbane and Gold Coast link and causing a kilometre-wide exclusion zone to be established.
The charred wreckage of the chemical truck was cleared from the motorway on Friday evening and traffic slowly started flowing after two southbound and all northbound lanes were reopened.
A damaged southbound lane remained closed and it may be some time before conditions return to normal, with police warning of significant delays on Friday night.
Buses travelling in both directions along the motorway were running up to an hour late because of the disruption.
It's expected engineers will inspect the road before it's given the all clear but police were unsure when that would happen.
The owner of the truck, Coogee Chemicals, had sent an incident response team to assist emergency services and said it was "relieved" no one was injured.

Related Articles

(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coogee Chemicals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loganholme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
