<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428385906095105</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/4a-shanks-rd-aldgate-hideaway-a-hit-with-wildlife/news-story/bfc82f2d0da9e93d091f43f12ba94bad</url>
  <title>4a Shanks Rd, Aldgate hideaway a hit with wildlife - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
AN Aldgate home is a peaceful escape and a pleasant distraction from the busyness of working life, says Sally McKenzie.
Ms McKenzie, who is selling her late mother Sheila McKenzie's  home, says the property's position opposite a reserve gives it a sense of privacy and a strong connection to its environment.

4A Shanks Road Aldgate. Supplied by LJ Hooker Stirling.

"The birdlife and animal life there is incredible - last time I was driving into Shanks Rd I had to stop for a koala to cross, and it's visited by an enormous amount of birdlife," Ms McKenzie says.

4A Shanks Road Aldgate. Supplied by LJ Hooker Stirling.

Ms McKenzie says her mother was attracted to the quality of the property, and made further improvements to both the house and garden.
"When she bought it she put leadlight glass either side of the front door, she put in a bay window in her bedroom with leadlight features, and some of the kitchen cupboards now have leadlight," Ms McKenzie says.

4A Shanks Road Aldgate. Supplied by LJ Hooker Stirling.

"She moved here from a Cricklewood Rd home on  3/4 of an acre and started planting another garden, and being her last garden, she planted the most exquisite one.
"She planned her garden meticulously. What's great about having someone with mum's knowledge plan the garden is that she knows which plants and ground covers to put in to make sure it's not only beautiful, but low-maintenance as well," Ms McKenzie says.

4A Shanks Road Aldgate. Supplied by LJ Hooker Stirling.

The home has three bedrooms, the master suite with a walk-in robe and an ensuite with shower, toilet and vanity unit.
A large timber kitchen is the heart of the home and opens to a family/meals area, and there is also a 7m x 5.08m living room.

4A Shanks Road Aldgate. Supplied by LJ Hooker Stirling.

"Mum loved having a sense of space and being able to feel uncluttered despite being surrounded by her impressive collection of antiques," Ms McKenzie said.
"The last party we had there for mum was her 90th and we were able to have her friends out in the garden. I think if mum had bought this place earlier then I'm sure she would have done a lot of entertaining here, because it certainly lends itself to entertaining."

4A Shanks Road Aldgate. Supplied by LJ Hooker Stirling.

Ms McKenzie says the home would suit a range of buyers, including professional couples, families or even singles.
"It will be very hard to say goodbye to this place because it's been an oasis for me in a lot of respects," Ms McKenzie says.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McKenzie</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanks Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanks Rd I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricklewood Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheila McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ Hooker Stirling</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldgate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanks Road Aldgate</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
