<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428338661453930</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/skit-warren-entschs-gay-marriage-communists-force-me-to-marry-young-latin-wisp-named-eduardo/news-story/148bdaed0ac8e62114c5c77668a9a919</url>
  <title>Entsch forces me to marry a man</title>
  <content>
SPOONING through the morning porridge prepared by my doting wife Glenda, I feel thoroughly unmolested by the threat of a blouse-wearing fellow shedding stray nipple hairs into my morning coffee.
I feel manly. I feel secure.
Here in my home, my fortress, everything is as it should be.
My silent offspring limit themselves to the periphery of my vision while enjoying the day's first 15-minute allotment of leisure time for such diverting activities as spinning tops or chinese chequers.
Of course I was apprehensive about letting them engage in the latter at first, given the ethnic connotations, but Glenda assured me it was in fact derivative of the German board game "sternhalma".
She is a good woman of Bavarian stock, if susceptible to occasional flights of fancy - learning to drive, volunteering at the library and other such nonsense.
The currawongs sing through the window of the drawing room, where I take my breakfast, and all is well and serene.
Thank goodness I finally shot the last of those maddening curlews.
Should I do it?
No, not yet.
Each day starts off with such unbridled confidence and clear-cut trigonometric order, only to be thrown into chaos, confusion and misery upon glancing at that accursed rag.
But routine is everything.
I must read it. It is inescapable.
No, I shall perform my ablutions and steady my nerve with a stiff morning whisky for what will surely be a steel-fingered slap in the face from those morally bereft Marxists.
A short, chilly rinse with the slick of Imperial Leader and the slap of aftershave always pacifies the voices.
Not this time.
My hand is atremble as I spatter the tumbler to a sufficient volume and take a curative slug.
I can feel my cotton velour bathrobe already becoming tainted with cold sweat as I reach for the newspaper and set my teeth for the inevitable anarchic onslaught of the modern world.
Deep breath.
You can do this, George.
You can do this.
Not even a turn is required before the repulsive influence of the left makes itself known in blinding black ink on the front page: "Libs fast-track same-sex showdown".
Who in damnation is this heathen Warren Entsch, and why is he so obsessed with forcing me to marry a man? Warren Entsch? More like Warren Stench, if you ask me!
It confirms a parliamentary conscience vote is all but inevitable, that the aggrieved future saint Tony Abbott holds little sway in his current political diminution and that, fundamentally, this world has become a ruinous bog of fornicatory sin.
Palpitations threaten to tear my heart from my chest as a foaming shame and degradation sprays from my lips.
Did not Leviticus say thou shalt not lie with mankind, as with womankind: it is abomination?
I dearly hope so, otherwise my Old Testament-based household bans on bacon, consulting psychics, wearing jewellery and sporting polyester tracksuits just seem silly now.
This Entsch character has personally targeted the sanctity of my home, trying to force me to divorce my wife, of whom I am fond, and take up a new life of debauchery with a swarthy young Latin wisp named Eduardo.
Already I have noticed Glenda becoming a little too chummy with -Agatha from croquet, and she has -increased her daily coffee intake from two cups to three, despite all my protestations.
I will not even mention what I caught the dog doing yesterday.
One more strike and Scout the Irish wolfhound will go the way of the curlews.
The end is surely upon us and not even single-malt will solve this.
I give up.
Call the office, Glenda.
I shall be working from home today.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marxist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entsch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Testament-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Stench</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leviticus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agatha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bavarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eduardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperial Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
