<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428424560801596</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/06/32/is-this-the-fittest-woman-on-earth</url>
  <title>Is this Queenslander the fittest woman on earth?</title>
  <content>
This Gladstone girl's got muscles on her muscles, and she's showing the world how to flex.
Meet Tia Clair Toomey. At just 24, she's in top contention to be crowned the fittest woman on earth at the 2017 Crossfit Games.
You wouldn't know it though - she's still showing off that country girl humility. Taking to  after wrapping up day one of competition in poll position Ms Toomey reflected on her efforts.
"This is special moment, I won't be forgetting this anytime soon," she wrote.
"Life isn't about finding your limits. It's about realising you have none."
That's certainly on show this weekend in Madison Wisconsin. The Crossfit Games are about finding the fastest, strongest and pretty much 'best' athlete on the planet.
Ms Toomey weighs in at just 58kg. At last year's Rio Olympics (yes, she's an Olympian too), the weightlifter clean and jerked almost double her body weight (107kg) and snatched much more than it too (82 kg). Not bad for a girl who's trained by her husband at the local gym they own together in Central Queensland.

Related Articles

This weekend though, Ms Toomey will be tested in much more than just weightlifting. Already, on day one of competition, she's taken to the start line for a 4.8km run, a 500m ocean swim, a gruelling mountain bike race, far too many muscle ups (a highly technical gymnastics movement) and throwing around a 40kg barbell.
Everything from hay bale clean burpees (it's as bad as it sounds), to a farmers log and yoke carry stand in the way of her claiming the title. The aim is to throw the unthinkable at athletes, the sport itself claiming to "forge elite fitness".
Ms Toomey has come close to taking out the podium before. In the best result ever for an Aussie she took out second place in her rookie year, backing up the same result in 2016. This year, she's hoping to go one better.
"Last season was an unreal experience..." she told the Crossfit media team.
"During your career there is very little time to sit down and reflect 'cause life doesn't stop, a week later you're back into training, training for the next season." 
To see whether all the hard work's paid off, you can  Tia compete this weekend. 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CENTRAL Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Toomey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madison Wisconsin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit Games</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tia Clair Toomey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
