<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428033718771679</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sc2067-community-must-drive-coasts-future/3209013/</url>
  <title>SC2067: 'Community must drive Coast's future'</title>
  <content>
COMMUNITY involvement to guide decisions made by local government will lead to "good outcomes" on the Coast 50 years from now, a Marcoola academic says.

Professor Ian Lowe expects the Coast will retain its natural appeal, should its people be consulted and listened to before changes are made.

The 74-year-old is an Emeritus Professor at Griffith University's School of Natural Sciences with a keen interest in the region's development.

He has lived on the Coast since 2004.

"I'd hope it would have retained the native vegetation and the natural features that people come to the Sun- shine Coast for," Prof Lowe said of the region in 2067.

"Just as the world we live in is the product of the decisions and actions of previous generations, the future will be the product of decisions and actions of us and our descendants."

He said he recently gave a talk which defined development proposals that probably would have happened had environmental activists not opposed them.

They included the entire Noosa National Park being developed as a housing estate, a large resort being constructed on the north bank of the Noosa River, the Weyba wetlands being drained and turned into a housing development and construction of a restaurant on top of Mt Coolum with a connecting cable car.

"There has been about 25 serious proposals that would have made the Coast very different from what it is and more like the Gold Coast. I think... there is strong community pressure for it not to become like the Gold Coast."

from  on .

Prof Lowe said the Coast needed to respond to predictions about climate change by taking on development characteristics of low-carbon cities.

A reliance on renewable energy was one of those traits.

"The Sunshine Coast Council is actually moving in that direction with the commissioning of a big solar farm.

"They are on that tram."

Low-carbon transport was another trait.

Prof Lowe said a reduced reliance on cars depended on construction of compact urban villages where amenities were within walking or cycling distance.

"If we want to have a sustainable city we should be planning now both for compact neighbourhoods that include a lot more things that people use every day .. and good public transport to connect with the facilities you can only pro- vide on a one-per-city basis."

His final component was self sufficiency.

"That means protecting the food-producing lands."

He said land was developed for housing because, in the short term, it was more valuable for that purpose rather than for growing fruit and vegetables.

As a result, primary prod- uce had to be trucked in from further afield.

"If we want to have a low- carbon city we need to protect the food-producing land rather than having it concreted over."

He said slowing the rate of population growth could improve the strength of the region's cultural institutions.

"Generally, they are not on the scale you would expect of a city of a quarter of a million people.

"If the rate of population growth slows down, you have fewer people who are recent arrivals and more who have been here a large fraction of their life.

"I think that probably means you have stronger communities and stronger social institutions."

He said he hoped Sunshine Coast people would identify with the region and be proud to live here.

"When people are consulted ... people are rational. They show an overwhelming preference for that sort of future, in which there are compact urban villages which protect the natural assets that make the Coast the sort of place that it is.

"You'd expect that a council that responds to that would do well."

He said the council's 2015 decision not to amend its planning scheme to allow for Sekisui House's original Yaroomba hotel and residential development proposal was an example of how residents could impact decisions.

"You would expect that a council that was eager for rateable income would be sympathetic to a proposal like that," he said.

"It was obvious that the community weren't and in the end, the council voted 10 to one against the proposal."

He was confident councillors who wanted to be re- elected would make decisions based on what their communities wanted.

"In principal you have got to say that if the community are happy with it, that's a good outcome," he said.

Experts willing to give a take on the future could often be found.

"I like the old adage that it's difficult to make fore- casts, especially about the future," he said. "The future doesn't unroll in a predictable way according to the laws of physics or what are even more improbably regarded as laws of economics. There is a wide range of possible futures - which one happens will be a result of our decisions and our actions."

Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Hopes children of 2067 will enjoy the same natural attractions
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffith University's School of Natural</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sekisui House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC2067</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weyba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcoola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emeritus Professor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Lowe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
