<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427995064065268</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/beenleigh-club-sticks-to-sunday-penalty-rates-despite-fair-work-decision/news-story/5ce4b55c9c0e87d0f8da6d90456b2344</url>
  <title>Club sticks to penalty rates</title>
  <content>
A MOVE on Friday to consolidate the Clubs Award with the Hospitality Award has raised concerns from clubs in Logan.
Clubs Australia Industrial met a 4pm deadline on Friday to ask the Fair Work Commission to merge the two awards. It said the action was to ensure smaller clubs - many of which were showing signs of financial stress - remained viable.
Clubs Australia said the changes, which included to Sunday penalty rates, were designed to help smaller clubs and it repeatedly invited United Voice to negotiate.
But the move was slammed by Club Beenleigh which called on Clubs Australia last week to reverse its position and abolish the Clubs Award in the Fair Work Commission.
Club Beenleigh general manager Perran Sonnex said his business would keep paying current penalty rates. "We have an agreement with United Voice union that if the Clubs Award is scrapped, we will seek an Enterprise Bargaining Agreement," he said.
Mr Sonnex said scrapping the Clubs Award would cut weekend rates for workers as the safety net of pay and conditions for club managers and staff. He said it would also axe a range of special conditions for the operation of clubs as not for profit organisations.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enterprise Bargaining Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hospitality Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perran Sonnex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Voice</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Beenleigh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clubs Award</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clubs Australia Industrial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sonnex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
