<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427690121382469</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/real-estate/wave-of-supply-to-hit-melbourne-office-market-by-2020-20170802-gxnm5o</url>
  <title>Wave of supply to hit Melbourne office market by 2020</title>
  <content>
Melbourne's vacancy rate is at 6.5 per cent and could go even lower before the market is faced with a flood of new supply around 2020.
Whether or not the Melbourne market has sufficient demand to soak up the uncommitted aspects of that new supply and then occupy the back-fill in other buildings is now top of mind for property players.
"Melbourne CBD stock is forecast to grow by 18,939 square metres over the second half of 2017,  92,400 sq m in 2018, and a significant 377,600 sq m from 2019 onwards." said the Victorian executive director of the Property Council, Sally Capp.
Prime gross effective rents in Melbourne are now at $481 per square metre.

There there have been some big moves revealed in recent months, among them under development on Bourke Street.

 will be into 6000 sq m at an Impact Investment-owned building on Collins Street, while at the other end of the same street, ExxonMobil will take up 7100 sq m in a new Mirvac tower. 
Broadband player NBN is expected to go to Lang Walker's Collins Square project in a tenancy of 20,000 sq m. The latest entrant in the market is China's answer to WeWork​, Naked Hub, which is looking for as much as 10,000 sq m.
JLL's Stuart Colquhoun expects much of the new supply to be fully leased by the time it is delivered, while the back-fill vacancy created as result of it is typically withdrawn for refurbishment.
"We tend to over-anticipate the impact of future supply," he said

Fresh demand is coming from project requirements associated with new infrastructure,as well as co-working hubs, such as RocketSpace​, which has leased 5300 sq m, he said.
Knight Frank's Hamish Sutherland expects prime net effective rents to rise by around 5 per cent over the next year, while the overall vacancy rate could fall to as low as 4.1 per cent.
By 2020, though, that picture will change as new supply hits and vacancies rise. Incentives, now between 24 per cent and 27 per cent could climb to between 28 per cent and 32 per cent.
Sally Franklin, who runs Investa's real estate services, points to another driver as residential values rise on the city fringe, crowding out office space.

"Some tenants have had no choice but to relocate to the city.  The technology sector has been quick to recognise that to attract the best staff, they need to provide amenity and convenience," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RocketSpace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Impact Investment-owned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirvac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lang Walker's Collins Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ExxonMobil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight Frank's Hamish Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JLL's Stuart Colquhoun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Capp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WeWork</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
