<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428046603673691</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:22</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sc2067-lifestyle-the-key-to-coasts-bright-future/3209019/</url>
  <title>SC2067: Lifestyle the key to Coast's bright future</title>
  <content>
NEW arrivals Chris and Lauren Graffen's outlook on life is brightening as they wind down from their former hectic existence.

A Sunshine Coast holiday late last year was enough to convince them it was time to leave Melbourne for sunny shores.

They have loved the community feel of their new town of Coolum since arriving about four months ago.

"Our three-year-old, she has changed completely since we moved," Mrs Graffen said.

"She has come out of her shell and I think it is because of where we are."

She said the differences in lifestyle, which stem from the differences in weather, were really noticeable.

"We were absolutely gobsmacked about how many people just walk around the streets.

"The Sunshine Coast is really different.

"It has its own little personality."

from  on .

The relaxed, friendly, community feel is something she and her husband hope is retained 50 years from now.

"I hope it stays the same," Mr Graffen said.

"Obviously it is not going to."

He hoped the region wouldn't over-capitalise on tourism, like the Gold Coast.

"It (the Gold Coast) is a great place to holiday but we wouldn't want to live there."

The refrigeration mechanic said life in Melbourne's suburbs revolved around work and stress.

"Down there I was working ridiculous hours and didn't have enough time growing up with the kids.

"Up here it is more of a lifestyle."

Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
Hopes children of 2067 will enjoy the same natural attractions
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC2067</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Graffen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Graffen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Graffen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
