<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428295711780207</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/snowmaking-the-future-in-face-of-climate-change/8752210</url>
  <title>Heading to the slopes this winter? Why much of the snow you'll see comes from a machine, not the sky</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

With below average rain and warmer than usual temperatures, this Australian winter has produced conditions that would have once spelled disaster for the local ski industry.

The first month of winter was the  in much of the country's south, while  and little rain.
But despite the mild conditions, it has been pretty much business as usual at many of the major alpine resorts, with visitor numbers tracking around average.
That is because Australian ski resorts have invested heavily in advancements in snowmaking machines that can produce enough snow to cover ski runs, even when Mother Nature provides no natural snowfall.

Need to know - making snow:

Conventional snowmaking produces snow by forcing water and pressurised air through a snow gun
Unlike natural snow that forms an ice crystal with six tiny arms, man-made snow is six-sided like an ice cube
Snowmaking was accidentally discovered in the 1950s when a Californian farmer sprayed his crop with water to prevent frost damage
It was first trialled in Australia at Perisher in 1967
Most Australian resorts installed significant systems in the 1980s and 1990s
Systems have become commonplace, sophisticated and more efficient in recent years
Some resorts have introduced new snowmakers that work like ice-cream churners to freeze water into ice chips.
Source: Australian Ski Areas Association, Wikipedia

This season, for the first time, some mountains have introduced a new generation of snowmaking technology that can churn out machine-made snow in just about any weather conditions.
And with predictions climate change could , resorts are making big investments in ramping up their snowmaking equipment to ensure the industry can keep drawing tourists to alpine regions in the winter months.
No snow, no problem

While natural snow was thin on the ground early this winter, according to the Australian Ski Areas Association it did not have a big impact on the number of visitors to ski resorts.
Figures compiled by Victoria's Alpine Resorts Co-ordinating Council showed visitor numbers to Mt Buller, in the state's north-east, in the opening week of the ski season were up 148 per cent on last year and the highest they had been in the past 10 years.
That was despite a distinct lack of natural snow in the region early in the season.
"I think the June in north-east Victoria was the driest since June 1907," Buller Ski Lifts general manager Laurie Blampied said.
But what Mt Buller did have for the first time this season was a new snowmaking facility known as the 'snowfactory'.
"The difference between the snowfactory and conventional snow making is that it doesn't rely on the ambient temperature conditions to be able to produce snow," Mr Blampied said.
"What that means is that we can make snow continuously 24 hours a day, seven days a week, virtually at any temperature."

The resort began making snow in April, which its stockpiled and spread around the slopes, ensuring there was enough snow on the ground to guarantee a start to the season come opening weekend.
"That's always been the challenge for the ski industry around the world," Mr Blampied said.
"You really have to wait for the snow before you can open, and natural snow can make that [season opening] come earlier or later.
"Conventional snowmaking gives you a little bit more surety around that, but with this technology and this approach to snowmaking we can guarantee an opening date."
New machinery churning out snow

Mt Buller is not the only mountain that has introduced the snowfactory type of machine this year.
The much smaller, family-focused Selwyn Snow Resort in the New South Wales Snowy Mountains has adopted a similar system on a smaller scale.
Colin Hackworth, chief executive of the Australian Ski Areas Association, which represents ski lift operators, predicts other resorts will follow suit and invest in the technology, which he describes as working like an industrial ice-cream churner.
"You plug it in, put water in one side and there's a drum that spins around inside that freezes the water and it gets spat out the other end as ice particles," he said.
Mr Hackworth thinks this way of making snow could be a game changer for resorts, particularly early in the season when there is a buzz about visiting the snow, but often little natural snowfall.
"This will make snow at 30 degrees Celsius. In April and May you can start making these big piles of ice chips and actually they are very resilient. They take a long time to melt," he said.
"When it comes close to the ski season you doze them all out with a machine so you have guaranteed snow.
"In years going forward all the resorts will have snow on the ground. June will become a regular part of the ski season. Before it was very much touch and go."
It is a huge leap from the early days of snowmaking in Australia, when manually operated snow gun systems were used to top up natural falls.
"Technology has improved from manual snow guns where someone has to go and turn the tap on and off in the middle of the night, to automated systems with their own weather stations," Mr Hackworth said.
Coping with climate change

Australian ski seasons have always been hugely variable from year to year, but the long-term trend for natural snowfall is towards declining levels of natural snowfall.
The CSIRO's  predicts, under a low-risk scenario, the average snow season across Victoria and some of New South Wales will become 20 to 55 days shorter and, under a worst-case scenario, 30 to 80 days shorter.
Victoria's Alpine Resorts Co-ordinating Council also commissioned , published last year, which found seasons had been getting shorter with less overall snow depth since the 1960s.
That trend was tipped to accelerate, while winter weather would become more unpredictable.
The council's executive officer Ian Swan said it was not a rosy outlook.
"The general feeling is that you will still get the cold fronts that will come through and dump a lot snow," Mr Swan said.

But he said little top-ups of snow falling in between the big dumps were predicted to not happen as regularly.
Mr Swan said a warming climate was also likely to affect the ability of resorts to operate conventional snowmaking machines.
His organisation is working on promoting winter activities that are not as reliant on big snowfalls, such as dog sled tours and snow-shoeing, to appeal to a broader base of visitors, as well as attracting visitors to alpine regions in the non-winter months.
Ploughing money into making snow

While snowmaking in Australia started as a way to smooth out some of the seasonal variability, it has increasingly become part of a strategy to mitigate the effects of climate change.
Australia's largest ski resort, Perisher in New South Wales, has spent $22 million in the past decade on expanding and upgrading its snowmaking capacity to cover more than 53 hectares of the resort with 236 snow guns, and has plans to increase the area covered to 110 hectares.
Even much smaller resorts like Lake Mountain, close to Melbourne, and Tasmania's Ben Lomond, have introduced snow guns to bolster natural snowfall.
Adrian Beswick, of the Ben Lomond Committee, said while the mountain was still heavily reliant on natural snow for skiing, the man-made snow had made a massive difference in generating a buzz and drawing tourists for snow play.

Mr Hackworth said many resorts could now open large areas of ski fields with no natural snow at all
"What the industry unquestionably has embraced is that they are no longer reliant on natural snowfalls," he said.
"If it comes to pass that climate change delivers zero snowfall, the resorts will cope with it."
What is at stake if alpine resorts cannot adapt to climate change is more than $1 billion in regional tourism spending and about 10,000 seasonal jobs.
The future of snow in Australia

At Mt Buller, Mr Blampied said snowmaking had proven to be a successful adaptive strategy for climate change, but he conceded it did have limitations, with more snowmaking requiring more water.

"Ultimately the availability of water will dictate the extent of the snowmaking system at any given resort," he said.
"If you had limitless water you could put snowmaking on every trail.
"We don't have that luxury here at Mt Buller and we are in the process of securing a planning permit for an additional 100 megalitre storage which can be filled from the existing water rights."
Mr Hackworth credits advances in snowmaking with helping Australian ski regions record steady visitation levels, with slow growth year on year, even in the face of unpredictable seasons, and he predicts it will keep playing a vital role in years to come.
"People seem to think the Australian ski industry is going to disappear - well, it's not," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Alpine Resorts Co-ordinating Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Beswick, of the Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales Snowy Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Swan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 1907</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSIRO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Blampied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blampied</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wikipedia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lomond Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwyn Snow Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Buller</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perisher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Hackworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Mountain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hackworth</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother Nature</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celsius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Swan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buller Ski Lifts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania's Ben Lomond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ski Areas Association</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
