<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427999359032577</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/real-estate/queensland/cairns/mission-beach-slowly-starts-to-regain-its-former-touch/news-story/91f674139250ebff2501a0b19c714aca</url>
  <title>Mission Beach slowly starts to regain its former touch - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Tourist Daisy Hijnen, 23, holidays in Mission Beach Photographer: Liam Kidston.

THE forecast is starting to look more promising for a beloved Far North coastal community.
Truus Biddlecombe-Sanders has lived through the highs and lows of Mission Beach since she moved to the famous tourism town with her husband Patrick Biddlecombe in 1997.
"After arriving in Australia we lived in Melbourne, Cairns and the Gold Coast but decided to retire here," she said.
"We had been all over the world: there were the Caribbean beaches and African outback; but Mission Beach offered us everything."
Every day Mrs Biddlecombe-Sanders walks along the beach with her dog, and on a Friday evening will enjoy a seaside drink with friends.
She said Mission Beach had not lost any of its charm over the past two decades.
"Of course it has grown but the village atmosphere very much remains," she said.
"I don't think it will change much; it is too far from the airport to become like Port Douglas."
The Wongaling Beach resident, who sits on the Mission Beach Community Association committee, said she hoped to remain in the town for as long as possible.
While a traditional favourite among Far North holiday-makers, Mission Beach recorded a population of 815 in the 2016 Census - a slight increase from 765 in 2011.
But like the entire Cassowary Coast, the community's property market has been languishing for almost a decade.
This was compounded by the devastation wreaked by cyclones Larry and Yasi.
But while still well below the levels reached in 2007, when Mission Beach median house prices soared above $400,000, the local real estate market is showing signs of improvement.
"The Cassowary Coast market has been gradually rebuilding in volume from the 20-year low it experienced in 2011, which coincided with market disruption caused by Cyclone Yasi," said Herron Todd White research director Rick Carr.
"Mission Beach has been through the worst and prices there are starting to slowly rebuild, but market conditions in Innisfail are still flat.
"Meanwhile the median house prices in Cardwell and Tully have tended to reduce."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herron Todd White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission Beach Community Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caribbean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innisfail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daisy Hijnen, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Biddlecombe-Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wongaling Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Biddlecombe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Yasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Truus Biddlecombe-Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassowary Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission Beach Photographer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Kidston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission Beach</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
