<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428218402367644</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/the-best-social-soirees-of-the-week-roxy-jacenko-and-erin-molan-talk-weddings-20170802-gxnmdd.html</url>
  <title>The best social soirees of the week: Roxy Jacenko and Erin Molan talk weddings</title>
  <content>
This time last year she was undergoing an operation for breast cancer while her husband, Oliver Curtis, celebrated his 31st birthday behind bars at Cooma Correctional Centre.
But fast-forward 12 months and all eyes were on an uber-glamorous Roxy Jacenko in a monochrome ensemble accessorised with her new 6.5-carat round-cut diamond engagement ring at the launch of Birkenhead Point's multimillion-dollar fashion precinct on Tuesday.
Photo gallery
Arriving in style in a black Aston Martin, worth a cool $400,000, the Sweaty Betty boss, who  to her husband of five years, Curtis,  about how his 12-month prison stint had taken a toll on their relationship. 
"The reality is I didn't know whether we'd stay together, that's the truth ... I didn't think there was any hope," she said.

Jacenko has yet to start planing their wedding, not too unlike Channel Nine's  The NRL Footy Show host, Erin Molan, who told Fairfax Media she and her fiance, police officer Sean Ogilvy, had yet to even decide on a location.
"We have not planned a thing. We won't wait that long. He's 42 and I am 33 ... but we are just waiting for a day to sit down and actually try and plan," she said.

"I'm so bad with all of that stuff; logistically, I just don't really care. We are very normal, simple people. As long as both of our families are there, that's all we really care about.
"For now we are just enjoying being engaged." 
Holly Asser, Jacenko's right-hand publicist at Sweaty Betty, oversaw the event that included a champagne-filled morning tea at a hedged pop-up French bistro, to welcome high-end store Bally and Harrolds to the Drummoyne outlet centre.
At the same time across town on Castlereagh Street, Cerrone celebrated its 45th anniversary with a rare diamond exhibition. An impressive 450 carats were on display, curated by society jeweller Nicola Cerrone.
Studio 10's Ita Buttrose was spotted trying on a 20-carat white oval-cut diamond worth $4.2 million for size, while 60 Minutes reporter Allison Langdon slipped on a $4.7 million, ​7.37-carat pink radiant-cut number.
Other heroes on display guests that could peruse as they sipped Veuve Clicquot included a $2.9 million, 1.52 carat blue pear-cut; and a 1.04 carat, deep green cushion-cut diamond valued at $865,000.
No one left empty-handed; each guest received a pair of Cerrone rose gold earrings valued at $500.
Later that evening at the Museum of Contemporary Art at The Rocks, overlooking the Sydney Opera House, one of the world's leading celebrity make-up artists for Marc Jacobs Beauty, Hung Van Ngo, unveiled six new Eye-conic Multi-finish Eyeshadow Palettes for the brand.
Hung, who has worked with the likes of Katy Perry, Karlie Kloss, Selena Gomez and Kendall Jenner, to name but a few, took to the stage to share his tricks of the trade with the gathered beauty industry types, media and influencers.
"Don't be afraid to experiment. It's not like a haircut, if you don't like [your make-up] you can wipe it off," Hung said.
He also suggested to go where no man or woman had gone since the 1980s - blue eyeshadow. "It's fun and it looks good with all eye colours; there are no rules," he said.
As seen on Sundays in The Sun-Herald's S liftout.
Do you have a Sydney social event coming up? Email amy.croffey@fairfaxmedia.com.au.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Curtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun-Herald's S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cerrone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ita Buttrose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allison Langdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Van Ngo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooma Correctional Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aston Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eye-conic Multi-finish Eyeshadow Palettes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicola Cerrone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Asser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katy Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Molan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacenko</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birkenhead Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendall Jenner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL Footy Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlereagh Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy Jacenko</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selena Gomez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drummoyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karlie Kloss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Veuve Clicquot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweaty Betty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Jacobs Beauty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museum of Contemporary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Ogilvy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
