<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427990769097905</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/cairns/welcome-to-your-own-oasis-of-peace/news-story/8b2b040610643caf8831bcfc4c086888</url>
  <title>Welcome to your own oasis of peace - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
94 Cassowary St, Freshwater

TWO years in a tranquil Freshwater home have given David and Stephanie Gandy the tropical lifestyle change they desperately craved.
The pair bought the five-bedroom house at 94 Cassowary St in September 2015 after a hellish few years in their beloved Christchurch, the New Zealand South Island city which was rocked by a catastrophic earthquake in February 2011.
"Our house was very badly damaged, effectively written off, and we knew people who had been killed," Mr Gandy said.
"We needed some time for us, and decided we'd go somewhere beautiful like Cairns for a couple of years.
"We had been here for a holiday, and absolutely loved it."
They were no strangers to the "challenge" of settling down in a new country, despite having very few plans or friends to meet.
"We just arrived in New Zealand from England in 2004 ... and thought we'd do the same here," said Mr Gandy, a business consultant.
But they did do some real estate research before coming to Cairns and, like many househunters, were drawn to the city-fringe suburb of Freshwater.
"We did our homework and looked at various options around the place, but Freshwater ticked all the boxes," he said.
"It's close to the city, Northern Beaches and airport, which was handy as I regularly fly back to New Zealand for business.

The five-bedroom home is listed for offers above $659,000

"And it has a bit of a village vibe to it, which was very similar to the Christchurch suburb in which we lived."
Set on a 1235sq m lot in a leafy street, their Cairns home has lived up to expectations.
A suspended deck allows for commanding views, with an in-ground swimming pool the backyard's centrepiece.
Mr Gandy said the home's self-sustaining downstairs area - featuring a kitchenette, bathroom and several bedrooms - was ideal for hosting guests.
"We've only just had friends visit us from New Zealand - you don't even notice people when they're downstairs," he said.
Other notable features of the home include a striking European-style bathroom, solar system and "wonderful neighbours".
"You can do plenty of research, but one thing you don't know before you move in is what your neighbours are like - but we've been so lucky," Mr Gandy said.
They have decided to sell to allow more flexibility.
"We might stay in Cairns, but who knows? It depends on what I decide to do for work," he said.
"But we have loved it here and have no regrets about coming at all. We'll really miss the views, location and what this house offers in terms of accommodating guests."
The property is listed through LJ Hooker Cairns Edge Hill for offers above $659,000; inspections can be arranged by appointment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Beaches</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Gandy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassowary St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christchurch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ Hooker Cairns Edge Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand South Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gandy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
