<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427861920077112</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4833844/last-time-we-checked-you-dont-own-the-waves/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Last time we checked you don't own the waves</title>
  <content>
Last time we checked you don't own the waves

exit

Are these waves in Hawaii, south Africa of even South America?
Nope, good ol' Shellharbour.
Our very talented Illawarra Mercury photographer Sylvia Liber took these amazing shots as the surf rolled into Cowries at Shellharbour last week.
How many other surf breaks in the world would you see offer surf like that literally hundreds of metres away from a town centre - Shellharbour Village in this case.

Yep, you can go for a surf, then jump out and walk to get a latte, a beard trim or even a fresh tatt of your latest choosing.
Now what I find interesting is every time we take surf photos like this or the ones from a couple of weeks ago at Barrack Point we get abused or threatened by local surfers for "revealing" the location of the breaks.
Really?
It's bloody surburbia mate? It's not like you've driven four hours in your Kombi and had to walk 10km just to get to it.
There are main roads running straight past these surf breaks so it's not some secret location we're exposing giving you some sort of God-given right to abuse us or our photographer on social media or anywhere else for that matter.
Last time I checked buddy you don't own the waves.

These images should sell our region not just across the country but across the globe.
Look at what surf tourism has done for Tasmania at places like Marrawah or Shipstern Bluff.
We will continue to showcase this region to the world and make no apologies for it.
Tourism for too long has been a poor second cousin in this region and those thousands of people who drive blindly further south from Sydney have every right to realise what they are missing.

Surf's up!
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrack Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God-given</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Mercury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shipstern Bluff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marrawah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
