<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427483962948841</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/woman-drops-35-kilos-meets-dream-guy-at-the-vitamin-store/news-story/b9092b923a77e17218b64f90ba6f6758</url>
  <title>Boyfriend confesses: 'I would have dismissed her'</title>
  <content>
KRISTINA Nedelkovska, a 23-year-old massage therapist living in Montauk, New York, says if she hadn't changed her diet, she never would have met her current boyfriend Sashe Trajanovski. She first laid eyes on 27-year-old Trajanovski at a health and supplement store in Skopje, Macedonia, where she is originally from.
They exchanged numbers and have been dating for a year since then.
"I just went to get some supplements and this handsome guy was there. I wasn't expecting it - he was like a gift from God," Nedelkovska told SWNS.
The pair spent a few hours talking at the store and Trajanovski eventually asked for Nedelkovska's number.
"I don't think I would've asked her to go on a date with me if she had been the weight she was before," he confessed.
Nedelkovska, who gained weight while working on a cruise ship in Europe in 2015, managed to drop 12 dress sizes after drastically changing her eating habits.
Nedelkovska initially packed on the kilos by indulging in Chinese food, hamburgers, and pizza from the boat's all you can eat buffet.
"I was eating like a pregnant woman - for two. The people serving me would say, 'Is that all for you?" Nedelkovska said.
"I started not being able to fit in my uniform after a while," she added.
In the five months she worked on the ship, she put on 30 kilos. She hated her body and was so out of shape that she'd start panting after just a few steps.
It was her family's concern that encouraged her to take her health more seriously.
"Everyone in my family is fit. People would say, 'Oh my God, what have you done with yourself?'" she said
"I love food but I knew something had to change," she added.
Instead of feasting on bread, eggs and sausages every morning for breakfast, she'd have a smoothie along with some honey and lemon water.
She swapped out her constant intake of fattening foods and sugary treats for five small healthy meals per day. She also started going to the gym regularly. After several months of hard work, she lost 35 kilos.
She and her boyfriend encourage one another to stay in shape and regularly exercise together.
"I'm very happy because I met the love of my life. She completes me," he said.
This article originally appeared on the and has been republished with permission.

Coffee is part of a daily routine for most people, but did you know your morning brew can help with weight loss?

Can coffee help you lose weight?
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trajanovski</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montauk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristina Nedelkovska</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sashe Trajanovski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedonia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SWNS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nedelkovska</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skopje</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
