<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428394496029901</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/seven-decades-of-bliss-for-cowper-couple/3208942/</url>
  <title>Seven decades of bliss for Cowper couple</title>
  <content>
AFTER 70 years of marriage, Ray and Gert Connor say the secret to their long and happy marriage is that it is "all about give and take."

Ray and Gert were married in St Paul's Presbyterian Church in Lismore on August 9, 1947 by Reverend James Mortimore. Gert's sister, Marie Olive, was bridesmaid, and Ray's cousin, Ian Benson, was groomsman.

At 94, they are both physically healthy and still self-supporting.

Ray and Gert met aged 21 when Gert, a school teacher, was transferred to Cowper Primary School from Wooli, where she had started her teaching career. At this time, Ray was managing his family's property.

Gert and Ray had three children: Bev (deceased) Pam and Russell, and now have 12 grand- children and 17 great grandchildren.

They have both had a strong involvement in the Clarence community. Ray's two passions, playing cricket and breeding prize Australorp fowls, have played a major part in his local community involvement.

Ray played cricket for many years, both with Lower Clarence and also Easts in Grafton. His last game, with the Golden Oldies, was at the age of 74.

Ray has also been heavily involved in local poultry clubs and has shown prize-winning birds (locally and also throughout Australia) for many years. He is still exhibiting! Ray's book, The Australorp, is highly sought after, within Australia and overseas.

Gert's community involvement has been largely through teaching.

After a break to raise her first two children, Gert returned to work at Lower Coldstream Public School (as sole teacher there) and after several years there, transferred to Ulmarra Public, where she remained until retirement in 1974.

Gert later did some relief teaching, largely at Grafton Infants School, and in South Grafton and Maclean.

Gert has also been a devoted gardener throughout her years in Cowper.

Ray and Gert have also had a strong involvement in the church community, in Cowper, and more recently in South Grafton.

Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Yaroomba Beach project will be "a fantastic coastal village"
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Clarence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Benson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ulmarra Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Coldstream Public School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reverend James Mortimore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowper Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowper</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie Olive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lismore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Grafton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maclean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton Infants School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wooli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Paul's Presbyterian Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Oldies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australorp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
