<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428003654000013</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/real-estate/queensland/cairns/sevenbedroom-parramatta-park-house-shows-how-thinking-outside-the-square-can-pay-off/news-story/bb34652d4103fe0793b30c3e970d85f1</url>
  <title>Seven-bedroom Parramatta Park house shows how thinking outside the square can pay off - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
108 Martyn St, Parramatta Park

SEVEN-BEDROOM Cairns houses are often tucked away in mansion-replete suburbs like Edge Hill and Bayview Heights, but this behemoth Parramatta Park Queenslander goes against the grain.
Built in the 1930s, the home at 108 Martyn St has undergone a significant transformation in recent years.
Now on the market for the first time since 2009, the new-look property is already gaining strong market interest.
"This home was originally a lowset Queenslander that's been lifted," said selling agent Tim Winborn-Sharp of Twomey Schriber Property Group.
"It has 1930s character but all the facilities you'd expect from a contemporary Queenslander."
Set on a 655sq m block, the home has four bedrooms in a self-containing downstairs area; the remaining three, including the master suite, are upstairs.
Mr Winborn-Sharp said the current owners had enjoyed "wonderful success" while listing the property through Airbnb.
He also said it was "very unique" for a Parramatta Park Queenslander to contain seven bedrooms.
Other features include a new magnesium swimming pool, freshly-painted walls and NBN connection.
"The market interest has been phenomenal," he said.
It comes amid a purple patch for properties at Parramatta Park, one of Cairns' older inner-city suburbs. According to the latest CoreLogic statistics, Parramatta Park median house prices have risen by almost 32 per cent over the past three years.
The suburb had an average house selling price of $475,000 during the 12 months to April - well above the Cairns average of $400,000.
Mr Winborn-Sharp said Parramatta Park was emerging as a Cairns real estate hotspot.
"It is definitely an up and coming suburb," he said.
"It has been underrated in the past but it's just so close to the city.
"Places like Edge Hill are always more pricey, but Parramatta Park is a suburb to watch."
The property at 108 Martyn St is open for inspection on Sunday from 12-12.45pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Park Queenslander</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edge Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Winborn-Sharp of Twomey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEDROOM Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schriber Property Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Winborn-Sharp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayview Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Park</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martyn St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
