<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428029423804289</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/the-property-games-been-a-roller-coaster-ride/3207560/</url>
  <title>The property game's been a roller-coaster ride</title>
  <content>
CONGRATULATIONS Sunshine Coast on your 50th year. I have been asked to put my recollections down in a few words and relive some of my memories.
First to mind was my introduction as a business owner in 1999, with a small team in a small office in Ocean St, Maroochydore, with a humming Big Top Shopping Centre on our back door.
Those were the days when you could buy a block of land off Sam White Dr for $32,000, a house in Kuluin for $85,000, a home with a view in Buderim for $250,000 and a property on Oceanic Dr at Kawana for not much more.
But things were about to change!
The first big event we went through was this thing called the First Home Buyers Grant, which was designed to stimulate the sluggish market. For good reasons as well - if you bought a house in 1990 in Buderim you were selling it for the same figure nine years later in 1999.
Almost every trade person was looking for a job in Sydney for the Olympic Games pre-build phase.
The second big event was of course on July 1, 2000: the introduction of GST.
Hang on! I forgot January 1, 2000 and the Y2K Bug, when all things important were about to come to an end. Anyway they didn't and people still continued to look at property.
The introduction of GST did have a small effect on how we did business. Were you GST registered for commercial property? Why do I have to pay GST on the commission? What is and what is not subject to GST? Anyway, by the end of 2000, all had settled down and we all understood the process.
Then the music was about to start with varying hits and flops for the next 17 years.
Away went the market from 2000 to 2004, making up for a decade of sluggishness. That house in Kuluin you missed out on for $85,000 was now $185,000 and the house on Oceanic Dr that you didn't buy for $250,000 was up to $500,000.
It was a great boost but came to an abrupt end in 2005 when the light at the end of the tunnel was actually a train!
Looking back, it was just the market catching its breath.
Then, off the back of a rising southern market, we took off again and this time the Coast wrote its own hit song, with record price after record price, new building after new building and new subdivision after new subdivision.
The house in Kuluin was now worth $425,000 and the Oceanic Dr property $1 million or more!
As usual, after one hit song comes the flop and by January 2008, the Global Financial Crisis took hold. Some saw it coming, some saw it coming but ignored it, and some were blindsided.
The 2008-2012 period was the most taxing and heartbreaking of my 30 years in real estate, seeing how a downturn can affect families, work colleagues, business partners and anyone trying to run a business.
Your house in Kuluin dropped from $425,000 to $300,000 and the property on Oceanic Dr, once worth $1 million, was back down to $600,000.
In April 2012, a significant political shift happened on the Sunshine Coast, with the current Mayor Cr Mark Jamieson and a raft of new councillors elected to lead the recovery of the region. There is no question the current view of the council leadership that we are "open for business" has created job opportunities and the subsequent flow-on effects.
By 2013, recovery was in the air. It was a slow recovery up to 2015 and now as 2016 and the current first half of 2017 continues, the hit song is playing again.
The future looks bright. Hospitals, airports, new designer suburbs and optimism is in the air. Surely it's here for another year or two, when we once again catch our breath and slow down again.
Today, your home in Kuluin is now worth $450,000 and the property on Oceanic Dr is back to $1 million or more.
Brett Graham is director of Ray White Buderim.
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oceanic Dr</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ocean St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Home Buyers Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Top Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuluin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y2K Bug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Financial Crisis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Cr Mark Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam White Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1, 2000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
