<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427999359032604</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/cairns/cairns-is-home-to-an-array-of-beachfront-bargains/news-story/9a66512f27e7c42463884f9a3ae21548</url>
  <title>Cairns is home to an array of beachfront bargains - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
52 Kewarra St, Kewarra Beach.

IF your heart soars at the thought of owning a home on the ocean's doorstep, but you don't necessarily have a spare $2 million, then look towards Cairns' Northern Beaches.
A host of absolute beachfront properties can be snapped up in the Far North for under $1 million.
Data from Herron Todd White shows the Northern Beaches median house price is on an upswing, now sitting above $450,000; median house prices in Cairns more broadly remain about $400,000.
"The Northern Beaches tends to be the recipient of migration into Cairns a lot of the time; and you know that when the Northern Beaches property market is booming, so too is population growth and vice-versa," said HTW Cairns research director Rick Carr.
Exorbitant insurance prices is one downside of living adjacent to a Cairns beach, but the land and house prices remain far more within reach here than many of the southern markets.
Rachel Blok of Ray White Cairns Beaches said value for money was exceptional on the Northern Beaches.
"There are certainly affordable suburbs where people are able to buy along the beachfront, for perhaps a third of what they'd pay in any southern city," she said.
"And you can't find a more picturesque time to present a property than in the middle of a tropical winter - there is a fair bit of stock available right now."
Here are three Northern Beaches that highlight the value for money on offer:
■ 145 O'Shea Esp, Machans Beach
This three-bedroom home, a stone's throw from the Coral Sea, is listed through Marsh Property for offers above $795,000. The attractive, airconditioned home has a pool and could be perfect as an Airbnb host.

145 O'Shea Esp, Machans Beach is listed for offers above $795,000.

■ 52 Kewarra St, Kewarra Beach
This high-end home with direct beach access, on a colossal 1650sq m, is listed through Cairns Beaches Realty for offers above $1.85 million.
A similar home would be nudging the $10 million price range in the Sydney market.

52 Kewarra St, Kewarra Beach, is listed for $1.85 million.

■ 167 O'Shea Esp, Machans Beach
Currently under contract, the charming four-bedroom house was listed for offers above $699,000.

167 O'Shea Esp, Machans Beach
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Shea Esp</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herron Todd White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Beaches</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HTW Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marsh Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Machans Beach</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Beaches Realty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coral Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kewarra Beach</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Cairns Beaches</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kewarra St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Blok of Ray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns' Northern Beaches</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
