<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428166862759391</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/cairns-man-labelled-serious-violent-offender-for-ganglandstyle-kidnapping/news-story/f7da4ae989f61c322e3cd65a6d72f7cc</url>
  <title>'his shirt was drenched in blood'</title>
  <content>
DEEP in grip of an ice addition, Melchor Restauro Garcia's life spiralled out of control and into the shady underworld of drugs and revenge.
A seven month crime spree littered with weapons and drug offending, escalated to violence when he kidnapped Maitland Chitty in February last year.
Garcia pleaded guilty last month to 24 offences between July 2015 and February 2016 including torturing Mr Chitty.
"The gravity of your prolonged gangland-style criminal conduct is extraordinary when considered in light of the complete absence of convictions prior to your offending... in 2015," Supreme Court Justice James Henry said yesterday as he jailed the 31-year-old for seven years.
Garcia kidnapped Mr Chitty, believing he'd been ripped off.
Mr Chitty was taken to shipping container on a remote Kuranda property and tortured violently.
Justice Henry said this included hitting Chitty with an axe handle, stabbing him twice in the arm with a knife, choking him and kneeing and punching him while he was tied to a cross beam with material over his head and a noose around his neck.

"He screamed in pain," Justice Henry said.

"Blood was dripping down Chitty's arms and pooling under his feet.
"He begged for forgiveness.

"He bled so profusely his shirt was drenched in blood."
Other violence Garcia unleashed on Mr Chitty included hitting him with a lump of timber, threatening to cut off his toes and threatening to kill him.
Garcia later drove Mr Chitty, still bound and gagged, along Black Mountain Rd to bushland at Mona Mona where he was forced to swallow five pills, a hangman's noose was placed around his neck and he was tied to a tree and left.
"Leaving him with no food or water or any means to send for help in a drugged, bloodied, bruised state," Justice Henry said.

"He could have died."
The court was told that Garcia had struggled with the relationship breakdown with the mother of his 10-year-old son and began using drugs.
Justice Henry declared Garcia a serious violent offender, meaning he must complete 80 per cent of the sentence before he is eligible for parole.
Garcia has already spent 523 days in jail.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melchor Restauro Garcia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuranda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chitty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mona Mona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Mountain Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Chitty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court Justice James Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garcia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Henry</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chitty</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
