<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427200495101525</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:05</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/job-interview-thank-you-note-2017-8</url>
  <title>A recruiter who's held 5,000 job interviews explains the strategy that always catches his eye</title>
  <content>
PwC US talent acquisition lead  has interviewed a lot of people.

Over the course of his career with the "Big Four" accounting firm, Adams has interviewed about 5,000 candidates.

He says that most interviewees  after the interview. They call, mail handwritten notes, and send emails.

But Adams doesn't care about the medium of .

He's looking for one thing - listening skills.

"When the follow-up is personal, that's when it stands out," Adams tells Business Insider. "They picked up on something in the conversation that they referred back to in the follow-up."

So, how can you personalise your post-interview follow-up? It's as simple as sending a book recommendation or an article related to a topic that you discussed with the interviewer. , so the conversation should still be fresh in your mind.

In addition to a personalised follow-up being more thoughtful then a standard "thank you," it demonstrates that you can listen and that you were engaged throughout the interview.

"That personal touch to the follow-up is something I see multiple candidates do that has been impactful," Adams says.

NOW WATCH: Ideas videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adams</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PwC US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
