<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428347251388663</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:32</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/punishment-exercises-would-cause-distress-trial-to/3208990/</url>
  <title>Punishment exercises would cause distress, trial told</title>
  <content>
A PEDIATRICIAN has told a court a young girl would have suffered if she had been made to do punishment exercises.
The doctor made the comments as she testified in Brisbane District Court during a trial where a 58-year-old man is accused of torturing children.
Multiple witnesses this week said the five-year-old Queensland girl was kept in squalid conditions and repeatedly soiled herself.
The court also heard allegations a child was made to repeatedly stand up and sit down, march on the spot and lift her knee up high.
The 58-year-old, who cannot be identified, has pleaded not guilty to four torture charges.
The pediatrician concluded the punishment alleged "would have been distressing at the time both physically and emotionally" but that did not mean the girl would suffer long-term damage.
She said similar exercises, done in the context of a short warm-up, were not necessarily problematic.
But if a child was made to do such exercises continually for up to 30 minutes "it would be very likely the child would get fatigued," the doctor said.
A different court has dealt with other adults who faced charges related to the alleged abuse.
Earlier, the trial heard allegations the girl was kept for up to five hours in a room which had its door handle removed.
The accused man, during a police interview played to the jury, said the girl was sometimes "sitting in her own sh*t all day".
Crown Prosecutor Victoria Trafford-Walker earlier told the jury the accused man and his co-accused would take the children to rough, steep dirt tracks in forests near the Sunshine Coast.
Adults would "hold" the children's hair or arms and "force" them to run beside the moving cars for up to 5km, the jury heard.
Defence counsel Simon Hamlyn-Harris said the accused man denied claims he tortured his own stepchildren.
He told the jury his client admitted giving the other adults "parenting advice". The trial continues. -NewsRegional
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Victoria Trafford-Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NewsRegional</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Hamlyn-Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
