<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428012243934789</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/from-a-fishing-town-to-holiday-favourite/3207539/</url>
  <title>From a fishing town to holiday favourite</title>
  <content>
THE Henzells story began in 1935 when founding forefather Roy Henzell, in partnership with a local Kings Beach shopkeeper, established a small real estate agency in Caloundra, giving the keen fisherman an ideal excuse to permanently relocate from Brisbane.
The Caloundra he fell in love with - a sleepy fishing town, with much of the surrounding area being tea-tree swamp - was vastly different to the one we know today.
For generations, Henzells Agency has been a major influence in shaping the landscape of Caloundra and the broader Sunshine Coast, both in its physical appearance and the lifestyle on offer.
In 1946, Roy purchased 810 hectares of land on the coast of Caloundra which would later become the master planned Pelican Waters community. He acquired the land for 2000 English pounds with development in mind. However, he could never have imagined the success story it would become.
Today, Roy Henzell junior, the grandson of Roy Henzell, along with partner Garry Waters and the firm's development team continue to build on the dream and the family legacy.
"When my grandad purchased the land, he definitely saw a future in the development of the land, though not to the extent that Pelican Waters is now," Mr Henzell said.
"He didn't envisage the canals, waterways and parks that we have today. His early plans were probably more in line with conventional subdivisions, with estate after estate."
Roy Henzell junior's father, Bevan Henzell, took over Pelican Waters when Roy was eight years old and came up with an idea that revolutionised the master-planned community.
"When my father took over, he had the idea of a main canal," Mr Henzell said.
"From that one idea, we have since developed lakes, waterways and a lock and weir system."
Roy Henzell took the helm of the family business in 1984 when his father died. He was 29 years old and ran the family business in partnership with his mother Judy Henzell until 1990, when he invited long-time friend Garry Waters to join as a partner and implement the development of Pelican Waters.
It has proved to be a highly-successful combination resulting in more than 3000 lots of land selling in Pelican Waters alone in the ensuing years, with a further 2250 dwelling lots in the planning for its final releases surrounding the emerging marina and town centre precinct in the estate's southern reaches.
The impact of the Henzells real estate business has been even greater, with more than 19,000 properties sold at an average of 20 per month since opening its doors 80 years ago, helping to transform the region from a sleepy fishing village to the sophisticated coastal destination it is today.
Henzells is a leading force in guiding the look and feel of Caloundra and surrounding areas through the development and marketing of some of the region's best-known residential apartment and land projects.
Since the 1990s alone, Henzells has marketed almost 50 residential apartment projects in the region including Rumba Resort (73 units), Monaco, (89 units), Outlook (49 units), Ramada Resort (116 units), Vardon Point (110 units) and Linear (40 units).
The company's reputation and expertise in the apartment project sector has seen it responsible for the marketing of in excess of 60% of all built form in the region.
Henzells continues to build its legacy as the leading expert for project development and marketing on the Sunshine Coast, with a number of exciting projects under way including the $15million residential sanctuary, The Carlyle Terraces, at Pelican Waters and boutique luxury apartments Ocean Verge at Kings Beach.
Entire suburbs have been shaped by Henzells including Aroona, Ridgehaven, Currimundi, Golden Beach and Pelican Waters.
Other development highlights include the Greg Norman-designed golf course and the region's only 4.5 star hotel - Pelican Waters Golf Resort and Spa - plus a major shopping centre, waterfront tavern and the soon-to-be-built town centre and marina precinct.
More than bricks and mortar, Henzells has also contributed greatly to community projects such as donating land for the Caloundra Cricket Club, Golden Beach bowls and tennis clubs and Caloundra City Private School, establishing numerous parks, building bridges and canals and raising hundreds of thousands of dollars for local charities and sporting groups.
Henzells' principals past and present including Roy Henzell Senior, Bevan Henzell, Roy Henzell and Garry Waters have been outstanding contributors to the community, serving on numerous councils and committees as well as founding and leading a wide variety of sporting, educational, health, community and fundraising organisations.
"As proud as we are of what has been achieved, the most exciting part of the Henzells and Pelican Waters stories is what lies ahead, such as the new town centre and marina project and the benefits to flow from the development of the Kawana health precinct and other major infrastructure projects in the pipeline," Mr Henzell said.
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Waters</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco, (89</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramada Resort (116</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pelican Waters</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ridgehaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Henzell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra City Private School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Henzell Senior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outlook (49</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bevan Henzell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlyle Terraces</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rumba Resort (73</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aroona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Norman-designed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Henzell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henzell</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Cricket Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henzells Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Henzell</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vardon Point (110</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pelican Waters Golf Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currimundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linear (40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ocean Verge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
