<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427999359032628</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/recipe-curried-salmon-rice-bake/3209045/</url>
  <title>Recipe: Curried salmon rice bake</title>
  <content>
RETRO. We embrace it - in all its forms - these days and the kitchen is no exception. In recent days I've enjoyed beef stroganoff, pepper steak and lemon delicious pudding, and who doesn't love a prawn cocktail in summer?
A neighbour's very welcome dinner invitation last week was accompanied by an apology that she was serving retro food. I was half expecting a pineapple spiked with toothpicks bearing Kraft cheese chunks, cabanossi and cocktail onions, but no, it was a nutritious curried salmon bake, the recipe for which was popular circa 1972.
It was truly delicious. The house was filled with an enticing aroma that made my mouth water, and it tasted as good as it smelled.
We all started reminiscing about favourite dishes from those days and I am now determined to find a fondue pot in one of our local op shops, as the crusty bread dipped in melted cheese was always a favourite.
But until then I'll have to revisit my youth with this winter warmer. It's easy to make and uses common pantry supplies such as canned salmon, brown rice and evaporated milk, so it's something you can whip up in no time if unexpected guests pop in.
You can use any vegetables you happen to have in the fridge; I've used zucchini but corn, grated kumara or asparagus would taste great also.
You can spice it up a little more by adding more curry powder if you like it hot.
Curried salmon rice bake
Serves 6
INGREDIENTS:
2 tbs olive oil, divided
2 cups cooked brown rice
1 x 415g can red salmon, drained and bones removed, flaked
1 zucchini, finely sliced
1 x 375ml can evaporated milk
2 large free-range eggs, beaten
2 tbs each chopped fresh flat leaf parsley and dill
1 tsp curry powder
1 1/2 cups grated tasty cheddar cheese
salt and pepper, to taste
fresh lemon wedges, to serve
METHOD: Preheat oven to 170C. Use a little of the oil to grease a 2 litre baking dish.
In a medium bowl, combine rice, salmon, zucchini, milk, the remainder of the oil, eggs, herbs, curry powder and half the cheese. Pour into baking dish, season to taste and top with remaining cheese.
Bake at 170C for 40 minutes or until set and golden brown on top.
Serve with mashed potatoes and steamed vegetables or a salad.
Contact Maggie at maggies.column@bigpond.com
Scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy waterways retained
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kraft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C. Use</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maggie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
