<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428257057073928</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/private-sydney/private-sydney-heiress-grace-forrest-denies-being-a-philanthropist-20170803-gxofaz.html</url>
  <title>Heiress Grace Forrest denies being a philanthropist</title>
  <content>
They just don't make heiresses like they used to, or at least they don't when they come from the billionaire Forrest clan.
No extravagant birthday parties, no social debuts in Paris, no front row fashion show appearances, no glitzy weddings, no $20,000 handbags and no string of handsome boyfriends filling up gossip columns.Photo: Hugh Stewart
Instead for 24-year-old Grace Forrest and her actor sister Sophia, 22, it's all work, work, work.
The daughters of mining mogul and philanthropist Andrew Twiggy Forrest have been on something of a publicity campaign in recent months, Sophia making her first major outing in Sunday Life magazine last month, while next monday it is big sister Grace's turn, with a revealing interview in the glossy pages of Harper's Bazaar Australia.Photo: Liz Looker
"I'm actually working as a researcher with a think tank called the Legatum Institute," she tells the magazine from her new London home. "Their aim is to understand and tackle the great challenges that face humanity."
Clearly the University of Notre Dame Australia graduate, who is now completing a master's degree in strategic communications, is not one to shy away from seemingly huge challenges. She and her father organised for faith leaders from around the world, including the Pope, to meet at the Vatican and sign a collective pledge to end slavery by 2020.

She is also a founding director of the Walk Free Foundation, which seeks to eliminate modern slavery and is funded by the Forrest family's Minderoo Foundation.

You will now receive updates from

Daily Life Newsletter

Daily Life Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In May her parents announced they would be donating $400 million of their personal $5 billion plus fortune to charity, $75 million of which was pledged to end modern slavery.
But don't label her a "philanthropist".
"Well, technically I'm not one," she says. "I also don't really like the separation in - dare I say it - class, which means when someone very wealthy gives away a small percentage of their fortune they are a philanthropist, but when a young family must manage their budget but they buy fair-trade tea or coffee or support a child's education in another country, that's not considered philanthropy. Often that family is giving up a lot more of their income, percentage-wise, and is also making a conscious decision to make positive change.
"Generosity is generosity; sharing one's wealth to help others less fortunate is powerful no matter what the number is or what you call it."
In the magazine spread, Grace also takes on the role of fashion model, though PS understands she was very specific in the labels she would wear for Harper's, ensuring that only "ethical" brands were included. No doubt that $32,300 Cartier watch fit the bill nicely given Cartier's extensive corporate responsibility policy.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper's Bazaar Australia.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vatican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Notre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walk Free Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grace Forrest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Twiggy Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minderoo Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legatum Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cartier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forrest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz Looker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
