<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428042308706371</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sc2067-group-fights-for-a-green-sunshine-coast-fut/3209046/</url>
  <title>SC2067: Group fights for a green Sunshine Coast future</title>
  <content>
COAST conservationist Narelle McCarthy says understanding a "collapsing Ponzi scheme" approach to the region's growth is vital to achieving sustainable progress.

Ms McCarthy and her colleague Leah Hays represent long-standing advocacy group the Sunshine Coast Environment Council.

They hope the region's scenic amenity, abundant biodiversity and healthy natural waterways will be retained in the coming half century.

Ms McCarthy said economic prosperity based on population growth was unsustainable.

"(We will achieve balance) by the development industry accepting the science which demonstrates the tenuous status of biodiversity and ecosystems and the need to reign in inappropriate development which has unacceptable environmental impacts and climate risk," Ms McCarthy said.

She expected Sekisui House's Yaroomba site would feature accommodation in 2067 but hoped it would be in a different form to the current proposed project.

"(I hope it will be) a low-rise ecoluxe resort on the entire site which is sympathetic to the natural environment and surrounding amenity and community- not a high-density residential estate with buildings as currently proposed.

"This beach provides optimal nesting attributes as it is a dark beach with no light glow which has supported increased numbers of turtles nesting here."

from  on .

Ms McCarthy said a low-rise resort embodying sustainable design principles and architecture would complement the area's amenity; providing a niche and desirable tourism offering and thereby contributing to the local economy.

She said the conservation status of the endangered loggerhead turtle would improve through increased numbers of nesting turtles and successful hatchlings if environmental values of the area were respected.

"As the ocean (in 2067) has warmed through climate change, Sunshine Coast beaches like Yaroomba provide critical nesting sites for the survival of marine turtles."

She and Miss Hays hoped wildlife corridors would be expanded upon.

"This would be a joint achievement between local council, private land owners, land care groups and State Government," Miss Hays said.

"(I hope there will be) green bridges across highways and main roads for wildlife to move across the built up environment with ease; as well as widespread use of wildlife bridges over roads to ensure safe movement for arboreal animals."

She said she hoped for an integrated public transport system which featured electric light rail.

"Electric bikes will become widely used, with ample safe space for bicycle users on our roads.

"Electric car charging stations will be at all service stations, shopping malls, schools and community spaces.

She hoped everyday fossil fuel vehicle use would be banned.

"New villages and towns will be smartly positioned around transport corridors and light rail, thus having reduced need for fossil fuel vehicles all together."

Ms McCarthy said the Coast had many special attributes that must be preserved.

"Its character, natural environment, rich cultural heritage and lifestyle are under increasing pressure from such things as escalating and increasingly inappropriate development, climate change, overpopulation and biodiversity loss," Ms McCarthy said.

"These compounding threats need to be tackled objectively through genuine collaboration and evidence-based policies with a degree of urgency.

"The Sunshine Coast community and its visitors highly value the scenic and natural amenity of this region and it is beholden on us all to be its stewards - now and in the future."

"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Professor Ian Lowe hopes the Coast will retain its natural appeal
Hopes children of 2067 will enjoy the same natural attractions
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Celebs are bravely stepping into the Kitchen with Marco Pierre White
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
REIQ members played pivotal role in naming of the Sunshine Coast.
Seclusion without isolation on magical 31ha Noosa holding
House and island for $3,500,000
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narelle McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Hays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sekisui House's Yaroomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC2067</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McCarthy</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leah Hays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ponzi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Environment Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
