<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427655761643613</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/mcdonalds-attempt-to-win-over-millennials-with-sriracha-backfires-2017-8</url>
  <title>People are ripping apart McDonald's latest attempt to win over millennials</title>
  <content>
As  tries to capture the attention of  the fast-food chain has turned to some familiar millennial bail: sriracha. 

In July, McDonald's added a  to the menu for a limited time. And, in August, the chain began serving Sriracha Mac Sauce in packets perfect for nugget dunking.

While sriracha has been associated with restaurants trying to stay on trend for , this time it looks like not everyone is willing to bite. 

The first sign something was wrong in sriracha paradise was the response to an Inc. article with the headline

On Twitter, people were quick to point out that sriracha was not millennials' favourite ingredient. Instead, the generation was craving something else  - universal healthcare, possibly, or maybe just some Adderall. 

A second strike against the Sriracha burger came this week, with a

"[T]he sriracha-and-kale combo smacks of desperation," Tim Carman writes. "It reeks of a corporate attempt to capitalise on two of the biggest food trends of the past decade (although far after each has peaked). It's the fast-food equivalent of watching your Dad sport rompers and pledge his undying love for Drake.

Ultimately, Carman finds the premise of the burger to be more offensive than the actual sriracha, which he says is fine, especially on the crispy chicken breast. (The kale is another story, as its too tough to be any sort of positive contribution to the burger.) 

Carmen's response and the Twitter backlash to Inc's "millennials" tweet reveal an inherent truth in fast food in 2017: nothing is wrong with adding new menu items, as long as chains don't try to be cool while doing so. 

In fact, many people are enthused about McDonald's serving sriracha.

Sriracha has lost its hipster charm. But, on a basic level, it's still just plain tasty - unlike kale, which has no place on a fast-food burger. 

If something it makes McDonald's burgers and nuggets taste better, that's all the chain needs - not an awkward attempt to appeal to "millennials."  

how do you get universal healthcare on top of a burger
- Jacob Rees-Strogg (@PrototypeCube)

finally a burger with Adderall
- slackbot (@pareene)

Mmmm... student loan debt forgiveness
- Brandy Lambert (@BrandyLamby)

McDonald's Sriracha Big Mac sauce is....
- Kyle Federline (@KyleFederline)

I want to eat that new sriracha burger at McDonald's.
I can't believe I want to eat something at McDonald's.
- Cesar R. (@BigC927)

Sriracha Mac Sauce ! Out everywhere The 25 or 26th !!! It's GOOD BTW
- luis (@LuisCyrus__)

McDonald's came out with this new sriracha Big Mac sauce and its amazing
- syd (@_sydneyjaclyn_)

This new sriracha Mac sauce from McDonald's is so good with these nuggets.
- asiamariah (@muglizzy)

PSA McDonalds has sriracha mac sauce and it's amazing.
- Mackenzie Jones (@mackycheez)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GOOD BTW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Federline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BigC927</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adderall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sriracha Mac Sauce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Carman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald's Sriracha Big Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BrandyLamby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LuisCyrus__</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackenzie Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KyleFederline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sriracha</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSA McDonalds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PrototypeCube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cesar R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Rees-Strogg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandy Lambert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mmmm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
