<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428007948967400</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/recipe-curried-salmon-rice-bake/3209045/</url>
  <title>Recipe: Curried salmon rice bake</title>
  <content>
RETRO. We embrace it - in all its forms - these days and the kitchen is no exception. In recent days I've enjoyed beef stroganoff, pepper steak and lemon delicious pudding, and who doesn't love a prawn cocktail in summer?
A neighbour's very welcome dinner invitation last week was accompanied by an apology that she was serving retro food. I was half expecting a pineapple spiked with toothpicks bearing Kraft cheese chunks, cabanossi and cocktail onions, but no, it was a nutritious curried salmon bake, the recipe for which was popular circa 1972.
It was truly delicious. The house was filled with an enticing aroma that made my mouth water, and it tasted as good as it smelled.
We all started reminiscing about favourite dishes from those days and I am now determined to find a fondue pot in one of our local op shops, as the crusty bread dipped in melted cheese was always a favourite.
But until then I'll have to revisit my youth with this winter warmer. It's easy to make and uses common pantry supplies such as canned salmon, brown rice and evaporated milk, so it's something you can whip up in no time if unexpected guests pop in.
You can use any vegetables you happen to have in the fridge; I've used zucchini but corn, grated kumara or asparagus would taste great also.
You can spice it up a little more by adding more curry powder if you like it hot.
Curried salmon rice bake
Serves 6
INGREDIENTS:
2 tbs olive oil, divided
2 cups cooked brown rice
1 x 415g can red salmon, drained and bones removed, flaked
1 zucchini, finely sliced
1 x 375ml can evaporated milk
2 large free-range eggs, beaten
2 tbs each chopped fresh flat leaf parsley and dill
1 tsp curry powder
1 1/2 cups grated tasty cheddar cheese
salt and pepper, to taste
fresh lemon wedges, to serve
METHOD: Preheat oven to 170C. Use a little of the oil to grease a 2 litre baking dish.
In a medium bowl, combine rice, salmon, zucchini, milk, the remainder of the oil, eggs, herbs, curry powder and half the cheese. Pour into baking dish, season to taste and top with remaining cheese.
Bake at 170C for 40 minutes or until set and golden brown on top.
Serve with mashed potatoes and steamed vegetables or a salad.
Contact Maggie at maggies.column@bigpond.com
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kraft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C. Use</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maggie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
