<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427436718307653</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/2798346/brain-cancer-battler-swamped-by-support/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Brain cancer battler swamped by support</title>
  <content>
Dying man still must job hunt 
 JOHN Grayson feels ''humbled'' by the avalanche of support  he has received since sharing his  story of living with a brain tumour.

The  Newcastle Herald reported at the weekend how terminally ill Mr Grayson, pictured, had been told he was ineligible for the Disability Support Pension, as he is still relatively physically healthy and hasn't yet begun radiotherapy. Instead, the 33-year-old from Lambton faced  spending his precious time documenting his search for work and visiting employment agencies  to  receive the Newstart allowance.
- John Grayson
 The community response to his plight was overwhelming.
''Viral is  the best way to put it,'' he said. ''It was an explosion ...
 ''It was syndicated through Fairfax but also ended up on the Indianapolis Post, in Shanghai media and on Reddit's Australia page.
''Even a lot of people from high school who I hadn't spoken to for 15 years were contacting me, which was really uplifting.''
 Mr Grayson's story garnered 207 comments on the Herald's website. It was shared 218 times on Facebook,  receiving another 236 comments.
''If I win even a $1,000,000 in lotto tonight I'll make sure you don't have to work again matey, stay strong,'' reader Josh Bellamy promised.
 ''John, I really hope and pray that what should come your way, happens without difficulties,'' Theresa Neill wrote on Facebook.
 Among those taking interest in Mr Grayson's case was music promoter AJ Maddah, who founded the Soundwave festival  and owned a stake in the Big Day Out.  ''I'll reach out and see if he wants some work with our crew,'' Maddah pledged on Twitter. 
Mr Grayson was contacted with offers to host a fund-raiser for him.
''It was very humbling and generous: I said thank-you, but no thank-you,'' he said. ''They say there's always someone worse off than you - I'm 33, but there are children with cancer who are facing an even worse situation than I am.

''I've asked for anyone who wants to donate to contact Starlight Children's Foundation.''
Mr Grayson was studying for a combined  engineering and science degree and working part-time when he started having focal seizures, which  were akin to forgetting ''all the words in the English language'' for  five seconds at a time. He soon stopped taking the dexamphetamines prescribed for his narcolepsy to reduce the severity of the seizures.
Mr Grayson had also ceased studying, working, driving and had qualified for Newstart a month before he suffered an unexpected tonic-clonic seizure on November 11. He had surgery at John Hunter Hospital on November 19 to remove an  egg-sized portion of a ganglioglioma tumour from his brain and was given a medical certificate  excusing him from Newstart appointments until February 19, while he recovered.
''My neurosurgeon said [my time left]  could be five to 10 years, or  three weeks,'' he said. ''He told me whatever you want to do, do it now.
 Mr Grayson's modest but meaningful bucket list includes visiting his brother in Victoria and his cousin in Western Australia.
His mother is his grandmother's primary carer, so any travel would have to be planned around arranging respite care.
 ''But if I am well enough to travel and that happens to be in a time frame where I have Newstart appointments, I don't want to have to choose between the two.''
Mr Grayson's rare type of cancer doesn't qualify him to be fast-tracked onto the Disability Support Pension via an amendment designed for people who have been diagnosed with a terminal illness.
When he sought advice from Centrelink about his options, he was told he would be ineligible for the pension because the criteria were being fully diagnosed, fully treated, stable and with symptoms that would last for two years.
Mr Grayson has not yet had radiotherapy, but has an appointment with his oncologist on January 12 to discuss when he can begin.
He received a call  from Centrelink after the Herald article, telling him the criteria had not made him automatically ineligible and only may affect his ability to apply for the pension.
While he is still physically well, Mr Grayson said his deteriorating mental health may provide a different avenue to qualify for the pension. But being under  35, he will still have to attend meetings about how to transition off the pension and into work or education.
 ''I'm not against having to attend meetings or contributing to society, but we do need special consideration and a certain degree of flexibility for what is a very unique situation,'' he said.
 ''What I'd like to see is an entirely new payment set up for people with terminal illnesses.''
Department of Human Services general manager Hank Jongen said pension assessment could be complex due to the medical information required and that people should test their eligibility by lodging a claim.
''We appreciate this is an extremely difficult time for Mr Grayson and we will provide him with ongoing support where we can,'' he said.
 ''Temporary exemptions from job search requirements may be available for eligible people diagnosed with a serious condition.
''If a doctor or specialist advises that a customer has a terminal medical condition, DSP may be granted without additional assessment, provided they meet other criteria such as income and assets tests.''

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starlight Children's Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOHN Grayson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AJ Maddah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Human</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Grayson</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disability Support Pension</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit's Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soundwave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newstart</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DSP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hank Jongen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theresa Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indianapolis Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Day Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
