<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428544819887747</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/martin-shkreli-convicted-on-fraud-charges/8777252</url>
  <title>Martin Shkreli: 'Pharma Bro' convicted at US securities fraud trial after 'lies upon lies'</title>
  <content>
Martin Shkreli, the eccentric former pharmaceutical CEO  and for his snide "Pharma Bro" persona on social media, has been convicted on charges he deceived investors in a pair of failed hedge funds.

Key points:

Prosecutors accused Shkreli of repeatedly misleading investors about what he was doing with their money
He blew money on bad stock picks, forcing him to cook up scheme to recover millions, they said
Investors accused Shkreli of keeping them in the dark as his scheme unfolded

A jury in the Brooklyn borough of New York City deliberated five days before finding Shkreli guilty on three of eight counts.
He had been charged with securities fraud, conspiracy to commit securities fraud and conspiracy to commit wire fraud.
Prosecutors had accused Shkreli of repeatedly misleading investors about what he was doing with their money.
Mostly, he was blowing it with horrible stock picks, forcing him to cook up a scheme to recover millions in losses, they said.
Shkreli, 34, told "lies upon lies", including claiming he had $US40 million in one of his funds at a time when it only had about $US300 in the bank, assistant US attorney Alixandra Smith said in closing arguments.
The trial "has exposed Martin Shkreli for who he really is: a con man who stole millions", added another prosecutor, Jacquelyn Kasulis.
But the case was tricky for the Government because investors, some wealthy financiers from Texas, who testified at the trial conceded that Shkreli's scheme actually succeeded in making them richer, in some cases doubling or even tripling their money on his company's stock when it went public.
The defence portrayed them as spoiled "rich people" who were the ones doing the manipulating.
"Who lost anything? Nobody," Shkreli's defence lawyer Ben Brafman said in his closing argument.
Some investors had to admit on the witness stand that partnering with Shkreli was "the greatest investment I've ever made", he added.
For the boyish-looking Shkreli, one of the biggest problems was not part of the case - .
'They blame me for capitalism'

Shkreli, who comes from an Albanian family in Brooklyn, was  he founded, Retrophin, of $US11 million in stock and cash to pay back the hedge fund investors.
Investors took the witness stand to accuse Shkreli of keeping them in the dark as his scheme unfolded.
"I don't think it mattered to him, it was just what he thought he could get away with," said Richard Kocher, a New Jersey construction company owner who invested $US200,000 with Shkreli in 2012.
"It was insulting."
Shkreli's lawyer agreed his client could be annoying.
"In terms of people skills, he's impossible," Mr Brafman said, referring to Shkreli as a "nerd" and a "mad scientist".
But he said his hedge fund investors knew what they were getting.
"They found him strange. They found him weird. And they gave him money. Why? Because they recognised genius," he said, adding that they had signed agreements that his client was not liable if they lost their money.

External Link:

Martin Shkreli takes the Fifth
, but rather than lay low like his lawyers wanted, he got into the act by using Facebook to bash prosecutors and news organisations covering his case.
In one recent post, he wrote: "My case is a silly witch hunt perpetrated by self-serving prosecutors. ... Drain the swamp. Drain the sewer that is the [Department of Justice]."
The judge ordered Shkreli to keep his mouth shut in and around the courtroom after another rant to new reporters covering the trial.
Prosecutors "blame me for everything", he said.
"They blame me for capitalism."
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retrophin, of $US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shkreli, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brafman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shkreli</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacquelyn Kasulis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brafman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Kocher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharma Bro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US200,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albanians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Shkreli</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alixandra Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
