<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428892712243585</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/local-afl/nt-thunder-forced-into-making-more-changes-for-sydney-uni-clash/news-story/007ec6ffbf6192134d621aa48cfb11bc</url>
  <title>Injuries and illness force Thunder's hand</title>
  <content>
NT THUNDER coach Andrew Hodges admitted his team had been "forced" into making four changes ahead of its Round 19 NEAFL clash with Sydney University at Henson Park today.
The Thunder will be looking to keep the good vibes going after a convincing win over Southport last Saturday, but will have its work cut out after Uni's 68-point win when the two teams last met in Round 10.
Midfielder Michael Coombes will miss this game after sustaining a hamstring injury in the first half against the Sharks, while Adam Sambono has been ruled out with a virus and big man Neil Vea Vea is sidelined with a knee complaint.
Jarred Erlandson is unable to travel due to work commitments, and Kyle Emery will make way for the experience of Jonathan Peris, who has been cleared of a recent groin injury.
The Thunder will also have some pace and flair injected into the side with Kayle Kossack lining up for his sixth game of the year, along with goal sneaks Michael Hagan and Davin Ferreira.
Scott McLeod is a straight swap for Vea Vea and will be the back-up ruckman to face the Students with Tony Olango named in the forward line.
Hodges said he had hoped to minimise the changes going into this round, but it was the reality of the situation. "The past couple of weeks we've been forced to make some changes which have led to some questions about our consistency because our results have not been as steady as we'd like," he said.
"It's the reality of the situation though. Our players have careers, families and commitments outside of football that they need to prioritise, which means we're not always naming the same side.
"But we believe that every player we name is capable of fulfilling his role for the team."
Hodges said the commitment on the training track had once again been impressive.
"The boys ... continue to put in the hard yards because they know it's only going to get harder from here," he said.
"Sydney Uni is a well-drilled team with plenty of depth, and they play with confidence, which last time forced skill errors on our part.
"So we're going to have to be cleaner and take better advantage of our opportunities."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davin Ferreira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott McLeod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Peris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Emery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erlandson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Olango</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henson Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 19 NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayle Kossack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Vea Vea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Uni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hodges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vea Vea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Coombes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Sambono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunder</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
