<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428725208516729</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/mcdonalds-delivers-szechuan-mcnugget-sauce-rick-and-morty-fans-2017-8</url>
  <title>McDonald's has finally delivered Szechuan McNugget sauce to diehard fans after a cartoon called for its return</title>
  <content>
McDonald's just brought back a cult-classic McNuggets sauce for a  Now, people are receiving their jugs of the sauce to try - or sell - themselves. 

In April, Adult Swim aired the first new episode of "Rick and Morty" since 2015. The episode ended with a plea from mad scientist Rick for McDonald's to bring back its Szechuan McNugget sauce, a plum sauce that was available for a limited time in 1998 to promote the Disney movie "Mulan."

After the episode aired, "Rick and Morty" fans began demanding that McDonald's actually bring back the sauce. 

Early Sunday morning, the fast-food chain did just that, sending the creators of "Rick & Morty" a jug of the Szechuan McNugget sauce and launching a giveaway for three jugs of the sauce.

Now, a select few "Rick & Morty" fans are receiving the sauce - and judging if it lives up to expectations after almost two decades off the menu. 

Two out of three of the lucky recipients posted online about their deliveries on Friday. 

"The taste is at first sweet, then sesame, then a hint of spicyness," David Wasman wrote in his review of the sauce. "It lingers for an hour, too. I am still tasting it!"

Meanwhile, another recipient is still trying to figure out what to do with his Szechuan sauce - and he may be willing to sell it. 

"I realise I can do some good with this and take care of myself as well," Robert "DCD" Workman wrote on . "So if you guys know someone that REALLY wants this... Hit me up tonight or tomorrow morning and let me know. Otherwise, I'll hit you with eBay details once it's live."

There seems to be one Szechuan sauce delivery that's still unaccounted for, so be on the lookout for one more jug of the stuff showing up on eBay. 

It doesn't seem like McDonald's has any plans to release the sauce to the rest of the US quite yet.

"For now, only a limited amount of Szechuan Sauce got through from the always-1998 dimension," a McDonald's spokesperson said in a statement earlier this week. "Who knows where space-time will take us because when our customers speak, we listen."

MFW    & the entire  team helped bring back  & I won one of the jugs!
- David Wasman ???? (@therealduckie)

Ahhhhhhhhhh!!
- Robert "DCD" Workman (@TheDCD)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Szechuan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Workman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TheDCD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morty</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Szechuan Sauce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahhhhhhhhhh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Wasman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Szechuan McNugget</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McNuggets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DCD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adult Swim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
