<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429030151198729</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/talking-about-your-oral-health/3208983/</url>
  <title>Talking about your oral health</title>
  <content>
FOR Dr Scott Geddes, Dental Week is an opportunity to continue educating patients - of all ages - about the importance of good dental health.
"Dentists and their support staff spend each day striving to promote good oral health habits to their patients," Dr Geddes said.
"Dental Health Week each year gives us an opportunity to try to get a particular message out to the broader community.
The theme this year is "Anytime Anywhere" - oral health habits for busy lives.
"Everyone seems to be time poor these days and this can have an impact on the health choices they make," Dr Geddes said.
"Fortunately, there are some pretty easy steps you can take that will have a marked effect on your oral health: brush twice a day with a fluoride toothpaste, floss at least once a day, eat more healthily and have  regular check-ups.
"Lots of people don't seem to realise that our eating habits play a major role in tooth decay. If keeping a healthy mouth is important to you then you should limit sugary treats to mealtimes rather than in between meals. Drink fluoridated tap water throughout the day and chew sugar-free gum after eating. These are simple measures that cost little or no time to implement.
The team at The Dental Centre look forward to the upcoming visits from local pre-school groups during Dental Health Week.
"As well as making sure the little ones have a good time, we'll try to get them into some healthy habits that will serve them well for their whole lives."
Visit www.coffsdental centre.com.au.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dental Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Geddes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dental Health Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dental Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Scott Geddes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
