<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428772453157751</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-05/coaches-survey-the-player-more-valuable-than-danger</url>
  <title>Who is the coaches' MVP? It's not Danger</title>
  <content>
Patrick Dangerfield has been pipped as the coaches' MVP

SYDNEY star Lance Franklin has edged out Geelong's Patrick Dangerfield as the game's most valuable player in the eyes of the senior AFL coaches.

Franklin received nine votes to Dangerfield's seven, with the men in charge asked to rate players based on their on-field skill, the position they play, crowd-drawing capacity and leadership qualities. Adelaide forward Eddie Betts was the only other player to receive a vote.

The coaches believe this year's NAB AFL Rising Star award is a three-horse race, with six tipping Port Adelaide's Sam Powell-Pepper and five giving the nod to Essendon's Andrew McGrath. Hawthorn's Ryan Burton was favoured by four of the coaches.

The coaches were split on which individual player award they rated highest, with the Brownlow Medal and the club best and fairest both snaring seven votes. Three ranked the AFLCA coaches' award highest.  

When it came to the type of player needed for team success, nine of the coaches identified inside midfielders, with four pointing to key forwards. None rated key defenders in the 'most vital' category.

The MVP 'vote' was part of a survey of coaches for AFL.com.au and the AFL Record conducted in July. The survey, facilitated by the AFL Coaches' Association, asked coaches to anonymously provide their views on all aspects of the game, including the game's stars, leading clubs and rules. Seventeen of the 18 coaches took part in the questionnaire. 

Read the full survey results in the round 20 edition of the AFL Record, available at all venues.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFLCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Rising Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Record</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Coaches' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon's Andrew McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide's Sam Powell-Pepper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn's Ryan Burton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
