<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651427217674971048</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/world/donald-trumps-tweetstorm-ignores-grand-jury-to-cheer-job-growth/news-story/6131d0109114153f004b86224114f730</url>
  <title>Trump's tweetstorm ignores grand jury</title>
  <content>
PRESIDENT Trump shrugged off news that a grand jury has been empaneled to probe Russian interference in the 2016 election to cheer Japanese car manufacturers Toyota and Mazda early on Friday for their plans to spend $US1.6 billion ($2.01 billion) on a joint-venture plant in the US.
"Toyota & Mazda to build a new $1.6B plant here in the USA and create 4K new American jobs. A great investment in American manufacturing!" Trump tweeted in praise of the giant automakers.
The plant will have an annual production capacity of about 300,000 vehicles, the companies said.
Toyota will produce Corollas at the facility and Mazda will make crossover models for its North American market, according to the companies, which are forming a capital alliance and splitting the cost for the plant equally.

Toyota & Mazda to build a new $1.6B plant here in the U.S.A. and create 4K new American jobs. A great investment in American manufacturing!

It is due to begin operations by 2021.
Trump had criticised Toyota for taking auto production and jobs to Mexico, where it had planned to produce Corollas at a plant under construction in Guanajuato.
The company has decided to produce its Tacoma pick-ups there instead, said Toyota President Akio Toyoda, who denied that Trump's statements influenced his decision.

Excellent Jobs Numbers just released - and I have only just begun. Many job stifling regulations continue to fall. Movement back to USA!

The companies have not announced exactly where the new plant will be built.
In a separate tweet, Trump also cited electronics maker Foxconn's plan to build a $10 billion display manufacturing plant.
"....and don't forget that Foxconn will be spending up to 10 billion dollars on a top of the line plant/plants in Wisconsin," he wrote.

....and don't forget that Foxconn will be spending up to 10 billion dollars on a top of the line plant/plants in Wisconsin.

The president on Tuesday claimed that the Taiwanese company's CEO, Terry Gou, told him privately that it could invest as much as $30 billion in the US, Fortune reported.
On Wednesday, Foxconn said the Wisconsin plant "will be the first of a series of facilities we will be building in several states."
But it did not address Trump's statement about the total investment amount or Trump's claims that Gou told it to him off the record.
"We have not yet announced our investment plans for other sites," Foxconn said in a statement. "We will provide an update as soon as we have finalised those plans."
Trump also tweeted that "consumer confidence is at a 16 year high .... and for good reason. Much more regulation "busting" to come. Working hard on tax cuts & reform!"
And in another tweet, he crowed about his visit to West Virginia late Thursday.
"West Virginia was incredible last night. Crowds and enthusiasm were beyond, GDP at 3 per cent, wow! Dem. Governor became a Republican last night," he wrote.
West Virginia Gov. Jim Justice told about 9,000 Trump supporters at a rally in Huntington that he will be changing his registration Friday.
On Thursday night, Trump blasted the Russia probe as a "fake story that is demeaning to all of us and most of all demeaning to our country and demeaning to our Constitution."
This article was
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guanajuato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota President Akio Toyoda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Virginia Gov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tacoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Virginia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S.A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobs Numbers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxconn</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wisconsin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Gou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corolla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
