<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428381611127681</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/country-lifestyle-near-city-at-701-greenhill-rd-burnside/news-story/fdc83cc15256f24dc01916637e51b3c2</url>
  <title>Country lifestyle near city at 701 Greenhill Rd Burnside - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
701 Greenhill Road, Burnside. Supplied by Harris Real Estate.

A  has provided Marianne Schmidt and Steve Howard with picturesque views, city conveniences and a peaceful, country-like lifestyle.
The couple moved into the home, which abuts the Greenhill Conservation Park 23 years ago, following a stint living overseas.
"We were looking for something in the east, in the suburbs but close to the city, and this had something unique about it," Ms Schmidt says.

701 Greenhill Road, Burnside. Supplied by Harris Real Estate.

"We liked its proximity to the city and the fact that it only had one neighbour. It still only has one neighbour.
"It's close to the city but has a country feel."
In fact, Ms Schmidt says it's not unusual to see native animals.
"There's lots of wildlife, we see koalas and kangaroos and at the moment there is a deer in the park, and echidnas," she says.
"Things you don't normally see that close to the city."
But it was the panoramic vistas from the front of the house, and the park next door that really sold the home.

701 Greenhill Road, Burnside. Supplied by Harris Real Estate.

"The views enticed us as well," she says.
"All the front rooms walk out on to the balcony and that's got a northern aspect and views of the city. And out of the kitchen you can see the national park.
"It's a very peaceful place to live.
"We love bushwalking and will walk out the door to the park and go for miles."
Built across two levels, the home offers five bedrooms, three bedrooms and multiple living areas. Outside is a double carport next to a garage, and a resurfaced and fenced salt-chlorinated pool.

701 Greenhill Road, Burnside. Supplied by Harris Real Estate.

The home's lower level is designed for entertainment with a large living room complete with a built-in bar and combustion heater, guest bathroom, a foyer and two bedrooms.
The living space opens to a veranda overlooking a garden with lawn and plants, and the pool.
On the upper level are another three bedrooms, including the master, which is complete with an ensuite and a walk-in wardrobe.

701 Greenhill Road, Burnside. Supplied by Harris Real Estate.

The minor bedrooms are serviced by a central two-way bathroom, and one has a built-in.
A neat timber kitchen overlooks a casual meals area, which opens to a balcony over the carport, and there's also a formal lounge and dining room with views.
"We've refurbished the home over the years," Ms Schmidt says.

701 Greenhill Road, Burnside. Supplied by Harris Real Estate.

"It was very seventies when we moved in so we did all the decor and recently we did it all again.
"We've repainted and added new carpets. About four years ago we added two new bathrooms."
The airconditioning has also been replaced and a new roof put on. Helping keep the bills down is a 10kW solar panel system.

701 Greenhill Road, Burnside. Supplied by Harris Real Estate.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenhill Road</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenhill Conservation Park 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harris Real Estate</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnside</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenhill Rd Burnside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marianne Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Schmidt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
