<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428768158190418</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/tom-cruise-movie-inspired-me-to-fly/3208745/</url>
  <title>Tom Cruise movie inspired me to fly</title>
  <content>
CHASING her dream of becoming an air force pilot, Claire Winterbourne was able to get a taste of the air force life at a recent Girls Flight Camp held at RAAF Base Amberley.
Claire was selected from more than 40 applicants and got to experience a week in the RAAF, undertaking a diverse range of activities from flying in aircraft and simulators to physical training and leadership challenges.
She also got to observe a live fire exercise and the military working dogs.
"I first thought about flying in the defence force when I watched the movie Top Gun," Claire revealed.
"Since then I've been driven to become a fighter pilot.
"This camp gave me an insight into what life in the defence force is like as well as what it takes to become a pilot in the air force.
"The flight in the Boeing C-17A Globemaster was amazing.
"To see the crew in action, as well as the enthusiasm they bought into their work. They acted as a tight knit team.
"The sheer size of the aircraft was mindblowing. You see pictures and think 'yeah, that's big' but when you are standing inside the military transport craft, taking off - I was stunned by its size.
"It's my dream to fly the F/A-18F Super Hornet or the E/A-18G Growler; used in electronic warfare.
"The defence force environment really appeals to me and I hope to one day be amongst it."
As well as experiencing military aviation, participants in the camp were also introduced to the day-to-day running of an RAAF base and had several opportunities to engage with serving members and recruiting specialists to discuss potential careers within the Australian Defence Force.
Flight Lieutenant Margaret Traill from Air Force Gender Programs said the Girls Flight Camp was a good way for young females to discover all the career possibilities that the Australian Defence Force had to offer.
"We find that the Girls Flight Camp is a great opportunity for girls who are interested in careers in the ADF to see what that future career could look like and all the opportunities that come with it," Flight Lieutenant Traill said.
The camps are open to young women aged between 16 and 24 and give them an insight into what a career in the air force would be like.
The next flight camp is scheduled for the RAAF Base Pearce, Perth next month.
Details can be found at
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Yaroomba Beach project will be "a fantastic coastal village"
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Home sells in just one day
Elegant home with seven levels hits the market
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant Margaret Traill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Girls Flight Camp</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top Gun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Force Gender Programs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF Base Amberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant Traill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F/A-18F Super Hornet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Winterbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing C-17A Globemaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF Base Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Cruise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E/A-18G Growler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
