<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429322208978634</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/teams/geelong/geelong-to-sweat-on-tom-hawkins-mitch-duncan-punches-as-joel-selwood-battles-ankle-injury/news-story/c842f416f23f66aa886b6192a80cca48</url>
  <title>Cats to sweat on Hawkins, Selwood</title>
  <content>
GEELONG was savaged for its lack of discipline after last night's loss to Sydney as forward Tom Hawkins faces the likelihood of another suspension for jumper punching.
To add to the Cats' woes,  in time for Saturday night's clash with Richmond.
Midfielder Mitch Duncan could also be in trouble for his blow on Swans forward Tom Papley as the Cats were left reeling from a horror night at Simonds Stadium.
The loss will have a significant impact on the Cats' hopes for a double chance, and they will slip out of the top four this weekend if GWS, Richmond and Port Adelaide all win their respective games.
And Geelong will be sweating on the availability of Hawkins, Duncan and Selwood for next week's crucial match against the Tigers.
Hawkins is in danger of being rubbed out of the next two games if he is cited for his jumper punch to Dane Rampe because of his bad record.
The forward was suspended for a similar incident earlier in the season against Adelaide, and last year also served a one-match penalty for striking GWS' Phil Davis.
Hawkins also remonstrated with Callum Mills with a fist to chest, but the force appeared minimal.
Duncan also has a nervous wait for match review panel findings for his round-arm hit on Papley, which gifted the Swans a second shot at goal after Dan Hannebery kicked the first goal of the final quarter.
Carlton premiership great Mark Maclure said if the AFL was serious about eradicating punching in the game then Hawkins and Duncan had to be suspended.
"I think they should suspend them because if you're going to finish it off (punching), finish it off, because it just keeps coming and coming," Maclure said on Fox Footy.
"If you don't want to stop it, give them a $1500 fine.
"Two different mindsets from two different clubs. One, Sydney, have no fines. The other blokes just want to punch the hell of people."
Sydney premiership coach Paul Roos said Duncan was in "huge trouble" for his strike on Papley.
Roos said Duncan's ill-discipline and the two-goal play in the last quarter ended any hope of a Geelong comeback.
"They've given two goals away that they shouldn't have given away," Roos said.
"(It was a) crucial time. They were back in the game. They lost the plot."
But Cats coach didn't agree with the decision to award Papley with a free kick.
"I have looked at it, and (you can) have an opinion on these things," Scott said.
"I think that if the umpire that paid it has a look at the vision I have looked at, he will be disappointed that he paid it. That's OK, mistakes happen.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Rampe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maclure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Hannebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Maclure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS' Phil Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkins</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
