<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429322208978600</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/cricket/legspinner-mitchell-swepson-chosen-for-bangladesh-test-tour-20170804-gxpxym.html</url>
  <title>Leg-spinner Mitchell Swepson chosen for Bangladesh Test tour</title>
  <content>
Mitchell Swepson's rise to becoming Australia's next frontline leg-spinner will continue after he was included in the Test squad to tour Bangladesh.
Swepson's position was confirmed on Saturday, after the national selectors opted against adding a fourth fast bowler, as had been the plan.
Spearhead Mitchell Starc will miss the two-Test series to rest his foot. Josh Hazlewood, Pat Cummins and James Pattinson had already been included, and the Australia A tour of South Africa was to have been used to settle the fourth fast bowling position.
However, that tour was scuttled because of the now-settled pay dispute, and the selectors opted to go in a different selection.
Swepson, 23, has been on the selectors' radar for some time, and their interest in him was confirmed when he was chosen for the Test tour of India earlier this year. He did not play a Test but benefited from the experience of training in the sub-continent conditions - a similar type he will face against a hungry Bangladesh keen to build on its improving form.
National selector Trevor Hohns was satisfied Australia had enough fast-bowling depth. Batting allrounder Hilton Cartwright can also provide medium-pace, if selected in the XI.

"We are comfortable with the fast-bowling stocks we have in the squad so have opted to add an additional spinner given the conditions we are likely to face in Bangladesh," he said.
 
"Mitchell is a very exciting young leg-spinner who we think will benefit immensely from further experience in the sub-continent."
Nathan Lyon, Australia's most successful off-spinner, and left-arm finger spinner Ashton Agar were already included, the latter a controversial selection ahead of Steve O'Keefe, who had bowled Australia to a shock victory in the opening Test against India in Pune when he claimed 12 wickets for the match.
That Swepson has now been chosen ahead of O'Keefe would suggest the national selectors have moved on from the left-arm finger spinner, who has found himself in trouble off the field. Swepson has not played in a game since the end of the Big Bash League series. The Queenslander's last first-class match had been in December.
Leg-spinner great Shane Warne has provided strong public and private support for Swepson, having called for him to be selected for India, and also to play in the first Test. Warne has also given him a one-on-one practice session.
He had initially caught the eye of skipper Steve Smith when he was used as a net bowler on Australia's tour of Sri Lanka last year.
Australia has not toured Bangladesh since 2006 when it claimed a 2-0 series win. The tourists will head into a pre-series camp in Darwin next week, before leaving for Bangladesh on August 18. They will play a two-day tour match in Fattulah from August 22, with the first Test in Dhaka beginning  August 27.
AUSTRALIA TEST SQUAD: Steve Smith (c), David Warner (vc), Ashton Agar, Hilton Cartwright, Pat Cummins, Peter Handscomb, Josh Hazlewood, Usman Khawaja, Nathan Lyon, Glenn Maxwell, James Pattinson, Matthew Renshaw, Mitchell Swepson, Matthew Wade
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dhaka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swepson, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashton Agar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve O'Keefe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Handscomb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pattinson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Renshaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usman Khawaja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Keefe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Swepson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIA TEST SQUAD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Lyon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swepson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Starc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hazlewood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Cummins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fattulah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Warne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilton Cartwright</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Hohns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
