<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428763863223033</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/travel/documentary-reveals-british-tourists-to-be-truly-awful/news-story/4227fc044bb842d8f4635cc795aaee5f</url>
  <title>Proof British tourists are the worst</title>
  <content>
THESE are the Brits who take relaxing on their holiday in Spain's Costa del Sol to a whole new level.
Sun-bed battles at dawn, endless all-inclusive boozing and even peeing in the pool - they're firmly set in their ways when it comes to jetting off.
And now they're brazenly laying bare their holiday confessions in a revealing new UK documentary,  reports.
Channel 4's The Secret Life of the Holiday Resort shows how the typical British family likes to unwind when they touch down in the Costa del Sol in southern Spain.
And the all-access doco doesn't try to tart up their less favourable habits - from stuffing themselves at the all-you-can-eat buffet to pinching apartment freebies like soap, shower-gel and even light bulbs.
One family, the Lloyds, say they look forward all year to their fortnight in the sun.
"When the bonus comes that's the first thing we put money down on," a member of the family said.
"We've done all-inclusive a couple of times and when you work it out it is more cost effective."
So it's no surprise they like to make the most of their trip by setting their alarms early to get their favourite sun-bed spot by the pool at the Holidayworld resort in Costa del Sol every single day.
But Nicky and Wayne, son Danny and daughter Ella aren't catching the rays when they put their towels down at 7am - they're either snoozing in bed or down at the breakfast buffet.
"I was down there at five to six, it was pitch black the stars are out and 80 per cent of the sunbeds are gone," one miffed holiday-maker said.
"I was then saying to different people, 'What time did you get up?' I think one of them was quarter past four. It's mad."
Meanwhile, the show explores the Brits' ravenous eating habits when presented with an all-you-can-eat buffet.
The average Brit puts on around 3.5kg during just a fortnight away, according to the program.
And some guests have even been known to gorge on up to 6000 calories a day at Holidayworld, the Costa's biggest all-inclusive resort.
The ability to eat is never-ending: the breakfast buffet opens at 6am, before a snack bar for crisps and other treats provided for peckish guests until 7pm, when the dinner buffet is served.
But while Brits clearly want to gorge on grub, they don't want to fuss with local cuisine.
A third of holiday-makers prefer to eat only British food or takeaway favourites like pizza or fried chicken.
"Their eyes are bigger than their tummies," waiter Andrey said on the show.
"Here if you are English, it gives you English options, so you don't have to eat Spanish food," young Danny Lloyd said, while mum Nicky added: "I don't do fish."
And there is little shame in taking the odd unofficial souvenir - or using the communal pool as your own personal toilet.
Mum Nicky said: "I've been in the cleaning cupboard and taken some extra towels and sheets we've needed and a few more toilet rolls.
"I've used it as my own personal cupboard. Although there's a camera so I've probably been spotted."
Cleaner Manoli said she once saw a room that had been stripped of all light bulbs, slippers, gowns and toiletries.
Little Danny said: "I weed in the indoor pool", but added: "Well everyone's weed in the pool!"
This article originally appeared on and was reproduced with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicky</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun-bed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manoli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sol</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holidayworld</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain's Costa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Life of the Holiday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
