<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429322208978584</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/from-bush-to-the-blues-rising-star-sam-petrevskiseton-is-ready-to-kick-on-20170803-gxp2a7.html</url>
  <title>From bush to the Blues, rising star Sam Petrevski-Seton is ready to kick on</title>
  <content>
Sam Petrevski-Seton doesn't want to hear any suggestions of being "tired" at this stage of a long season. Rather, he says it's about finding ways to heighten his excitement levels come game day.
For some, that comes through music or video in the hours leading into a match. For others, it can be visualising expected on-field moments. For Petrevski-Seton, one of Carlton's emerging weapons, it's an area he continues to refine in what has been an encouraging season, complete with a Rising Star nomination.

Up Next

Swans slay Cats to make finals statement

01:28

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

Sam McClure previews all the footy action ahead of round 20 in the AFL.

"It's a learning curve at this time of the year about what to expect. I wouldn't say I was tired. It's little habits about how to get up for each game," he said.
One added moment of inspiration came when forward Harry McKay made his debut, against the Brisbane Lions at the Gabba a fortnight go. Petrevski-Seton remembered his own debut, against Richmond in the season opener, and the emotion he felt.Photo: Scott McNaughton
"I felt what he [McKay] felt and how excited I was for him to be given a debut. I am trying to be more excited ... trying to get a routine before the game. Try and get yourself up, try and work on your arousal levels to compete on the weekend," he told Fairfax Media.
There's nothing more Petrevski-Seton loves than competing. Whether it be rodeo riding, which he has slapped a self-imposed ban on, or battling the contested-ball beasts of the AFL, the lad from the remote Western Australian town of Halls Creek loves a challenge.

"You just have to have guts to ride in a rodeo. Footy, I like to play on instinct but footy is also challenging mentally and physically. That's what I have found in my first season," he said.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Now I am getting a bit of exposure to the midfield, building my confidence leading into the pre-season and next season."
That move from half-forward to more time in the middle has come through necessity, for the hardened bodies of Ed Curnow (throat) and Patrick Cripps (broken leg) are on the sidelines, meaning veterans Marc Murphy and Bryce Gibbs have needed more help in a midfield that already was thin. It was in the midfield where Petrevski-Seton, with dash and class, made his name as a junior, and had recruiters salivating before he reached draft age.
"Having the likes of 'Gibbo' and 'Murph' in there helping me out, and with Ed and 'Crippa' out for the season, I am just giving myself the opportunity to, hopefully, play some good footy, just apply some pressure on the footy and, hopefully, get my hands on the footy as well," Petrevski-Seton said.
"I see myself as a good ball user, whether it's flicking it out by hands to Gibbo or Murph or whether they give it to me and I use it by foot, or reading the play to get forward of the ball."
He has averaged 13.5 disposals a game but had 20 against Geelong last week. It's hoped he can maintain that in what shapes as a tough final month of the season, beginning against Essendon at the MCG on Saturday.
You just have to have guts to ride in a rodeo. Footy, I like to play on instinct but footy is also challenging mentally and physically. That's what I have found in my first season.
Sam Petrevski-Seton on his rookie campaign.

The Blues will want to finish well but it's the bigger picture the club has in mind, and Petrevski-Seton represents that.
He made it clear he wanted to come to a Victorian club heading into last year's draft. He had spent four years in Perth, rising through the levels at WAFL club Claremont, before heading east as the No.6 overall pick. He is still finding his way, as his housemates - and many other teammates - are.
He lives with fellow Sandgroper Zac Fisher and Harrison McReadie, the latter he knew through the AIS Academy and who had been a member of Greater Western Sydney's academy.
"I just wanted to come over here, be in a different state rather than WA. I, obviously, had the challenge of moving down to Perth from home in Halls Creek. I spent four years in Perth ... it was a new challenge to come over here," Petrevski-Seton said.
"Knowing them [Fisher and McReadie] beforehand, I had played with both of them, and now living with them and playing with them, has made my life more easier and more comfortable over here. This is just where the home of footy is - it's good to be a part of it."
Halls Creek is found in the East Kimberley region. It has a population of about 1200, according to the 2006 census, and a lifestyle Petrevski-Seton misses, for bush life is in his blood. He spent the first three years of his life on a cattle station before his family moved to the bigger town of Halls Creek.
While he has embraced city life, it's clear he does miss his family. His mother, Angeline, who carries the Yugoslavian name of her father, and Christopher Seton, his father, were in town for round one, when their son was a shock selection despite having not played an official practice match because of injury. However, their work in Halls Creek - and the travel required to get to Melbourne - means visits will be sporadic.
"They don't move around much because of work. Mum is the manager of the Centrelink office that looks after the town and outer communities. Dad is the manager of the water corporation. They are both very busy with work," said Petrevski-Seton, one of four siblings.
However, his older brother Cody and two cousins are in Wangaratta and visit, while another two cousins have started university in Melbourne.
"Probably the No.1 thing I miss is family. I have heaps of family back home. They all are getting to the age where they are now breeding kids. That childhood that my little nieces and nephews and cousins ... they are growing up. I miss their childhood," he said.
"I miss the freedom back home as well. There is a lot of freedom, whether it's kicking back, having a lot of quality family time, also having motorbikes there to ride - just little things like that. You just cross the road and it's the bush. I also miss the waterholes back there, that childhood memory when you go swimming."
Petrevski-Seton's time as a rodeo rider were well documented leading into the draft, and he says the Blues won't have to worry about him hopping on a bull over the off-season.
He has former Carlton star Andrew Walker, now the Blues' development and integration coach, as his mentor, along with midfield coach Tim Clarke. He recently went to Walker's home town of Echuca on a day off and joined Walker and his father for a spot of fishing.
"I was lucky enough to catch myself a Murray cod for the first time. It was a good day. It was a cold day as well," Petrevski-Seton said, clearly still adjusting to Victoria's fickle weather.
Walker has provided guidance off the field, for he, too, knows how difficult a new life can be.
"What I have 'Walks' for -  early it was to get me out of my comfort zone a bit, but now he gives me advice and feedback, reviewing the game together, just trying to get that feedback from his experience and knowledge," Petrevski-Seton said.
"He is here every day. He is easy to approach and have a chat with - talk about family, not just footy, footy, footy."
For a man who only learnt English as a teenager - he grew up with Kriol, a broken form of English, as his native language - Petrevski-Seton has come a long way.
Coach Brendon Bolton wants him to play on instinct but the challenges of the modern, highly choreographed game take time to adjust to.
"Going into the game knowing what you want to do; how to stop the opposition from scoring and attacking. It's more mentally - you can be pretty exhausted by half-time," Petrevski-Seton said.
He says he has largely adjusted to the tempo of the game but the size of opponents - at times - has been a challenge. Listed at 74 kilograms, he has put on weight since summer, but is keen to add more "lean muscle".
His Rising Star nomination came after the round-seven win over Collingwood when he had 21 disposals, including two goals. There have been quieter moments since but he was among the best against the Cats, suggesting that pre-season comments made by Darcy Coffey, the head of football at WAFL club Claremont, could prove to be spot on. Coffey had said Petrevski-Seton's raw talent was better than what Melbourne's Jesse Hogan and Gold Coast's Jack Martin had shown during their time with the Tigers.
"I didn't hear that from 'Darc' but I will have to give him a shout-out about that. He got me down to Perth to represent Claremont, from under 15s to 16s to 18s and I played a few league games," Petrevski-Seton said.
"Darcy saw a bit of me. I am very grateful for him to say that. There are a lot of talented boys, not only myself but the likes of Jesse and Jack Martin, who I admired in my junior days."
Petrevski-Seton already has many admirers of his own, including the Blues, who extended his contract by another three years until the end of 2021 after just his first 10 games.
Aside from sampling Melbourne's cafe culture, he spends his spare time at the club working on his craft and body, reinforcing why recruiters were impressed with his desire and professionalism at an early age. Study will likely come next year. In the meantime, there are football matches, hopefully, to be won.
"The next four weeks are big, not just for myself but for the team. We are going out there to win and perform," he said.
As "Sammo'" has shown through his life, the name he took from his maternal great grandfather per cultural tradition, he is ready to embrace any challenge.
ON THE RISE: CARLTON'S 2017 RISING STAR NOMINATIONS
Round 6: Caleb Marchbank
Round 7: Sam Petrevski-Seton
Round 12: David Cuningham
Round 13: Jack Silvagni
Round 16: Charlie Curnow
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrison McReadie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angeline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Echuca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wangaratta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gibbo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caleb Marchbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry McKay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Coffey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kriol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam McClure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce Gibbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Silvagni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rising Star</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Cripps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Curnow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yugoslavian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Curnow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Jesse Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HALLS CREEK</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crippa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sammo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott McNaughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIS Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Kimberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McReadie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast's Jack Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claremont</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cuningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murph</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CARLTON'S 2017 RISING STAR NOMINATIONS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandgroper Zac Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
