<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429107460611088</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/09/18/tasmania-clamps-down-on-serious-criminals</url>
  <title>Tasmania clamps down on serious crimes</title>
  <content>
Criminals who commit serious violent, sexual and drug offences in Tasmania will no longer be eligible for suspended sentences under new laws in the state.
A draft bill has been released to phase out suspended prison sentences for serious offenders in Tasmania while introducing new sentencing options for the courts, including home detention.
"The community sees suspended sentences as a soft and ineffective response to crime," acting attorney-general Matthew Groom said on Saturday.
The reforms also make home detention and community correction orders an option for sentencing judges in the state.
Offenders can be detained at home for up to 18 months and electronic monitoring devices can be fitted to track their whereabouts.
Mr Groom said a new report found Tasmania had been imposing suspended sentences more than any other Australian state.
"These changes send a strong message that if you do the crime, you do the time," he said.

Related Articles

The reforms follow amendments the Liberal government made in February to expand drug treatment orders.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Groom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Groom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
