<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429021561264069</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/real-estate/queensland/furbaby-trend-turning-aussie-backyards-into-pet-cemeteries/news-story/fcb285a1dc4169f4fe95b12a6b4a5b51</url>
  <title>Furbaby trend turning Aussie backyards into pet cemeteries - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
L to R, Emmeline Bowles, 3, with brother Edward Bowles, 8, at the grave of his beloved pet cat Slynx, with father David Bowles watching from the deck. Picture: AAP/Steve Pohlner

ALMOST half of Aussie pet owners bury their furbabies at home, with even rented properties being turned into cat and dog cemeteries, a new study has found.
Potentially around 785,000 rental properties were being turned into pet graveyards, with the latest finder.com.au survey naming home burial as the preferred option for almost half of all furry pet owners.
Finder.com.au insurance expert Bessie Hassan said 'furbaby' attachments were so strong that the majority of pet owners didn't want to part with them even in death.
"The fact that some Aussies may be breaching the terms of their lease in order to bury their pets on rented land is indicative of just how much we treasure them," she said.
The Australian Veterinary Association said companionship was the number one reason to own a pet in 2016, with a marked increase in cats and dogs being viewed as part of the family.

Slynx, beloved pet of Brisbane boy Edward Bowles, 8. The furbaby trend is seeing a rise in Aussie home burials for pets. Picture: Supplied

One in four pet owners preferred cremation for their furbabies, leaving their pet at the vet shop was the third most popular option, 5 per cent were partial to using an actual pet cemetery and 3 per cent favoured taxidermy.
Ms Hassan said "for animal lovers wanting to preserve the memory of their beloved pet, some pet insurance policies will provide a payment upon death to assist with accommodating for the loss".
Brisbane boy Edward Bowles, 8, can visit a memorial to his beloved cat Slynx, any time he wants in the yard of his home.
"We've got a grave there with a black cat statue and a stone the colour of Slynx who was orangey ginger and it's also got a little post with his name on it and a picture of him."
He's currently saving to buy another pet, his father David said.
"I would like to get another cat like Slynx," the primary schooler said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slynx</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hassan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bowles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bessie Hassan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furbaby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Veterinary Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward Bowles, 8</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward Bowles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmeline Bowles, 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Steve Pohlner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
