<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429193359957865</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/rugby/super-rugby-final-2017-michael-alaalatoa-has-gone-from-the-waratahs-scrap-heap-to-big-time/news-story/599e4a232b80edcc6cc04fc5d4b01c7c</url>
  <title>Aussie reject a key for Crusaders</title>
  <content>
HE was rejected by the Waratahs, and now Michael Alaalatoa is not only playing in a Super Rugby final for the Crusaders, but strongly stating his case for the All Blacks next year.
And this just as his younger brother Allan Alaalatoa has become part of the Wallabies' leadership group.
Michael, 25, left Australia frustrated after no Aussie Super side wanted to sign him for 2016, so he crossed the ditch and played for Manawatu Turbos.
Eighteen months later, he is an established member of the otherwise all-All Black front row of Joe Moody, Owen Franks and Wyatt Crockett.
Michael will come off the bench for the Crusaders against the Lions in South Africa in the decider, with the Kiwi team seeking their first premiership since 2008 and the Lions their first ever.
Allan and the rest of the Alaalatoa clan will have the pot of coffees on the go in the early hours of Sunday.
"All credit him and the hard work he's put in, as his brother I'm backing him in everything he does and I couldn't be prouder of him and this opportunity he has in front of him in Johannesburg," Allan Alaalatoa said.
"We were hoping the Hurricanes had a win there last week so they could get the home final and dad could go over there and watch.
"But our family and friends can't wait to watch the game early on Sunday morning."
In an intriguing twist, Allan will be cheering on the same front rowers he will scrummage against in the opening Bledisloe Cup Test in a fortnight.
"I told Mike to take this opportunity in the grand final, because I wish the two brothers could've been there, I'm supporting him all the way and I'm supporting the Crusaders," Allan said.
"I said: 'I'll support you just for this one game and we'll leave it all alone'. I wouldn't let anything come between family.
"Because of our strong bond we both know that, I'm just hoping they come away with a win."

Rugby: Sonny Bill Williams has had his suspension reduced making him available for the Bledisloe Cup.

SBW cleared for Bledisloe
Michael becomes eligible for New Zealand next July once the Super season is finished and will have a huge decision to make; whether he wants to become an All Black, or return to Australia to pursue the Wallaby gold alongside his brother.
"He's got another year with the Crusaders next year, he said he just wants to see how that pans out," Allan said.
"The way he's going now, it's opening up some doors he maybe didn't have earlier on in his career.
"He's got a good opportunity, that Crusaders team is very good."
2017 Super Rugby final
Lions v Crusaders, Johannesburg, Saturday, 11.55pm (Live on FoxSports 1)
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owen Franks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyatt Crockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Alaalatoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday, 11.55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manawatu Turbos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Super</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alaalatoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FoxSports 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe Cup Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOHANNESBURG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Moody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Alaalatoa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
