<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429150410284425</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/afl/collingwood/collingwood-premiership-captain-tony-shaw-says-the-magpies-should-look-to-lure-ben-brown/news-story/69283dc991e0e5d669b4604faab34896</url>
  <title>Collingwood premiership captain Tony Shaw says the Magpies should look to lure Ben Brown</title>
  <content>
Big Cat on the edge
0:21

AFL: Tom Hawkins needs to tread carefully after having already been suspended for a jumper punch earlier this season.

August 4th 2017
12 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/AFL/

Ben Brown celebrates. (Photo by Quinn Rooney/Getty Images)

Anna Harrington

Share

COLLINGWOOD premiership captain Tony Shaw says the Magpies should attempt to lure North Melbourne spearhead Ben Brown with a big-money, long-term deal.
The 24-year-old is among the contenders for the Coleman Medal, having booted 51 goals this year.
While the Pies have been linked to a move for Sydney tall Sam Reid, Shaw said his former side was better off looking to Brown.
"If I was going to spend money, Sam Reid - would I spend a million dollars on Sam Reid? No way known - because he's injury prone, inconsistent, plays well when his contract comes up a lot, Sam Reid," Shaw said on 3AW Radio.
"The other one around - and he's still got one more year (on his) contract, is Ben Brown.
"Now they're thinking about giving him more.
"I think Ben Brown - if I was Collingwood - I'd go out and offer Ben Brown a million dollars."

Ben Brown is congratulated by Taylor Garner. (Photo by Quinn Rooney/Getty Images)Source:Getty Images
Shaw said the combination of Brown's age, room for improvement and demonstrated ability to perform in a struggling side made him the perfect target.
"I'd offer him a million dollars for five years because he's 25 in November, he's shown (he can perform) in a side that's struggled and maybe not great ball movement to get it in their forward line," he said.

"He's shown he can perform in a side that struggles - and he's improving. Wayne Carey says there's a lot of improvement because he's improved things that he (knew) he had to but he's got other things he can improve on.
"I reckon a million dollars is under the ante for five years of a player of his ilk and it's what Collingwood needs to allow Moore and other players around him - Fasolo, Elliot, those types to become better players."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
When posed the possibility of North Melbourne offering Brown a contract in the region of $700,000, Shaw said the Pies should look to blow that out of the water.
"$700 (thousand) in the next? Well I'd be just knocking on his door, just saying 'son, here's a million a year for five years, just come over, baby,'" Shaw said.
While Josh Kelly has been valued at up to $1.5m per season, Collingwood great said he'd pay Brown that sort of money before the Giants midfielder.
"I'd be paying $1.5 for Ben Brown before Josh Kelly any day because he's a key position player and goal kicker," he said.
"It's what your club needs, too, isn't it? Someone needs a midfielder like Kelly, they'll pay.
"But $1.5 (million) for Kelly, that's crazy."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Harrington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaw</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Garner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fasolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinn Rooney/Getty Images</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Shaw</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Reid</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
