<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429279259305160</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/parliament-houses-secrets-revealed/news-story/590d0f8fa7cd3f5f69d13a4c9653afc2</url>
  <title>Parliament House's secrets revealed</title>
  <content>
Belinda TaskerAustralian Associated Press

Share

Annabel Crabb has spent years as a political journalist traipsing the corridors of power in Parliament House but the famous Canberra landmark still holds plenty of surprises even for her.
Like the vast underground space dubbed "the cathedral" that's been left unfinished with a dirt floor because the money ran out to do anything with it.
There's also a fascinating army of workers who keep the enormous building running, from the cleaners who shampoo carpet in the lifts to the horologists who fix the clocks.
Crabb says such discoveries were her favourite part of the 10 months she spent making her latest documentary series for ABC TV, The House.
The six-part series is Crabb's own "uber tour" of Parliament House and shows viewers what the building's thousands of visitors don't see on official tours.
"One of the things we really wanted to do with this series is bring the people into the people's house because Australian voters and citizens pay for that building, we are directed by it, we are affected by it," she told AAP.
"Only about 10 per cent of it is open to the public or can have cameras taken in. So there's whole stretches of the building that people who work there know very well but people outside never see on television."
Crabb, who took political junkies into the homes of dozens of pollies for the Kitchen Cabinet series, was given unprecedented access to parts of Parliament House where cameras are usually banned.
Once the official go ahead came through, Crabb and her camera crew set about filming behind-the-scenes action in places such as the prime minister's office and press gallery.

Viewers also get an insight into the late-night wheeling and dealing on legislation by senators, why pollies sometimes can speak only while holding a piece of paper over their heads, and which minister has a life-size Darth Vader figure.
Crabb was particularly blown away during a visit to the building's vast basement, which has its own street names and where workers get around using electric vehicles.
"There's 1100 rooms down there including this incredible space called The Cathedral, which is this vast unfinished underground cavity, which is seriously church size," she said.
"It's through a little door off a plant room. It's just bizarre. The building is full of these surprises."
Crabb was also surprised to discover just how self-sufficient the building is thanks to the in-house team of cleaners, gardeners, horologists, carpenters, electricians, mechanics and chefs.
"Anything that goes wrong inside the building can be pretty much fixed inside the building," Crabb said.
"There's hardly any buildings that function like that."
* The House premieres on ABC TV and iView at 8pm AEST, August 8.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darth Vader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crabb</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kitchen Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iView</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda TaskerAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annabel Crabb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
