<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428729503484061</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-05/a-shining-knight-in-white-boots</url>
  <title>A shining knight in white boots</title>
  <content>
'Fabulous' Phil Carman
Watch highlights of the career of Phil Carman

PHIL Carman believes he played better games during his controversial AFL/VFL career, but it is difficult to remember him having more impact than in round 20, 1975.

Resplendent in white boots, Carman kicked 11.4 against St Kilda at Moorabbin, including five in the last quarter, as Collingwood stormed home to defeat the Saints by 19 points, 24.12 (156) to 20.17 (137).

It was the only time the man dubbed 'Fabulous Phil' booted double-figure goals in his 100-game career.

"I was fortunate that day in that the shots I had at goal were pretty accurate," he said.

Carman does not remember too many games, but one that comes easily to mind was the previous round against Essendon at Victoria Park when he wore the white boots for the first time.

Returning from an eight-week stint on the sidelines after breaking a bone in his right foot playing for Victoria against Western Australia, he booted 6.8 at Victoria Park.

After being given the boots at training by adidas representatives Ted Whitten and Maurie Plant, he initially had been reluctant to wear them.

"I opened up the box and laughed, saying I couldn't possibly wear those," Carman said. "Then 'E.J.' handed me an envelope with a cheque for $200 in it and I agreed."

Carman was a late starter to League football aged 24, but made a huge impact in his debut season in 1975.

He won the Copeland Trophy as Collingwood's best and fairest player, was the club's leading goalkicker with 41, and was unlucky not to win the Brownlow Medal.

Despite missing eight games, he finished only three votes behind the winner, Footscray ruckman Gary Dempsey.

Carman and his white boots were never far from the centre of attention. 

Carman never quite reached those lofty heights again, leaving the Magpies at the end of 1978 and having stints at Melbourne, Essendon and North Melbourne.

But on August 16, 1975, he was truly fabulous.

Leading into the game, the stakes were high for both teams. The Saints were fourth on the ladder with 44 points while the Magpies were just outside the five on 40.

Played in perfect conditions, the high-scoring encounter was entertaining from the first bounce.

St Kilda spearhead George Young recalled the electric atmosphere among the packed stands and outer at Moorabbin.

"The ground was in good nick and it was a big crowd - one of the few times that Moorabbin was full in the mid to late '70s," he said.

Young attributed the Saints' control of the game in the first three quarters to a dominant display by centreman Glenn Elliott and Jeff Sarau being on top of Len Thompson in the ruck.

But all that changed in the final term, with Thompson feeding the fresher Magpies in the middle of the ground.

Collingwood went on to win its next two games and make the finals, at the expense of St Kilda.

While Young capitalised on the good work further afield to boot 8.4, his effort was overshadowed by Carman's virtuoso performance at the other end.

For most of the final quarter, Young was left "picking his nose" as the ball remained in the Magpies' forward half.

"We were well in control of the game, then Phil has turned the whole game around off his own boot in the last quarter," he said.

"What stood out most about those five goals was that he was playing on Barry Lawrence.

"I regarded Barry as one of the best players I've seen in VFL footy and to kick five in one quarter on 'Tubby' Lawrence was something unheard of.

"Teams coached by 'Jeansy' (Allan Jeans) just didn't lose when leading by four goals at three-quarter time, especially on your home deck. For Carman to do what he did, you'd probably never see a quarter of football like that."

Playing at full-forward was a new experience for the West Australian, who crossed the Nullarbor as a half-forward flanker in 1973.

This was only his second game as the Saints' spearhead, a switch that happened by chance in the previous round against Footscray at Whitten Oval.

The left-footer had been ruled out against the Bulldogs with the flu, but Jeans convinced the club doctor Young could make a contribution by playing out of the goalsquare.

Young kicked nine goals as St Kilda won by 68 points and he played out the remainder of his career at full-forward.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Carman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tubby' Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carman</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Dempsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitten Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footscray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fabulous Phil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted Whitten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Copeland Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nullarbor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeansy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Jeans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Len Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E.J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorabbin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL/VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Sarau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maurie Plant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16, 1975</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
