<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429150410284429</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/showdown-afl-crows-port-adelaide-chase-critical-win/8776282</url>
  <title>AFL Showdown: Crows and Port Adelaide chase critical win</title>
  <content>
Sunday's AFL Showdown at Adelaide Oval between the Crows and Port Adelaide is critical for both sides as the finals near.
The Crows are sitting on top of the ladder, a game clear of Geelong, then two wins separate third-ranked Greater Western Sydney and 11th-placed Saint Kilda.
On that crowded ladder, the Power is holding onto fifth spot.
It is generally consistency that wins premierships, as the AFL grand final has been won 10 times by the side at the top of the ladder after 18 matches, across the past 23 seasons.
But no team in top place after 18 games - but with fewer than 14 wins at that point - has gone on to take out the premiership.
The Crows are on top this season with 13 wins and a draw, but is that consistent enough to finish the finals as the last team standing?
On the other hand, only five sides have grabbed the premiership cup from outside the top three.
Just last season the Western Bulldogs ended a premiership drought which dated back to 1954 - the Dogs having been perched in sixth position after 18 games.
The other four clubs were the Swans  in 2005, Port Adelaide the year before that, Brisbane  in 2003 and Adelaide in 1998.
For the record, no team in fifth after 18 games - the position currently occupied by Port Adelaide - has gone on to win the premiership over the past 23 seasons.
What does it all mean?

The general rule remains that the best team throughout the minor round more often than not is the best bet when finals time arrives.
Adelaide fans have seen their team notch six wins and just two losses against teams in the top half of the ladder this season, while Port fans have seen just two wins and six losses on the same measure.
If the Crows can take out the 43rd Showdown on Sunday evening, they have a chance of finding themselves two games clear of the chasing pack, with three more games to play.
A win for Port Adelaide could see the Power jump to as high as third on the ladder.
There is plenty to play for in a season which has thrown up the unpredictable at times.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Showdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday's AFL Showdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
