<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429627151659484</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/nt-christian-schools-ordered-to-pay-50000-over-2015-death-of-student-after-pleading-guilty-in-nt-worksafe-prosecution/news-story/90a124d13cb26e354726eaf41a058ec6</url>
  <title>Justice over 'troopy pull' death</title>
  <content>
NT CHRISTIAN Schools has been convicted and fined $50,000 over the 2015 sports carnival death of a 12-year-old student at Gawa Christian School.
The student, who can only be referred to as Jethro, was killed during a "Troopy Pull" event at the school's annual sports carnival in August 2015, with Territory Coroner Greg Cavanagh finding last year the way the event was held was "manifestly dangerous".
The event involved students and community members using a rope to pull a Toyota Troop Carrier. Jethro tripped and fell while dangerously close to the moving four-wheel-drive, and the man steering the vehicle did not see the boy disappear under the wheels.
NT Christian Schools representatives appeared in Darwin Local Court yesterday, where the organisation entered a guilty plea to failing to comply with health and safety duties.
The organisation agreed Jethro's death was the culmination of 12 key failures of the school's safety duties.
Mark Thomas, prosecuting, said a fine should serve a "significant penalty imposed" to deter other organisations from neglecting their duties to provide safe schools and workplaces.
Judi Truman, defending, said NT Christian Schools was already cash-strapped, with government funding not keeping pace with the costs of running schools.
She said a fine should not be so large that it would take away from the organisation's students, many of whom are enrolled at schools in remote areas. Judge Elizabeth Morris said the organisation had shown "deep remorse" and gone to great lengths to help the close-knit Gawa community come to terms with Jethro's death.
"They can only be described ... as a model defendant, if there is such a thing," she said.
Ms Morris echoed Mr Cavanagh's comments in his inquest finding, where he said, "It is such a tragedy that it took the death of this child for the organisation to realise its shortcomings and fully understand its duties."
She said the school's breach was "serious" but that it had taken steps to improve safety processes.
She said the organisation, despite being run similar to a charity, was a registered company and had the capacity to pay a fine.
In a statement yesterday afternoon, NT Christian Schools said it accepted the penalty imposed.
"Our hearts and prayers continue to be with the family and community members who have suffered as a direct result of this incident," the statement said.
"Although we wish this tragedy had never occurred, we give thanks that the commitment of the community and the schools to work together in genuine partnership is stronger than ever."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jethro</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cavanagh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Elizabeth Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territory Coroner Greg Cavanagh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Christian Schools</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawa Christian School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judi Truman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Troop Carrier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troopy Pull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
