<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429579907018900</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/technology/2017/08/05/09/52/new-ring-to-change-how-phones-are-used</url>
  <title>A ring soon to hit the market will change how we use our phones</title>
  <content>
A ring that allows phone users to use their device through a finger is to hit the market early next year.
The Orii Ring allows people to handle calls, text messages and interact with a phone's digital assistant by putting a finger to their ear all by transferring sound to a through bone conduction.
The ring, designed by Hong Kong-based start-up Origami Labs, was inspired by Peter Wong, the visually impaired father of the firm's co-founder Kevin Wong.
"As a visual-impaired person, I rely on the software on the smartphone to read the icons, the texts to me," Peter Wong, who is a technical adviser for the ring, said.
A key feature ensures only the user can hear the information conveyed by the ring.
"Can you imagine it reading out your password? That's inconvenient and inappropriate," Mr Wong senior said.
What began as a  has become the latest example of wearable, screen-free technology.

Related Articles

"We want to keep our heads up, we want to be able to stay more in the moment," Kevin Wong, 29, said.
Mr Wong set up Origami Labs in November 2015 with three friends from university.
The tech wearable market grew 51 percent in Asia last year, according to consumer research firm GfK.
The overall industry is expected to be worth $US34 billion globally by 2020, research provider CCS Insight has said.
The Orii ring is expected to reach the commercial market by February.
(C) AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Wong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCS Insight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orii Ring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Wong, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origami Labs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
