<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429064510937598</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4835443/new-road-sends-foxground-tourist-attraction-down-the-gurgler/?cs=298</url>
  <title>New road sends Foxground tourist attraction 'down the gurgler'</title>
  <content>
New road sends Foxground tourist attraction 'down the gurgler'

John Grant, owner of Granties Maze in Foxground. Photo: Georgia Matts

John Grant, owner of Granties Maze in Foxground. Photo: Georgia Matts

John Grant, owner of Granties Maze in Foxground. Photo: Georgia Matts

John Grant, owner of Granties Maze in Foxground. Photo: Georgia Matts

John Grant, and the flowering tree he has used to construct walls of Granties Maze in Foxground on Friday. Picture: Rebecca Fist

John Grant showing off the tyre maze he's in the midst of building at Granties Maze in Foxground on Friday. Picture: Rebecca Fist

One of the dozens of attractions at Granties Maze in Foxground on Friday. Picture: Rebecca Fist

The 'Spider' climbing gym at Granties Maze in Foxground on Friday. Picture: Rebecca Fist

The lane costing Granties Maze owner $300,000 in Foxground on Friday. Picture: Rebecca Fist

exit

Princes Highway upgrades have been a blessing for motorists and a curse for John Grant, grand designer and owner of Granties Maze.
His roadside attraction developed beside a then, heavily-congested motorway has become a white elephant.

Each day, 70,000 cars that passed by Granties Maze now take a different route.

Instead of crawling over a hill on a windy, congested one-laned road, often limited to 40km per hour in a 60 zone, motorists fang along the newly-built double-laned road at Foxground.

"During the week I get no one here," Mr Grant said.

"I was getting a lot of Indians and Chinese driving from Sydney to Melbourne, this would be their first pit stop.

"They'd buy a drink, have a tea or coffee, and quite often they'd use the maze.
"Now, during the week I don't get any of that."

The downturn in business has led Mr Grant to recently lay off two full-time workers.

Some nearby tourist attractions, such as Crooked River Wines, have also been bypassed, and attained approval for signage along the Princes Highway, directing visitors to the venue.
Mr Grant's application has been knocked back.
"The state body said, 'Yes you qualify,' then I get a letter from (Kiama) council saying, 'No, you cannot put one up,' he said.

"You put an application in, and they will think of 50 reasons why you can't have it."
At 70, the Vietnam veteran and former real estate agent doesn't expect to make a profit off his business venture in his lifetime.
However, he has no regrets.

"This has always been my dream," he said.
"No matter what council throws at me, no matter what obstacle, I'll jump it.
"I haven't had a wage for two years, if I didn't have investment properties I wouldn't survive.
"I will never make money out of this place in my lifetime, but my kids and grandkids will have a job.

"I'm a stubborn bastard, I will just keep persisting.
"That persistence has been drummed in from an early age.
"I spent 12 months in Vietnam, that probably has a lot to do with it."

He does resent spending $300,000 on an exit lane on the old Princes Highway.
The exit lane's now obsolete, but as a condition of opening the park, Mr Grant was forced to fund construction of the lane to ensure motorists could access the park safely at the bottom of a steep descent.
He said he was assured Princes Highway upgrades would take three years, and decided three years would be enough time to establish his business.
To Mr Grant's detriment, upgrades finished a year and a half ahead of schedule.
Despite challenges he has faced, Mr Grant couldn't hide his pride as he led the Kiama Independent on a tour of the fun park.
It's a vortex into the 1950s, packed with quirky carnival rides.

Visitors can ride the bomber, a carousel built with World War II bomb seats, rides that require manual operation, ponies and 'the spider' a series of ropes that kids climb to reach a spiral slippery dip.
"I've been to 50 mazes in Australia and a lot of them have gone bankrupt, not because the maze is no good but because they don't have other attractions," Mr Grant said.
"I'm importing a lot of rides from Mexico, China, Canada, that no one else in Australia has."
The attractions, designed to safeguard his business, are the reason council will not approve signage on the Princes Highway.
Kiama council's general manager Michael Forsyth said Mr Grant has failed to meet planning regulation standards.
"Planners are working with Mr Grant to ensure the significant number of new attractions at Granties Maze meet relevant planning regulations," Mr Forsyth said.
"Once the business is fully compliant, council will be able to support an application to the NSW Government's Tourist Attraction Signposting Assessment Committee."
Read more

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Matts</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government's Tourist Attraction Signposting Assessment Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes Highway</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Fist</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Forsyth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granties Maze</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Grant</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Forsyth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama Independent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxground</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Grant</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crooked River Wines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
