<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429588496953567</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/absolute-carnage-three-crashes-in-12-hours/3209147/</url>
  <title>Absolute carnage: Three crashes in 12 hours</title>
  <content>
THE Bruce Highway was shut down for about six hours during what was a night of carnage on Sunshine Coast roads.
A horror 12-hour stint on our roads started with a domino-like Bruce Hwy crash just before 8pm.
A boat, believed to be a 13-feet tinnie, came off its trailer, colliding with a motorbike and rider.
Another vehicle swerved to miss the boat, side-swiping another vehicle which then collided with another vehicle.
The motorbike rider was taken to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital in a serious but stable condition, suffering chest and arm injuries.
A Police Media spokesman said the southbound lanes were closed off until almost 2am as traffic was diverted around the crash which happened about 2km north of Roys Rd.
Sunshine Coast Forensic Crash Unit and scenes of crime officers attended the scene, given the scale of the crash, the spokesman said.
A Queensland Ambulance Service spokesman said a woman was also taken to Caboolture Hospital in a stable condition as a result of the crash.
Meanwhile a woman believed to be about 20 was taken to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital as a precaution, complaining of lower leg injuries, after what was reported to police as a "massive crash" at Sippy Downs.
A Police Media spokesman said they were alerted to a "massive" accident on Lakehead Dr and University Way in the early hours of this morning, when the woman's car crashed into a brick wall at about 1.10am.
Emergency services were again called into action at about 7am, after two cars crashed at the Cunning Rd exit of the Sunshine Motorway.
Four occupants were involved in the incident, with one taken to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital for treatment.
CLAIRE got to experience a week in the RAAF.
Torture trial continues after house of horror claims.
Jobseekers learn they may not have work despite training.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Forensic Crash Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakehead Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roys Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cunning Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
