<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429648626496056</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:35</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/dubais-unfortunately-named-torch-tower-wont-stop-catching-on-fire/</url>
  <title>Dubai's Unfortunately Named Torch Tower Won't Stop Catching On Fire</title>
  <content>
Some Dubai residents woke up to a familiar sight early Friday morning: Flames engulfing an enormous skyscraper. In fact, the fire that spanned 50 of the 86 stories of the massive Torch Tower was . The same skyscraper burned in 2015, and the causes appear to be related.

Gif source: YouTube / AP

Luckily, there were no reported deaths or injuries in the latest Torch Tower fire. Unless local regulators do something about the building's flammable aluminium cladding, however, there's a decent chance the building could burn again. At 352m tall, Torch Tower is one of the tallest buildings in Dubai, and it's covered in aluminium panels that are filled with combustible plastic. So when even the smallest flame lights up the exterior, the blaze can spread with breakneck speed.

That appears to be what happened on Friday morning. The conditions of the fire eerily  that killed at least 80 people in London in June. In that case, it appears that the Grenfell Tower cladding may have violated regulations, and the Dubai government has also acknowledged the risk of installing flammable cladding on tall buildings. The construction technique has been linked to three separate tower fires in Dubai, and the government  of aluminium cladding on new construction. Those rules currently don't cover older buildings that might already have the material installed.

And so, . The fact that the Torch Tower has gone up in flames twice in two years' time isn't just frightening. It almost seems inevitable due to known risks of its building materials. Who knows if this latest fire will force the Dubai government to crack down further on building regulations. Let's just hope another catastrophe doesn't strike before that happens.

[]

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torch Tower</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stop Catching On Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grenfell Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GIF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai's Unfortunately Named Torch Tower Wo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
