<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428635014202357</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/apartment-development-attracts-interest-ahead-of-commonwealth-games/news-story/054bc7030b1e08f560135a9d9b13f749</url>
  <title>Apartment development attracts interest ahead of Commonwealth Games - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
BCM Property Home liftout. $150 million Beach Apartments, Broadbeach, developed by Anthony Moreton Group and Pryde Group.

THE final floor of  Broadbeach has been poured with 95 per cent of the $150 million development already sold.
Builder Mulitplex poured the floor on level 35 of the 219-apartment tower which is being developed in joint venture by Anthony Moreton Group and Pryde Group.
Purchasers from around Australia are snapping up the final two-bedroom, two-bathroom apartments selling from $639,000.

Brett Hohn (Avani), Warren Pryde (Pryde Group), Tony Hazell (Anthony Moreton Group), Cory Hinds (Multiplex) at The Beach Apartments Broadbeach.

Holiday-makers have already begun capitalising on the summer holiday period and the Gold Coast Commonwealth Games in April 2018 with bookings rolling in.
Anthony Moreton Group CEO Tony Hazell said while the opportunity to capitalise on the 2018
Commonwealth Games was part of the appeal, most purchasers were taking a long-term view
due to the property's premium location.
He said  was set to take 'centre stage' on the Gold Coast over the coming years.
"The Beach Apartments is also the only new residential high rise property to be delivered and
operational prior to the 2018 Commonwealth Games, and is therefore assured of being solidly
booked from the first day of opening," he said.
"The Pacific Ocean, expansive beach and Gold Coast hinterland are the 'hero views' of every single residence in the property."
Mr Hazell said: "The Beach will be ready for occupation this Summer, so it is appealing to purchasers who want to secure a brand new apartment off-the- plan without a long wait to pick up the keys or to start earning rental income".

The Beach Apartments, Broadbeach

The apartments, which feature sweeping views of the beach and Gold Coast hinterland, will be
managed by international hotel owner, operator and investor Minor Hotels.
Minor Hotels will manage The Beach as AVANI Broadbeach Residences, which will signal the first AVANI to open in Australia.
The project is three months ahead of schedule and is expected to be finished by December.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AVANI Broadbeach Residences</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbeach</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Moreton Group CEO Tony Hazell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AVANI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Hohn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulitplex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach Apartments</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minor Hotels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Moreton Group</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pryde Group</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hazell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Pryde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Hazell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cory Hinds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach Apartments Broadbeach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
