<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429708756038655</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/politics/flight-crackdown-on-security-the-new-rules-at-airports-coming-after-terror-scare/news-story/61be55be23efda506bdef12f20e84c8b</url>
  <title>Flight crackdown on security: the new rules at airports coming after terror scare</title>
  <content>
AFP allege Sydney terror plot suspects attempted to build IED
1:12

The Australian Federal Police allege the Sydney terror plot suspects attempted to build an Improvised Chemical Dispersion Device (IED) to detonate on an international flight

August 4th 2017
a day ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

A woman undergoes a full body scan at Melbourne International Airport, a security measure that may be introduced for domestic flights.

Candace Sutton

Share

NEW rules for travellers at Australian airports are coming in after a flight crackdown has been ordered following the Sydney airport terrorism plot.
The dramatic new security clampdown will tighten restrictions for taking liquids on board, photo IDS and possibly introduce biometric ID checks and full body scans.
The stringent new measures may also prohibit anyone without a current boarding pass from being let through domestic security,  reported.
The new rules will be in line with US domestic terminal practice and will reverse the relaxation of rules regarding liquid, aerosol and gel restrictions.
The so-called liquid and gel rules or "LAGS" over 20ml being placed in plastic bags were introduced after the 2006 UK plot to detonate liquid explosives on flights.
Metal detectors at domestic terminals throughout Australia cannot recognise liquids held on a person, which could be picked up on a full-body scanner.
Currently at US airports no-one can pass through security to a domestic terminal gate without a boarding pass.

A woman undergoes a full body scan at Melbourne International Airport, a security measure that may be introduced for domestic flights. .Source:News Limited

The Etihad check-in at Sydney airport, where a terrorist bomb plot was foiled a week ago. Picture: Justin LloydSource:News Corp Australia

Long queues at Adelaide Airport following the foiled Sydney bomb plot could become a permanent feature as security is stepped up. Picture: Keryn Stevens.Source:News Corp Australia
Mandatory security checks of passengers could be tightened and the Federal Government is believed to be considering biometric checks, by iris or fingerprint.
The proposal to again tighten domestic Australian airport security is a direct response to the alleged plan to blow up an Etihad Airlines flight from Sydney to Abu Dhabi.

Police say the plot was foiled only at the last minute, at check-in. The alleged plot failed when hand luggage, in which a metal meat grinder containing a military grade explosive was concealed, was deemed too heavy for boarding.
Authorities described the plan as "one of the most sophisticated plots" attempted in Australia which came close to a "catastrophic event".
The Weekend Australian's exclusive report says an Australia-wide rollout of new flight security rules has been discussed at senior levels within the Federal Government.
This follows an emergency National Security Committee meeting following the detainment of four men a week ago for questioning.

Full body scans, as practised in the US and the UK (above) could become mandatory at all Australian airports as security is ramped up.Source:AFP
Police have since charged two men with acting in preparation for or planning a terrorist act.
The proposed security measures are being discussed by Border Protection Minister Peter Dutton, Justice Minister Michael Keenan and Transport Minister Darren Chester.
They are likely to go before the Federal Cabinet within weeks, although the government expects major airlines to resist the moves which would add costs.
These would ultimately be passed on to passengers, increasing ticket prices.

Security officers check luggage at Sydney airport following the terror raids last weekend. Picture: Justin Lloyd.Source:News Corp Australia

Police at one of the addresses raided over a terror plot a week ago that will likely see stringent new security measures at airports. Picture: Brook Mitchell.Source:Getty Images
However, the new security measures are likely to become permanent and Mr Chester said security at all domestic airports had already tightened since last weekend's arrests.
Police allege that brothers Khaled Mahmoud Kayat, 49, and Mahmoud Kayat, 32, planned to use the improvised explosive device (IED) after carrying it to Sydney international airport.
A third brother, who was unaware of the terror plan, was unwittingly boarding the Etihad flight with the device in his luggage.
Terrorism investigators say parts of the IED had been sent from Turkey via air cargo from a fourth brother, who is an Islamic State commander.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IED</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekend Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Darren Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Minister Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia-wide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Lloyd.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin LloydSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Kayat, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Candace Sutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Protection Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Mahmoud Kayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brook Mitchell.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keryn Stevens.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Improvised Chemical Dispersion Device</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne International Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
