<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428849762570125</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/kim-snowball-offers-health-advice-to-wa-government/8776100</url>
  <title>WA missing out on $430 million annually due to GP shortage: Former Health Department head</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

When Kim Snowball ran Western Australia's Health Department, the iron ore price hit an all-time high and people were moving to the state in droves.
Today the economic and demographic problems facing WA are vastly different, but Mr Snowball has some advice for the Government as it grapples with ballooning health costs.
"My pitch is to say, don't just focus on hospitals. The key issue is actually in primary health care and we need to get both of those right," Mr Snowball said.
The former director general, who spent just over three years in the role, said a major problem was the lack of GPs in WA, relative to other states.
"Because of our shortage of GPs, we are $430 million per year worse off in terms of our community-based services," Mr Snowball said.
"One of the things the hospitals are having to do is pick up for a shortfall in general practice.
"A lot more people are attending our emergency departments and also we have preventable admissions to our hospitals.
"With enough GPs, and enough community-based services, you'll see the sort of pressure start to come off our hospitals, and I think any focus of this State Government needs to be not just hospitals but the broader health system."
Figures from the State Government show there are 95 GPs per 100,000 people at a national level.
In WA, the figure is 77 GPs, which the Government says amounts to a shortfall in Medicare benefits of $190 for every person in the state.
Calls to rebate GPs for video consults

Mr Snowball, who now heads advisory firm Healthfix Consulting, said that shortfall could be partly addressed by rebating GPs for consults conducted over video conference to people in country areas.
"To my mind, having telehealth or GPs able to consult or use Medicare for patients in rural areas, that overcomes our tyranny of distance and our isolation that we've struggled with for so long."
Tim Shackleton is the chief executive of Rural Health West, which recruits and provides support to rural health workers.
He says medical specialists already use video conferencing to treat patients in country areas, funded by Medicare.
"We think a GP video service, recognised by the Medicare Benefits Scheme, will be important for occasions where a solo GP leaves a community and there is a delay in attracting a replacement," Mr Shackleton said.
"This state is huge. We spend a lot of money on patient transport services, both emergency services and non-emergency services, so anything that we can do to reduce [that] ... is a good thing."
Rural Health West estimates about $100 million of the $430 million Medicare shortfall is lost in the bush, due to a lack of access to GPs.
Having online GP consults funded by Medicare would reduce some of that gap, but health experts say other measures should be considered in the short term.
One option is for the State Government to pursue a one-off grant from the Commonwealth.
"It's been done before, so there's no reason why it couldn't be argued again, I would think," Mr Snowball said.

"The difficulty is it's a big number, it's $430 million and that's a big hole for the state."
Health Minister Roger Cook told the ABC he tabled a paper on the issue of WA's Medicare shortfall at a COAG health meeting in Brisbane on Friday, but declined to say whether the Government would seek a one-off federal grant.
"Western Australia should be considered for a special arrangement or agreement with the Commonwealth, and we've indicated that we're very keen to sit down with the Commonwealth and make that happen."
But Federal Health Minister Greg Hunt said Medicare funds were tied to service delivery, and WA's funding was already growing at a faster rate than the national average.
"Medicare funding responds to particular services. What we can do is exactly what we are doing - [providing] immediate, current, rural GP training programs."
Mr Hunt said the Government was about to appoint a Rural Health Commissioner, which would consider whether GP consults by video conferencing should be rebated.
"That commissioner will specifically look at the need for and role of additional rural telehealth services right across the Medicare system," he said.
"I think there's enormous prospect here both in terms of increased service and increased affordability. It has tremendous potential."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COAG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rural Health Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Roger Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Snowball</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare Benefits Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Healthfix Consulting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Health Minister Greg Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Snowball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA's Medicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rural Health West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shackleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Shackleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia's Health Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Former Health Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
