<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429455352965931</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/world/prince-henrik-refuses-to-buried-with-his-wife-queen-margrethe-as-he-is-not-her-equal/news-story/f6648326ff2dcec9f51653ba168a600e</url>
  <title>Danish Prince's 50-year grudge</title>
  <content>
THE husband of Denmark's Queen Margrethe is causing a stir in one of the world's oldest monarchies.
Prince Henrik has announced he won't be buried next to Margrethe in the Roskilde cathedral where Danish royals have been buried since 1559. She has had a specially designed sarcophagus made for them there.
"Traditions are important to all monarchies so this is felt pretty violently," said Lars Hovbakke Soerensen, an expert in Danish history.
The royal house gave no reason for Henrik's decision, but the 83-year-old French-born prince has long complained that he didn't become monarch instead of his wife when she acceded to the throne in 1972.
"Any man who is not equal to his spouse is not worthy to be buried in the same grave," Henrik said today, according to the Ekstra Bladet tabloid.
The royal house later confirmed the quotes to Reuters.
"It is no secret that the prince for many years has been unhappy with his role and the title he has been awarded in the Danish monarchy. This discontent has grown more and more in recent years," the Royal Danish House's director of communications told tabloid BT.
"For the prince, the decision not to buried beside the queen is the natural consequence of not having been treated equally to his spouse - by not having the title and role he has desired," she added.
The prince 'retired' last year, and renounced his title of prince consort. He is still officially married to the queen.
Hovbakke Soerensen said "this is the culmination of his grumbling in the past. It has become more and more pronounced in the past 10-15 years. This is a way to say to Danes and Denmark 'thanks but no thanks."
The palace said yesterday that Margrethe, 77, has accepted Henrik's decision, adding it didn't change her burial plans.
Henrik, who retired from public life last year, said through the royal household that he wanted to be buried in Denmark but didn't say where.
Born Henri Marie Jean Andre de Laborde de Monpezat, he met Margrethe in London where he was a diplomat with the French Embassy. He changed his name to Henrik, converted to Denmark's state Lutheran Church and became prince consort.
Henrik has two sons with the queen, Crown Prince Frederik and Prince Joachim. Frederik is married to Crown Princess Mary, an Australian.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roskilde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Princess Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Joachim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henrik</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margrethe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lars Hovbakke Soerensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Henrik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lutheran Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frederik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prince Frederik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Danish House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monpezat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark's Queen Margrethe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henri Marie Jean Andre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hovbakke Soerensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekstra Bladet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laborde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Embassy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
