<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429451057998593</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/discount-prices-to-banned-from-queensland-petrol-station-boards/8777480</url>
  <title>Fuel discount prices to be banned from service station boards</title>
  <content>
Service stations in Queensland will be banned from displaying discounts on their price billboards under new state laws.
Treasurer and Acting Energy and Biofuels Minister Curtis Pitt said "what you see is what you pay" regulations will from January 31 next year outlaw confusing discounted prices, which are not available to all motorists.
It comes after last year's Fuel Price Summit, where concerns were raised that motorists were being tricked into paying more at the pump.
"Calls for truth in petrol price advertising has long been a burning issue for motorists," Mr Pitt said.
"These strict regulations mean fuel retailers will still be able to a promote discount fuel price schemes, but only the full price available to all motorists can be displayed on the price boards."
RACQ spokeswoman Renee Smith said the change was a major win for motorist who felt cheated by unfair prices for too long.
"Too many petrol stations are luring motorists in by advertising cheaper fuel prices, where you need a voucher to redeem or first buy items in the store," Ms Smith said.
"These dodgy advertisements mean many motorists are suckered into filling up before realising they're not eligible for the fuel discount.
"It's fantastic the State Government's now making this practice illegal."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biofuels Minister Curtis Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acting Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuel Price Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
