<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429584201986220</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/11/03/new-service-helps-seniors-with-medications</url>
  <title>New app helps keep track for those on multiple medications</title>
  <content>
Whether it's common painkillers or prescription drugs, many people have a variety of medications in their homes.
They're meant to keep people healthy but it can be easy to mix them up or even miss vital doses, leading to an adverse medicine event.
It's something that worried former tennis coach Allan Nash who takes a number of pills to keep on top of his health and fitness.
"I particularly take quite a few supplements on a daily basis and occasionally a bit of ibuprofen for an injury or something like that," Nash told 9NEWS.
He now uses his smartphone to help him keep track - downloading a free Australian app called MedicineWise. It stores a log of everything he takes, reminding him when to take it by pushing a special alert.
While it's handy for long-term medications, short-term prescriptions like antibiotics can be entered in as well.
"You can set the end date as well so after seven days it will stop alerting you because you've finished your course," Nash said.

Related Articles

The free service has been developed by NPS MedicineWise, a government funded service that provides independent information for anyone with concerns about the medication they're taking.
Aine Heaney from NPS MedicineWise says to use the app, simply enter the medicine details or  photograph the bar code on the packet.
"So indeed if you have a child who's taking medicines or if you have a parent or someone else that you're caring for, you can absolutely build multiple profiles within the app," Ms Heaney said.
She believes it's especially useful for medications that need to be taken at the same time every day, like the contraceptive pill.
"Having a tool like this app to help you remember is a really great way to make sure you're taking them correctly, safely and well - the more medicines you're on the more complicated it can get."
For those needing to keep up with multiple medicines, pharmacies like Chemist Warehouse can also make up sealed blister packs for a small cost.
They're available in weekly, fortnightly or monthly compartments.
The MedicineWise app can be downloaded for all types of smartphones.
For more information visit .
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Nash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPS MedicineWise</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chemist Warehouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aine Heaney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MedicineWise</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Heaney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
