<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429201949892589</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/nitv/nitv-news/article/2017/08/05/pm-shorten-miserable-leaders-says-pearson-after-no-bipartisan-commitment-voice</url>
  <title>PM, Shorten 'miserable' leaders, says Pearson after no bipartisan commitment on voice to parliament</title>
  <content>
Disappointment after political leaders fail to give voice to parliament proposal full bipartisan support.

By

NITV Staff Writer

5 Aug 2017 - 9:16 AM  UPDATED 20 MINS AGO

Prominent Aboriginal Australian Noel Pearson has delivered a scathing assessment of the "miserable" political leadership shown by the prime minister and opposition leader towards constitutional reform.

Many senior Aboriginal figures had hoped Malcolm Turnbull and Bill Shorten would commit to an indigenous voice to parliament when they attended the Garma Festival opening ceremony in northeast Arnhem Land on Friday.

But Mr Pearson echoed the bitter disappointment of Referendum Co-chair Pat Anderson, who slammed the "empty platitudes" offered by both politicians as gutless.

"It is such a miserable scene, the leadership scene in Australia," Mr Pearson said.

"But we have never let that in the past determine our fortitude, and we must keep our eyes on the prize."

Mr Pearson urged comrades to continue agitating for a national vote on an Indigenous advisory body, insisting such a "profound proposition" deserves a response "in the lifetime of our current leaders".

"Political cycles come and go, but this agenda will never go away," he said.

Mr Shorten called for a joint parliamentary select committee to finalise a referendum question on the Aboriginal voice proposal, but Mr Turnbull is yet to commit bipartisan support.

"I regard Garma as an opportunity to provide us in Canberra with inspiration. To actually argue for a Makarrata Commission, for truth telling and for treaties," he said.

"In amongst everything else here at Garma, perhaps all of us: Aboriginal leaders, the Government, the Opposition, can sit down and work out the next steps towards achieving it."

Yesterday at the Garma opening ceremony Mr Turnbull said the relationship between Indigenous and non-Indigenous Australia is based on mutual respect. 

"Our relationship is based on mutual respect and we build that and care for that as we learn from each other and as we learn from you. We learn language, we learn culture, and based on that is respect," he said.

"As the Prime Minister, one of my most important roles as a leader is to listen. So, we've come to learn, and participate in this festival, respectfully."

Ms Anderson said Indigenous Australians needed another expert panel "like a hole in the head".

She said Mr Turnbull, who delivered much of his speech in Yolgnu Matha language, had been disrespectful to land rights champion Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu, who stressed the urgent need to resolve unfinished business of reconciliation and self-determination.

"We live side by side, but we're not yet united," Dr Yunupingu said.

With AAP

A new paper examines the ways "whiteness" reproduces racial advantages and disadvantages.

The only identified Indigenous Australian woman in WWI was actually serving for Canada.

Several people, including members of the Stolen Generation, have gathered at the Sydney Opera House to launch commemorations for the 20th anniversary of the Bringing...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Co-chair Pat Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolgnu Matha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 20 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makarrata Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NITV Staff Writer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stolen Generation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal Australian Noel Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 2017 - 9:16 AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
