<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429713051005993</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/hilary-duff-slams-body-shamers-over-beach-picture-tells-them-to-kiss-my-ass/news-story/3ff590539b32466a1564dbcb70a672cc</url>
  <title>Hilary Duff slams body shamers over beach picture, tells them to 'kiss my ass'</title>
  <content>
Hilary Duff Addresses Body Issues on Instagram, Celebrates Her Legs
1:45

Hilary Duff is baring some major leg and getting candid about some of her past insecurities. And now fans are praising her for it. In one of her latest Instagram posts, Hilary confesses: "I didn't always love my legs, but as I've grown, I've learned to love and celebrate myself, just as I am," Hilary looks happy and healthy in the post saying: "I began to realize that my legs are strong and they carry me every. Single. Day. Our bodies are amazing and something to be grateful for. I'm me and that's really enough!" But this isn't the first time Hilary has opened up about some of these real life struggles. She recently told US Weekly that she learned to accept her body saying: "I feel good about myself," but admits that also comes with being human and feeling the all too familiar "5-pound battle" saying because being 5 feet 2, everything is going to show on me!"

February 4th 2017
6 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Hilary Duff has a message for anyone trying to body shame her. Picture: Ari Perilstein

NY Post

Share

HILARY Duff is calling out everyone who's called her out already.
"Since websites and magazines love to share 'celeb flaws' - well I have them!" she wrote on Instagram of a pic snapped from behind while she holds her son at the beach.

on

The Younger star, soon to be 30, is holidaying in Hawaii after "a long season of shooting," where she has been getting in some quality time with her son.
But her trip was interrupted when trolls began picking apart her "flaws" after bathing suit pictures shot by paparazzi emerged.
Duff clapped back by saying, "My body has given me the greatest gift of my life: Luca, 5 years ago. I'm turning 30 in September and my body is healthy and gets me where I need to go."
She ended her lengthy post by inspiring women to accept their bodies as they are.
"Ladies, lets be proud of what we've got and stop wasting precious time in the day wishing we were different, better, and unflawed."
Her advice for anyone else? "#Kissmyass."
This isn't the first time the Lizzie Maguire star has encouraged other women to have more self confidence.

In February, the actress took to Instagram to encourage her followers to love themselves.
"Our bodies are amazing and something to be grateful for. I'm ME and that's really enough!" she wrote.

A post shared by Hilary Duff (@hilaryduff) on

originally appeared on The New York Post and has been republished here with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NY Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DUFF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luca, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Us Weekly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ari Perilstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilary</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kissmyass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lizzie Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilary Duff Addresses Body Issues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilary Duff</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
