<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429451057998589</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/celebrity-selfies/drew-barrymore-shows-off-her-weeks-of-work-to-get-into-character-as-a-californian-housewife/news-story/133466e23fc3beed5ab7d3ca014e370f</url>
  <title>Drew Barrymore shows off her weeks of work to get into character as a Californian housewife</title>
  <content>
Drew Barrymore Doesn't Think She's 'Hot' Anymore
1:00

Drew Barrymore explains what it means to be "hot" in Hollywood, and doesn't think she fits the bill at the moment.

February 5th 2016
2 years ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

A lot goes into getting Drew Barrymore ready for Santa Clarita Diet Picture: Netflix

Natalie Wolfe

Share

DREW Barrymore went viral earlier this week for a photo that revealed, just like us, she occasionally lets her brows get out of control and forgets to dye her roots.
"OH MY GOD. How did I let it get this bad. Base and brows needed," the 42-year-old actor captioned her refreshing selfie.

on

Barrymore was praised the world over for the realistic photo and now, after weeks of working out, a visit to the salon for a full head of foils and a perfect manicure, the actress has showed off the finished product.
The Charlie's Angels star posted the "post-make-over" selfie to prove what goes into getting ready for her role on Netflix's Santa Clarita Diet.

on

"Back in the saddle again. Thank you to all the experts who helped me get here. It's no wonder I don't want to deal with all that being a lady entails sometimes. I'm a mum. I work like crazy. And the first thing to go is usually yourself," she wrote.
"I love this job because it forces me to put back into myself, even if it's really for someone else like Sheila. I feel so grateful to have a job I love. I know how lucky I am and I never take it for granted. Period. Becoming her took weeks and weeks. It gets harder the older you get. But working hard is always worth it. OK. Time to be cool. Because I'm usually not. But she is. So I will be. You know ... fake it til you make it. But don't ever stop short!!!!!!!" she added.
Barrymore, who has been working in Hollywood for more than four decades, has become one of the most refreshing celebrities on Instagram, constantly empowering her 7.4 million followers with truthful messages about what goes into being a celebrity.
Instead of just posting a picture of her perfect manicure yesterday, the actress decided to add an empowering and hilarious message to the picture.

"Gosh, being a girl is time consuming. No wonder I let it all go," she wrote, adding the hashtag "It takes a village".

A post shared by Drew Barrymore (@drewbarrymore) on

And when the actor visited the salon to get her regrowth sorted, her daughter Olive came along for the trip, with the hairdresser putting conditioner in her four-year-old's hair for "solidarity".

A post shared by Drew Barrymore (@drewbarrymore) on

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Wolfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hot' Anymore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OH MY GOD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrymore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Barrymore</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheila</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Clarita Diet Picture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Think She</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie's Angels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix's Santa Clarita Diet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Barrymore Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
