<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429279259305155</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/tyre-stockpile-dumped-cattle-station-reef-north-queensland/8777388</url>
  <title>Tyre stockpile found dumped at north Queensland cattle station</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

About 15,000 used tyres dumped on a property near the Great Barrier Reef will be shredded and converted into biofuel, after they were discovered by the Queensland Government.
The Government bought the $7 million cattle station north of Cairns, known as Springvale Station, without realising it also contained the massive tyre stockpile.
It has now spent about $135,000 to take the tyres to recyclers Tyrecycle in Ipswich.
Environment Minister Steven Miles said it is another example of a rogue operator hoarding tyres instead of destroying them responsibly.

"These kinds of tyre stockpiles, if they catch fire, it's literally like burning oil," he said.
"It's almost impossible to put out and very dangerous to the wider environment."
The Environment Department was not looking to take action against the former owners of the station -which was purchased to reduce run-off into the reef - but warned others who stockpiled tyres would be investigated.
Tougher rules pitched

External Link:

Tyres building up at the Rocklea site
Mr Miles blamed a rise in rogue operators on the former Liberal National Party government, which scrapped tyre storage regulation.
One operator, Tony Di Carlo, .
In June, .

Mr Miles said Labor was working with the industry to craft new regulations for tyre operators.
However that might not be enough given Labor's minority government status in the Queensland Parliament.
"We would need to convince the cross-benchers to support those laws," he said.
"I've worked on the assumption the LNP would oppose them, given this is reversing the damage that they did in government."
If the negotiations do not work, Mr Miles said Labor would craft new regulations if it wins a majority at the state election.
Tyres to be shipped to China

Tyrecycle chief executive Jim Fairweather said tyres from Springvale Station would be chopped up, packed and sent to Asia where they would be converted into fuel.
"You're diverting waste from landfill, you're reducing the use of fossil fuels and the simple way to put it is, it burns cleaner and hotter than coal," he said.
Mr Fairweather said the industry needed to be properly regulated, with many legitimate businesses being undercut by rogue operators.
"Stockpiling tyres is a lot cheaper than trying to re-process them into an alternate fuel," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrecycle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Barrier Reef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Fairweather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocklea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springvale Station</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Di Carlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Miles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fairweather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
