<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428506165181241</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834729/the-store-officially-listed-on-market/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>The Store officially listed on market</title>
  <content>
Picture: Phil Hearne

THE Store has officially been taken to market by agency Colliers International. 
Agents Peter Macadam and Matt Kearney have listed the 12,000 square metre site at 854 Hunter Street for expressions of interest, closing 3pm on September 8.

"The Store site comprises a large strategic holding occupying a prime position within the CBD, forming a key site under the LEP," the agency wrote on its website. "The purchaser is required to deliver a bus interchange to integrate with the adjacent Newcastle Interchange, with the site capable of development of up to 60,000 square metres gross floor area under a mixed use scheme or 96,000 square metres gross floor area under a commercial scheme. A requirement has been confirmed by Property NSW for 5000 square metres of commercial office space. PNSW is investigating additional tenancy requirements but this cannot be guaranteed at this time. Additional space, should it be required, will be confirmed during this sale process."  The government confirmed in July the heritage-listed building would be demolished by the end of 2018.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Interchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Hearne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colliers International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Kearney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Macadam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
