<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429408108325249</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828133/fine-work-of-fairfax-staff-recognised/?cs=310</url>
  <title>Fine work of Fairfax staff recognised</title>
  <content>
The work of Fairfax reporters and photographers has been recognised in the 2017 PANPA Newspaper of the Year Awards

Finalists were announced for news media publishers from around the Asia-Pacific region this week.

The PANPA awards will be held in Darling Harbour on September 6. 
Now enjoy the work of Fairfax Regional staff.
Portrait photography finalists

Alan Langdon and his daughter Que became the object of an international man hunt until they were . Jessica McInerney's photo captures the high emotion of the situation.

Alan Langdon. Photo: Jessica McInerney, Milton Ulladulla Times
Lauren Darlington shared her "messages of hope" after years of self-harm. In a sometimes uncomfortable honest article, Liber's photographs added even more raw emotion. To see the full article  or on the image below.

Scars laid bare. Photo: Sylvia Liber, Illawarra Mercury

Mia Gundy was the first winner to be announced at the Newcastle stage of the Aboriginal Model Search, a competition which scours the country to find the next generation of indigenous models. .

Aboriginal Model Search Finalist Mia Gundy. Photo: Marina Neil, Port Stephens Examiner
Six-year-old Kody O'Brien has Cerebral Palsy and a rare Epilepsy condition and needs a $20,000 device fitted to give him quality of life. Marina Neil captured his spirit perfectly. . 

Big Fight for Little Kody. Photo: Marina Neil, Maitland Mercury
Seven-year-old Jayde Romero was the first person to notice the thick smoke pouring from the fire that went on to raze her home. Glenn Daniels' images reinforced the devestation facing her family. .

Kids' courage in crisis. Photo: Glenn Daniels, Bendigo Advertiser
Rohan Thomson worked over four months with Canberra's famed National Zoo and Aquarium to capture a series of stunning animal portraits using techniques usually used for indoor studio work.

Wild Side. Photo: Rohan Thomson, The Canberra Times
And featuring as finalists in the various features and lifestyles sections are:

Marta Pascual Juanola's article on Aboriginal activist Aunty Judith, published in the Mandurah Mail. .

Aunty Judith. Photo: Marta Juanola, Mandurah Mail
This stunner from Geoff Jones at the  also earned a finals nomination.

The Jumps. Photo: Geoff Jones, Hawkesbury Gazette
Newcastle Herald photographer Jonathan Carroll has spent the past 12 months trekking across the Hunter to put his own spin on the night sky.

Space Cowboy. Photo: Jonathan Carroll.
In her own words: "The idea behind Underwater Playground has been a project that I've wanted to do for a while now. I wanted to create an underwater visual paradox. I wanted to create an underwater world that would encompass dance and passion draped by the innocence of water."

Part of Sylvia Liber's photographic essay featuring local dancer Olivia Mitchell at Bass Point.
Among the finalists in the various sports categories were:

Marta Pascual Juanola from the Mandurah Mail for her portrait of MMA pro Ray Karaitiana. . 

Ray Karaitiana. Photo: Marta Juanola, Mandurah Mail
And then there's Jonathan Carroll's "footy" series as featured in the Newcastle Herald. Check out the series below.

Fine work of Fairfax staff recognised

exit
International cyclist Richie Porte puts in the legwork for this year's 3516-kilometre Tour de France by completing up to 1000km a week around Tasmania. Scott Gelston's camera lens captured just some of the behind-the-scenes hard work. .

Geoff Jones' gloriously uninhibited image of young footballers doing kid things, published in the , is a finalist

Water Fight. Photo: Geoff Jones, Hawkesbury Gazette
Jarrod Poort became an instant cult hero after the 2016 Rio Olympics for his brazen race in the 10km marathon open water swim. When the Illawarra Mercury caught up with home on home turf after the Games, Syvia Liber's images helped tell the story.
Among the finalists in the various news sections are:

Rio heartbreak. Photo: Sylvia Liber, Illawarra Mercury
wanted to make sure everyone knew the 2016 Census was on. Renee Powell's image "let's be counted" says it all.

Let's be counted. Photo: Renee Powell, Forbes Advocate
Western Sydney University students made sure they entered into the spirit of things early May. Included in her "May The Fourth Be With You" photo collection was Isabella Lettini's eye-catching shot. 

May The Fourth Be With You. Photo: Isabella Letini, Parramatta Sun
Marina Neil is a finalist for her work during the K which threatened scores of properties in the Hunter region of NSW.

Burning Kurri Kurri. Photo: Marina Neil, Newcastle Herald
To many in his Newcastle suburb Bernie Sessions was known as . He was there day and night, usually with a beer in one hand, and with the other, he would wave at walkers, drivers, anybody. He died. The outpouring of emotion in the community was captured by Max Mason-Hubers.

Grieving the man in the doorway. Photo: Max Mason Hubers, Newcastle Herald
The Northern Daily Leader's Gareth Gardner is also a finalist for his capture of a lone child as he looked at the long list of names of servicemen who fought for their country, listed on the gates at ANZAC Park. 

Spirit lives on. Photo: Gareth Gardner, The Northern Daily Leader
The full list of Fairfax finalists for PANPA 2017 awards

NEWS SITE OF THE YEAR - Regional: ; , , . National/Metropolitan:
DAILY NEWSPAPER OF THE YEAR - Regional: Bendigo Advertiser, The Advocate, The Examiner, Newcastle Herald. National/Metropolitan: The Canberra Times.
NON- DAILY NEWSPAPER OF THE YEAR - Community: St George & Sutherland Shire Leader, The Maitland Mercury; Regional: Queensland Country Life, The Land.
PHOTOGRAPHY

PORTRAIT - Community: Marina Neil, Port Stephens Examiner; Jessica McInerney, Milton Ulladulla Times; Marina Neil, The Maitland Mercury. Regional: Glenn Daniels, Bendigo Advertiser;  Sylvia Liber, Illawarra Mercury. National/Metropolitan: Rohan Thomson, The Canberra Times.
FEATURES AND LIFESTYLE - Community: Marta Juanola, Mandurah Mail; Geoff Jones, Hawkesbury Gazette. Regional: Jonathon Carroll, Newcastle Herald; Sylvia Liber, Illawarra Mercury.
SPORT - Community: Marta Juanola, Mandurah Mail; Geoff Jones, Hawkesbury Gazette. Regional: Jonathan Carroll, Newcastle Herald; Scott Gelston, The Examiner; Sylvia Liber, Illawarra Mercury.
NEWS - Community: Renee Powell, Forbes Advocate; Isabella Lettini, Parramatta Sun. Regional: Marina Neil, Newcastle Herald; Max Mason Hubers, Newcastle Herald; Gareth Gardner, The Northern Daily Leader.
TECHNICAL EXCELLENCE

SINGLE-WIDTH - Community: Penrith Gazette, North Richmond Print Centre; Regional:  Newcastle Herald, Beresfield Print Centre. DOUBLE-WIDTH - Community: Yass Tribune, Canberra Print Centre. Regional: The Land. National/Metropolitan: The Canberra Times. PRE-PRINT OR SUPPLEMENT - Kids in our Community, Singleton Argus. PRINT CENTRE OF THE YEAR - Canberra Print Centre.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Richmond Print Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabella Lettini</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Daily Leader</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Mercury</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Kody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Underwater Playground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Jones</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes Advocate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bendigo Advertiser</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRE-PRINT OR SUPPLEMENT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aunty Judith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal Model Search</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PANPA 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kody O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National/Metropolitan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Daily Leader's Gareth Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Poort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mia Gundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Site of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PANPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Zoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yass Tribune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Gelston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bass Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Print Centre of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkesbury Gazette</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milton Ulladulla Times</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syvia Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Times</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Mercury</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Regional</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith Gazette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Daniels</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Print Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandurah Mail</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sutherland Shire Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Darlington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fourth Be With You</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wild Side</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gareth Gardner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Langdon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Powell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens Examiner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabella Letini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal Model Search Finalist Mia Gundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica McInerney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marta Juanola</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Sun</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Country Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cerebral Palsy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayde Romero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singleton Argus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Newspaper of the Year</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richie Porte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Karaitiana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beresfield Print Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marta Pascual Juanola</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PANPA Newspaper of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
