<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429064510937644</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/travel/holiday-ideas/ski/australian-ski-resort-lift-pass-prices-thredbo-perisher-mount-hotham-falls-creek/news-story/8f8f088fee806597885cc687771dfe25</url>
  <title>The trick to getting cheap ski passes</title>
  <content>
Most Aussies baulk at the cost of a day pass in the snow but if you play it smart there are great discounts to be had.
Comparison site,, has rounded up the best ways to save your dollars on your next ski holiday. From lift tickets, accommodation, ski hire and the one thing most Aussies forget to do, here's what you need to know.
LIFT PASSES
Most ski resorts will provide discounts for purchasing lift passes in advance online. There is also better value in buying lift passes in bulk. For example, finder.com.au found that in some resorts you can purchase a week's lift pass for the equivalent cost of 3.5 single day lift passes.
"If you're a keen skier it's worth looking into a season pass - at some resorts you only need to hit the slopes 11 times for it to be good value. They can also attract additional bonus benefits such as free leisure centre entry, bring-a-friend vouchers, and discounts at affiliated resorts," says Bessie Hassan, Money Expert at finder.com.au.
ONLINE DISCOUNTS
THREDBO, NSW - full price for one adult day pass is $125. There is a 20 per cent discount if purchased online seven days in advance
PERISHER, NSW - full price for one adult day pass is $128. There is a 25 per cent discount if purchased online seven days in advance
CHARLOTTE PASS, NSW - full price for one adult day pass is $103. There is no discount for purchasing in advance.
MOUNT HOTHAM, VIC - full price for one adult day pass is $129. There is a discount of up to 15 per cent off when purchased online 14 days in advance.
FALLS CREEK, VIC - full price for one adult day pass is $134. There is a 15 per cent discount when purchased online 14 days in advance.
MOUNT BULLER, VIC - full price for one adult day pass is $124. There is a discount of up to 10 per cent off when purchased the day before.
SKI HIRE
According to , pre-booking your ski or snowboard equipment online or in store can usually nab you a discount.
"If you are a regular ski bunny it's worth looking into purchasing ski gear at the end of a season or online at the end of the northern hemisphere season to get the best 'bang for buck'," says Hassan.
SKI LESSONS
Private lessons are a sure way to blow your budget but taking a group ski class will help cut the costs. And it's good news if you're under 18 or over 65 as these age groups often receive discounted passes.
"Buying lift and lesson packages (offered in some resorts like Thredbo) can cut costs for both kids and adults. These are often a discounted price that covers lift passes and ski classes," says Hassan.
ACCOMMODATION
Simple steps can help you save dollars on your stay. Book well in advance to avoid last-minute fees, travel off-peak and consider booking in September towards the end of winter.

Hassan says looking a bit further afield will also cut costs.
"The further away from the ski fields, the cheaper the accommodation. Many ski resorts offer complimentary or cheap shuttle buses to the snow if you're happy to compromise on the extra travel time."
SKI SPECIFIC TRAVEL INSURANCE
Booking travel insurance for a holiday in Australia is one thing many Aussies don't think about doing.
But finder.com.au says having a ski-specific policy will cover you for events such as emergency evacuations, prepaid ski hire, passes and lessons, piste closure and bad weather.
"Ski travel insurance is worth considering particularly for those booking their holiday well in advance as there is more of a chance of something unexpected popping up. Make sure you purchase it as soon as you book the other parts of your holiday so that you are covered if the trip does get cancelled due to unforeseen circumstances. Ski-specific policies start from $38 for a week at the snow," she says.

Most viewed

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Buller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thredbo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Hotham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hassan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPECIFIC TRAVEL INSURANCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bessie Hassan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Money Expert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHARLOTTE PASS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
