<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429579907018862</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/brave-skiers-set-to-hit-slopes-even-as-blizzards-predicted-for-alpine-areas-20170804-gxpxn3.html</url>
  <title>Brave skiers set to hit slopes even as blizzards predicted for Alpine areas</title>
  <content>
Thousands of skiers are expected to hit the slopes in the state's Alpine region in what is likely to be the "week of the season" even as the weather bureau forecasts strong winds, blizzards and poor visibility in the area. 
Bureau of Meteorology senior forecaster Dean Stewart said the worst of the conditions were predicted overnight Saturday through to Sunday.Photo: Chris Hocking
"There will be further snow showers today ... Tomorrow, they are expected to see another 50 centimetres on an average in the Alpine region. It is likely it could be the biggest snowfall this season in a 24-hour period," Mr Stewart said. 
"When you have got snow falling and strong winds, that leads to blizzard conditions.
"We are expecting winds to strengthen overnight tonight [Saturday] and they will be strong up there during tomorrow. It is pretty hazardous ... the visibility wouldn't be good ... not good conditions to be out there tomorrow."

But Mount Hotham Skiing Company general manager Belinda Trembath said they were expecting "a few thousand" skiers.
She said the resort's 5000 beds were all booked out, and nearby Dinner Plain had 2500 beds. The slopes also had day trippers from the region including Omeo and Bright. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Everyone is raring to go here," Ms Trembath said.
"There is nearly 20 centimetres of fresh snow, 34 centimetres in the last two days, so all the powder hunters are getting out there early.
"We are expecting some pretty heavy snowfalls tomorrow ... up to 40 centimetres."
But she said strong winds could affect how many chair lifts would be open. 
"It is minus 2 degrees ... the wind is blowing quite strongly, so we could have some challenges with opening our chair lifts up high," Ms Trembath said. 
"We have got 12 of 13 [chair lifts] planned to open, and we'll see how we go with the winds."
Mount Buller Ski Lifts spokeswoman Rhylla Morgan said they had opened almost the whole of the mountain, with 20 of the 22 lifts running. 
"We have had 26 centimetres of snow since Thursday ... we have had 10 centimetres falls today [Saturday]," Ms Morgan said. 
Falls Creek Resort spokesman Nathan Fenton said they expected all their lifts to be running on Saturday.
"There has been significant snowfalls overnight, 22 centimetres has fallen since yesterday," Mr Fenton said. 
"We are expecting blizzard conditions tomorrow [Sunday], [but] the snow public tends to get excited about a blizzard rather than scared away. 
"We'll see a lot of visitors arriving from today and tomorrow, and particularly through early next week, to take advantage of the fresh snow. We are looking at what will likely be the week of the season."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Fenton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Trembath</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omeo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Buller Ski Lifts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhylla Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Fenton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Hotham Skiing Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Creek Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Trembath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alpine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dinner Plain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
