<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429279259305156</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/dad-abused-daughter-after-family-break-up/news-story/fc895930d8e58dc47522b9a68de5f432</url>
  <title>Dumped dad sought comfort with daughter</title>
  <content>
A FATHER who admitted sexually abusing his teenage daughter in a relationship that started when he looked for comfort after his partner left him was yesterday jailed for 13 1/2 years.
The 44-year-old, who cannot be named to protect the victim's identity, was sentenced in the District Court for crimes committed in Kununurra between 2013 and last year.
He had previously pleaded guilty to 10 charges including multiple counts of sexual penetration of a child and the possession of child exploitation material.
In sentencing, Judge Philip Eaton described the man's offending as being of a "high order of seriousness".
Judge Eaton said it appeared his liking of pornography had subjected the teenager to his own sexual desires for gratification.
"In doing so you completely disregarded your obligations to her as a parent and subjected her to conduct which will, I have no doubt, have a lasting impact upon her," he said.
"It is the role of a parent to provide solutions, advice and guidance."
"She presumably thinks to some extent that you have done so, when in truth you've been incredibly destructive and selfish."
Police arrested the man at the home he shared with his daughter last year, finding him naked in bed with the girl.
It later emerged the pair had started a sexual relationship in mid-2013 after the man's partner and other children had moved out. On many occasions he filmed their sexual contact.
"There is the suggestion that the two of you, to console each other ... began to cuddle and hug," Judge Eaton said.
"Such activity might be regarded as normal in circumstances of loss or family crisis.
"In complete derogation of your role as the father of a teenage girl who had been neglected and abused as a child before going into your care, from about mid-2013, you began to treat your daughter as your sexual partner."
Judge Eaton said the psychological report suggested the man was either attempting to find excuses for his conduct or completely misunderstood of the role of a parent.
"To suggest that what occurred between you in your sexual relationship was consensual and that you used no force or coercion misses the point," he said.
"My assessment is that you knew what you were doing was wrong and yet you persisted for entirely selfish reasons."
The sentence was backdated to August last year and the man will be eligible for parole after serving 11 1/2 years.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Philip Eaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kununurra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Eaton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
