<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429708756038645</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/snow-falls-on-victorias-alps-as-blizzards-forecast/8777332</url>
  <title>Strong snow falls on Victoria's alps, as authorities prepare for blizzards</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Victoria is set for more wild weather this weekend with strong wind gusts in Melbourne and blizzards forecast for the alps.

External Link:

Twitter Falls Creek: It's dumping #snow at #FallsCreek. 22cm of new snow o/night. 27cm storm total. Dumping now!
The Bureau of Meteorology's Dean Stewart said Victoria's alpine areas received good snow falls overnight ahead of the forecast conditions.
"We did have a front go through overnight which did contribute some 15-25mm totals up over the north-east ranges and the good news for the ski resorts is that it did fall as snow," he said.
"So they got a top-up of snow last night."
The Victorian snow report recorded 22 centimetres of snowfall at Falls Creek over 24 hours and 20 centimetres at Mount Hotham.
Mr Stewart said light snowfall would continue across the day, blizzard conditions were likely to hit on Sunday.
"As we go into tomorrow the heaviest falls up over the north-east alpine areas, we're expecting some falls of around 50mm, perhaps even a touch higher in some areas, and will it all fall as snow over the alpine areas," he said.
"So that's about half a metre of snow expected during tomorrow.
"But with a combination of the snow and those strong winds, blizzard conditions are expected up there tomorrow."

"Ensure you play it safe up there,' he said.
"It's going to be big dumps, hopefully very enjoyable, but blizzards can pose particular dangers and we don't want anybody to go missing up in the mountains."
Mount Hotham's Alyson Lamb said lifts would stop running if the winds were too dangerous, but said they were protected by the valley.
She said people did not need to be concerned by the conditions.
"We have our road clearers, they work 24-7, they do an amazing job and they clear the road for us," she said.
"So as long as you're coming up to Mount Hotham with your chains on your car, everything will be okay."
In Melbourne, winds will be strongest in bayside and elevated areas, and will linger until late Monday, but the BOM said conditions would not be as severe

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FallsCreek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Hotham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter Falls Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Hotham's Alyson Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falls Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
