<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429287849239829</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/is-your-patch-of-green-right-for-the-comp/3208963/</url>
  <title>Is your patch of green right for the comp?</title>
  <content>
HAVE you entered your garden in the this year's local competition?
Your garden doesn't need to look like the Hanging Gardens of Babylon or the grounds of Buckingham Palace to be a serious contender in the Coffs Harbour Garden Club Spring Garden
Competition.
This is a real garden competition for real people, that's why it's so popular. Local gardeners have the chance to show off what they have created on their patch of green.
The garden competition has many different sections so whether you have created a paddock full of flowers, a water feature with a twist, a perfect patio garden or a garden that doesn't "drink" much, there is a category for you to enter.
The idea of this friendly competition is to be inclusive and promote the fun of being outdoors creating your own little slice of paradise no matter your age or ability or size of your garden.
Entires are now open and can be obtained at your local nursery or at
The judges will be looking for well-presented, well-weeded, well-mulched gardens so these fine winter days are the ideal time to get outside and get organised.
Is your garden new, maybe not yet at its prime?
No problem there is a section for new gardens.
Are you a tenant rather than an owner or landlord?
There is a section in
this competition for you as well.
Closing date for entries is September 1. Judging to take place around September 10 and 11 so you need to plan that your garden will look its best at that time.
It's free to enter. For more information visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanging Gardens of Babylon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour Garden Club Spring Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
