<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429459647933283</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/police-fear-terrorists-planned-to-release-deadly-gas-on-sydneys-public-transport/news-story/5122ca53ce2c54efd4d2244b52edb015</url>
  <title>Alleged gas threat on public transport</title>
  <content>
POLICE feared a group of accused- terrorists planned to release deadly hydrogen sulphide- gas into Sydney's public transport network.
Briefing media yesterday at AFP headquarters in the CBD, Australian Federal Police deputy commissioner of national- security Michael -Phelan revealed that a second terror plot was allegedly being discussed by the accused.
"The second plot related to the building of an improved chemical dispersion device," Mr Phelan claimed. "We will allege these individuals attempted to create an improvised dispersion device (which could) release a highly toxic hydrogen sulphide. This hydrogen is very difficult to make so I want to make it quite clear that while it may have been a hypothetical plot for the people ... we were a long way from having a functional device."
Mr Phelan said "hypothetical" information intercepted from the accused terrorist's Syrian contact pointed to public transport being targeted.
"They were talking about crowded enclosed spaces, potentially- public transport and so on, but there were no plans," he claimed.
"I just want to make it quite clear they got nowhere near making (a chemical weapon) and there were no well orchestrated plans to put a device (anywhere) specific."
Charles Sturt University counter-terrorism Associate Professor Nick O'Brien said the city's public transport network was more vulnerable than airports to terrorism.
"You can't have the kind of protections you have at the airport because of the volumes of traffic," he said.
"Public transport has been a terrorist target for a number of years. Look at what happened in London in 2005.
"Trains were attacked in Spain, also in Russia.
"The public transport is a good target for terrorists because it can put large portions of the population in fear and when the strike is in a capital city it can paralyse transport systems. That is what happened in London.
ROTTEN AND DEADLY
The gas compound which was allegedly about to be used in a terror plot is the most common toxic gas used in chemical suicides, given the fact it can be created from common household substances.
Hydrogen sulphide, which federal police allege was planned to go into an improvised chemical dispersion device for an attack, is an asphyxiant which has a rotten egg odour and suffocates victims at the cellular level. That largely means that victims' cells are unable to use oxygen.
It can render victims unconscious at 400 parts per million and at 1000 ppm can produce immediate cardiopulmonary arrest. Once it reaches the brain, death is all but guaranteed.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Sturt University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associate Professor Nick O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROTTEN AND DEADLY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Phelan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
