<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429584201986243</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/technology/online/social/man-takes-legal-action-claiming-a-nightmare-tinder-date-got-him-fired/news-story/d01cc96dbe5e84248c35df2f19b9be92</url>
  <title>Man takes legal action claiming a nightmare Tinder date got him fired</title>
  <content>
This Tinder date turned out to be a nightmare. Picture: Leon Neal/Getty Images
A HOUSTON man who says a Tinder date has made his life a "nightmare" has taken legal action against the jilted woman.
Joseph Lazarus, 32, sued a woman he matched with on the dating app in 2014, claiming she blackmailed him and spread lies that ultimately got him fired,
He filed a lawsuit Wednesday seeking $A250,000 in damages from the ex-girlfriend.
"I feel terrible," Lazarus said. "I feel like I'm living in a nightmare I can't escape."

Man's nightmare Tinder revenge case.Source:Supplied
According to Lazarus, the couple dated for several months before he told her that he did not want to continue seeing her. He said she wanted to stay friends, but he did not.
He said he thought that was the end, but within a few months, she started harassing him.
"You're revolting - like a blemish on my otherwise perfect skin," she allegedly wrote in one message.
The suit claimed that she messaged him demanding he fork over $12,600 - or she'd accuse him of rape.
The threats didn't stop there, according to court documents.

"Pay money and I'll stop," she reportedly messaged him.
In the autumn of 2016, Lazarus was fired from his job after his boss saw posts on gossip site thedirty.com that said he "would have sex/rape fat chicks just to amuse his friends".
She also reportedly contacted friends of his claiming that Lazarus bought her dildos instead of flowers and that he was a "rapist, liar, cheater".
"I don't know what she's talking about. I certainly didn't mail her any sex toys," Lazarus told the Chronicle.
The woman, who was not identified by the Chronicle, did not respond to request for comment from the newspaper.
Lazarus' lawyer Joseph Mathew told the Chronicle that his client just wants to "be left alone."
"There's no way Joe Lazarus can defend himself against these baseless allegations," his lawyer Joseph Mathew told the Chronicle. "If anybody finds themselves in a similar situation and I encourage them to speak out and find legal representation. Everybody has the right to be left alone."
This story was first published on the and is republished with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Lazarus, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lazarus</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Mathew</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Lazarus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Neal/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chronicle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinder</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
