<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428501870213929</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/grange-residences-to-deliver-premium-townhomes-on-infill-site/news-story/5309ad368c796a024d782571c614b845</url>
  <title>Grange Residences to deliver premium townhomes on infill site - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Grange Residences are getting the lifestyle balance right, close to the CBD but right on the much-loved Kedron Brook with plenty of space to play.

WITH a design brief to 'design something you'd be proud to live in', Grange Residences overlooking Kedron Brook is sure to hit the right notes as a luxury boutique development.
Developer is launching Grange Residences to market this month, in a private appointment campaign, with the official public release to take place next month.

Grange Residences

The 41 northeast facing townhomes on 1.15ha in Agincourt Street, , will come in two, three and four-bedroom layouts with the majority of yards fronting Kedron Brook.
JGL Properties managing director John Livingstone said the vision for Grange Residences was to create an inner-city product that appealed to a range of buyers - young professionals and families, but also downsizers who wanted to remain in the local area close to family and friends.

Grange Residences.

"Our brief to Arkhefield was to design something they'd be proud to live in, and we have been careful to underdevelop rather than overdevelop the site," he said.
"We're delivering a product that offers the benefits and scale of a house, with enviable open space at your doorstep and the architectural flair Arkhefield have been renowned for over the past 25 years.
"This style of product is virtually unrepeatable due to the rare nature of this premium infill site, we are targeting local downsizers with this one off opportunity."

Grange Residences.

Kedron Brook is a 29km watercourse with a much-loved bikeway, walkway and series of parks that link many of Brisbane's northern suburbs to the Brisbane Airport.
Mr Livingstone said many of the townhomes has been designed for adaptable housing with provision for a lift, wider door widths, improved circulation, flat entries, reinforced bathrooms for the installation of grab rails and provision of natural light on three sides.
"We've done a lot of thinking about the modern Brisbane way of life and we believe Grange Residences offers an active, healthy lifestyle but also the opportunity for ageing in place," he said.
"The Grange Residences site has allowed us to create a high quality product - with a great aspect and abundant open space and catchment access to premier local schools such as Wilston State School."

Grange Residences.

The development, to be constructed by Hutchinson Builders, will include a pedestrian and bike path thought the site to join up with Kedron Brook, and will also include extensive native landscaping.
JGL Properties has a good reputation for innovation and quality, with its $200 million Newstead Series, a boutique townhome and apartment project, nearing completion.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kedron Brook</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilston State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JGL Properties</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange Residences</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agincourt Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arkhefield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hutchinson Builders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newstead Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
