<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428630719235029</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/bulimba-is-proving-a-haven-for-downsizers-and-boutique-developers/news-story/f0f0e60a40eaebf33e5072e731064f35</url>
  <title>Bulimba is proving a haven for downsizers and boutique developers - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Developers Munro Group have just launched Reside Bulimba at 18 Love Street, in response to market demand for luxury owner-occupier apartments in blue chip suburbs.

BULIMBA is proving to be a powerhouse suburb for luxury apartment developers as owner-occupiers find it the perfect place to downsize and enjoy life.
Munro Group have almost sold out of their completed 10 apartment project at ,  and have early works construction underway at in Love St.

Reside Bulimba at 18 Love St, Bulimba.

John and Julie McNamara moved into their new Wambool St apartment in December and are loving their new life.
Having sold their house in Hawthorne, the couple have downsized to the apartment just down the road.

Julie and John McNamara are loving their new apartment at Wambool St, Bulimba.

"We absolutely love the area," Mr McNamara said, "both my wife and I work full-time and long hours so it's nice to come back to Bulimba and be close to restaurants and shops.
"It's a nice location to come back to and has most things that you need or want to do."
Having also lived on the other side of the river in New Farm, Mr McNamara said he preferred Bulimba as it was less busy and more homely.
"The Oxford St precinct is a lovely precinct, it's not as overcrowded from a units point of view and there are less people, so it's easier to get around," he said.

Only two apartments remain at 23 Wambool Street, Bulimba starting at $829,000.

Munro Group director Brett Munro said the company specialised in small boutique developments targeting good quality design and construction for owner-occupiers.
"We like to specialise in the blue chip areas ... building boutique size developments where we pay a bit more for the sites and spend more on the construction so we produce a good quality product," Mr Munro said.
With only two apartments remaining at Wambool St, early works construction has now started at Reside Bulimba.
Mr Munro said the 20 architecturally designed apartments on Love St would also feature a lift to cater for the older demographic who were keen to purchase in the area.

Only two apartments remain at 23 Wambool Street, Bulimba starting at $829,000.

The Munro Group has been operating since 1975, with Brett Munro taking over the business from his father around 12 years ago. Having started out as a commercial building company, the Group ended up specialising in retirement villages and having built thousands of units then moved into the boutique apartment market.
Place estate agent Brenton Faehrmann said there were only two three-bedroom apartments left at Wambool St, one with 180 degree panoramic views.
"These apartments have superb high end finishes and just 100 metres from Oxford St," Mr Faehrmann said. "So you have all the benefits of Oxford St without having to find a car park."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wambool St</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulimba</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie McNamara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brenton Faehrmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Faehrmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wambool Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munro Group</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Love Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Munro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McNamara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McNamara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Love St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Munro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reside Bulimba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
