<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429627151659468</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/entertainment/2017/08/05/11/10/upcoming-game-of-thrones-episode-leaked-online</url>
  <title>Upcoming</title>
  <content>
The next episode of Game of Thrones has been leaked online just 48 hours before it was set to go to air.
The leak is the second blow the HBO hit has taken in the past week, after an anonymous hacker  from secure databases, including Game of Thrones scripts.
In an email to Wired, the hackers claimed: "We successfully penetrated HBO's huge network and gathered most imporatnt [sic] files and films & scripts."
Overnight the fourth episode from Game of Thrones' seventh season was aired online, in a low-quality format.
HBO's Indian distribution partner, Star India, confirmed the leak came from within its company.
"We take this breach very seriously and have immediately initiated forensic investigations at our and the technology partner's end to swiftly determine the cause," a spokesperson for Star India told .
"This is a grave issue and we are taking appropriate legal remedial action."

Related Articles

HBO handed its distribution duties to Star India in 2015 after struggling with operations.
This is not the first time HBO has had to deal with leaks. In 2015 the first four episodes of season five were leaked online.
The leaked episode is set to air in Australia on Monday.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star India</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO's Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
