<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428806812896534</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/bikinis-next-to-hijabs-cultural-festival/news-story/576773a8d33086b3dc31d93a04564c6b</url>
  <title>Bikinis next to hijabs: Cultural festival</title>
  <content>
A GIANT representation of Mother Earth will today lead a convoy to herald the Townsville Cultural Festival, which opens next week.
Developed with local indigenous groups, the 4m-high statue of a pregnant woman represents Earth as a goddess who protects resources.
The convoy, which will start at Harmony Park in North Ward at 4.30pm, will head to James Cook University ahead of the 23rd Cultural Festival.
Executive director Dr Farvardin Daliri said the five-day festival, which starts on Wednesday, was a celebration of everything good about Australia.
"It's about how lucky we are and how colourful our history is," Dr Daliri said.
"We have traditions and the legacy of a young nation."
High-profile acts are set to attract thousands of people this year, including Iain Smith, known by his stage name Fred Smith.
He wrote a powerful collection of songs about the reality of life for soldiers and civilians in the Afghanistan war, and recently released an album, Dust of Uruzgan.
Slim Dusty's daughter Anne Kirkpatrick is also among the performers.
Hundreds of local groups are participating in this year's festival, which will feature cultural arts, theatre and music.
Dr Daliri said the festival epitomised the cultural diversity of Australia.
"We'll have dancers in bikinis and girls in hijabs from Somalia and they'll all share the experience," he said.
"This is a unique and extraordinary festival and it's only possible here in Australia.
"We want so show off our value to the whole world."
Dr Daliri said it would be one of the largest comings together of indigenous nations.
"They're all coming together to perform aboriginal content in the program.
"We also have the largest Papua New Guinean and participation from Pacific Islanders."
Food will also be a major drawcard with dozens of international delicacies on offer.
For more details, visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Islander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cook University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uruzgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harmony Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Cultural Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iain Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cultural Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Farvardin Daliri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Daliri</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Kirkpatrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother Earth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
