<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429494007671940</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/world/venezuela-ushers-in-new-progovernment-chamber-opposition-struggles-20170805-gxpyes.html</url>
  <title>Venezuela ushers in new pro-government chamber, opposition struggles</title>
  <content>
Caracas, Venezuela: Amid the blaring sounds of socialist anthems, hundreds of newly elected pro-government lawmakers triumphantly entered the Federal Legislative Palace, sending up victory whoops on a day critics called a death blow for democracy in Venezuela.
Their entry into the neoclassical complex marked the inauguration of an all-powerful lawmaking body elected last Sunday in a vote that has been condemned internationally. Opposition lawmakers elected in 2015 - and now shunted aside - decried the new body as a puppet congress installed by President Nicolas Maduro.

Up Next

'That' Scaramucci audio released

00:56

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Venezuelan police set fire to motorbikes

Violence erupts in Caracas as citizens vote to elect a new assembly with powers to rewrite the constitution.

As members of the new "Constituent Assembly" entered the building's red-colored Elliptical Salon, they held high portraits of the late leader Hugo Chavez side by side with images of Maduro, his anointed successor. In a sign of Maduro's tightening grip, one of his most loyal lieutenants, former foreign minister Delcy Eloina Rodriguez, was sworn in as the body's new president.
"President Nicolas Maduro Moros is made huge today," she said, using Maduro's full name.

The 545-member assembly represents a sweeping shift in how the country will be run, with its supporters calling it the vehicle needed to complete Chavez's socialist vision. It is vested with the authority to change the country's constitution and overhaul laws.
Only a few hundred people appeared to be joining an opposition march to protest the new assembly. After four months of street protests against the authorities and the country's economic collapse, government opponents seemed angry and exhausted, and struggling to find a path forward.

About five minutes after one group of protesters began marching toward the legislative palace, security forces moved in on motorbikes, lobbing tear gas bombs and firing rubber bullets. Opposition legislators ran in all directions. At least one man's face was hit with rubber bullets.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

As the new assembly was sworn in, international pressure on the government built. The Vatican joined a chorus of worldwide condemnation Friday against the constitution-writing body, and demanded the government not use excessive force against demonstrators.Photo: Bloomberg
The nation's economy, meanwhile, moved closer toward the abyss.
In a nation where malnutrition is soaring amid food and medicine shortages, the near worthless currency, the bolivar, has entered free fall. The Venezuelan currency lost 45.3 per cent of its value in one week, as the price of the dollar in the black market nearly doubled.Photo: Bloomberg
In a supermarket in eastern Caracas, shoppers expressed sticker shock.
"I came a week ago and saw rice for 5,700 bolivares," said Gina Angelats, a 62-year-old retire. "I didn't buy it because it seemed too expensive. But now it's 18,000! This is unaffordable . . . blame the government and its socialist policies. They've ruined the country."
Washington Post
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugo Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delcy Eloina Rodriguez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Legislative Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vatican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nicolas Maduro Moros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliptical Salon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gina Angelats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
