<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429021561264029</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/netanyahus-former-top-aide-turns-states-witness-in-graft-case/8776954</url>
  <title>Benjamin Netanyahu's former chief of staff turns state's witness in bribery cases</title>
  <content>
A former chief of staff to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has agreed to provide testimony on behalf of the state in two graft cases in which he has been questioned as a suspect.

Key points:

Ari Harow will confess to fraud and breach of trust under the plea bargain
He served as Mr Netanyahu's top aide twice before resigning in 2015
Mr Netanyahu has labelled the investigation a "witch-hunt"

The decision by Ari Harow to turn state's witness as part of a plea bargain in his own, separate corruption case adds a new dimension to a long-running investigation involving Mr Netanyahu.
The four-term premier has denied any wrongdoing.
His family spokesman said Mr Netanyahu would withstand what he described as a "witch-hunt" designed to force him from office.
In a Facebook video posting, Mr Netanyahu dismissed Friday's developments as "the inevitable scandal of the week".
"I would like to tell you, citizens of Israel, that I do not heed background noises," he said.
"I continue to work for you."
Mr Netanyahu, 67, has been questioned under caution by police in two cases, one dealing with gifts given to him and his family by businessmen, and another related to conversations he held with an Israeli publisher.
A court injunction said the cases involved suspicion of the commission of the felonies of bribery, fraud and breach of trust, but did not specify who might be charged for the crimes.
Mr Netanyahu and his wife, Sara, are said to have received more than $125,000 worth of cigars and liquor from Hollywood producer Arnon Milchan, who reportedly asked Mr Netanyahu to press the US Secretary of State in a visa matter.
Australian billionaire James Packer has reportedly lavished Mr Netanyahu's 26-year-old son Yair Netanyahu with gifts.

These allegedly included extended stays at luxury hotels in Tel Aviv, New York and Aspen, Colorado, as well as the use of his private jet and dozens of tickets for concerts by Mr Packer's former fiancee, Mariah Carey.
, since Mr Packer is reportedly seeking Israeli residency status for tax purposes.
Former aide to confess to fraud, breach of trust

Harow served two stints as Mr Netanyahu's chief of staff before resigning in 2015 amid allegations he had improperly handled private business affairs.
The court injunction said he had turned state's witness but barred publication of any details about what he would tell investigators or testify to.
Under the deal, Harow agreed to confess to fraud and breach of trust, the court injunction said, and will be sentenced to six months' imprisonment commuted to community service as well as a fine of 700,000 shekels ($243,000).
Even if eventually indicted, Mr Netanyahu would not be obliged by law to resign, although his opponents have called on him to do so.
In his 11 years of office, the conservative who last won elections in 2015 has weathered several scandals and police inquiries.
His approval ratings are generally solid, putting him ahead of potential challengers.
Reuters/AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Netanyahu (67</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yair Netanyahu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ari Harow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Netanyahu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colorado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Packer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariah Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Netanyahu</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aspen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tel Aviv</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters/AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnon Milchan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
