<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428510460148657</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/martin-shkreli-live-stream-securities-fraud-guilty-conviction-2017-8</url>
  <title>'Pharma bro' Martin Shkreli held a surreal live stream minutes after being convicted of security fraud</title>
  <content>
Moments after , "pharma bro" Marin Shkreli launched into a trademark Youtube livestream.

Shkreli, the former pharmaceutical CEO best known for a price-gouging scandal, took questions from fans, streamed an interview with a New York Daily News reporter, and talked about everything from a possible appeal of the case to his one-of-a-kind Wu Tang Clan album.

Shkreli said it was a "50-50" chance he would be sentenced to prison - he faces up to 20 years - but was also upbeat about possibly getting the charges dismissed.

"I think I can get probation," Shkreli said. "There's a decent chance there's a complete vacation of the charges."

Shkreli was found not guilty on five other counts. The most serious of the charges, Shkreli and his lawyer argued Friday, was one alleging he paid back investors in his hedge fund using money from his former biotech firm, Retrofin. Shkreli was found not guilty on that charge.

"When you throw spaghetti at the wall, some of it sticks," Shkreli said. "And some of this s- stuck."

Asked by a viewer why he thought the charges were brought up, Shkreli said it was simply prosecutors "trying to get famous."

In addition to talking about his case, Shkreli talked about the exclusive Wu Tang Clan album he famously purchased. He said that he wouldn't stream the album, but was in discussion with the rap group on where and when to possibly release the music.

Later in the stream, Shkreli let New York Daily News reporter Ellen Moynihan into his apartment. He continued to streamed the exchange, which became tense at times when the conversation turned to the infamous price increase of the life-saving drug Daraprim by Shkreli's company, Turing Pharmaceuticals.

The interview came after Shkreli attacked the media and the Daily News, calling it "fake news."

You can watch the stream below:

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Daily News</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellen Moynihan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turing Pharmaceuticals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shkreli</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retrofin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daraprim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marin Shkreli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wu-Tang Clan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Shkreli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
