<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428892712243573</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/moving-an-orchard-of-fruit-and-nut-trees/8772072</url>
  <title>How to move fruit and nut trees and build a community orchard</title>
  <content>
External Link:

Fact Sheet: Get Grafting

External Link:

Fact Sheet: Pruning Fruit Trees

Now is the time to prepare fruit and nut trees for the coming spring - and sometimes that means moving them to another suburb.
When Mini Hogan spotted an abandoned orchard on Marys Hope Road in Hobart's northern suburbs, she wondered if there was a way to save some of its fruit and nut trees.

Ms Hogan volunteers at the Child and Family Centre in Chigwell, which was looking at establishing a community garden, and she saw a chance to help out with some free trees.
"It's all about food security and biodiversity," she said, adding that she was not even sure if established fruit trees could be moved.

"I consulted the Royal Tasmanian Botanical Gardens and I had a long conversation on the phone to the tree guy there," she said.
"What you do is cut them back, chose the smallest ones, and then take as much of the root as you can and see how you go."
With help from locals volunteering their time and gardening experience, Ms Hogan has begun the process of selecting smaller trees to dig up and move to a new home.

"We're pretty sure about the cherry and exactly sure about the almonds," she said of the bare-branched trees.
"But we're not exactly sure about everything else, so there's a bit of a lucky dip about what will grow."
The end of winter is a good time to move fruit and nut trees when they are still dormant.

Once the warmer weather comes and the larger trees start to bud, Ms Hogan and her helpers will be back to the orchard to take cuttings to try to strike and graft varieties that are too big to move.
"You take a length of growing shoot and you bury a number of nodes in a well-draining mixture of cow poo and sand," Ms Hogan said.
"Then this time next year they'll have roots and be little trees."

While there is no guarantee the moved trees will survive, the project has already been a success for Ms Hogan.
"It is a majorly significant and very intensely, highly meaningful start of what is going to be a bigger, longer and slower process," she said.
"It's just such a treat to have an idea and to actually execute it."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hogan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Get Grafting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mini Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Tasmanian Botanical Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pruning Fruit Trees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marys Hope Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chigwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
