<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429159000219094</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/thunderstorms-damaging-winds-to-hit-sunshine-coast/3209123/</url>
  <title>Thunderstorms, damaging winds to hit Sunshine Coast</title>
  <content>
MAKE the most of the sunshine while it's here because damaging thunderstorms are set to roll into the Sunshine Coast.
The Bureau of Meteorology is preparing to issue several thunderstorm warnings over the coming hours, with thunderstorms expected to strike the Coast and regions further north.
Bureau meteorologist Julian De Morton said the Coast could be buffeted by damaging wind gusts in excess of 90km/h, while heavy rainfall was expected in some areas.
An inland trough delivering showers to the west should move across our region over the coming hours, with storms set to hit tomorrow.
Mr De Morton said Sunday afternoon was when the thunderstorms were expected to hit and would hang around through Sunday evening and into Monday.
He said the region's north would feel the brunt of the wild weather, with Noosa, Gympie and into the Wide Bay all set to cop the full force of the system.
In Maroochydore, there was a 60% chance of showers tomorrow with Weatherzone also predicting thunderstorms Sunday and into Monday.
The Coast will cop a dousing, but only 1-5mm is expected to fall, with the heaviest rainfall of 5-20mm expected further north in the Capricornia region.
Despite the battering, maximum temperatures are set to remain a toasty 24-26C throughout the weekend, although tomorrow morning looks to be a little chilly.
A cool change is set to sweep through following the storms as dry, cooler air moves in, with minimum temperatures set to plunge into single digits.
A low of 9C is forecast for Wednesday, with inland areas to drop even further and Mr De Morton said it wouldn't be a surprise if revised forecasts pushed those lows further down.
On the seas the winds were expected to stay between 10-15 knots, possibly hitting 20 knots late tomorrow afternoon.
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Yaroomba Beach project will be "a fantastic coastal village"
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Home sells in just one day
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
In 1967, Nev was a member of the REIQ Near North Coast branch.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capricornia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wide Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian De Morton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weatherzone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr De Morton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
