<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429494007671917</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/sleeping-toilet-block-melbournes-housing-crisis-suburbs/8766298</url>
  <title>Melbourne's housing crisis worse in suburbs than CBD, welfare agencies say</title>
  <content>
They're disturbing images in such a wealthy country like Australia - rough sleepers in central Melbourne, camped out in the cold along busy thoroughfares such as Flinders and Swanston streets.
But welfare agencies are warning the homelessness crisis is actually much worse in the suburbs and on the urban fringe.
It's just not as obvious because people are taking shelter in places such as toilet blocks, bushes and cars.
Hundreds of people are being turned away every day from support services because there is nowhere for them to stay, according to Kate Colvin from the Council to Homeless Persons.
She said private rentals are expensive, shared accommodation is often full, cheap motels are only a short-term fix and the waiting list for public housing is only getting longer.
"Two in three people who are sleeping rough and who come to services for help actually do so in the suburbs or in regional towns, so it's a massive problem outside of the CBD," Ms Colvin said.
She is calling for a radical State Government overhaul of suburban and regional support services aimed at ending the cycle of homelessness.
One of those sleeping rough is 45-year-old Terry (not his real name), who began living outdoors about two years ago, after his job and social life unravelled.
He said many others like him were sleeping rough on the Mornington Peninsula.

"I would know about 30 to 50 people that are sleeping rough at the moment along the foreshore, just as a rough guess, whether that be tents, makeshift sort of accommodation or vehicles," Terry said.
Sometimes up to 40 people line up at the Salvation Army's Sunshine office in Melbourne's west, seeking basics such as food vouchers and accommodation.
'Jail the only time I've ever been clean'

The ABC spoke with a 44-year-old man in the queue who had been homeless for almost half of his life - excluding a stint in jail.
"(Jail) was probably the best time of my life, the only time I have ever been clean from drugs since probably 18, 19, because I have always been on marijuana, and then late 20s got onto heroin," he said.
He is currently living in a rooming house, just surviving on welfare payments, and after more than a decade waiting for public housing has all but given up on a home of his own.
"Been on the streets living in a car, just couch surfing and boarding houses, nothing really stable, where you can call home," he said.

The Council to Homeless Persons said getting help in suburban and regional areas was harder than in the CBD, where there was a greater concentration of support services.
The organisation has drawn up a $7.5 million plan to deploy teams of 12 outreach workers to five homelessness hot spots at Frankston, Dandenong, Broadmeadows, Sunshine and Shepparton in the state's north.
Community work hard slog without public housing

Ms Colvin said the seven-day-a-week operation would include specialists such as case managers and nurses, with the aim of finding people housing and keeping them there.
"They might have mental health issues, maybe a disability, like acquired brain injury, they might have addiction or childhood trauma that they're trying to manage and being chronically homeless makes that extremely difficult," she said.
But she said the teams would not work unless backed up by a major investment in public housing.
"We have an absolute crisis in availability of public housing in Victoria; there's been some investments but it's not keeping up with demand," Ms Colvin said.

State Government figures show there are currently more than 35,000 Victorians waiting for public housing.
Housing Minister Martin Foley declined to say whether the Government would support the proposal.
"We're working with them right now on that and other proposals, and we'll have a lot more to say," he said.
"There'll be further innovative programs that we'll work out with our not-for-profit organisations."
The teams would operate in a similar way to the Salvation Army's Streets to Home program in Melbourne's CBD.
Firefighter's fall from grace, back to recovery

Jason Russell is one of the program's success stories. The former firefighter and father of three's downfall came after being misdiagnosed with schizophrenia.
"That lead to being put on the wrong medication, then my career fell apart. I started to medicate with illicit drugs," he said.

"That was just the beginning of the end, to be honest with you."
Mr Russell ended up living on the streets of Sydney and Melbourne. One of his worst experiences was staying at St Kilda's notorious Gatwick rooming house, which recently closed.
"Went up to my room, unpacked, about five minutes lapsed, stepped out of my room, I tripped over somebody who was OD-ing and landed on his mate who was already dead," he said.
He was on the public housing waiting list for five years before the Salvation Army's program provided the catalyst to securing a unit in North Melbourne.
"Probably why I stayed on the streets for so long, because one service would help me with my mental health problems, another service would help me with my homelessness and another was helping with my drug addiction - I kept falling in the cracks."
He credits Streets to Home with providing the ongoing support he needed to get his life back on track.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army's Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OD-ing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Martin Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army's Streets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shepparton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeless Persons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swanston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Colvin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
