<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428501870213917</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/short-term-renting-not-a-guaranteedholiday/news-story/285f5073a1ad32a7b036832e95364ea2</url>
  <title>Short term renting not a guaranteed holiday - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Advantage Property Consulting director Frank Valentic.

OWNING an investment property as a short-term holiday rental can be lucrative but industry
experts warn those considering the option will need to weigh up their options.
Advantage Property Consulting director Frank Valentic said buyers needed to follow the golden rules of standard investment purchasing when considering entering the holiday rental market.
RELATED:
RELATED:
Mr Valentic said access to amenities, public transport, infrastructure and proximity to the city were just as important for a holiday-maker as they were for a long-term renter.
He said it would also help protect the investment should the property need to be switched from a holiday rental to a private rental in the future.
Mr Valentic said he would encourage an investor looking to buy a holiday rental home to look for properties that were less than the median house or unit price for the area, and to avoid city apartments.

Advantage Property Consulting director Frank Valentic.

"Look at Rosebud or Dromana on the Mornington Peninsula, or St Kilda and Richmond near the city," Mr Valentic suggested.
He said his firm managed a few holiday rental properties, including two apartments that were renovated on The Block, and that holiday rentals could be good earners if done properly.
One of The Block properties in South Yarra was rented out for $650 a night, the other $2000 a week, compared to $1200 a week as an unfurnished private rental.
He said a house in Dromana was rented for $375 a night as holiday accommodation but $450 a week privately.
"It can be quite a good strategy but you just have to make sure you invest in the right area and be careful about the country areas," Mr Valentic said.
"Some people are generating about 20-50 per cent more rental income as a holiday house.
"Some of the risks are that there are high vacancy rates, transient tenants and you don't have certainty of income."

WBP Group executive chairman Greville Pabst.

WBP Group executive chairman Greville Pabst agreed the rental returns were generally higher than the long-term market but there was a lot more maintenance.
"I think many people underestimate what is involved - laundry bills for sheets, toilet rolls, soaps and furniture," Mr Pabst said.
"There are companies, like AirBnB, that will manage if for a fee but you need to be aware of the tax and ongoing maintenance and cleaning requirements.
"It is very seasonal. Anyone looking to go into it really needs to do their homework first and talk to their accountant or financial adviser."

REA Group chief economist Nerida Conisbee.

Realestate.com.au chief economist Nerida Conisbee said short-term rentals could be a good idea but it came down to the location and income versus cost.
She said the management of holiday rental properties was more involved than with long-term arrangements. "People tend to use holiday rentals more heavily and don't look after it as much as if they were living there," she said.
Ms Conisbee said she preferred the stability of a long-term tenant rather than having lots of holiday-makers through a property.
"I am more conservative and I would be worried about the capital growth of my asset," she said.
Ms Conisbee said the growing trend of turning investment properties into short-term accommodation had the potential to damage the private rental market. "It is not great for rental rates," she said.
"It's effectively taking property out of the mix for full-time rentals - it's not a positive for the market."
HE DID HIS RESEARCH

Sean Wroe in his Richmond studio apartment he rents out short term.

INVESTING in the short-term accommodation market has proved more financially sound than the private rental market for a Richmond homeowner.
Finance broker and former Olympic 400m runner Sean Wroe bought a studio warehouse at the end of 2013 as an investment property.
Mr Wroe said at the time it had full-time private tenants but about six months later they moved out.
"I looked at the opportunity of jumping on AirBnB and did some research and there were about three apartments in the same complex doing the same thing," Mr Wroe said.
"I reached out to the hosts, and they said it was quite lucrative, depending on how much you want to do."
Mr Wroe figured out it could be viable and gave himself a three-month trial that would see him return the apartment to the private rental market if things didn't work out.
He renovated the apartment with a graffiti artwork and polished concrete floors, and decorated it with recycled furniture.
Mr Wroe said demand was "very seasonal" but the flat had an occupancy rate of about 90-95 per cent in summer and 70-80 per cent in winter.
He said being close to Richmond train station made the property good for sporting events and concerts at Rod Laver Area or the MCG.
His guests stay for an average of 1.8 nights and he charges $85 a night Sunday-Thursday and $129 a night on Friday and Saturday, plus a cleaning fee.
"It covers the mortgage repayments," he said. "A long-term tenant would be paying about $310 a week.
"Although there are other costs involved - linen, power, water and internet - you are running a small business.
"I would love to buy another one and put it on AirBnB.
"A one-bedroom apartment is probably more lucrative than a two-bedroom."
Mr Wroe said there were more people getting on board the platform and other holiday accommodation outlets, and believed a point of difference was necessary to stand out from the competition.
hayley.goddard@news.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>REA Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realestate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Consulting</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday-Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic 400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Laver Area</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Conisbee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBP Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pabst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greville Pabst</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Wroe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Valentic</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wroe</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nerida Conisbee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dromana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Valentic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
