<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429408108325267</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/talk-of-the-north-madness-on-the-nq-milk-run/news-story/3066562aa3b5ae26a8e9d0a8beb6832b</url>
  <title>Talk of the North: Madness on the NQ milk run</title>
  <content>
IN another kick in the duodenum for our milk producers up on the Atherton Tableland, the state Health Department has cancelled its milk order from local producers and is now buying it from Parmalat and is bringing it up from Brisbane. So, now, the milk that was made up there at Malanda by Lion Dairy and was sent to hospitals all over the Far North has to be now sent to Brisbane at a cost of 25 cents a litre. The trucks carrying this milk south pass the Parmalat fleet ferrying the Brisbane milk north. Surely Health Minister Cameron Dick can sort out this silliness.
Deaf ears on dust-up
THERE'S a dust-up brewing out along Dingo Pocket Road near Calcium. Local residents are fed up with dust being kicked up by heavy trucks that travel along the dirt road and want the Townsville City Council to do something about it. So far it's a case of deaf ears on the part of the council.
Adani action picks up
THE Adani project is getting up a head of steam. Vehicles are being bought and I understand tenders have been let for many more. More than 80 families have moved into the city and are renting in the city. We understand Quest Apartments are doing quite well - employees are being put up there by the company for two weeks while they search for a place to live.
and airport takes off
AND my mate down at Bowen tells me Downers are due to start work on the $32 million airport that will service Adani's Carmichael mine.
Geographic apartheid
AND speaking of airports you can't blame coal country identities like Mike "Moscow" Brunker and Mayor of the Isaac Shire Anne Baker for being angry about Bowen Basin traineeships advertised with recruitment agency Chandler Macleod. The ads stipulate that the applicants must live within 100km of the Brisbane airport. This smacks of geographic apartheid.
'Showies' have taste
TULLY Show is done and dusted for 2017 and once again the wild caught Gulf of Carpentaria mackerel cooked to the local Rotary Club's secret recipe has won the hearts and minds of the "showies". Rotary stalwart and mackerel cook Ron Hunt told me the "showies" reckon it's the best cooked fish at any show along the east coast of Australia. "It's wild caught fish and it's caught on lines, not nets," Ron said.
Dogs get the show jump
THE Etheridge Show and Turnout is on in the tiny Gulf Country town of Forsayth today.
One of the features of the show apart from the greasy pig race is the working dog jumping competition.
Out here in cattle country it's important that a dog be able to jump up onto the back of ute piled high with hay, saddles, a quad bike or two and the boss's fencing repair gear.
A dog or a "turner" that can't jump can be a liability when the whips are cracking and speed is an absolute necessity. The boss does not take kindly to having to take time out to lift ol' Rover up onto the back of the ute (they call them 'turners' at Forsayth because their sole role in life is to turn cattle).
Last year Aaron Gallagher and Kara Saunders' four year old Collie-Kelpie cross, Bilgus, won the jumping competition. Aaron with little son Victor were back putting him through his paces yesterday. Psssst. Here's a bit of inside oil for the punters. A rogue cow charged Bilgus last week and hurt one of his legs. He has been a bit tender, but Aaron reckoned he was making good progress. We'll see how he goes today. As well as the Dog Jump there is the Bungee Pull, Dingo Derby (dog race), Catch the Chooks, or in the this case Catch the Guinea Fowl. "We couldn't get any chooks, but Hooter Young has lent us some guinea fowl. I'd like to see any bastard catch them," said show president Simon Terry. There are foot races, a kick a goal competition, and three legged races.
Maggie has key assest
THE Radical Bay piano is back. Tourism Magnetic Island launched it's new committee and strategy with Townsville Enterprise on Thursday night. Norman Jenkin of Sealink Queensland was elected chair.
Norman was involved with Instagram promotion and social media strategies with the internationally famous piano that appeared at Radical Bay in 2016. Time stands still for no piano and eventually wind, rain and salt air took their toll and the weather-beaten art installation was removed from public display. To this day international visitors still hunt for the piano in Radical Bay. Magnetic Island's Art installation has mysteriously remerged and again is delighting visitors with its sounds over the beachfront of Radical Bay. After playing the piano, head over to Horseshoe Bay and have breakfast with the koalas at Bungalow Bay.
Book up to stay young
EVER heard of the drug metformin? If you are like me probably haven't.
It is used in the first line of defence against type 2 diabetes. It features in Townsville gastroenterologist Dr Stephen Fairley's, new book dealing with looking after your body, Ageing, How to Kick the Habit. Dr Fairley says everyone middle-aged and over should be talking to their doctor about taking Metformin.
He believes it could be useful in fending off cancer, cardiovascular disease and dementia.
He cautions there could be studies down the track that show it is of no use whatsoever, but he doubts it. He's blunt. He doesn't have a lot of sympathy for people who live on a diet of sugary drinks and carbs and who never exercise and wonder why they are obese and have high blood sugar. This book, like his others, is all about people helping themselves.
His tips for delaying the ageing process, are: Minimise animal-based protein and focus more on beans and lentils. Eats lots of vegies.
"This is to be the mainstay of your diet. Not just any vegetables but the more colourful the better," he says.
Avoid carbohydrates as much as possible - put starchy vegetables like potatoes, grains and all added and concentrated sugars on the banned list. Dr Fairley's loyal readers will recall that he is no fan of carbohydrates. His last book was titled Death by Carbs. "If food is processed, forget it. You should not eat processed foods, they contain large amounts of sugar, dangerous saturated vegetable fats and emulsifiers which worsen your insulin resistance or diabetes," he says.
Drink alcohol in moderation, one to two glasses a day, preferably wine. Drink coffee regularly. "If you don't like coffee, keep at it at until your do" he advises. Dr Fairley's mission is to try and put a dent in the obesity epidemic.
Don't get him started on the government paying drug companies for anti-obesity drugs. "No one wants to say the truth which is simple. If you stop eating too much carbohydrate and to a lesser extent protein, you cut fatty liver disease. Even without exercise. No drugs required," he said. The book costs $10 and it is steal. It is available Dr Fairley's rooms at 163 Kings Rd, Pimlico, Townsville Day Surgery, GP clinics and Mary Who? Bookshop.
Story of family fame
IT has been a big couple of weeks for book releases in Townsville. Yvonne Cadet-James, Robert Andrew James, Sue McGinty and Russell McGregor have written the story of the Gugu Badhun, People of the Valley of Lagoons. This is richly illustrated and tells the stories of the different indigenous families who lived in the Gugu Badhun homelands of the upper Burdekin. The Gertz, Hoolihan and Snider families and many others all feature in this detailed account about life and history on the upper Burdekin. There is even space given to how Parky Atkinson or "Parky Woologorang" found his way to the Greenvale area from the Northern Territory. The Gertz, Buller, Snider, Hoolihan families along with many others feature in the book. It is available at Mary Who? Bookshop.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor of the Isaac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Enterprise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pimlico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Island's Art</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yvonne Cadet-James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atherton Tablelands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bilgus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman Jenkin of Sealink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quest Apartments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooter Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dingo Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Andrew James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horseshoe Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collie-Kelpie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burdekin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani Carmichael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Fairley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulf of Carpentaria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bungalow Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dog Jump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulf Country</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Stephen Fairley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snider</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radical Bay</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley of Lagoons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dingo Pocket Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chandler MacLeod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Cameron Dick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etheridge Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kara Saunders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Who</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shire Anne Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malanda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotary Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Psssst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maggie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guinea Fowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forsayth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parky Woologorang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Magnetic Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion Dairy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TULLY Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gugu Badhun</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gertz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue McGinty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Day Surgery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parky Atkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parmalat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bungee Pull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoolihan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
