<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428549114855097</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/sanctuary-cove-has-released-some-of-the-last-available-waterfront-lots/news-story/a745848f94ca57239c7d9b1187157539</url>
  <title>Sanctuary Cove has released some of the last available waterfront lots - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Sanctuary Cove has just released stage two of Sanctuary Point with a limited number of north-facing waterfront lots with prices from $1.78 million.

A LIMITED number of north-facing waterfront lots have just been released in stage two of Sanctuary Point on the Gold Coast, following the sellout of stage one.
One of the last opportunities to secure prime waterfront living at , the 10 lots are under construction and expected to be completed in September.
Mulpha Sanctuary Cove general manager international sales John Hughes said stage two of The Point release provided a rare chance for buyers to purchase the last of the waterfront land lots.
"After 30-years, we're releasing some of Sanctuary Cove's last waterfront blocks," Mr Hughes said.
"Several lots have already been snapped up by savvy buyers, with the remaining land set to be in high demand.
"There is a small window for buyers to act on this exclusive opportunity to secure the last of this unique residential land."

Sanctuary Cove

Mr Hughes said a mix of young families through to retirees had chosen to build their dream home within the prestige community, with a recent spike in locally based buyers.
With prices starting from $1.78 million, lots in the new release range in size from 795sq m to 911sq m, some with 25m of water frontage, suitable for luxury motor boats and yachts.
"These premium waterfront lots feature stunning northerly views with mooring capabilities and direct access to the sparkling waterways of the Gold Coast and beyond," Mr Hughes said.
"Providing a rare entree to the ultimate lifestyle embraced by residents of Sanctuary Cove."
Residents will benefit from the planned Town Centre which, when complete, will include a major supermarket, department store and specialty retail offering, alongside commercial offices and food outlets.
Sanctuary Cove is continuing a record-breaking year of land sales, reaching more than $100 million, almost double the 2016 total.
Limited lots remain for sale in Sanctuary Cove's golf course-fronting The Pines and within stage two of The Greens, with stage three to have blocks from $700,000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanctuary Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hughes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulpha Sanctuary Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanctuary Cove</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
