<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428639309169689</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/new-laws-spell-end-false-fuel-prices/3209108/</url>
  <title>New laws to spell the end of false fuel prices</title>
  <content>
THE Queensland State Government has announced new laws it says will spell the end of misleading fuel prices.

Treasurer and Acting Energy and Biofuels Minister Curtis Pitt said new 'what you see is what you pay' style regulations will ban fuel retailers from displaying confusing discounted prices on fuel price boards which aren't available to all motorists.

"These strict regulations mean fuel retailers will still be able to promote discount fuel price schemes, but only the full price available to all motorists can be displayed on the price boards," Mr Pitt said.

"These reforms have been introduced due to on-going concerns that some motorists may be paying more at the bowser than they were initially led to believe, which is typically when fuel retailers display prices that are only available to motorists who have a discount voucher or make an in-store purchase."

The main elements of the laws are: a ban on the display of conditionally discounted prices on fuel price boards, such as those that require a discount voucher or an in-store purchase; and the coordination of prices changes so motorists never pay more at the bowser than the price advertised on the board.

Service station owners will have until the January 31, 2018 to implement the changes.

Mr Pitt said the reforms respond to concerns raised at the Palaszczuk Government's Fuel Price Summit in 2016.

"Consensus at the summit was that the regulatory model in place in South Australia and Victoria is the preferred approach, and the new regulations will adopt this model rather than the more prescriptive and onerous approach adopted by NSW," Mr Pitt said.

"The laws also follow comprehensive community and industry consultation undertaken by the Department of Energy and Water Supply earlier this year and support for the changes expressed by stakeholders including the RACQ and the Motor Trades Association of Queensland.

"Calls for truth in petrol price advertising has long been a burning issue for motorists."

Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Yaroomba Beach project will be "a fantastic coastal village"
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Home sells in just one day
Elegant home with seven levels hits the market
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 31 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biofuels Minister Curtis Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Supply</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acting Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pitt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk Government's Fuel Price Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Motor Trades Association of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
