<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429408108325260</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/moreland-council-works-with-h2u-and-cnh-industrial-to-run-waste-fleet-trucks-on-hydrogen/news-story/16a5d958ff0b039bd336b49473738b26</url>
  <title>Hydrogen-powered trucks a clean winner</title>
  <content>
MORELAND'S fleet of garbage trucks will run on 100 per cent renewable and sustainable hydrogen under an Australian-first pilot announced this morning.
More than $2 million in Moreland Council and State Government funding has been committed to kickstart the construction of a hydrogen refuelling station.
The council has partnered with hydrogen utility company H2U for the project and international vehicle manufacturer is set to develop the hydrogen fuel cell trucks.
Moreland Council plans to build a 1.2 megawatt solar system as part of the project and secure grid connection with a wind farm to power the electrolysis technology needed to produce the hydrogen power from water.
The water used will be harvested from the rooftops of buildings.
Moreland Mayor Helen Davidson said the project aimed to revolutionise how councils across the globe operate, particularly in the waste collection sector.
"Council can continue its transition away from fossil diesel fuel and toward renewable hydrogen for all our heavy fleet vehicles," Cr Davidson said.
H2U chief executive Attilio Pigneri said the $1 million in funding under the State Government's was an important milestone for the project.
"It provides us with significant support to progress project development, and importantly, it recognises and validates the twin goals of emission reduction and jobs creation that we share with our partners at Moreland City Council and across the H2U Consortium."
Minister for Energy, Environment and Climate Change Lily D'Ambrosio said the initiative demonstrated the potential of renewable energy to address greenhouse gas emissions from heavy fleet operations.
"I hope other councils look at this project and see its potential for replication across Victoria," Ms D'Ambrosio said.
The total cost of the project is estimated at $10 million. Moreland Council has allocated $1.5 million over three years to fund the solar component of the project and the balance is to be sourced by the developers with state and federal governments being asked to contribute.
RELATED:
●
●
●
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attilio Pigneri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H2U</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland Mayor Helen Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Climate Change Lily D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-first</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H2U Consortium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambrosio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
