<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429708756038676</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/hilary-duff-slams-body-shamers-over-beach-picture-tells-them-to-kiss-my-ass/news-story/3ff590539b32466a1564dbcb70a672cc</url>
  <title>Duff's brilliant clapback to mum body shamers</title>
  <content>
HILARY Duff is calling out everyone who's called her out already.
"Since websites and magazines love to share 'celeb flaws' - well I have them!" she wrote on Instagram of a pic snapped from behind while she holds her son at the beach.
The Younger star, soon to be 30, is holidaying in Hawaii after "a long season of shooting," where she has been getting in some quality time with her son.
But her trip was interrupted when trolls began picking apart her "flaws" after bathing suit pictures shot by paparazzi emerged.
Duff clapped back by saying, "My body has given me the greatest gift of my life: Luca, 5 years ago. I'm turning 30 in September and my body is healthy and gets me where I need to go."
She ended her lengthy post by inspiring women to accept their bodies as they are.
"Ladies, lets be proud of what we've got and stop wasting precious time in the day wishing we were different, better, and unflawed."
Her advice for anyone else? "#Kissmyass."
This isn't the first time the Lizzie Maguire star has encouraged other women to have more self confidence.
In February, the actress took to Instagram to encourage her followers to love themselves.
"Our bodies are amazing and something to be grateful for. I'm ME and that's really enough!" she wrote.
originally appeared on The New York Post and has been republished here with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DUFF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luca, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kissmyass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lizzie Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilary Duff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
