<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428772453157785</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/opinion-plan-will-protect-our-marine-parks/3208691/</url>
  <title>OPINION: Plan will protect our marine parks</title>
  <content>
WE all know that the Sunshine Coast has the best beaches and the best seafood in Australia.
What is less well known is that we also have the largest long-line tuna and prawn fishing fleets on the east coast. You could say that Mooloolaba is our nation's fishing capital.
Fishing on the Sunshine Coast generates $42.5 million in direct sales every year, with more than $30 million in exports. Throughout South-East Asia people are serving Mooloolaba prawns and Coral Sea tuna, caught right here.
Local fishing, though is about much more than a successful industry; it is part of our culture. Between here and the Gold Coast there are 140,000 recreational boats.
For more than a century Sunshine Coast residents have exercised their right to throw a line over the side of their tinnie. Today, five million Australians are recreational fishermen.
The ocean off the Sunshine Coast has been bountiful but it is not a bottomless resource. It must be carefully maintained. We have to protect our reefs and sustain our marine life, while ensuring that local people and businesses can use their boats for fishing, diving, and tourism.
That is why we need Marine Parks.
In July the Commonwealth Government released its new draft plan for managing these parks. The documents are online now for all of us to read and have our say at .
The previous plan, created by Julia Gillard's Labor Government, increased the size of our marine parks to almost 40% of Commonwealth waters and locked commercial fishermen out completely from more than a third of that area.
Everyday recreational fishers were banned from an area of ocean the size of the Northern Territory with no environmental benefit in sight. Something had to be done.
The new plan dramatically increases the area available to recreational fishers, opening up 97% of the Commonwealth waters which are within 100km of the shoreline. This includes fantastic sites in the Coral Sea like the Cato, Wreck, Shark and Vema reefs.
For commercial fishing, we got smarter about how we manage marine parks. The size of the parks will stay the same but only 20% of them will be designated green zones, where no fishing can happen. In those zones the fish will be able to spawn and feed, while the remaining 80% will protect the sea floor but allow fishing in the waters above.
The environmental outcomes from the plan will be world class. We should not be distracted by the complaints of northern hemisphere lobby groups whose own fisheries have been decimated and who now seek to criticise us.
With 36% of our surrounding waters covered by marine parks we will have smashed the UN's target of 10%. We will have the second largest area under marine management in the world and sustainable stocks of marine life for the future.
We will have increased the number of protected ecological features on the sea floor from 192 to 265 and expanded the areas where oil and gas exploration is banned.
However, we will also have halved the economic impact on commercial fishers to a manageable $4.1 million nationwide and opened up 80% of the parks to sensible sustainable fishing.
As part of my work to help make the Sunshine Coast the place to be for education, employment and retirement, I met some of our hard working local fishers, like Pavo Walker from Walker Seafoods and Johnny Rockliff from Rockliff Seafoods, when I brought Assistant Minister Ruston to Mooloolaba last month.
Like many others, they were rightly concerned about the future of fishing in Australia, but I am pleased to say that they were reassured by the new draft plan.
The Federal Government supports and will maintain the Australian tradition of being allowed to throw a line over the side of a boat.
Every Australian should be able to serve fresh, wholesome, locally-caught and sustainable seafood to their families.
This new plan enshrines that ability and will keep Mooloolaba an Australian fishing capital for years to come.
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
"The Sunshine Coast is different. It has its own personality."
Yaroomba Beach project will be "a fantastic coastal village"
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Markets have plenty of fresh and locally made foods, arts and crafts
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
The words "hustler!" and "bitch!" were hurled.
Home sells in just one day
Elegant home with seven levels hits the market
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coral Sea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vema</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pavo Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Minister Ruston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Gillard's Labor Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-east Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockliff Seafoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker Seafoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
