<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429451057998609</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-05/nauru-security-guard-charged-sacked-after-alleged-attack-on-refugee/1691446</url>
  <title>Nauru security guard charged, sacked after alleged attack on refugee</title>
  <content>
A Nauruan security guard has been charged after allegedly assaulting a refugee at the settlement camp he was employed to protect.

Key points:

Bronton Namaduk was employed by an Australian company and has been sacked
A 27-year-old Bangladeshi refugee was left with facial cuts and bruising
The refugee alleges Namaduk punched him multiple times and struck him with a liquor bottle

The incident at the Anibare Lodge refugee accommodation area happened about midnight local time on Wednesday morning.
Police charged Nauruan man Bronton Namaduk, who was employed by an Australian company hired by the Nauruan government to provide security at the site.
In a statement, the Nauruan Government did not specify what crime police had charged Namaduk with, or the name of the company that employed him.
He allegedly attacked Kamal Parvez, a 27-year-old Bangladeshi refugee, who was later taken to the Republic of Nauru Hospital to receive treatment for facial injuries.

Photo:(Supplied)
Mr Parvez had just returned to the accommodation site when the incident occurred.
"As soon as I got in my room he came straight away and he kicked the door, and he carried a bottle of vodka," Mr Parvez told the ABC.
"He was completely smashed, out of control."
In video footage shot by a resident of the refugee camp, neighbours can be seen attempting to restrain Namaduk as he grabs and knees Mr Parvez in the stomach area.
"He started to grab my collar, and then I tried to hold him but he's a very tough guy so I couldn't," Mr Parvez said.
"All of my neighbours, they woke up and they tried to hold him but couldn't."
Mr Parvez alleges Namaduk punched him multiple times and later struck him with a liquor bottle.
Police were called to the scene and arrested Namaduk, and his employment at the site has been terminated.
In its statement, the Nauru Government said it understood the incident was "not random ... but connected to a relationship between the refugee and a female relative of the Nauruan man".
Mr Parvez denied that claim, and said he is not in a relationship with a Nauruan woman.

Photo:(Supplied)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauruan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anibare Lodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladeshi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kamal Parvez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauruan Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronton Namaduk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republic of Nauru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Namaduk</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Parvez</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
