<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651428849762570161</docid>
  <date>04/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/malcolm-turnbull-wa-charm-offensive-delivers-cynical-politics/8775622</url>
  <title>Malcolm Turnbull's WA charm offensive delivers nothing but the most awkward bromance</title>
  <content>
It was billed as the charm offensive listening tour of WA - designed to woo back voters in the West.
But it's arguable whether Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull's near week-long visit to WA would have won over a single voter. Instead, it probably left many scratching their heads.
For days Mr Turnbull and Premier Mark McGowan traded soundbite blows over the shortfall in GST payments to WA.
There was lots of hype and uncertainty about if the two would hold a one-on-one meeting. By the time it was finally confirmed, both leaders had intensified their war of words over the GST.
Mr McGowan stoked the fire, telling Mr Turnbull to , while the Prime Minister accused the Premier of being belligerent and told him to "put some steel in his spine".
In the end, their planned half-hour meeting ran for 1 hour and 45 minutes, but ended with no resolution on the difficult GST issue - including the latest $2 billion hit to WA finances courtesy of updated data showing a population drop in WA.
In a strange twist of events, by the next morning  for a ribbon-cutting ceremony at the opening of a freeway extension.

Just before that event the Prime Minister was on ABC Radio Perth's morning program, where he accused the media of living in a "parallel universe" in response to suggestions West Australians were angry at him and his Government over the state's low GST share.
"I have met with hundreds of West Australians this week ... and the reception I have had could not have been warmer, or more positive or more welcoming," Mr Turnbull said.
"It is a complete parallel universe between what the media is saying and what the people I am meeting in the real world are saying to me."
Bring on the bromance

Journalists certainly felt like they were living in a parallel universe when after days of enduring a GST war words between Mr Turnbull and Mr McGowan at press conference after press conference, they turned up to the freeway extension media event to witness what looked like a bromance between the pair.
It was smiles, back pats and handshakes all round for the cameras as the Prime Minister declared: "See we get on very well, don't believe what you read in the press."

Newfound bromances aside, there were at least 11 state and federal politicians in attendance at the opening, all vying to get into the ribbon-cutting picture.
The event had all the trademarks of the satirical television series Utopia and begged the question - just how many politicians does it take to open a freeway extension?
If it felt bizarre for journalists, then there's every chance WA voters who had watched the week's events unfold felt equally dumbfounded.
It's WA voters who must surely feel like they live in a parallel universe when the Prime Minister comes to their state on a highly anticipated and promoted rare visit with his whole Cabinet but fails to deliver anything of real significance, including any more funding for new infrastructure.
It's WA voters who must feel confused about how two leaders can use a whole week fighting - at taxpayers' expense - over the GST but apparently not progress the issue or reach any resolution after a meeting that lasted so long.

These are voters who are repeatedly told by many politicians that same-sex marriage is "not a priority issue", only to continually see it thrust upon the political agenda time and again by MPs without any resolution.
It's a universe where, as political events in WA this week showed, politicians come out strongly on serious issues of significance but it quickly turns to having the appearance of being little more than political theatrics designed to grab headlines and air time when it can all be thrust aside on a whim because there's a ribbon to be cut or a politically advantageous picture opportunity to be had.
These voters live in a world where reviews and inquiries are set up into many an important issue, including GST, with great hope and promise of change and action, only to result in a report that garners headlines for a few days before gathering dust and delivering nothing.
Failing the pub test

One train ride to Mandurah and a politics at the pub gathering surrounded by party faithful won't give any politician, including the Prime Minister, an insight into how voters in WA, or indeed in any other state, feel.

External Link:

Goodenough tweet

External Link:

Porter tweet
The level of voter apathy, disenchantment, distrust and frustration caused by the current state of politics and political discourse in this country, at both a state and federal level, is arguably the surest sign that it is politicians who the voting public think live in a parallel universe.
In the end, if the GST system is not fixed before the 2019 federal election, the test of the much talked about WA voter anger towards the PM and his Government over the issue will be shown at the poll.
As one avid watcher of politics, who's a WA voter, remarked this week - the PM might be hoping for a parallel election.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utopia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandurah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodenough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull's WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
