<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429322208978592</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/domain/domain-news/latest-news/squash-world-champ-rodney-eyles-palm-beach-mansion-for-sale-20170804-gxpek9.html</url>
  <title>'I would pinch myself': Prime Palm Beach mansion for sale</title>
  <content>
Former squash world champion Rodney Eyles has listed his stunning Palm Beach beachfront mansion at  for sale.

"I would pinch myself every single morning that I lived here. I love this house," Mr Eyles said. "It's been the best place in the world for our kids to grow up."

You can walk directly off of the 597-square metre block and onto the sands of Palm Beach and there's unbeatable ocean views from the home's living areas too.

Former squash world champion Rodney Eyles. Photo: Supplied

"It is truly [heaven] to walk out the back door and be right on the beach," Mr Eyles said.

After 17 years the Eyles family are giving up the family home; they no longer need it. Recently, the former squash world number two has been working in the US.

 agent  said apart from the obvious benefit of being able to walk onto the beach, Jefferson Lane was a prime location.

63 Jefferson Lane, Palm Beach. Photo: Supplied

"On a global scale, Palm Beach also has something special as its gated by two estuaries on either end with national parks at Currumbin to the south and Burleigh Heads to the north."

Mr Eyles said he was a big fan of the opportunities for fun the lifestyle offered. "I love to surf and kayak here," he said. "There's great spots from here to Currumbin to go running and cycling."

Jefferson Lane includes the addresses of a number of high profile and high net worth individuals such as Ryan Stokes, Kelly Slater, and Peter Dutton.

The Eyles have lived in the home for 17 years. Photo: Supplied

Mr Dowker said Jefferson Lane was often overshadowed more well known streets like Hedges Avenue. "It's always been a part of the who's who but it's sort of been shadowed by Hedges but now Jefferson is coming into it's own," he said. "It attracts a lot of high profile people and they choose  over anywhere else on the Gold Coast.

Jefferson Lane's sale prices were also closing in on Hedges Avenue.

"Hedges has always been the pinnacle. In 2007 is was twice the price [of Jefferson Lane] as a rule of thumb, but now it's 1.5 times," he said. "Jefferson is closing the gap."

The four bedroom house goes to auction on September 2.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eyles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jefferson Lane</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hedges Avenue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dowker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palm Beach</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Palm Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Eyles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currumbin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jefferson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eyles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
