<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429884849699421</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/recipe-the-salad-that-stacks-up/3208803/</url>
  <title>RECIPE: The salad that stacks up</title>
  <content>
Caramelised pineapple, coconut, quinoa salad with spicy chilli dressing

INGREDIENTS: 1 cup quinoa grains &frac12; pineapple &frac12; red cabbage &frac14; white drum cabbage &frac12; bunch spring onions, sliced 1 carrot, peeled 1/2 bunch coriander, washed well, stalks chopped finely and leaves picked 1 roast chicken, meat pulled off the bones and shredded 1 cup shredded coconut toasted Extra coriander for garnish

For the dressing:  2 long green chillies, sliced &frac14; cup lime juice 60ml fish sauce &frac14; tsp sesame oil 150ml sweet chili sauce

METHOD: Rinse the quinoa and cook as directed on the packet, drain and set aside to cool.

Peel the pineapple and slice it into rounds of 1cm thickness, depending on how many people you are feeding.

Heat a grill pan over a moderate to high temperature and place the pineapple in the pan, leaving it for 4-5 minutes before looking or turning it over - you want to caramelise the pineapple and see the char lines.

If you don't have a grill pan you can use a frying pan.

Set the pineapple aside.

For the remainder of the salad, either shred or finely chop the red cabbage, white cabbage and the carrot together - you can also do this by placing the ingredients in a food processor and pulsing the ingredients for a couple of seconds.

To assemble the dish, combine the quinoa with the chopped cabbages, carrot, spring onions, coriander and shredded chicken.

Add the toasted coconut and the dressing and toss well to combine the dressing and the salad.

Place a slice of pineapple on the plate and then pile up a portion of the salad, garnish with coriander, a slice of lime and a scattering of toasted coconut and serve.

Police believe Sam may have hidden the bodies of three people
CLAIRE got to experience a week in the RAAF.
Torture trial continues after house of horror claims.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
