<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429627151659476</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/so-sexism-is-good-after-all/news-story/8b834ad0556add73ecccfee62320551e</url>
  <title>SO SEXISM AND RACISM ARE GOOD, AFTER ALL</title>
  <content>
As I say, with the Left it's not the principle that counts but the side.

Brunswick cafe  has caused a stir with a new initiative designed to raise awareness of the gender wage gap. A chalkboard at the cafe reads:
"House Rules, Rule #1: women have priority seating. Rule #2: men will be charged an 18% premium to reflect the gender pay gap (2016) which is donated to a women's service. Rule #3 respect goes both ways."
Actually rule 3 lies. There is no "both ways" here.
What this shows is that sexism isn't actually wrong at all to Handsome Her. Not as long as it's men being oppressed.
(Note that these rules are predicated on  or  statistics on the gender pay gap. Name a single cafe where men are paid more than women for the very same job.)

The spires of George-town University in Washington, alma mater of Bill Clinton, serve as a beacon for students across America. Competition to secure a place is ferocious, but the playing field is uneven. Late last year Georgetown said it would give preference to the -des-cendants of 272 slaves the university sold in 1838 to pay off debts. It was, the university said, a small atonement for a terrible event.
The move was welcomed by -the descendants but criticised by -others who said it was a case of misguided political correctness that gave African-American students an unfair advantage over higher-scoring applicants, including white and Asian students...
Roger Clegg, a civil rights official in the Reagan and first Bush -administrations, says: "The civil rights laws were deliberately written to protect everyone from -discrimination, and it is frequently the case that not only are whites discriminated against now but -frequently Asian-Americans are as well."
US law states that universities have an interest in creating a -diverse student body and that race can be used as one of a multiple factors to influence admissions.
Just over a year ago the US -Supreme Court ruled narrowly against a challenge to race-based university admissions. The case involved a white student from Texas, Abigail Fisher, who claimed she had missed out on a place at the University of Texas because she was white.
Because Fisher didn't get in the top 10 per cent of test scores, her application was evaluated on a -series of other criteria, one of which was race. "I was taught from the time I was a little girl that any kind of discrimination was wrong," -Fisher said...
[T]he university -argued that her marks, rather than her race, were the determining -factor.
The Supreme Court ruled 4-3 in the university's favour. Justice Anthony Kelly said "it remains an enduring challenge to our nation's education system to reconcile the pursuit of diversity with the constitutional promise of equal treatment and dignity".
Which suggests it wasn't her marks but her race that counted in the end.
What this shows is that racism isn't actually wrong at all to the court and the universities and the activists. Not as long as it's whites being oppressed.
Increasingly the Left is what it condemns: racist, sexist, anti-Semitic, bigoted and authoritarian.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgetown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEXISM AND RACISM ARE GOOD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Semitic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handsome Her</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George-town University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rule #1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Anthony Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Rules</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Clegg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abigail Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
