<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430310051465081</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/retail/shrinkflation-to-rise-as-grocery-manufacturers-offset-rising-costs-20170803-gxoipt</url>
  <title>That shrinking feeling - 'shrinkflation' to rise as suppliers' costs soar   </title>
  <content>
Peeved your favourite grocery product has shrunk but the price has stayed the same? Get used to it.
So-called shrinkflation - which has pushed up the unit price of brands such as Tiny Teddy, Magnum ice-creams, Smiths chips and Cadbury chocolates - is set to escalate as food and grocery manufacturers try to , a , and a slowing economy.
As  to cut wholesale prices, reducing pack sizes is one of the few options available to brand owners committed to manufacturing in Australia rather than shifting offshore.
This year alone, Arnott's has cut the number of packets of Tiny Teddies and Shapes in multi-packs to eight from 10, but the price has stayed the same, according to consumer group Choice, while Unilever has put its top-selling Magnum ice-creams on a diet, shrinking servings from 117 millilitres to 107.

Industry sources say Heinz is in the process of scaling back 420-gram cans of baked beans, while standard Kleenex facial tissues have become so small they're barely fit for purpose and Huggies nappy wipe refills rattle around in their original containers.

"It highlights the pressure on manufacturers where you've had price deflation for the last five years," says Australian Food and Grocery Council chief executive Tanya Barden.
"If costs are rising and you're unable to raise wholesale prices, the variables are the amount you produce or scaling back products," Barden says.
Arnott's cited rising energy and input costs as one of the reasons for cutting the number of Tiny Teddies and Shapes in some multi-packs.
"As with all businesses, from time to time it is necessary for us to review the prices of our products. Recent increases in energy and input costs mean costs across our Australian bakeries are higher," a spokeswoman says. "We have removed two snack packs from the 10 packs instead of increasing the price at which we sell these products to retailers."

Unilever argues it can no longer absorb rising costs.
"Any decision involving reductions in size is always difficult to make, however, with continued rises in raw material and production costs, such as the price of energy, it can become no longer feasible to absorb costs across our product range," says a spokeswoman.
"In the case of Magnum, rather than pass on additional costs to our consumers, we slightly decreased the size of our ice creams."
Inflation disguised

It's not only an issue for consumers grappling with rising living costs, record high household debt and low wages growth, it's also one for the federal government and the Reserve Bank, as shrinking pack sizes contribute to inflation.
That might not be a concern right now when inflation is tracking below the government's 2 to 3 per cent target band but economist Dr Pippa Malmgren, author of Signals: How Everyday Signs Can Help Us Navigate the World's Turbulent Economy, says .
Shrinking Tim Tam packets and Toblerone bars are a signal that the cost of making them is rising and the only way companies can preserve profits is to make products smaller while maintaining prices, Malmgren told journalists during a recent trip to Australia.
"It's signalling that inflation is coming back into the system and it's an early indicator that your rent and rail fares are going to go up," Malmgren said.

Australian Bureau of Statistics chief economist Bruce Hockman is all too aware of the phenomenon.
"It's been going on for years," says Hockman, who prefers to use the term quality adjustment. "I can remember in my younger days being involved in debating and hearing someone do an erudite presentation on the reduction in the size of the Iced Vovo."
"Some of it is illusory - everything seems smaller now you're no longer a kid," he says.
But there's no doubt shrinkflation is occurring on a regular basis.

In the UK last week, the Office of National Statistics released figures showing more than 2500 products including chocolate bars, toilet paper, coffee and fruit juice had shrunk in size over the past five years but were being sold for the same price.
In Australia, half the 200 product categories analysed by Nielsen had smaller pack sizes, either because suppliers were selling smaller pack options, such as Coca-Cola Amatil's 200 ml cans of Coke, or because suppliers had downsized volumes.
Of the categories with smaller pack sizes, prices had risen on one-third, says Alfredo Costa, Nielsen's head of retail.
The ABS tracks shrinkflation by sending staff into supermarkets to examine shelf stickers and peruse sales dockets, but does not keep a public record of changes in pack sizes.
"We don't track it in the way they [the ONS] did, but what we do is continuously adjust for it in the CPI," Hockman says.
"If a packet of [Arnott's] BBQ Shapes goes from 200 grams to 175 grams and the price doesn't change we treat that as a price rise of 12.5 per cent. What we don't do in quality adjustment is adjust for the fact that the new BBQ Shapes taste worse than the old BBQ Shapes," he said, referring to a social media debate after recipe changes.
Sensitive on toilet paper

"The other sensitive one would be toilet paper. It's shrunk in width and the number of sheets per roll. We find it harder to pick up width change than the number of sheets per roll.

"Shrinkflation is one side of the quality adjustment we do in the CPI. The other side is quality improvement stuff, the constantly improving quality of computers and smartphones and things like that - quality changes in a number of ways," Hockman says.
Nielsen research suggests consumers are willing to put up with shrinkflation if it means they don't have to spend more of their hard-earned cash.
"Do not raise prices is the message that came through loud and clear," says Costa. "According to the findings, almost half [46 per cent] of consumers would prefer that manufacturers offer an economy-size package with lower cost per usage/serving."
However, consumer group Choice says consumers are unhappy about creeping price rises and has called on suppliers to be more transparent.
"The cost of food and groceries continues to rank as one of the top cost-of-living concerns," says Katinka Day, Choice's senior policy and campaigns adviser. "When food manufacturers reduce their pack size without reducing the price, consumers lose out.
"Manufacturers can often reduce the size of their product without consumers realising they are getting less value for money.
"This is why quantity statements on front of pack are so important," she says, referring to industry attempts to remove weight displays from the front of packages. "Without weight information on front of pack, food manufacturers can get away with shrinking pack sizes without consumers knowing."
Consumer advocate Chris Zinn agrees, saying regular pack size changes emphasise the importance of unit pricing, which enables consumers to better compare prices across different packs and brands.

'We're far more attuned to the price of something than the weight of it," says Zinn. "The real answer here is unit pricing ... which allows people to make side-by-side comparisons. We have some very powerful advocates for unit pricing here ... but there's been some slippage and it's not regulated."
Zinn says manufacturers should be honest with consumers about when and why they reduced pack sizes while maintaining prices rather than using dubious consumer research to justify their actions.
"There's incredible consumer sensitivity to this, particularly on social media. Things do change and they need to be transparent about it."
The AFGC's Barden says suppliers aren't trying to hide pack changes but agrees the sector needs to be clearer with consumers about the cost pressures they are facing.
As for the major retailers, industry sources suggest that while Coles and Woolworths are clamping down on supplier price rises they turn a blind eye to shrinkflation because it has a less obvious impact on consumers.
Woolworths says it works closely with suppliers to ensure they offer customers the products they want.
"As part of this, we undertake regular feedback sessions with customers to ensure these preferences are being met," a Woolworths spokesman says. "It's our job to offer best value for customers and we will continue to do that in partnership with our suppliers."
Coles says it is intent on providing value and quality that customers could trust.

"This is why we've continued to lower prices on the products our customers buy the most - like more than 30 lines of bread and 10 lines of washing products in July - so customers can get the same products for less," a spokeswoman says.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFGC's Barden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnum</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ONS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toblerone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Pippa Malmgren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfredo Costa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malmgren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coca-Cola Amatil's 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiny Teddy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya Barden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World's Turbulent Economy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Zinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBQ Shapes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kleenex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nielsen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNILEVER</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hockman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everyday Signs Can Help Us Navigate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hockman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grocery Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shrinkflation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Tam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iced Vovo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heinz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huggies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cadbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katinka Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Food</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zinn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
