<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429833310091368</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/special-counsel-robert-mueller-asks-white-house-for-michael-flynn-documents-20170805-gxpz4l.html</url>
  <title>Special counsel Robert Mueller asks White House for Michael Flynn documents</title>
  <content>
Washington: Investigators working for the special counsel, Robert Mueller, recently asked the White House for documents related to former national security adviser Michael Flynn.
They have also questioned witnesses about whether he was secretly paid by the Turkish government during the final months of the presidential campaign, according to people close to the investigation.

Up Next

'This culture of leaking must stop': Sessions

01:39

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Memo: Trump asked Comey to shut down Flynn probe

A report that President Donald Trump asked former FBI Director James Comey to shut down an investigation into ousted national security adviser Michael Flynn is being disputed by The White House.

Although not a formal subpoena, the document request is the first known instance of Mueller's team asking the White House to hand over records.
In interviews with potential witnesses in recent weeks, prosecutors and FBI agents have spent hours poring over the details of Flynn's business dealings with a Turkish-American businessman who worked last year with Flynn and his consulting business, the Flynn Intel Group.

The company was paid $US530,000 ($668,000) to run a campaign to discredit an opponent of the Turkish government who has been accused of orchestrating last year's failed coup in the country.
Investigators want to know if the Turkish government was behind those payments -- and if the Flynn Intel Group made kickbacks to the businessman, Ekim Alptekin, for helping conceal the source of the money.

The line of questioning shows that Mueller's inquiry has expanded into a full-fledged examination of Flynn's financial dealings, beyond the relatively narrow question of whether he failed to register as a foreign agent or lied about his conversations and business arrangements with Russian officials.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Flynn lasted only 24 days as national security adviser, but his legal troubles now lie at the centre of a political storm that has engulfed the Trump administration.Photo: AP
Flynn declined to comment. Ty Cobb, special counsel to President Donald Trump, said, "We've said before we're collaborating with the special counsel on an ongoing basis."
Investigators are examining the flow of money into and out of the Flynn Intel Group -- a consulting firm Flynn founded after being forced out as the director of the Defence Intelligence Agency -- according to several potential witnesses who have been interviewed by prosecutors and FBI agents.Photo: AP
Taking money from Turkey or any foreign government is not illegal. But failing to register as a foreign agent is a felony, and trying to hide the source of the money by routing it through a private company or some other entity, and then paying kickbacks to the middleman, could lead to criminal charges.
Prosecutors have also asked during interviews about Flynn's speaking engagements for Russian companies, for which he was paid more than $US65,000 in 2015, and about his company's clients -- including work it may have done with the Japanese government.Photo: AP
They have also asked about the White Canvas Group, a data-mining company that was reportedly paid $US200,000 by the Trump campaign for unspecified services. The Flynn Intel Group shared office space with White Canvas Group, which was founded by a former special operations officer who was a friend of Flynn's.
Flynn has now had to file three versions of his financial-disclosure forms. His first version did not disclose payments from Russia-linked companies. He added those payments to an amended version of the forms he submitted in March. This week he filed a new version, adding that he briefly had a contract with SCL Group, the parent company of Cambridge Analytica, a data-mining firm that worked with the Trump campaign.
The new forms list at least $US1.8 million in income, up from the roughly $US1.4 million he had previously reported. It is unclear how much of that money was related to work Flynn did on Turkey issues.
Flynn's campaign to discredit the opponent of the Turkish government, Fethullah Gulen, began August 9 when his firm signed a $US600,000 deal with Inovo BV, a Dutch company owned by Alptekin, a Turkish-American businessman.
Gulen, a reclusive cleric, lives in rural Pennsylvania.
New York Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alptekin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge Analytica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish American</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ty Cobb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia-linked</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Flynn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inovo BV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCL Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US530,000 ($668,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flynn</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Canvas Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mueller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$600,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pennsylvania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekim Alptekin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US200,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flynn Intel Group</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fethullah Gulen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Director James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defense Intelligence Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US65,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
