<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430395950811696</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/celebrating-jarryd-rougheads-250th-those-who-know-him-in-their-own-words-20170803-gxoxfw.html</url>
  <title>Celebrating Jarryd Roughead's 250th: Those who know him, in their own words</title>
  <content>
Joe Ingles, NBA basketballer, friend:

Jarryd Roughead is just a very regular dude and he would be that way whether he had won four AFL premierships or not.
The people that know him know what he is about.Photo: AAP
He has always been there from me ever since we became friends during my time with the South Dragons. We are the same age and we were both young men in a new city. So he has been there for me during a lot of my career, in fact a lot of my contract negotiations happened on his sofa.
That only happens because I know he is going to give me an honest opinion and I know he doesn't care about anything else except Renae [Ingles' wife] and my happiness.
Aside from having my interests at heart first and foremost, he is a big basketball nuffie. A lot of the time it's me bouncing thoughts off him as he knows every league in the world, Euros, internationally - he knows it all so it's my wife and Roughy who I really speak to about serious things.
People would never believe what an ultra-professional athlete he is. They just wouldn't believe it with his scraggly beard. But he is just that. He is one of the most professional people I have been around and he takes his job as being an AFL player really serious and I think that has showed.

If you look at him 10 or 12 years ago he was never athletic, he wasn't going to blow you out of the water with anything but by going about it the right way.
The mutual friendship we have is awesome, just to have someone who you know will have your back no matter what.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

It was cool for me to support him with what he recently went through, just to go and sit with him at the hospital and be a mate, to give back, was the least I could do. It was a privilege.
Over the years we have had a lot of green teas on the sofa and late nights talking about all kinds of different things. Although he is more of a coffee man, with an extra shot.Premiership teammate and close friend Jordan Lewis:

The person that I know is a loyal friend, someone that is always willing to help people in any way.
Fantastic teammate, very selfless in the way that he plays, a competitive person, someone that has always wiling to push himself and look for areas in his game to work on.
You sort of take for granted when your teammates and you rock up to the club every day, it's not until you're out of that environment that you realise how much you miss playing with him.
He's a country kid at heart and enjoys the simple things in life, although I think he's a bit confused. He's a country lad, like he drives a big Hilux and everything, but then you'll see him in Balenciaga shoes and drinks fine wine. I think the older he gets the more confused he gets.
I'll tell you one thing: he thinks he's a good drinker, but he's not. He's always the first one there but always the first one to leave. He'll always let you know when he finishes a beer.
He's not the fittest bloke I've ever met. He hates running, he only runs if there's a ball in front of him to get.
In all seriousness, though, when I think about it, the same traits that have made him a good footballer really helped him go through his treatment. He's resilient, diligent, he's never wanted to push his issues on anyone else, he wanted to deal with them himself.Hawthorn's head fitness coach Andrew Russell:

Roughy has been such a key part of the Hawthorn journey. He brings people together, he's a man who creates really strong relationships and he thrives on having strong relationships. He needs to know that you like him and you rate him and you value him.
He's been extremely resilient with issues he's had over the years. When he's ruptured his Achilles, he just said: "OK, I've ruptured my Achilles. Let's get on with it and get a good result."
He doesn't dwell on things, he doesn't get down on himself. He's very practical and very pragmatic.
When he had his cancer, he was unbelievably strong. From the start he was saying, "This is what it is, we've got to deal with it. Don't feel sorry for me, I don't want to hear it."
I remember last year, it was a week before the finals. I was up the other end of the oval doing a drill and he walked out onto the oval. I couldn't recognise him, I didn't know who it was. He looked like a frail old man. But he would never complain, never whinge. Never once. He did a photo shoot with the players and he didn't look well at all.
Form that point onwards, to think that he could come back and be ready to play round one is outstanding. It just shows his resilience.
I don't know, only he would know, but I don't know if he dealt with it as a life-threatening situation. My feeling is that he wiped it out and just said this is an issue I have to deal with - let's get on with it.
He dealt with it just like an injury. When am I going to play again? How long will it be until I can get back to playing with the boys? What can I do? Can I run around?
It was new ground for all of us!Leading oncologist Professor Grant McArthur, the doctor who led Roughead through his treatment:

I've looked after a lot of people that have had advanced cancer and clearly this is the biggest challenge that people have faced in their life.
Clearly it tests people in many ways and what I've seen with Jarryd is some real strength. He's faced with his own predicament, he's looked to protect others, he's had some tough times that he got through with a very positive outlook.
When faced with what is a challenge when coming out of intense treatment and then being out up as captain of the club, no real hesitation despite personal difficulties he wanted to put his hand up and lead.
And being a footy fan myself I couldn't help but pay special attention to how he went in his first game back which was a practice game.
And I remember vividly the commentators saying at half-time that he was best on the ground.
To see after everything he'd been through that he could come out and approach that game with such enthusiasm in a game that didn't mean a lot to the club but meant a lot to him - it was pretty inspirational to me.
When someone is a high-profile person they can make an educational contribution to the community, I'm very careful not to push someone to do that just because they're a high-profile person.
But with Jarryd, he's the one volunteering. In summer he trains with long sleeves and wears a hat; yes, he's looking after himself but he's also being a role model to others.
That is real leadership.
Some people rely a lot on others. Jarryd just loved taking responsibility.
Watching him play footy is interesting because when the Hawks are in strife they often put you on the ball - he takes responsibility - that's the way he approached his illness. He wasn't passive, he took it on himself.
Interviews by Roy Ward and Sam McClure
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead's 250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Achilles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam McClure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balenciaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Grant McArthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
