<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430395950811643</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/margaret-river-pro-saved-by-world-surf-league-boss-dirk-ziff/news-story/7398d01ab4f919e579cdc5a002dec8f9</url>
  <title>Margies Pro saved by WSL boss</title>
  <content>
THE organisers of WA's premier surfing event have admitted the contest was to be axed from next year until a last-minute intervention from the owner of the sport's global governing body.
Surfing WA chief executive Mark Lane revealed on Friday that the Margaret River Pro "didn't have a pulse" last year when the event's place on the elite world tour from 2018 came up for negotiation with the World Surf League.
But it has emerged that a change of management at the top of the WSL - billionaire owner Dirk Ziff replaced former boss Paul Speaker - spared Margaret River from the chop.
Mr Lane joined by Tourism Minister Paul Papalia on Friday to confirm the Margaret River Pro would stay on the World Championship Tour until at least 2019 after the WSL agreed to renew its contract for another two years.
The move caps a remarkable turn of fortunes for the event, after Surfing WA was told last year that Margaret River would be relegated from the top flight of surfing contests as part of efforts to trim the Australian leg of the tour from three events to two.
Mr Papalia said the deal was a coup for tourism in the South West and WA more broadly because the event perfectly showcased the region's natural beauty, clean and green image and hospitality sector.
The Minister said the event was also valuable advertising given that, on average, about 3.5 million people tuned in to watch the action via live broadcasts online.
On top of this, Mr Papalia said the Margaret River Pro was also an important platform for WA's young surfers to get competition experience and exposure at a global level.
"It has a fantastic world audience, Mr Papalia said. "I can say that the Government was 100 per cent behind this event - we went out from day one wanting to retain it."
Under the multimillion-dollar deal, which is being largely funded by Tourism WA, the contract for the Pro will be extended at least two years, with the option of a further extension.
Mr Lane said the agreement almost never happened after the WSL earmarked Margaret River as the event to be axed from Australia rather than the Gold Coast of Bells Beach in Victoria - both longstanding events.
"It didn't actually have a pulse at all," Mr Lane said.
According to the Surfing WA boss, the event was vital to developing the sport in WA, with male and female wildcards being chosen from the local trial beforehand.
"Clearly we've had wonderful support from the State Government - that just gives you a lot of confidence when you're going in to bat."
Jack Halsow and Jamaica Selby, the state under 18 and national under 16 champions respectively, said they were "stoked" the event would stay on the WCT as it gave them the chance to surf with and against the best surfers in the world.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Papalia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaica Selby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championship Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Surf League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WCT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margies Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dirk Ziff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret River Pro</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfing WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast of Bells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Minister Paul Papalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret River</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Speaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Halsow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
