<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430314346432413</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/former-roosters-star-tai-tuivasa-set-to-make-ufc-debut-in-sydney/news-story/4e9f8e9544933ce7010255e73fb1df7e</url>
  <title>Gone in 96 seconds: UFC rookie's record</title>
  <content>
NINETY-SIX seconds.
That's all the time it takes for Tai Tuivasa to win a fight.
A stunning average which drops even lower should you include his previous career as a Sydney Roosters prop.
"I've had a couple of slaps on the field, yeah,'' the rising Sydney heavyweight said. "But not too many ... and never for too long."
Once slated for an NRL career with the Tricolours, Tuivasa will instead make his highly-anticipated UFC debut in Sydney on November 19.
Five years after giving up his place alongside the likes of Dylan Napa and Roger Tuivasa-Sheck, the 140kg slugger will challenge Texan Rashad Coulter on the Fight Night card at Qudos Bank Arena.
UFC officials believe Tuivasa can become a genuine contender in the heavyweight division.
Of his seven wins as a professional, none have gone past the first round.
Apart from needing only 68 seconds to finish his first three opponents, the St Marys local then squared off against rugby league bad boy John Hopoate in 2012 - and ended that contest in 93 seconds.
Since then, the man who looms as Australia's new KO king has won three of four fights, become more focused, signed with the UFC and still never required more than one round to secure a victory.
Indeed, the longest Tuivasa has taken to win was last start, retaining the AFC heavyweight title after rival James McSweeney failed to answer the bell for round two. Which, to be fair, was a closer showdown than it sounds.
"James snapped three of my knee ligaments with a leg lock,'' Tuivasa revealed. "After the fight, I required a knee reconstruction - that's why I've had to wait an entire year between fights.
"I signed with the UFC almost immediately after the win but I've just had to wait for the knee to get right. And now, it feels awesome."
Asked if he regretted walking out on the Roosters to pursue a career in mixed martial arts, the slugger said: "I honestly believe I could be playing NRL right now.
"But I've always been a better fighter than I was a footballer.
"So I didn't just give up rugby league. Didn't just leave without having plans. I've always wanted to be where I am now."
And then, laughing, he added: "Plus I'm too angry for the NRL. The way things are these days, I'm not sure I'd be much good to anyone. You can't even slap a bloke without getting marched."
Despite having fought only eight times since his professional debut in 2012, the tattooed Sydneysider has also spent the past five years working as a full-time sparring partner for fellow UFC heavyweight Mark Hunt, who challenged for the world title in 2014.
"And if you can stand and trade with Mark Hunt,'' Tuivasa shrugged, 'who can't you fight'?"
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>KO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydneysiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hopoate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texan Rashad Coulter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fight Night</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qudos Bank Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tai Tuivasa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plus I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Marys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James McSweeney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuivasa</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Tuivasa-Sheck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Napa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Hunt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
