<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429923504405528</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/golf/jason-day-leaps-into-weekend-contention-at-wgc-bridgestone-invitational/news-story/c5c94b3fc56b948499f862f3b4dc20df</url>
  <title>'Felt like 2015': Day hits form</title>
  <content>
SEEING signs of his world-beating 2015 form has Jason Day poised for a weekend charge at the World Golf Championships-Bridgestone Invitational in Ohio.
Australian world No.7 Day played through back pain during Friday's weather-interrupted second round, making long-range birdie putts and tricky par saves to keep himself in the mix at the final WGC of the US PGA Tour season.
Day bagged five birdies in his opening nine holes before a three-hour weather delay halted his momentum heading into the back side.
But the Queenslander felt he turned the clock back two years, finishing day two just four shots off the pace.
"On the front nine, it definitely felt like 2015 or 2016. I was just pouring in every putt," said Day, referring to his breakout 2015 season which delivered a maiden major title at the US PGA Championship among five Tour wins that rocketed him to a debut stint as world No.1.
LIVE stream the PGA Championship on FOX SPORTS. Get a free 2-week Foxtel Now trial & stream LIVE within minutes.
The 29-year-old Day's four-under-par 66 elevated him to three-under after 36 holes of the 76-man WGC event at Firestone Country Club.
Jimmy Walker (65) leads at seven-under, two shots clear of Belgian Thomas Pieters (70).
Rory McIlroy (69), Zach Johnson (67) and Japan's Hideki Matsuyama (67) are tied for third at four-under.
Sharing sixth place with Day are five others, including world No.2 and recently- crowned British Open winner Jordan Spieth (70).
"I'm just excited about the next two rounds, trying to tackle the lead and get in contention again," said Day, who led the 2016 WGC-Bridgestone before a late collapse handed the title to Dustin Johnson.
Day winced and often clutched at his back on Friday, prompting fears of a recurrence of the injury which forced him to withdraw from last year's FedEx Cup playoffs and end his season prematurely.
But he says it won't be an issue as he prepares for a weekend run at his first Tour victory since May 2016.
"No, no, there's no issue. Everything's fine," said Day.
Fellow Australian Adam Scott failed to capitalise on a superb driving display, carding a disappointing 71 to be in a share of 13th at one-under alongside countryman Scott Hend (69).
World No.17 Scott leads the WGC field in strokes gained off the tee, hitting 19 of 28 fairways and ranking third in driving distance with an average of 318.7 yards.
"I missed a couple putts I would have liked to make. I just couldn't get it going," said Scott, who won the event in 2011.
"There are some good scores out there for me this weekend if I sharpen my irons up." Also failing to fire on day two was world No.1 Dustin Johnson, who shot 75 to sink to three-over in a tie for 40th in a group that includes Queensland veteran Rod Pampling (70).
Rounding out the Australian contingent are Marc Leishman (71) and Sam Brazel (70), tied for 52nd at four-over.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Spieth (70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian Thomas Pieters (70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Adam Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Walker (65</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Firestone Country Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Hend (69</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WGC of the US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OHIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FedEx Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Leishman (71</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US PGA Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Hideki Matsuyama (67</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Pampling (70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WGC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Golf Championships Bridgestone Invitational</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PGA Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PGA Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Brazel (70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory McIlroy (69</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World No 17 Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WGC-Bridgestone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Johnson (67</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
