<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429889144666741</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/new-baby-hardtop-stars-at-total-performance-car-sh/3208799/</url>
  <title>New baby hardtop stars at Total Performance Car Show</title>
  <content>
Beautiful little Kaia is only two weeks old and is Brock Mahoney's first child ... but she's his third baby.
Brock and Claire welcomed Kaia into a world of Ford fanaticism. She has rocketed into the number one position, but their prized hardtop pair are still close behind.
Ford fans would be well versed with Brock's multi-award winning 1977 XC GS, but many would not have seen the new addition to his garage - a 1975 Ford XB Falcon Hardtop John Goss Special, which will be on display at Pacific Ford's Total Performance Car Show on August 13.
Only available in limited numbers and released to commemorate John Goss's win at the Bathurst 1000 the previous year, Brock managed to get his hands on the rare offering in Ireland.
He travelled to Dublin to bring this awesome piece of motoring memorabilia home to Buderim.
"Claire and I got married a year ago and we used my XC and a mate of mine has a John Goss special in apollo blue so we used his car and another Mustang," Brock said.
"From January I had started to look seriously at buying one. Ben Atkinson, who runs Seven82motors, went and checked one in Sydney for me. It wasn't what we wanted.
"Then I was in Sydney with work a few weeks later and Tom Regan posted one for sale on Facebook. I sent him a message straight away and he called me back within 20 minutes. You could tell he was super passionate, even though he was Irish and it was an Australian car."
The consulting managing director paid a holding deposit, sent Ben a text message "are you interested in a trip to Dublin" and seven days later the XB was his.
The Falcon got to Ireland courtesy of three brothers from Western Australia in the hardtop fraternity. Ten years ago one had moved overseas and had a friend who came to Australia and fell in love with the hardtops.
Three vehicles were sent across to the UK, one was the John Goss Special.
"He didn't really understand what we had bought. He wasn't mechanically minded and no one knew how to repair them, so he had it for 12 months and never used it," Brock said.
"Tom bought it off him, that was 10 years ago. It was getting tired and in 2012 Tom did a bare metal restoration on it over there ... ordering parts from Australia."
With an expanding young family and needing a home renovation, Tom made the decision to sell the much-loved Falcon.
Brock and Tom are now good mates and he will come to Bathurst in November for the Hardtop Anniversary, which is an event dedicated to celebrating the famed one-two finish at Mount Panorama in 1977.
Originally launched with a 302 Cleveland V8 partnered to a four-speed transmission, Brock's John Goss Special has been upgraded to a 351 with a T5 shifter.
But after hearing of his efforts to bring the vehicle back to Australia, the Western Australian brothers got in touch, who still had the matching engine block in their shed.
After some negotiations, Brock bought the original matching block - but for now he's happy with the extra grunt.
"I have the block there, I can do that whenever I want," he said.
The Ford fascination began as a youngster for Brock. His father Kevin bought the '77 XC GS brand new in Tasmania.
Used as the family car and to tow the boat, it was motivated by a stock 4.9-litre V8 with a three-speed auto.
During Brock's teenage years, Kevin was thinking about selling.
"I was in grade 10 at the time and I said if you sell it I am leaving school to get a full-time job and I'm going to have it," Brock said.
To keep him in school, Kevin hung on to the car, and when Brock attended university his parents moved to Queensland in 2000, which was when dad handed over the keys.
"There I was, 20, and had the hardtop. It was all original and the first thing I did was unbolt the tow bar," Brock said.
It wasn't until more than a decade later the Falcon was given a street machine overhaul.
Taking more than two years and more bank withdrawals than Brock cares to count, the spectacular red hardtop called In Envy was born, with the initial inspiration coming from Howard Astill's Die Hard coupe, followed by Rob Zahabi's Kamaro.
Retaining the classic two-door shape, the hardtop was modernised and under the skin is a blown 351 Windsor, while the door handles, key locks, fuel filler and drip rails were shaved.
Sitting on 20- and 22-inch wheels, it has RideTech air struts, full custom interior with black leather and full digital gauges.
Tuned down, the XC GS produced 490horsepower (365kW) at the wheels, but it's capable of doing more than 800 (600kW).
Collectively, the XC GS is priceless, but engine parts alone are valued at more than $80,000.
"Someone could offer me $2million and I would say no. To many people that would seem crazy, but easily I would turn that down," he said.
"It all stemmed from growing up with that car.
"I love all old cars but I have an affinity with Ford. I have a Ford Ranger Wildtrack, Claire has a Ford Focus which has been kitted out and lowered."
Both hardtops will be on show at the ninth Total Performance Car Show, where more than 150 hot Fords will be on show.
AT A GLANCE
WHAT Pacific Ford's ninth Total Performance Car Show.
WHEN Sunday, August 13, from 9am-1.30pm.
WHERE Pacific Ford, 122-124 Sugar Rd, Maroochydore.
COST Free for both spectators and car entries.
DETAILS More than 150 cars, V8 Supercars driver Cameron Waters Q&A session at 11am, legendary car collector Dan Bowden at noon, there will be food and drinks available on-site.
Police believe Sam may have hidden the bodies of three people
CLAIRE got to experience a week in the RAAF.
Torture trial continues after house of horror claims.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Zahabi's Kamaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Regan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland V8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Bowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mustang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T) 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Mahoney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Goss Special</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RideTech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven82</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Goss</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Astill's Die Hard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock's John Goss Special</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Total Performance Car Show</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Ford's Total Performance Car Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst 1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XC GS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Focus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardtop Anniversary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Atkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford XB Falcon Hardtop John Goss Special</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Ranger Wildtrack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sugar Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Waters Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROCK</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Panorama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
