<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429798950352541</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/warrandyte-wonder-combines-contemporary-and-natural-design/news-story/b6b63c986f874af3cb7cd17a7de11174</url>
  <title>Warrandyte wonder combines contemporary and natural design - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, has price hopes of $1.8-$1.98 million.

SOAK in the bush vista from the comfort of the spa or kick back on the huge decked entertainment area of this stunning home.
Jellis Craig, Blackburn, agent Stephen Le Gat said the house at , was built about two years ago and was "virtually brand new".
RELATED:

Relax in style.

"It features Grampians stone and silvertop ash timber," Mr Le Gat said.
"It has that earthy inspiration but also this modern edge to it.
"The inspiration was to have a home with earthy elements that blends with it's natural environment."

There are plenty of leafy green trees.

Mr Le Gat said it was designed to allow a family to enjoy the space together, as well as separately in three wings: one for the parents, one for children and the main hub.
The house has an open-plan kitchen and living area that flows through sliding glass doors to the wide balcony.
The kitchen has a long, wide island bench that doubles as a breakfast bar, a combined freestanding oven and gas cooktop, a black sink and tapware, a mirrored glass splashback and a butler's pantry.

The kitchen is modern and sophisticated.

There are two other living areas, a study nook and a home office.
Two walk-in wardrobes, an ensuite and a full-height corner window are features of the main bedroom.
The minor bedrooms have built-in wardrobes and share the use of the main bathroom, which has a spa bath.

There is an easy flow from the indoors to the outdoors.

A big laundry with plenty of storage and bench space, and a powder room are also included.
Mr Le Gat said families looking to upgrade, as well as downsizers from bigger land parcels, were interested in the property.
The property, which has price hopes of $1.8-$1.98 million, is set to go under the hammer at 1pm, August 6.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Le Gat</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jellis Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grampian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Le Gat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrandyte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
