<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429923504405564</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/tom-dont-do-that-daniel-menzel-is-hopeful-teammate-tom-hawkins-will-avoid-suspension/news-story/a288428191a29d19348430292e6266ca</url>
  <title>'Tom, don't do that!' Big Cat treads fine line</title>
  <content>
DANIEL Menzel says he's hopeful teammate Tom Hawkins will avoid the scrutiny of the MRP and be available to play against Richmond next weekend.
Hawkins jumper punched Sydney defender Dane Rampe in the neck in the second quarter.
While the force was minimal and the power forward was not reported on the spot, Hawkins' poor record may come back to haunt him when the match is reviewed.
Hawkins was suspended in Round 11 for jumper punching Adelaide's Matt Crouch, and last season copped a one-week ban for a similar incident involving GWS skipper Phil Davis.
As a result, if Hawkins is cited he will certainly miss at least a week through suspension.
"You don't like seeing it and you think, 'Tom, don't do that' because we've seen guys go for little incidents that people don't think there's much in, but they're stamping down on it," Menzel said on Fox Footy's AFL Today.
"You'd hate to see him miss (a week) again with it, but at the same time I don't think there was that much in it.
"You just hope his prior record doesn't hurt him in this instance because it's not one of those ones where it was excessive force or could have caused injury."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Menzel watched his side's 46-point loss from the sidelines, as he manages his body heading into finals.
While he said he didn't subscribe to the theory that Geelong was lacking without the suspended Patrick Dangerfield, Menzel suggested he'd be a welcome inclusion next weekend.
"We all know how good Danger is and obviously a player is going to come in and replace him, but at the same time we knew that we had to cover him in a lot of different ways and we probably didn't last night," Menzel said.
"At the same time, our depth was tested with Joel (Selwood) getting injured.
"It was unfortunate for us that (Sydney) jumped us again and we couldn't quite contain them in the first quarter.
"When that happens you spend so much energy trying to get back on level terms and we just weren't able to do that. We went close in the last quarter but they blew it out in the end."
Menzel said he expected skipper Selwood to recover from his ankle injury for Saturday's blockbuster clash against Richmond at Simonds Stadium.
And he also threw his own hat in the ring.
"I'll certainly put my hand up to play next week and hopefully be back to play the Tigers," Menzel said.
The 25-year-old is uncontracted beyond this season, but suggested he was confident a deal would be struck with Geelong soon.
"My manager is speaking to the club about it at the moment," Menzel said.
"I'm very happy with the situation and playing with the Cats as well. I do (think I'll be at Geelong next year)."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Rampe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzel</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's Matt Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Menzel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkins</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL Today</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
