<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429923504405589</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/realestate/everything-entertainers-dream-of/news-story/f497160d28ef4ed48a529b749d98bbef</url>
  <title>Everything entertainers dream of</title>
  <content>
POLISHED floor tiles, crisp white interiors and striking pendant lighting create striking contemporary appeal in this premier Fannie Bay home.
Combine this with a spacious open plan living and dining area and an impressive high-end chef's kitchen - featuring Miele appliances, a wine fridge, butlers pantry and huge separate food pantry - and you have yourself a five-star residence.

Real Estate Central selling agent Sascha Smithett said this prestigious and modern tropical residence sat at the absolute top of its class, with stunning five-star interiors opening to elegant poolside alfresco living, designed with families and entertaining in mind.
"It is ideally set in one of Darwin's most exclusive coastal suburbs, walking distance to Fannie Bay Beach and the Parap Markets," she said.
An enormous carpeted media room downstairs offers a true home cinema experience, and a separate wet bar with floor to ceiling built-in glass cabinetry will impress any enthusiastic entertainer.
"The living and dining area features extra-high ceilings," Ms Smithett said.
"Doors also open to an elegant patio outdoor entertaining area with timber-panel ceiling and a large built-in alfresco kitchen that overlooks the in ground pool.
"Lush tropical gardens in the manicured luxury resort-style backyard add to the tropical feel."
Also downstairs is a fabulous outdoor Balinese-style bathroom with shower and circular stone freestanding bath accessible directly from the pool, a separate guest toilet and a private fourth bedroom with marble ensuite.
A striking split open timber staircase connects to the second level, where the presidential master bedroom joins the second and third bedrooms.
The stunning master suite features an immaculate polished timber floor, a huge walk-in robe with tropical garden view and an ultra-modern marble ensuite with twin vanities and enormous four head shower.
"The generous second and third bedrooms also feature timber floors, built in robes and garden views through large glass louvre windows, and a sleek freestanding bath stars in the chic main bathroom," she said. "The house has fibre optic for fast broadband and all bedrooms have access points for digital TV and Austar."
There's also a well-equipped internal laundry, under-stair storage and a double lockup garage with built-in storage.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parap Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balinese-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estate Central</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smithett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fannie Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fannie Bay Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sascha Smithett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
