<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429798950352635</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/what-weird-kitchen-appliance-can-you-not-live-without/</url>
  <title>What Weird Kitchen Appliance Can You Not Live Without?</title>
  <content>
Hello, and welcome to What's Cooking?, the open thread where you get to share all of your brilliant thoughts, advice, recipes and opinions on all things food-related. Today I want to know about your favourite odd but necessary kitchen tools, even if they are - gasp - .

Photo via Amazon.

In the world of kitchen appliances, there are the obvious workhorses - the items I can't (and shouldn't be expected to) live without. These include my , my giant wooden spoon, my cast iron pan and (shockingly) my  (all three of them). But then there are the surprise must-haves, the true heroes that I never saw coming. Then there is my .

This is a bad way to use this. Photo via Amazon.

Though it looks like a humble little spatula, this thing is so much more. On one end, you have a stiff, nylon scraper-spreader which - you guessed it - is very good at scraping and spreading. But it's the other end, the silicone scooper end, that is absolutely essential. Not only is it fantastic for cooking eggs, but it can get the last drop out of any jar, bottle, pan or bowl. It's also a very helpful plating tool, as nothing sticks to it. It's one of my favourite things, is what I'm saying.

So now I want to hear from you! Which weird kitchen tool stole your heart by surprise? Do you have any single-use appliances you refuse to give up? Is there a tool more useful than a big wooden spoon? Does anyone else out there have a collection of wooden spoons? Can we start a wooden spoon club?

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weird Kitchen Appliance Can You Not Live Without</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
