<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430142547739352</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/passenger-spotted-texting-about-molesting-kids/3209165/</url>
  <title>Passenger spotted texting about molesting kids</title>
  <content>
A NOSEY airline passenger was peeking at the SMS messaging of a man in the row in front of her. What she saw saved two children, and could send a man and woman to jail for a long time.

San Jose media is reporting the woman passenger had been able to read the SMS texts being exchanged by Michael Kellar on a flight from Seattle to San Jose International Airport earlier this week because he was angling it away from passengers sitting alongside, and was using an enlarged font.

What she saw prompted her to use her own smartphone to photograph the screen as evidence, and quietly alert cabin crew.

"In my eyes she is our hero," a San Jose police spokesman has said. She prevented a "catastrophic" and "horrific" attack.

San Jose Police say the aircrew notified the airport to have authorities ready to arrest the 56-year-old when the aircraft landed.

"The conversations were very particular in regards to sex acts that were to be performed on ... children," a San Jose police spokesman said, describing the text messages as "disturbing".

"Some of the sex acts talked about not only molesting children, but performing bestiality."

When confronted by police, Kellar dismissed the texts as a sexual fantasy game.

But investigators quickly used the texts and photos being exchanged to trace the suspect at the other end of the SMS exchange who was to allegedly carry out Kellar's sexual instructions.

Gail Burnworth, 50, of Tacoma, was arrested by FBI and Crimes Against Children Task Force officers.
Two children, aged five and seven, were found with her and quickly judged to be the victims of the planned sexual assault. They have been placed in protective custody.

Burnworth was a childcare provider, police said, and had "some type of dating relationship" with Kellar.

Kellar has been charged with two counts of attempted child molestation and two counts of solicitation of a sex crime. Burnworth has been charged with sexual exploitation of a minor, rape of a child in the first degree and dealing in sexually-explicit child imagery.

"If it wasn't for that young lady (passenger's) actions, another sexual assault would have occurred," a police spokesman said.

"It's kind of mind-blowing," San Jose sex-crimes Detective Nick Jourdenais added.

"She gets on a plane, a normal citizen minding her business. A couple of hours later, she's intervening on quite possibly the most traumatic thing children can go through. This was life-altering for them."

Major traffic incident as boat comes off trailer, causes carnage
Police believe Sam may have hidden the bodies of three people
CLAIRE got to experience a week in the RAAF.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Nick Jourdenais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Kellar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAN JOSE</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Burnworth, 50, of Tacoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellar</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Jose Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Jose International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnworth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimes Against Children Task Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
