<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429966454078840</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/domain/domain-news/location-canberra/auction-watch-jerrabomberra-lures-buyers-from-queanbeyan-region-and-canberra-20170805-gxpz7u.html</url>
  <title>Auction watch: Demand growing for Jerrabomberra homes</title>
  <content>
A refurbished Jerrabomberra home with views across the region and beyond was among Saturday's successful auctions.

A mixed bag of weather wasn't enough to deter prospective buyers from competing for the four-bedroom house at 10 Dennis Place.

Selling agent Larry Eckhoff, of Ian McNamee and Partners Real Estate Jerrabomberra, said a $750,000 bid kicked off the proceedings.

The renovated house boasts views across the region. Photo: Supplied

The bidding climbed quickly the $800,000-mark, before young couple of first home buyers from the area snapped up the property for $820,000.

Mr Eckhoff said house had been "beautifully refurbished". The cul-de-sac location was also a drawcard.

"It has magnificent views right through Jerrabomberra to Canberra," he said.

​Mr Eckhoff said Jerrabomberra and greater Queanbeyan continued to lure buyers across the ACT border.

He said the NSW government's new stamp duty concessions, which exempt first home buyers from paying stamp duty on new and existing properties up to $650,000, continued to draw first home buyers from Canberra.

"We're still getting a lot of ACT buyers coming over and buying now," he said.

"Jerrabomberra has been a popular area for a while but in the last six months it's getting more and more popular.

"You can't get enough properties in Jerrabomberra at the moment. Possibly, that might change once we get into September; there's certainly a few people holding off. There's definitely a shortage of homes at the moment."

While some sales have cracked the million-dollar mark, Mr Eckhoff said Jerrabomberra offered quality houses on big blocks at more affordable prices compared to the nation's capital."

More to come.

Quarterly house price report

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerrabomberra</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Eckhoff, of Ian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Partners Real Estate Jerrabomberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Eckhoff</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McNamee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
