<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429790360417857</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/north-west/families-snap-up-city-farms-as-historic-significance-deters-developers/news-story/ffa27bb5bfb9110ee813e16f428e525e</url>
  <title>Families snap up city farms as historic significance deters developers - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, includes the former Stevenson's Cheese Factory, built in the 1850s.

VICTORIA'S oldest known cheese factory has been picked up for a gouda result.
The vintage slice of history at , sold for $1.45 million.
The 6.35ha acreage which includes the 1850s bluestone remains of what was once Stevenson's Cheese Factory, was one of two city-fringe farms sold as residential abodes in the space of a few weeks.
With a heritage overlay from Hume City Council, the property, which also featured a three-bedroom weatherboard house, had been in the one family for 44 years.
Stockdale & Leggo Craigieburn sales agent Ricky Goodman said the factory's heritage overlay as well as the acreage's sloping block had deterred developers, and the property would become another family's garden of edam.
The new owners - a Glenroy family with several children - now plan to give the old factory a make over.

30 Farleigh Court, Mickleham, includes the bluestone remains of an 1850s cheese factory, as well as a three-bedroom weatherboard home.

RELATED:
"The new owner is a builder by trade and he plans to fully restore the cheese factory and make it a kids room or a man cave," Mr Goodman said.
"But I daresay he will eventually bulldoze the main house and build his dream home there."
And in Templestowe, another unique acreage with a long history attracted a "massive" number of inquiries before selling on July 14 for $2.5 million.
The tiny 1900s weatherboard cottage at  is believed to be the first farmhouse built in the suburb.
RELATED:

7 Watties Rd, Templestowe, features a 1900s two-bedroom farmhouse on a 1.37ha block.

One family has owned the 1.37ha property for 25 years.
Fletchers Manningham sales agent Steve Schumann said while the home had no heritage overlay, the area in the suburb's green belt did have a single dwelling covenant and the block couldn't be subdivided.
"I did get calls from developers who would have loved to built 100 townhouses there," he said.
"But they lost interest when I told them the details about the land."
Mr Schumann said a young family won the keys to the charming home.

7 Watties Rd, Templestowe, still offers plenty of charming features.

"The new owners had been looking around at other acreage blocks but they loved the peace and privacy of this property, and its outlook," Mr Schumann said.
"It has 180 degree north-facing views.
"And there is room for the kids to play.
"You do feel like you're in the middle of the country here - but you can still jump back into civilisation quickly."

The Templestowe farmhouse has 180 degree north-facing views.

SUBURB PROFILES: ,
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Schumann</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stevenson's Cheese Factory</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Goodman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Goodman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leggo Craigieburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mickleham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletchers Manningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Templestowe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watties Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Schumann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farleigh Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
