<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430099598066100</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/bma-miner-seriously-injured-at-site-investigation-/3209112/</url>
  <title>BMA miner seriously injured at site; investigation under way</title>
  <content>
UPDATE 11.30am: A BMA worker has been seriously injured at the Goonyella Riverside mine site on Saturday morning.

He is a husband and father of a 11-month-old baby boy and believed to be in surgery currently.

A BMA spokesman confirmed the incident.

Queensland Ambulance Service was called to the site about 1am on Saturday.

The 31-year-old man is believed to have sustained a head injury.

"BHP Billiton Mitsubishi Alliance (BMA) confirms that an incident occurred at Goonyellla Riverside Mine today, which resulted in a serious injury to one of our people," the spokesman said.

"Our highest priority at this stage is for the care of the individual involved in the incident.

"BMA is working closely with the relevant authorities on this incident."

The Daily Mercury understands that workers turning up for their shifts this morning didn't get past the gate, and were sent back to camp.

The injured worker was transported to Mackay Base Hospital.

Goonyella Riverside is an open cut mine that's about 30km north of Moranbah.

Mining began at Riverside in 1982.

INITIAL: A man is in a serious condition at the Mackay Base Hospital after sustaining a head injury at Goonyella Mine, Moranbah.

Queensland Ambulance was called to the scene at 1:05am on Saturday morning.

It was suggested that he was hit in the head with an object.

The man will later be transported to Townsville Hospital.

Major traffic incident as boat comes off trailer, causes carnage
Police believe Sam may have hidden the bodies of three people
CLAIRE got to experience a week in the RAAF.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Billiton Mitsubishi Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moranbah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goonyella Mine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goonyellla Riverside Mine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Mercury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goonyella Riverside</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Base Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
