<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430009403752168</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/southeast/southside-schools-shone-brightly-following-the-latest-release-of-naplan-data/news-story/919db63899233b20121d76178c9a278a</url>
  <title>Southside schools shine in NAPLAN</title>
  <content>
SOUTHSIDE school students have not been left behind following the release of data showing Queensland schools had improved most Australia-wide since NAPLAN the tests were introduced.
Robert Randall, the Chief Executive of the Australian Curriculum Assessment and Reporting Authority said on the 10th anniversary of the launch of NAPLAN, Queenslanders shone.
"The Year 5 and Year 9 students have out performed the national average in every strand of NAPLAN literacy and numeracy testing, with 20% of the top students above the national average,'' he said.
Mansfield State High School students were toward the top of the class when it came to Year 9 NAPLAN results.
Executive principal Karen Tanks .said the high Year 7 cohort had jumped to 12th in the state.
"There is absolutely something magical happening at our school and it is hard work from teachers and students and parents," Ms Tanks. said.
"We don't have scholarships and we don't select students.
"We are just an ordinary school doing extraordinary things."
Across the western side of the M3 school results also shone brightly where the MacGregor State School ranked in the top 10 in the state for Year 3 and 5.
Emphasising the improvement of local schools were results from Runcorn State High School.
While Runcorn will not appear on any top 10 state wide data merit lists, the improvements have been astonishing.
"Runcorn State High acting principal Ms Mel Harth said in writing the Year 7 cohert of 2015 had gone from 53 per cent for writing pieces to 89 per cent per cent now they are in Year 9.
"Our commitment to The Runcorn Way; High Expectations and Personalised Learning through individual student goal setting and tracking, and quality teaching have produced pleasing results and improvements,'' Ms Harth said.
Calamvale Community College principal Lisa Starmer said outstanding improvement in her school was a result of "hard work and dedication of the college students and staff''.
"The year 5 and year 9 students have out performed the national average in every strand of NAPLAN literacy and numeracy testing, with 20% of the top students above the national average,'' she said.
St Thomas More principal Les Conroy acknowledged improvement. "Our results across the year 7 and 9 students are well above the state mean in all areas, including both male and female results,'' he said.
Robert Randall, the Chief Executive of the Australian Curriculum Assessment and Reporting Authority praised Queensland teachers and parents for their education efforts.
"We should quite rightly acknowledge the efforts of teachers, and school principals and mums and dads who've been behind all that improvement," Mr Randall said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>M3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mel Harth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Runcorn Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Executive of the Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 9 NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mansfield State High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Randall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 9</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Harth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MacGregor State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Tanks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Conroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia-wide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Personalised Learning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Runcorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reporting Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curriculum Assessment</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Randall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calamvale Community College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Runcorn State High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Thomas More</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Runcorn State High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Tanks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Starmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
