<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430782497871673</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/mission-accomplished-for-buyers-searching-for-the-perfect-property/news-story/a47e58ffba7806d0508467c0794d36de</url>
  <title>Mission accomplished for buyers searching for the perfect property - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
14 Caesar Court, Sunnybank Hills.

The new owners of this Sunnybank Hills home were on a mission to find a home with enough space for their daughter's grand piano. And they found it.
The four-bedroom, two-bathroom home at  sold at auction for $949,000.
Allen & Lee selling agent Mark Allen said there were seven registered bidders, including one as far as South Australia bidding on the phone.

14 Caesar Court, Sunnybank Hills.

Mr Allen said the property sold to a local family in front of a crowd of about 40 people.
"The owners had lived here for 31 years. They bought the land and built the home," he said.
"The home was so well presented, that was the drawcard.
"It's like the Botanic Gardens as far as the landscape goes."

Check out the gardens at 14 Caesar Court, Sunnybank Hills.

Mr Allen said the new owners had a daughter who was a great pianist, and needed space for a grand piano.
The property, on a 944sq m block, features a swimming pool and insulated pergola.
It is close to all amenities.

19 Wolsey Parade, Wynnum.

The new owners of this beautiful Queenslander at Wynnum searched for a new home for a long time, and the wait was well worth it.
They bought this four-bedroom, two-bathroom home at 1 for $1.3 million.
Belle Property selling agent David Lazarus said the starting bid was $1.24 million.

19 Wolsey Parade, Wynnum.

He said a crowd of about 50 people attended the auction and there were four registered bidders.
With panoramic views of Moreton Bay, the property on a 600sq m block, is just moments from Manly Harbour Village and the Wynnum CBD.

28 Hawthorn Terrace, Red Hill.

A three-bedroom, two-bathroom home at sold at auction for $977,000.
In front of a crowd of 70 people, 15 registered bidders showed a keen interest in the character home.
With four active bidders on site, a single woman from Melbourne who is retiring, bought the property.
She has plans to be closer to her family.

15 registered bidders were keen to call 28 Hawthorn Terrace, Red Hill home.

Place - Newmarket selling agent Ashley Horswill said: "We've seen huge interest throughout the campaign as opportunities like this rarely come on the market in Red Hill".
"This blue chip suburb continues to thrive with prospective buyers wanting a piece of the inner-city lifestyle," Mr Horswill said.

28 Hawthorn Terrace, Red Hill.

The property features VJ walls, soaring ceilings, French doors, sash windows, and richly hued polished timber floors throughout.

23 Chester St, Highgate Hill.

A 405sq m block of land at sold for $780,000 under the hammer on Saturday.
SPACE Property Agents - South Brisbane selling agent Angus Commins said the land was in a secluded cul-de-sac, adjacent to the Brisbane River and University of Queensland and snapped up by a cash buyer.
Mr Commins said there was only one registered bidder at the auction, but plenty of post auction interest.

11 Fassifern St, Durack.

A, built by the seller 35 years ago, sold under the hammer for $476,000.
Situated in a quiet, leafy and child-friendly cul-de-sac, this solid flood free brick and tile home was marketed as being perfect for first home buyers, families and renovators.

11 Fassifern St, Durack.

Ray White - Sherwood selling agent Kris Matthews said there were eight registered bidders keen on the four-bedroom, three-bathroom home.
The property is on a 907sq m block.

15 Attwood Way, Goodna.

This three-bedroom, two-bathroom home atfetched $312,000 at auction.
Ray White Auctioneer Phil Parker said there were eight registered bidders on site.
Ray White selling agent Jon Townend marketed the property as having security screens, ample storage and a large internal laundry.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>VJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunnybank Hills</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolsey Parade</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Commins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botanic Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Horswill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Townend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Durack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Harbour Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belle Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wynnum</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Auctioneer Phil Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Allen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wynnum CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Agents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newmarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highgate Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fassifern St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Horswill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Lazarus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn Terrace</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angus Commins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caesar Court</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwood Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
