<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429837605058679</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4829984/wheres-russell-police-appeal-to-find-missing-illawarra-man/?cs=298</url>
  <title>Where's Russell? Police appeal to find missing Illawarra man</title>
  <content>
WHERE ARE YOU?: Police are appealing for information, as part of Missing Persons Week, to find missing Kiama man Russell Wilson, 46. He was last seen on January 11.

Police have renewed public appeals to find a number of people who have disappeared from the Illawarra and Southern Highlands. 
This week - July 30 to August 5 - marks National Missing Persons Week, with investigators using the period to highlight individual cases and raise awareness.
Russell Wilson, who was last seen at his unit on Manning Street, Kiama, is among the thousands of people across the country who have been reported missing.

No one has seen Mr Wilson, 46, since January 11 and he doesn't carry a mobile phone.

Inquiries suggest Mr Wilson travels for long periods of time. However, concerns are held for his welfare given the prolonged period of time without contact.
Mr Wilson has been described as being of Caucasian in appearance, 187 centimetres tall, medium build, with dark brown short hair, a bushy beard and blue eyes.

SEARCH: Bowral woman Kathleen Lidden was last seen leaving her home on June 13. She hasn't been seen or heard from since, despite an extensive search in the area.
In a more recent case, police have reissued an appeal to find missing Bowral woman Kathleen Lidden. 
Mrs Lidden, 52, was reported missing by her family on June 13 after leaving her Gibraltar Road home on foot and failing to return.
Read more: 
She was spotted on the same day in Mittagong, where she was captured on CCTV. An extensive, multi-agency search around Mount Gibraltar, Lake Alexandra and the Mittagong CBD followed the sighting.

Mrs Lidden is described as being of Caucasian appearance, about 162 centimetres tall, of slim build, with short brown hair.
She was last seen wearing a cream-coloured fleece jumper, think grey tracksuit pants, white joggers, a white scarf and had a brown backpack/satchel.
This year's National Missing Persons Week campaign is themed 'Still waiting for you to come home'.

The campaign is aimed at highlighting the high number of young people who are reported missing to police each year and the impact it has on their family and friends..
"For families of missing persons, not knowing if their loved one is safe is a traumatic experience that never goes away," Acting Superintendent of the NSW Police Missing Persons Unit, Commander Kristy Walters said.

Also included on the missing persons register are Toni Cavanagh and Kay Docherty, then aged 16 and 15 respectively, who vanished from near a bus stop outside the Warilla Grove shopping centre in July 1979.

Cheryl Grimmer, who disappeared from Fairy Meadow beach in January 1970, is also on the list, as is Brendan Crinis, now aged 33, who has been missing since he left his house in the Wollongong area in September 2002.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mittagong CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Lidden, 52</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Lidden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Alexandra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 11</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manning Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Crinis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Missing Persons Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Missing Person Week</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent of the NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni Cavanagh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairy Meadow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2002</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowral</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathleen Lidden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gibraltar Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missing Persons Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mittagong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caucasians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Gibraltar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 13</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1970</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warilla Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1979</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheryl Grimmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay Docherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristy Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Highlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
