<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430696598525140</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/manly-sea-eagles-centre-dylan-walker-hopes-to-mark-milestone-with-a-win-20170805-gxq14w.html</url>
  <title>Manly's Walker hopes to mark milestone with a win</title>
  <content>
Dylan Walker is hoping his 100th NRL appearance will be one worth celebrating.
The premiership-winning centre is part of a Manly side that is in danger of undoing all of its good early season work if it crashes to a third-straight loss to the Roosters. Sunday's match shapes as a potentially season-defining one: win and their hopes of a top-four finish remain alive; lose and risk falling out of the top eight just as the finals near.Photo: AAP
It has been a week of introspection at Brookvale. The Sea Eagles have conceded 92 points in their past two games, an alarming figure as they come up against one of the premiership heavyweights. There have been a series of honesty sessions before Sunday's encounter in an attempt to reverse the trend.
"Obviously you have to talk about it, that's one thing," Walker said.
"It's about us having a chat and staying together. We can't sugar-coat these moments. It's a professional sport and everyone wants to be in the finals. We've got to address it pretty quickly and be totally honest with each other.
"It shouldn't be too hard at all. We'll have a bit of a chat, a bit of a talk and we should fire in no time."

Manly have surprised everyone but themselves so far this season. They sit in seventh spot on the ladder, a much loftier position than most pundits predicted. One of the big scalps they jagged along the way was the Roosters, who they upset in round five. It is a result they will take confidence from before Sunday's rematch.
"You definitely do - we know that we can match it with a benchmark side like that if we put a performance in," said fullback Tom Trbojevic.
"But then again, it's been a long time since we played them, so we will have to be a lot better this week.
"It would be massively disappointing [to miss the finals from here]. We're hoping not to do that and there's no better way to turn the last two weeks around than to beat the Roosters at home.
"You want to play finals footy, that's the main motivator for me now."
The Sea Eagles need not look far for inspiration. The reigning premiers, Cronulla, had a similar hiccup about 12 months ago but ended up going on a run that ultimately took them to their maiden title.
"The big thing is getting on a run of form and momentum running into the finals," said pivot Blake Green.
"We saw Cronulla do it last year, they won three or four in a row and were flying. It can be done. They did it from inside the four, but they were still able to do it. Anything is possible.
"We haven't even got ourselves there yet and the next five weeks will shape our season as to whether it's successful or not successful."
The Roosters are in ominous form. They have beaten North Queensland, Newcastle and South Sydney following their shellacking at the hands of Cronulla in round 17 to climb into second position on the ladder.
Rather than being daunted by the assignment, the Sea Eagles are welcoming the opportunity to test themselves against a form side.
"That's the best part of it," Walker said.
"They are one of the top teams of the year and for us to go up against them after two hard losses, we've really got to show some character as a collective group.
"We'll find out what we're made of."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly's Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Trbojevic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brookvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
