<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430825447544968</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/police-say-no-known-threat-to-queensland-despite-increased-security-at-ekka-20170805-gxq0l6.html</url>
  <title>Ekka 2017: Increased security, more police, periodic bag checks</title>
  <content>
The security is being ramped up for this year's Royal Queensland Show, with more security guards and police officers, expanded CCTV coverage, barriers at entrance gates and periodic bag checks.
While the National Terrorism Threat Level remained at probable, the Queensland Police Service were quick to reassure Queensland that there was no known specific threat to the state.Photo: Bradley Kanaris
However, based on QPS advice, the Royal National Agricultural & Industrial Association (RNA) has decided to bolster security for the show, which begins next Friday.
"Each year the RNA works closely with the Queensland Police Service (QPS) to review our security measures for the Ekka," RNA chief executive Brendan Christou said.
"Our measures include increased security and police personnel on grounds, expanded CCTV, barrier measures at all gates and spot bag checks at gates at undisclosed times. Spot bag checks are a measure the RNA has always reserved the right to do.
"These are just some of a full range of security measures in place which, for obvious reasons, we cannot fully disclose.

"We have always had a large contingent of police and emergency services on grounds throughout the 10 days of show with a fully operational 24-hour emergency centre."
An RNA spokesperson would not comment whether the barriers at the gates were designed to prevent vehicles or people from entering the showgrounds, but did say the bag checks would be conducted "at all gates at different times".

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Police reassured the public that they were ready for the event, but encouraged patrons to remain vigilant.
"Queenslanders can rest assured that the QPS is continuously monitoring world events and has the capacity to quickly adapt to a changing security environment if necessary.
"Anyone who sees anything suspicious should contact the National Security Hotline on 1800 123 400, Policelink on 131 444 or Triple Zero (000) in an emergency."
.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal National Agricultural</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Terrorism Threat Level</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Policelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Queensland Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple Zero (000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QPS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RNA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Kanaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Industrial Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security Hotline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Christou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
