<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430782497871676</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/the-mail-waller-has-his-eye-on-a-spring-cups-with-lightlyraced-sayed-20170805-gxq10d.html</url>
  <title>The mail: Waller has his eye on a spring cups trail with Sayed</title>
  <content>
Chris Waller has his eye on a spring cups trail - perhaps culminating with The Metropolitan - after Sayed crushed his rivals to make it back-to-back wins since switching to Sydney. The lightly raced stayer ambled home under Kerrin McEvoy by more than five lengths from Get On The Grange to win the Randwick 2400-metre race on Saturday, with Waller quickly refuting it wouldn't be until 2018 that  Sayed  produced his best. "I wouldn't necessarily think so," Waller said. "He's a mature horse now and this is the time to get in with those up-and-coming horses with a light weight in your Newcastle and Wyong cups. He could come back here next year with top weight in a Wyong or Newcastle Cup. I love a horse like him with confidence. It's a big thing."
No rest for BowmanPhoto: AAP
Hugh Bowman jumped off the plane and headed straight to Rosehill to partner Winx in a track gallop after trekking the Kokoda Trail in less than four days to raise money for the National Jockeys Trust and Mark Hughes Foundation. Corey Brown and Kathy O'Hara both rode at Randwick on Saturday while the suspended Bowman had an earlier appointment with the queen of the Australian turf before her second barrier trial on Tuesday. "Hughie rode her this morning straight off the plane from [Papua] New Guinea and he said she's in exactly the right spot," Chris Waller said. "She's come up terrific and she's exactly where we need her to be. I don't think she'll need [a hard hitout before she races], she's picture perfect."
Martin 'one of the smartest trainers'
Adam Hyeronimus rated Tim Martin as one of the best in Sydney after his relationship with the canny Rosehill trainer  continued to flourish at Randwick. Hyeronimus whisked King Darci into a stalking position and gunned down Imperator Augustus to win the third. Asked about the keys to their blossoming association, Hyeronimus said: "Communication. He trusts me and I respect him. He has to be one of the smartest trainers I've ridden for. I've been working [King Darci] all campaign and he's slowly been getting there. It was good as the leader bowled along at a good tempo and I was able to relax."
Care needed: Angland

Tye Angland's blessing of Care To Think came with a caveat for trainer Matt Dunn not to push the smart four-year-old too much further this campaign. The odds-on favourite mowed down his rivals from near the tail of the field to continue Dunn's Highway juggernaut, notching an 11th win in the country-only concept. "He didn't relax great in the run and I was trying to hold onto him for as long as I could, but I had Corey's horse [Assurity] stopping in front of me," Angland said. "We got going early. He's a nice horse, but I wouldn't want to push him too far because he'll go from winning like this to finishing way back in the field. He's a horse that has plenty of improvement [though]." Dunn was celebrating his wedding anniversary with wife Keira, who travelled with the horse to Sydney and was full of praise for Angland as he got the best out of the horse, which wandered off his line late in the race.
Steyne cruises
Punters left the money in bags around Australia when Steyne was the best-backed runner country-wide a fortnight ago, but they didn't miss a second time when  Peter and Paul Snowden's lightly raced five-year-old cruised to victory in the sixth at Randwick. Last season's champion apprentice Andrew Adkins parked Steyne in the perfect spot and pounced to easily hold off Admiral Jello and Gold Ambition. "He's a momentum horse and he just didn't get it the other day and you could make a real argument to say he should be unbeaten as he's had genuine excuses in every race he's been beaten," Paul Snowden said.
Lees in good form
Kris Lees started the new season in the same rich vein of form he finished the last when Wahng Wah rounded up her rivals in the  second after being on trial at 1800 metres. The backmarker finished hard  under in-form apprentice Rachel King to beat Miss Dubois and the Newcastle-based Lees is intent on using King's dwindling claim as much as he can. "[Wahng Wah]  was produced at the right time and she's riding so well [is] Rachel," Lees said. "It was a good effort. She's been a run-on type and she's certainly matured. She didn't come up at all last preparation and she's put a few wins on the board this campaign. It was mares company so it was the right type of race for her."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sayed</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care To Think</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Dubois</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyeronimus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle-based Lees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waller</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosehill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunn's Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy O'Hara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Waller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Jockeys Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BowmanPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wahng Wah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Ambition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Guinea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokoda Trail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steyne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Hughes Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Darci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tye Angland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Get On</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Hyeronimus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Snowden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Admiral Jello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Lees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperator Augustus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Adkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assurity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
