<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430825447544988</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829897/tales-of-riding-the-endless-wave/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Tales of riding the endless wave</title>
  <content>
Jarratt and MR: . . . I watched in amazement as a small kid carved huge backhand turns all the way down the point.

A few years ago Phil Jarratt pitched a memoir about his life-long surfing addiction to one of his publishers.
It was hardly an ego over-reach. For four decades the surfer-author had been as close to the eye of the surfing biosphere as anyone. He'd churned out more than 30 books, many about his passion for wave-riding and everything that went with it. He'd been at or around every turn of the surfing tale - in and out of the water - and had written about them in an easy, fearless style that made anything appearing under his byline a must-read. He'd surfed and clubbed with the elite, ghosted their biographies, edited magazines, produced documentaries, won Australian Surfing Hall of Fame's media award four times, moonlighted as a surfing industry suit and penned sharp accounts of the experience. Oh, yeah, and he'd surfed most places on wave-riding's world map.
Who better to write a surfing memoir?
The publishing house said no.
That might have been the end of it, but for an odd blip on the other side of the globe. In 2015, New Yorker writer William Finnegan released Barbarian Days, his acutely personal account of a wave-riding life. It generated great reviews and booming sales. Apparently, readers had an appetite for the surfing yarn. The Jarratt pitch was back in play.
Life of Brine - a Surfer's Journey is out and I have to declare an interest: don't expect an unbiased review here - I've been a mate of Jarratt's for 40 years and, before that, was already a follower of his work. He had it - the writer's gift of making the difficult look effortless.
We met in 1972 when he'd bailed out of the Sydney Morning Herald and Canberra's parliamentary press gallery to get back to the coast via a writing job on the Newcastle Morning Herald. It was his second stretch in the port city and by then he had figured that, beneath the industrial crud, Newcastle held its own charms: a watering hole on every other corner, a nurses' home full of young ladies, and, at the top end of town, waves.
We shared a flat near the Channel 3 studios. He had few possessions: a salt-ravaged VW Beetle; a portable typewriter; a seven-two pintail and a couple of records - Daddy Cool's Sex, Dope, Rock 'n' Roll- Teenage Heaven, and Dory Previn's post-breakdown On My Way to Where. The vinyl stash was a tip-off - this bloke was not entirely conformist. Back then, regional journalists aspired to metropolitan papers like the SMH. Yet, here was a writer heading the other way - stepping from the city to the provinces. For what? Surf, was my best guess. As a goofy-footer he gravitated to Nobbys Bank and Newcastle Point.
Foreign places called. In pre-digital 1973, back-packing offered room for reading. We thumbed Tom Wolfe, Hunter S. Thompson, the gonzo pioneers. And the great travel writers: Kerouac on the road, Hemingway on blood and booze, Graham Greene on life at the margins, Christopher Isherwood on identity, Laurie Lee on dancing to your own rhythm. On the eve of running with the bulls in Basque country, James A. Michener's profile of the wild Irish-American bar-owner and bull-runner Matt Carney offered inspiration.
Reflecting on those seminal times while reading Life of Brine, it occurs that the road and selected readings rubbed off on Jarratt's passage to full-blown writer.  Forty years on, while his life story presents as three journeys in one - writer, surfer, man - it's also a travel yarn of vast sweep, wild colour and rough landings. That first backpacking foray as a 22-year-old was just the beginning. Since then, the author has logged more frequent flyer miles than the space shuttle crew and holed up in a hundred exotic locales from the Mentawis to Morocco, south-west France to the Seagull Inn, Mendocino, California.
NO FILTERS

The inner journey is equally momentous. Like many of his literary and surfing influences (except the abstemious Michener) Jarratt has, to put it mildly, dabbled a bit in drink and drugs. They fuelled his party urge, fired his imagination, took him deep inside his subject matter, and infused his words with street-wise audacity. And, sometimes, they made him tired and cranky. In Brine, he covers this with a brutal honesty laced with a lethal dose of self-deprecation.
"We seemed to have no filters," he confesses.
In the years we worked together I grew used to the sight of him, nursing a ferocious hangover, brow furrowed in concentration as he bashed another raft of purple prose out of a punch-drunk keyboard.
Like those who hang deepest in the barrel, not everybody comes out the other side. Jarratt wonders how, as a husband and father, and now a grandfather, he made it.
That said, his account of sharing a coke-fuelled San Francisco breakfast with the gonzo king Hunter S. Thompson at 10 o'clock at night is priceless.   
Luckily, he has been blessed with two great anchors in his life. Surfing would rescue and restore him. His family, especially his resilient and ever-wise wife Jackie, would reclaim him. And that in itself is a miracle. As he recalls about their early romance: "Her friends had warned her off me as a self-obsessed womaniser."

Fins and spins: Life of Brine, by Phil Jarratt, is published by HardieGrant Books. It retails for $29.95 and is in book stores this week.
By now you've guessed this yarn isn't all foam and bubble. There's loss, in its cruelest guise, causing the wise-arse writer to examine anew what it is we value most.
But in the main, there are people, and Jarratt is at his best writing about the individuals who found their way to his end of the bar.

Rogues, ratbags, surfers from every era (Kahanamoku to Kelly), musos, pollies (Keating, Rudd, Abbott, Turnbull, Goss, Carr), humanitarians, tarts and tycoons. The list of surfing royalty is too long to run here, but sample his account on paddling out two days before the historic first Stubbies contest marked the dawn of the professional era:

Sweet times: Newcastle Beach in the 1970s.
"As I paddle around to the Cove, let me describe the first wave I see. Midget Farrelly and Terry Fitzgerald take off together and share the first section. Michael Ho drops in on his five-four, works it for a while and flicks off. Shaun Thomson takes the inside section and disappears inside, leaving the rest to Reno Abellira and Col Smith. That was just one wave!"
Like a water-colour wash on canvas, surfing sets the backdrop for his storytelling. A cavalcade of characters crams the foreground. Across the middle drifts the temper of the times: Vietnam, conscription, apartheid, The Dismissal, sexual revolution, rock 'n' roll, counter culture, headlong hedonism, wars on drugs and terror, environmental awareness, 9/11, aboriginal rights, the rise and decline of the international surfing industry and the inevitable clench of mortality. Yes, Brine is a helluva ride, a helluva read.
A couple of years ago my old mate Phil had a heart attack while surfing. He recovered, but it reminded him that everything is finite. We get only so many turns at what we love most. It makes us cherish it all the more.
"Most of all now," a post-coronary Jarratt concludes, "I treasure every moment in the ocean. . . . My surf sessions get shorter and recovery takes longer, but as long as the passion remains, every day you catch a wave is a good one."
Rogues, ratbags, surfers from every era (Kahanamoku to Kelly), musos, pollies (Keating, Rudd, Abbott, Turnbull, Goss, Carr), humanitarians, tarts and tycoons.
The list of surfing royalty is too long to run here, but sample his account on paddling out two days before the historic first Stubbies contest marked the dawn of the professional era:
"As I paddle around to the Cove, let me describe the first wave I see. Midget Farrelly and Terry Fitzgerald take off together and share the first section. Michael Ho drops in on his five-four, works it for a while and flicks off. Shaun Thomson takes the inside section and disappears inside, leaving the rest to Reno Abellira and Col Smith. That was just one wave!"
Like a water-colour wash on canvas, surfing sets the backdrop for his storytelling. A cavalcade of characters crams the foreground. Across the middle drifts the temper of the times: Vietnam, conscription, apartheid, The Dismissal, sexual revolution, rock 'n' roll, counter culture, headlong hedonism, wars on drugs and terror, environmental awareness, 9/11, aboriginal rights, the rise and decline of the international surfing industry and the inevitable clench of mortality. Yes, Brine is a helluva ride, a helluva read.
A couple of years ago my old mate Phil had a heart attack while surfing. He recovered, but it reminded him that everything is finite. We get only so many turns at what we love most. It makes us cherish it all the more.
"Most of all now," a post-coronary Jarratt concludes, "I treasure every moment in the ocean. . . . My surf sessions get shorter and recovery takes longer, but as long as the passion remains, every day you catch a wave is a good one."

Master of words: Phil Jarratt with one of his earlier books.
EXCERPTS FROM LIFE OF BRINE

In his new book, Jarratt's recollections of Newcastle are sharp and poignant. Here are a few excerpts highlighting his period in the city.
He was sent to Newcastle for a  term as an assistant to the  Sydney Morning Herald's correspondent Brian Cogan in the spring of 1970. His first impression:
"The Newcastle posting came with accommodation of sorts, a grimy flat attached to a house in the backblocks of East Newcastle. It had one proper bedroom with another room, not much bigger than a broom closet, that might have been an office or surfboard storage, but for the fact that it was already occupied by a former Herald cadet who had struck a deal with the previous incumbent. He offered me eight bucks a week rent so I let him stay, well ahead of the game now.
"What the company flat lacked in comfort, it made up for in convenience. It was a short walk to four surf spots between Nobby's, at the mouth of the Hunter River, and the south end of Newcastle's main beach; about the same distance to the office, the courthouse, the cop shop, the Masonic Club, and the Great Northern Grill and Cafe Continental,  where Cogan was keen on a waitress and thus where we often ate."
MEETING MR

Jarratt writes on about his social life in Newcastle, eventually reaching this descriptive passage:

Best of times: Downtown Newcastle in the 1970s.
"I developed an affection for Newcastle, in part because it was a place where you could live a louche inner-city lifestyle and still surf every day. I surfed wherever there were waves, but I really enjoyed the left-breaking point at the north end of the main beach. It wasn't particularly consistent, but on its day it offered fast inside sections across scattered outcrops of rock.
"It was here one morning that I watched in amazement as a small kid carved huge backhand turns all the way down the point, flapping his arms around and cutting deftly under soupy sections. He finished his ride with a big roundhouse cutback before plopping into the deeper water, almost on top of me.
"'Hey, nice wave,' I said. He said thanks, but looked like he might cry, and paddled faster to get away from the creepy older guy. This was my first encounter with Mark Richards, a decade away from establishing himself as the greatest surfer of his generation."
TREACHERY RUNS

After being reassigned to Canberra, Jarratt returned in Newcastle in 1972, and once again teamed up with Jameson and another Herald employee, Tony Dickson. In the book, he recalls their exploits: 
"Within days of returning to Newcastle, I had moved into a share flat at Cooks Hill with Neil Jameson, a cadet journalist on the paper who shared my love of surfing, a cold beer and a good laugh.
"Tony Dickson, who worked in the front office, was also a keen surfer, and since we all worked mostly in the afternoons, we started making pre-dawn runs up the coast to Treachery Head when conditions were right. 
"That summer and into the autumn we enjoyed many days of beautiful waves with few, if any surfers in the water.
"Treachery was at least a 90-minute run each way, but Tony was a kick-arse driver, and Jamo and I would sometimes sleep all the way home, showing up for work refreshed, although often dripping saltwater from deep in our nasal cavities."

Life of Brine - A Surfer's Journey by Phil Jarratt (Hardie Grant Books) RRP: $29.99.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Jameson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teenage Heaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cove</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seagull Inn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarratt</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbarian Days</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dory Previn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HardieGrant Books</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mendocino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooks Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mentawis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Carney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VW Beetle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Isherwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ho</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morocco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James A. Michener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Cogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jameson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfer's Journey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardie Grant Books</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keating</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nobbys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Wolfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Morning Herald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter S. Thompson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goss</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hemingway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treachery Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reno Abellira</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cafe Continental</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kahanamoku</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farrelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Dickson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerouac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Thomson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Col Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life of Brine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masonic Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Morning Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Northern Grill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downtown Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Finnegan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Surfing Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daddy Cool's Sex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Jarratt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nobbys Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
