<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430610699178441</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/killer-whale-research-tasmania/8777668</url>
  <title>Killer whales: New research hopes to shed light on elusive predators</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Killer whales, or orcas, are fast, fearsome predators, but comparatively little is known about the species.
While from the wholesale slaughter of previous centuries, it is not clear how killer whales numbers are tracking, PhD student Ben Sellers told ABC Hobart.
"Killer whales are listed on the International Union for the Conservation of Nature (IUCN) Red List as 'data deficient' so we have no idea how many there are worldwide, or even their population at the moment," he said.
Where killer whales travel and what they eat matters, because as an 'apex predator', one at the top of the food chain, they can have a strong influence on marine system and biodiversity.
"If we can be informed as to what they are eating, we can look at conflict issues, so if we eat the same things they eat, those sorts of things, plus it gives us an idea of where they go.
"They tend to pinch fish off fishing boats, I work a little bit with (a commercial fishing operator) so I've been out on their vessel, and had a look at the killer whales depredating the long lines.
"They tend to take blue eye fish, they're an expensive, oily fish we like to eat, and killer whales like to eat them too.
"They're quite selective, they'll leave fish like ling on the line, but they'll take blue eye off, so it's really interesting that they can tell the difference between high quality fish and low quality fish.
"And they're really careful too, they pull the fish of real gently, they don't hit the gear or anything like that.
"[Killer whales] are hard to see, they're free-ranging marine mammals and so they spend 90 per cent of their time under water and they also don't take prey on the surface very much, so any interactions you're likely to see are very rare so they'll take prey mostly underwater, fish, other marine mammals  and they're quite elusive."
Citizen scientists taking photos of killer whales around Australia are helping with Mr Sellers' research, as images of fins are compared in a database to help identify individual whales.

Mr Sellers takes biopsy samples of the known whales to study their diets.
"Specifically I use a chemical technique called signature fatty acid analysis where we take small biopsies from killer whales and we look at the percentage of fatty acids in the tissue and it tells us what they've been eating over a period of time," he said.
The not-for-profit group Killer Whales Australia helped track a pod down the east coast of Tasmania, until Mr Sellers could locate them by boat off Eaglehawk Neck.
"In this instance we just got photo IDs and what we aim to do is biopsy the animals. There was a calf in this pod, so we wouldn't biopsy, if there's no calves present, then we will look at deploying a dart and taking a small tissue biopsy from the animal and then analysing that, matching it to a fin ID in the catalogue and then we have an idea of what that animal eats," he said.
Mr Sellers aims use satellite tagging this summer and get more samples from killer whales in Western Australia, as well as examine French sub-antarctic samples before completing his PhD.
"So we will probably write up two or three research papers on their diet and range, and from that work with fisheries too and advise them about what we've found," he said.
Earlier this month a rare audio recording of killer whales in the wild was captured off Tasmania's south east, and Mr Sellers said despite years of studying the species it was the first time he had heard it.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eaglehawk Neck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red List</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IUCN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Sellers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PhD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sellers</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Killer Whales Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservation of Nature</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
