<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430614994145837</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/national/labor-backs-indigenous-referendum-at-the-garma-festival/news-story/8c14da632d54f932d4ff6dc9a4ab5b68</url>
  <title>PM won't back referendum but Labor will</title>
  <content>
BILL Shorten has backed a referendum question on an indigenous voice to parliament, but the prime minister has failed to commit bipartisan support, warning that Australians are "constitutionally conservative".
During a speech at the Garma Festival in northeast Arnhem Land, Mr Shorten pledged Labor's support for a constitutionally-enshrined Aboriginal advisory body.
"We support a declaration by all parliaments, we support a truth telling commission, we are not confronted by the notion of treaties with our First Australians," the opposition leader said.
Malcolm Turnbull acknowledged many Aboriginal leaders were disappointed the government didn't give "instant fulfilment" to the Referendum Council's recommendations.
Mr Turnbull said he was respecting the council's report by giving it careful consideration and called for collaboration to develop a winnable referendum question to put to Australian voters.
"This cannot be a take it or leave it proposal ... an all or nothing approach, sometimes results in nothing," he said on Saturday.
Prominent Aboriginal Australian Noel Pearson on Friday delivered a scathing assessment of the "miserable" political leadership shown by Mr Turnbull and Mr Shorten towards constitutional reform.
Many senior Aboriginal figures had hoped for a bipartisan commitment to an indigenous advisory body referendum question at the four-day event on Gove Peninsula in the Northern Territory.
But Mr Pearson echoed the bitter disappointment of Referendum Co-chair Pat Anderson, who slammed the "empty platitudes" offered by both politicians as gutless.
"It is such a miserable scene, the leadership scene in Australia," Mr Pearson said.
"Political cycles come and go, but this agenda will never go away." Mr Shorten called for a joint parliamentary select committee to finalise a question to put to voters, but Ms Anderson said indigenous Australians needed another expert panel "like a hole in the head".
She said Mr Turnbull, who delivered some of his opening ceremony speech in Yolgnu Matha language, had been disrespectful to land rights champion Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu, who stressed the urgent need to resolve unfinished business of reconciliation and self-determination.
"We live side-by-side, but we're not yet united," Dr Yunupingu said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Co-chair Pat Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolgnu Matha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gove Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal Australian Noel Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
