<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430619289113174</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/i-felt-very-helpless-residents-shocked-by-fatal-cr/3209174/</url>
  <title>'I felt very helpless': Residents shocked by fatal crash</title>
  <content>
NEARBY residents have described their shock after tragedy struck a social motorbike ride in the Sunshine Coast hinterland today.
Palmwoods man Lee Vieritz was at home in his Hunchy Rd property, watching a movie when his mum yelled out to him that a motorcycle rider had gone down, just before midday.
He said he went running outside to find the rider off his bike in the middle of the road, about 20m from his motorcycle.
"I felt very helpless, I couldn't really do anything, I didn't even have my phone on me to ring triple-0," Mr Vieritz said.
"It's not something I was expecting on a Saturday, no, I was just sitting down watching a movie and yeah, it all just happened so quickly.
"It's not something that I'm used to seeing really."
Mr Vieritz said a number of people came to the rider's aid.
"They got his helmet off and just started trying to work on him," he recalled.
"I didn't want to get in the way, I was just trying to keep traffic away and that. I didn't know what I was doing.
"There was a few people that actually knew what they were doing and that and they just sort of tried to take control of it."
His neighbours, Mahalia Ervine-Roy and her sister, Sian, were also home.
Mahalia said she got out of the shower, heard the sound of the impact and "just knew straight away" what had happened.
"It wasn't good," she said.
She said she was the third on scene, and efforts were already underway to save the man's life when she got there.
Mahalia said an off-duty policeman began doing CPR, assisted by a nurse, while a jogger passing by ran over and said she was a doctor and also began to help try and save the man's life.
"It's very unfortunate and I'm very sad for their family," Sian said.
"It's really sad, it's a really sad thing that's happened here and it's probably going to take its toll on all of the people," Mahalia said.
Mr Vieritz said the rider's friend had told him it was the man's second time riding that particular bike.
"They were just on a Saturday lunch time cruise," Mr Vieritz said.
"It's a very, very sad outcome."
Forensic crash unit officers are investigating the accident.
Major traffic incident as boat comes off trailer, causes carnage
Police believe Sam may have hidden the bodies of three people
CLAIRE got to experience a week in the RAAF.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunchy Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahalia Ervine-Roy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Vieritz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Vieritz</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahalia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
