<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430739548198469</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/musicians-clifton-hill-townhouse-passes-in-at-auction/news-story/d178141a7b2bb83053568bf8388864c3</url>
  <title>Musician's Clifton Hill townhouse passes in at auction - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Gypsy & the Cat member Lionel Towers' converted warehouse apartment passed in at its auction after just one bid.

A MUSICIAN'S inner city converted warehouse apartment failed to hit the right note with prospective buyers at it's auction this morning, passing in after just one bid.
Owned by one half of indie pop duo, Gypsy & the Cat, the two-bedroom townhouse at 2/41 Dally St, Clifton Hill, only notched one bid of $860,000 from a young family in front of a crowd of 20 before it was passed in.
Nelson Alexander, Fitzroy, auctioneer James Pilliner said the bidder negotiated up to $870,000 but the offer was rejected by owner Lionel Towers.
It is now on the market for $960,000.

2/41 Dally St, Clifton Hill, has direct street access.

Mr Pilliner described the property as a fusion of contemporary style and industrial edge.
He said it was an enchanting industrial warehouse conversion in a residential street of heritage homes in a family belt near Merri Creek, the Yarra River, cafes, trams, trains and a school.
"It is rare to find a piece of real estate like this in such a central spot with its own street entrance," Mr Pilliner said.

Inside the renovated townhouse.

Mr Pilliner said the soaring ceilings, north-facing heritage windows and flexible floorplan with a studio or office were special features.
The property's heritage warehouse facade and modern interior boosted its appeal, he said.
Towers, who formed the band with fellow Melbourne DJ Xavier Bacash in 2010, bought the property for $687,000 in early 2014, CoreLogic records show.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne DJ Xavier Bacash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifton Hill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pilliner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merri Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pilliner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Towers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dally St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
