<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430653648851817</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/agriculture/crops/mackay-sugar-2-grower-levy-not-so-sweet-20170728-gxkusi</url>
  <title>Mackay Sugar $2 grower levy not so sweet </title>
  <content>
Rex Stroppiana's family has been sugarcane farming since 1928 when his parents arrived from northern Italy. His 250-hectare farm in the Pioneer Valley in North Queensland produces up to about 26,000 tonnes of cane per year.
A former director of Mackay Sugar, Stroppiana is now part of a breakaway group of growers at the centre of divisive debate about a much-needed recapitalisation plan for the nation's second-largest sugar miller.
Stroppiana, and fellow farmers Simon Mattsson and Colin Ash are spearheading legal action against the miller over a proposed $2 per tonne grower levy that would help .
"We have got over $200 million of debt and we need $100 million to fix our mills, so we are pretty snookered at the moment," says Stroppiana, who was a director from 2004 to 2013.

"The company has sought to impose the $2 deferred cane payment, which is unlawful. Most agribusinesses are carrying an enormous amount of debt. We can't debt fund the repair of our own business. We need foreign or new investment."

Mackay Sugar has four operating sugar mills at Racecourse, Marian, Farleigh and Mossman. Revenue streams include raw and refined sugar, molasses and renewable energy. Mackay also holds a 25 per cent per cent interest in sugar refiner, Sugar Australia, with the balance owned by Wilmar.
Scuttled plans

The court action could scuttle the recapitalisation plan put forward by Mackay Sugar advisor Kidder Williams, which includes the  for around $100 million and the $2 levy, as well as its 900-odd grower shareholders keeping control of the business.
Stroppiana says he would be happy to retain 30 per cent or 40 per cent of a JV or sell the business outright.

He says about $2.98 per tonne was lost last year for growers due to poor milling performance, and he personally says he lost about $350,000 last year.
"I left 4000 tonne of cane unharvested because mills performed so poorly and we had a long season, and got rained out," he says.
Mackay Sugar troubles started a few years ago when it was forced to finish building its $120 million co-gen plant after the contractor went bust. It also didn't get the crop size that it needed to feed the plant. It was caught up in the sugar industry M&A activity, buying the Mossman Mill for $25 million, which one source called "sub economic and very run down".
"They have since stuck another $5 million into it, but over the past two years they have written it down to almost zero," says one source.

Ballooning debt

Over the past five years Mackay Sugar's debt has ballooned from roughly $25 million to over $200 million. Its secured facilities of $115 million are with NAB and Rabobank.
Specialist fixed income broker FIIG Securities managed the sale of $50 million of bonds to Mackay Sugar. In a July report FIIG highlights that unless the miller achieves a recapitalisation soon, there is potential for failure of repayment of the unsecured notes - which pay 7.5 per cent on 85¢ in the dollar - by maturity date of April 5, 2018.
Mackay Sugar's real earner has been its share of Sugar Australia, however, increased competition from offshore refineries and excess local capacity has seen earnings from Sugar Australia decline. The raw sugar price has fallen by around 30 per cent this calendar year and is now below the cost of production, hurting the entire industry.

Despite its troubles, grower owners want to keep control of the miller. When Mackay Sugar and industry body Canegrowers Association ran surveys on the proposed levy versus selling the company, farmers voted by a narrow margin in favour of the levy.
Within days of the meeting, Stroppiana and those that agreed with his view had raised over $200,000 to take legal action against Mackay Sugar over the imposed levy.
Law firm Wallace and Wallace partner Greg Smart is leading the case on behalf the farmers, who have a group of about 170 growers backing their view.
Legal arguments

"This is not about poor management. We are staying clear of the corporate governance and politics of the company," says Smart.
"We are seeking a declaration from the court that the mill does not have the right to impose this $2/tonne levy on a proper construction of the contract. This is a legal argument. We are asking the court to determine the correct interpretation of the contract. There is no claim for damages at this stage."
An application hearing is set for September 8 in the Supreme Court of Brisbane.
Industry sources say Mackay Sugar is too big to fail and state and federal politicians are watching the situation closely.
Several industry sources say some farmers blamed former Mackay Sugar CEO Quinton Hildebrand for being too entrepreneurial buying up assets like the co-gen plant and Mossman mill, which meant there was no money left for needed going capital maintenance of the mills. He left the business in 2015 after seven years.
Stroppiana says there is no accountability for the state of the company, calling the board "dysfunctional".
Plan B

Mackay Sugar chairman Andrew Cappello says while the company's executives need to take responsibility for company performance, growers own the mill and need to also invest.

"They invest in the farms and they need to invest in the mills. They need to put their hand in their pocket and contribute," he says.
"If growers win the legal challenges and we can't collect the levy, we have to go to Plan B, which means bringing a JV partner or sale."
Cappello, who has been on the board since 2001, says Mackay Sugar took $10 million of costs out of the business last year, and is looking to do the same this year.
Compounding Mackay Sugar's balance sheet problems, new 2016 marketing legislation has hurt the miller.
Farmers now have the right to choose who markets and prices their sugar, that represents the amount that they would get paid for their sugarcane. Capello has previously stated this legislation has helped devalue Mackay Sugar since the miller now no longer has the right to sell 100 per cent of the sugar.
Canegrowers Queensland chairman Paul Schembri says he understands that some of his members voted against the levy but more were in favour of keeping control.
"I think you can spend time apportioning blame but we have had a number of bad seasons. It's difficult for grower-owned businesses to raise capital," he says.
"The majority of growers believe this business is worth fighting for and needs to be retained by grower control."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mossman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Mattsson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Sugar CEO Quinton Hildebrand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Smart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pioneer Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabobank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Sugar</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Cappello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Stroppiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sugar Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stroppiana</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mossman Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIIG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidder Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court of Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canegrowers Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIIG Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Sugar $2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plan B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Schembri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canegrowers Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cappello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
