<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430619289113185</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/yourlanguage/punjabi/en/article/2017/08/04/now-youll-see-pammi-aunty-four-different-avatars?cid=trending</url>
  <title>Now you'll see Pammi Aunty in four different avatars!</title>
  <content>
Pammi Aunty, the gossip-mongering, vitriolic, and acid-tongued Punjabi woman from Delhi will soon be seen in a series made in collaboration with Ekta Kapoor, with actor Ssumier Pasricha not only essaying Pammi Aunty's character, but three more!!

Language
English

By

Manpreet K Singh

4 Aug 2017 - 4:05 PM  UPDATED YESTERDAY 4:13 PM

Speaking to SBS Punjabi, actor Ssumier Pasricha revealed what's next on the cards for Pammi Aunty:

'Well, she is moving to Mumbai with her son Timmy. Instead of Sarla Bhenji, her closest friend will now be Kishori Lal, who is a man aged in his late seventies, living in Mumbai. Pammi Aunty will also have a Marathi bai, who'll help out with the household chores."

"And the interesting thing is, I will be playing all four of these characters in this amazing new Balaji production," said Ssumier. "I'm certain that the audience will absolutely love all four avatars of me."

Talking about the actor Ssumier Pascricha, and what he is up to, Ssumier said," I'm working on at least two new shows. I can't reveal much more than that, just yet. But yes, I'm really proud that I've just won another award - the Rajasthan Rattan. Its a great feeling to receive this acknowledgement for my acting skills."

And he also had some great news for his fans in Australia.

"I will be coming to Australia on a tour this year - the dates will be announced soon, but I can tell you I'll be performing in Melbourne later this year."

In a fantastic treat for Australian fans, Ssumier has been producing videos exclusively for SBS Punjabi for a few months now - and we hope to continue the collaboration till at least the end of this year. And just in case you haven't heard the two interviews the SBS Punjabi has conducted with Ssumier S Pasricha aka Pammi Aunty, here are the links:

If you've missed some of Pammi Aunty's videos on SBS Punjabi, click on the links below.

For more news and updates, follow SBS Punjabi on

and

.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marathi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Punjabi</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 2017 - 4:05 PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ssumier</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rajasthan Rattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kishori Lal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balaji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punjabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ssumier S Pasricha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarla Bhenji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED YESTERDAY 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manpreet K Singh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ssumier Pasricha</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ssumier Pascricha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pammi Aunty</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumbai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekta Kapoor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
