<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430786792838988</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/world/can-we-stop-the-collapse-of-democracy-20170804-gxpxmv.html</url>
  <title>If we want to protect democracy, the answer is: more of it, please.</title>
  <content>
London: By the year 2000, democracy was in the ascendant. Starting with Portugal in 1974, then spreading across the Mediterranean, Latin America and the Far East, before crescendoing in the great liberation of Eastern Europe after 1989, nation after nation joined the ranks of liberal democracies. Yet now, as Venezuela becomes the latest country to tumble towards dictatorship, we should ask ourselves again how democracy - the most powerful guarantor of personal freedoms there is - dies.
In Britain, it's easy to forget how fleeting democracy can be. The first great wave of democratisation in Europe came in 1918 with the end of the First World War. Yet of the nations set free by the war, by January 1939 only Czechoslovakia and Finland had escaped dictatorship.

Up Next

Wall Street rallies on jobs report

01:19

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Venezuelan police set fire to motorbikes

Violence erupts in Caracas as citizens vote to elect a new assembly with powers to rewrite the constitution.

Of course, 2017 is not 1933. But Venezuela and Turkey are just the latest demonstrations that, far from being on the march, democracy is in retreat. Freedom House, the US think tank, estimates that for the 11th year in a row global freedom has declined. So it's time to ask: what topples democracies, and how can we prevent it?
The first question is best answered by flipping it on its head. What makes democracies strong? The rule of law, secured by an independent judiciary; freedom of speech and the press; a strong civil society; firm civilian control over the security services and the military; and most important of all, a strong system of checks and balances on government.

The problem is, these can all be nibbled away at, so that when the final blow comes, it seems just the logical next step and not a significant break with tradition. Look at any nation in the past decade where democracy has been threatened and you will see that it is the press, the judiciary, and NGOs that are the first to be undermined.
That is why developments in Hungary and Poland - where the government is seeking to curb the independence of the judiciary - are so worrying. The courts, press, NGOs, and political critics are all under attack. Viktor Orban, Hungary's prime minister, has declared himself a fan of "illiberal democracy" and an admirer of the "successful" regimes of China and Russia. Liberal democracies, he thinks, are incapable of making the necessary decisions to remain competitive in the 21st century because their systems of governance are "anachronistic". In other words, checks and balances get in the way of authoritarians like him. And that is the nub of it. It is the checks and balances on government that stop democratic systems from being destroyed from within.

Yet even these are not infallible. In Venezuela, they were dismantled, piece by piece, by the nation's most popular president in decades, Hugo Chavez. Every attack on press freedom and political dissent, every crony placed at the head of a watchdog or the judiciary, was justified by reference to the popularity of Chavez.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

That is what links Turkey, Poland, and Hungary now with Venezuela and Russia, when they still held genuine elections. Attacks on democracy have been carried out by democratically elected leaders, in a toxic combination of populism and crude majoritarianism. The diminishing of democracy is presented as precisely the opposite, because it has the support of a significant majority.Photo: AP
But we only have to look to the United States to see that checks and balances really do work. President Trump would no doubt love to overturn decades of democratic consensus, objectors be damned. But the system won't let him. It is precisely that "anachronistic" form of decision-making so loathed by Orban that stops centuries of democratic growth from being blotted out in a heartbeat.
So what is to be done? "Rewrite the constitution" might be an odd battle cry for defenders of democracy, but it could just work.Photo: AP
The EU thought that it had hit upon the answer by sucking up power and wielding the bully stick when nations misbehave. Instead, its high-handed and anti-democratic approach is fuelling the siege mentality of Poland and Hungary's illiberal majoritarians. What is needed is the opposite: more democracy, grounded in smaller polities. De-centralisation is the enemy of the autocrat; the states and regions of true federations jealously guard their devolved powers against the overbearing centre: just look at response of California to Trump. So yes, if we want to protect democracy, the answer is: more of it, please.
Telegraph, UK
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedom House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugo Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Czechoslovakia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First World War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Viktor Orban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1939</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGOs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
