<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430868397218309</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/flights/budget-airline-redesigns-seats-with-more-legroom-but-no-seatback-pocket/news-story/67aecaea6ee041b9b7809d6a3e855d9e</url>
  <title>Budget airline redesigns seats with more legroom but no seat-back pocket</title>
  <content>
Can you spot what is missing? Ryanair's new seat. Picture: Ryanair/Supplied

Holly ChristodoulouThe Sun

Share

BUDGET carrier Ryanair has unveiled its new "game changer" seats designed to give passengers more legroom - but there's still a key thing missing.
Travellers on the budget airline are often left juggling their iPads, books and magazines because of a lack of seat-back pockets, reports .
Even though Ryanair has upgraded its seating on its new fleet of Boeing 737 MAX 200 to give passengers an inch of extra legroom, they have still not included the pockets.
And they have finally revealed the reason why their planes don't include them - it's all because of a speedy turnaround.
The airline says having the pockets gives cabin crew something else to check and clean, which takes up precious time.
A spokesman told the : "Since 2004 Ryanair seats have not included seat-back pockets, allowing us to maintain our industry-leading 25-minute turnaround, and reduce cleaning costs.
"Adding seat pockets to our seats is not something we are asked for by our customers."
The Telegraph reports another reason for not including the pockets is due to weight.
In 2012, the airline cut the size of its in-flight magazine in the hope of reducing its fuel bill.

A spokesman for the company said at the time: "We also considered removing armrests, but decided against it.
"We even encourage staff to watch their weight - with the motivation of appearing in the annual Ryanair calendar."
This story was first published in  and is republished with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing 737 MAX 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryanair</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryanair/Supplied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly ChristodoulouThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Since 2004 Ryanair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
