<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430314346432436</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/whatever-you-do-dont-mention-2016-to-the-roosters-20170805-gxpy14.html</url>
  <title>Whatever you do, don't mention 2016 to the Roosters</title>
  <content>
The year 2016? It's taboo within the walls of Roosters HQ. No one wants to remember it. And no one wants to speak about it to each other.
But for individuals? The year 2016 is the exact reason the Roosters won't let one of those improbable near worst-to-first stories fizzle out at the end of 2017.

Up Next

Storm grab 16th win of the season

01:30

More Rugby League Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Bunnies steal late win from the Dragons

With 10 minutes to go St George thought they had it in the bag, but two late tries for South Sydney secured a 2-point win for the Rabbitohs.

"Last year is motivation for us," Roosters prop Jared Waerea-Hargreaves said. "It sucked. It was tough. That's motivation for us. I wake up each day and I don't want to think about '16, I'm all about '17.
"The fire is still burning for us. It's cool to look back and see how much it's changed or swung in our direction - a bit of belief there.

"When you work as hard as we have, you start believing in what works. We know what works. When you start believing in the system, it's a cool thing to reflect on and see how far we've come for sure in the past 12 months.
"This is why we play footy and work hard. You don't want to let it slip. Little sacrifices here and there go a long way to the end result."

Which for a club as successful as the Roosters will only be satisfying if Trent Robinson can capture a second premiership as an NRL coach.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The tricolours, perennial minor premiership contenders, can keep the pressure on pacesetters Melbourne with a win over struggling Manly at Lottloland on Sunday.Photo: Brendan Esposito
Lose and the minor premiership bounty might be headed south again. But is the gap that big between Craig Bellamy's title favourites and the rest of the competition?
"They are a good footy team," Roosters five-eighth Luke Keary said. "It's fair to say they are a fair way ahead of the rest of the competition at the moment, but we've seen funnier things happen."
Robinson has spoken of the Roosters getting a real test of their premiership mettle in the next few weeks when they play the Sea Eagles, Storm and then the Sharks in round 25, where they will need to exorcise some demons from a Central Coast drubbing last month.
But that will count for little if they can't get past a brittle Manly, every bit the top four contender for much of the season before an error-strewn past fortnight.
"When you see teams coming off a tough year they don't bounce back like we have done where ... usually they'd come back mid-table," Keary said.
"They knew why they finished where they did last year. And knew what they had to do to get back to where they were in the previous years. They went about it pretty quickly."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Waerea-Hargreaves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lottloland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Keary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters HQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Esposito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
