<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430305756497775</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/transport/shipping/port-operator-dp-world-eyes-amazon-opportunity-20170804-gxpcdf</url>
  <title>Port operator DP World eyes Amazon opportunity </title>
  <content>
Paul Scurrah, the boss of the country's biggest stevedoring firm DP World, sees a huge opportunity from  and says logistics companies would be mad not to try and work with the online retail giant, which is planning to build a massive distribution network.
"We all know Amazon is going to change things here a bit and it would be irresponsible of any business not to have an aspiration to work with them," Mr Scurrah told AFR Weekend. "Amazon's history is they will establish a presence and vertically integrate themselves. That is a big unknown in this market and I'm on the side of potentially seeing the opportunity ... to become an integral part of the Amazon story."
Amazon announced plans this week to create thousands of Australian jobs and invest millions of dollars in the country as it confirmed the location of a giant distribution centre in Melbourne. Mr Scurrah would not confirm if he was already talking to Amazon but it is understood DP World has had exploratory discussions with the retailer about using its Somerton inland freight hub.
Amazon's arrival will be important for the nation's port operators which face growing margin pressure from new competitors and soaring rents from newly-privatised port owners.  into the Australian market could make Qube's Moorebank freight hub attractive to retailers.

Mr Scurrah, who was last month appointed a director of Australia Post, is four years into a five-year contract running DP World, which has around 50 per cent of the market where it competes with Patrick.

The former Queensland Rail boss has repaired DP World's relationship with its powerful shipping customers, which was at a low point when he joined.
He has introduced incentives aimed at cleaning up the notorious blokey waterfront culture and taken the lead responding to astronomical rent hikes by port owners in Sydney and Melbourne.
"The culture at our company is chalk and cheese to what it was a couple of years ago," says Mr Scurrah, who has banned his 2000 staff from swearing and is recruiting more women to work on the male-dominated waterfront.
He has doubled the percentage of female employees from 4 per cent to 8 per cent, which is still low compared to other industries. Mr Scurrah, a former professional footballer, is recruiting female AFL players from the Brisbane Lions to work part-time for the company.

"They don't earn enough from football full-time so they were looking for flexible employment to supplement that. We are rolling that program out nationally."
DP World says it has continued to grow market share despite the arrival of new competition and the $9 billion acquisition of Asciano by Qube Holdings and Brookfield Infrastructure Partners last year. That deal saw DP World's biggest competitor Patrick back in the hands of waterfront warrior Chris Corrigan. Mr Corrigan stepped down as Qube chairman late last year.
"I always considered Asciano under (former chief executive) John Mullen's leadership to be an incredibly robust competitor. We are dealing with a different competitor but it doesn't make them any more or less competitive. We have to do everything we can do to stay a step ahead of them," Mr Scurrah said.
After defeating a push by Port of Melbourne to raise rents 750 per cent in 2015, Mr Scurrah  and introduced a levy in Sydney. It was controversial move in shipping circles and the risk was that Patrick would not follow. It eventually did.

"For many years we have absorbed property-related costs as best as we can but they have escalated to a point where we reluctantly need to pass that through," he said.
"The next few years will also see some already agreed cost increases. We are going to see the infrastructure levy move in line with the property increases we will see in the future. I certainly felt the pressure to do something on behalf of my shareholders."
The board of DP World, which is 75 per cent controlled by US-based Corsair Infrastructure Management and 25 per cent by Dubai-based DP World, has approved a $180 million capital investment program that includes nine new ship-to-shore cranes which can handle huge Super Post Panamax vessels, 20 new straddle carriers for Sydney and other infrastructure. It is DP World's biggest capital investment in Australia for decades.
Plans to automate DP World's Port Botany operations has been put on hold as new technology comes onto the market and after lifting performance without automation. "Automation in our industry is inevitable but there is no hard and fast deadline for it. Right now the pressure is not there," Mr Scurrah said.

DP World expanded into land side logistics in July with the launch of a new business at Port Botany which handles rail freight and other container services. It is also developing Tasmania's first international container terminal.
The federal government appointed Mr Scurrah to the Australia Post board last month, along with Holly Kramer as deputy chair and Deidre Willmott. Mr Scurrah, 49, is the former chief executive of queensland Rail - the government-owned passenger rail service which was separated from QR National ahead of its privatisation. He spent two decades in customer service roles at Qantas, Ansett, American Express and Flight Centre.
While he briefly played AFL in his late teens before a leg injury ended that career, Mr Scurrah retains strong links with the sport as a board member of the Gold Coast Suns.
His appointment to the board of Australia Post has created something of an AFL cohort. Australia Post's new chief executive Christine Holgate is on the board of Collingwood, the team Mr Scurrah backed before he became loyal to the Suns, while outgoing boss Ahmed Fahour used to be on the board of Carlton.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Botany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brookfield Infrastructure Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Corrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR Weekend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Corrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DP World</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deidre Willmott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qube's Moorebank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Post Panamax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scurrah</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qube Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scurrah, 49</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Kramer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Holgate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asciano</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Scurrah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DP World's Port Botany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based Corsair Infrastructure Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Mullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Fahour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QR National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flight Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai-based DP World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Express</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ansett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somerton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
