<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430395950811711</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/technology/science/space/boy-writes-adorable-letter-applying-for-job-at-nasa/news-story/466d0dcda62fb9eb17e6fc8e6eebc0a7</url>
  <title>Boy writes adorable letter applying for job at NASA</title>
  <content>
NASA recently announced it was looking for someone to be a "planetary protection officer". One little kid reckons it should be him. Picture: NASA/AFP

FOLLOWING NASA's recent announcement that it is looking for someone to be an effective guardian of the galaxy, one applicant send the space agency a particularly adorable letter.
Hoping to have a shot , this little boy decided to take his chances and wrote to NASA, the  reported.
He doesn't think his age should be an obstacle.
"I may be nine, but I think I would be fit for the job. One of the reasons is my sister says I am an alien also, I have seen almost all the space and alien movies I can see," he wrote.

This could be the most adorable job application you'll ever read. Picture: Reddit/millamberSource:Reddit

Jack makes a very good case. Picture: Reddit/millamberSource:Reddit
"I have also seen the show Marvel Agents of Shield and hope to see the movie Men in Black. I am great at video games. I am young, so I can learn to think like an Alien."
Sure, he may lack some of the more technical skills the six-figure-salary job requires but Jack has seen a lot of space movies and is as keen as can be.
Your move, NASA.
This article originally appeared on the  and was reproduced with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA/AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Agents of Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit/millamberSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
