<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430911346891772</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/care-to-think-gives-trainer-matt-dunn-another-reason-to-celebrate/news-story/5ddd8d4ac9459eba4139051e3229dd06</url>
  <title>Dunn thinking big with Highway hero</title>
  <content>
MATT and Keira Dunn had double the reason to celebrate on Saturday as Care To Think won on their fifth wedding anniversary at Randwick.
The Murwillumbah stable had a winner in the first race in Brisbane (Arrestar) as well and while there was nothing but smiles from Matt and Keira at Doomben and Randwick respectively, it could have easily been different.
SUNDAY PREVIEW:
"Keira rang me on Thursday and said, 'are you going to pick me up from the airport on Saturday night' and I said, 'yes'," Matt said. "She said, 'do you want to go do something special' and I said, 'why'? She said, 'no reason'.
"My office staff later reminded me it was our wedding anniversary (on Saturday)."
Care To Think gave Dunn his 11th Highway triumph and, while Hanwritten and Quatronic might be the stable's two best Highway winners to date, don't be surprised if this So You Think four-year-old surpasses them one day.
"He did a fair bit wrong up the straight and if he keeps on improving the way we think he can, he will be a horse of the future," Keira said.
"Quatronic and Hanwritten were probably the two horses coming here we knew could go somewhere else and really be competitive in a Listed race. But if he continues to improve he might (follow them) and he is just not there yet. Next prep he is going to be even better again."
Care To Think was backed into a $2 favourite and his supporters had no need to worry as he came from well back to score by 1 1/2 lengths.
Keira said the $200,000 Anniversary Highway (1400m) on Everest Day (October 14) at Randwick might be an aim for Care To Think.
"Matt tagged that Anniversary race as a possible target if he travels back all right and still holds his condition," he said. "Whether he fits into that category we will wait and see.
"Originally I remember letting him down one day and Matt said, 'Wow, look at that horse', and he ran really quick time with an older horse.
"Whether we put him out and start again I'm not sure and he did the most wrong he has ever done in today's race, so maybe he is looking for a break."
Jockey Tye Angland said Care To Think had a lot to learn.
"Going to the gates he was a handful and in the run, he didn't relax really well, so I was trying to hold onto him as long as I could," he said. "When he got there he had a good look and hung in and he is a nice horse but I wouldn't want to push him too far because he will go from winning like this to doing things wrong and finishing back in the field.
"He is a horse that has plenty of improvement."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arrestar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care To Think</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUNDAY PREVIEW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanwritten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doomben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keira Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anniversary Highway (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tye Angland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murwillumbah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quatronic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keira</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
