<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430610699178496</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/news/state/vic/2017/08/05/melbourne-driver-put-kids-lives-risk-court/</url>
  <title>Melbourne driver allegedly put kids' lives at risk: court</title>
  <content>
A man has faced court with cuts on his forehead and a bruised eye after he allegedly drove at speed on a footpath near a school, narrowly avoiding children.
Tyson Anthony Vidal, 34, is accused of driving a stolen car on the wrong side of the road on the Mornington Peninsula on Friday afternoon before a dramatic arrest at a petrol station in Clayton.
Vidal faced Melbourne Magistrates' Court on Saturday charged with seven offences, including driving on a footpath while children were in the area, endangering their lives.
The court heard he is addicted to heroin and ice, and was on bail at the time of the offences.
Vidal was allegedly spotted driving erratically in Mt Eliza before police tracked him speeding along the Eastlink toll road towards Melbourne. He reportedly reached speeds of up to 200km/h.
Police moved in to arrest him when he stopped to fill up with petrol in Clayton.
He did not apply for bail when he faced court with a gauze pad on his head and a noticeably swollen cheek.
"He has sustained some bruising on his eye and abrasions on his forehead," defence lawyer Therese Wattis said.
"He has withdrawal from alcohol, heroin and ice."
After his arrest Vidal was taken to Monash Hospital where he spent more than six hours while three police officers were treated at the scene.
He's charged with reckless conduct endangering lives and injury, stealing a car, stealing petrol, driving without a licence and resisting police.
Vidal was remanded in custody and is expected to return to court on August 16.
-AAP 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Eliza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Therese Wattis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson Anthony Vidal, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vidal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
