<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430954296565072</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/fishermans-bend-park-comes-with-a-catch--planning-mess-means-itll-cost-19m-20170804-gxpn10.html</url>
  <title>Fishermans Bend park comes with a catch - 'planning mess' means it'll cost $19m</title>
  <content>
Work has begun on a new inner-city park, in a grey industrial area that could one day be home to tens of thousands of people.
The Andrews government unveiled its design for the future park on Saturday: a grassy, tree-lined public square on what is now a demolition site wedged between two light rail routes and the West Gate Freeway viaduct.Photo: Supplied
At a cost of $19 million for 8000 square metres, Fishermans Bend's newest patch of urban greenery will not come cheap for Victorian taxpayers.
The value of land on which the park will be built soared overnight when it, along with 250 hectares of industrial land, was rezoned in 2012.Photo: Luis Enrique Ascui
The rezoning, by the former Napthine government's planning minister Matthew Guy, who is now Opposition leader, was criticised by an expert committee for being done "without due diligence".
The report said the rezoning was "a windfall gain for landowners in the area".

The Andrews government has covered two-thirds of the land's $19 million price tag, and the City of Port Phillip chipped in the remaining $6.3 million.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Previously the site, on Buckhurst Street in South Melbourne, had a permit for two residential towers, and a discretionary height limit of four storeys.
Planning Minister Richard Wynne said the park would provide much needed open space in Fishermans Bend, "the largest urban renewal project in Australia".
"It will be the ideal place for families to get together and enjoy their new-look community, and local students to blow off some steam after a day in the classroom," Mr Wynne said.
The park will open next year, as will a nearby five-storey "vertical school" on Ferrars Street.
Port Phillip Mayor Bernadene Voss said the concept design for the park would be amended after discussions with locals, and could include a playground and fitness equipment.
Martin Foley, the MP for Albert Park, said, "unfortunately this park cost far more than it should have because of Matthew Guy's planning mess".
Opposition planning spokesman David Davis said Labor's planning efforts at Fishermans Bend were deeply flawed.
Development decisions were being made without the government having provided details on what transport links would be built for the suburb's forecast 80,000 residents and 60,000 employees, he said.
"They've got some colourful brochures that cover large sweeping areas but there are no detailed structure plans to support them," Mr Davis said.
The government vision for Fishermans Bend includes an unconfirmed tram connection into the area and a major freight link to the Port of Melbourne.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrars Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Napthine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip Mayor Bernadene Voss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Enrique Ascui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckhurst Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisherman's Bend</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Guy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Richard Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Gate Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Port</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
