<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429962159111541</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/afl-saturday-live-coverage-of-todays-matches/news-story/f110f5897e5b1db5dc1f7896856e3a74</url>
  <title>'He'll regret it, ridiculous thing to say'</title>
  <content>
Live: AFL Saturday
Welcome to AFL Saturday, our coverage of today's games:
GWS vs Melbourne, 1.45pm
Essendon vs Carlton, 2.10pm
Brisbane vs Western Bulldogs, 4.35pm
North Melbourne vs Collingwood, 7.25pm
Fremantle vs Gold Coast, 7.40pm (AEST)
EVERY game is a must-win for sides looking to cement a spot in the top eight as the season draws to a close. Melbourne has been inconsistent of late but can strengthen its finals push with a win over GWS, who finally recorded a victory last week after two draws and two losses.
Essendon can also move up from 10th if it defeats 17th-placed Carlton and other results go the Bombers' way, while Western Bulldogs can keep the faint dream of repeating last year's miracle alive by overcoming Brisbane at the Gabba this afternoon.
North Melbourne is in a fight to avoid claiming the wooden spoon and it will be interesting to see how it goes against a Collingwood side that will either be demoralised or intent on making amends after giving up a 50-point lead in last week's draw with Adelaide. Fremantle and Gold Coast round out Saturday's matches when they do battle in the west.
1pm
'He'll regret it, what a ridiculous thing to say'
Former Western Bulldogs star Luke Darcy hasn't taken kindly to a sledge dished out to him by Eddie McGuire during Fox Footy's coverage of Sydney's win over Geelong on Friday night.
Darcy once wore leather gloves when covering a game for Channel Seven in Geelong and McGuire was quick bring the incident up while talking to the ex-Dog's former teammate Brad Johnson, who was doing TV work at last night's game.
"Good to see, despite how cold it is down there mate, you're not wearing gloves like that soft ruckman Luke Darcy you used to play with," McGuire joked.
Darcy and McGuire co-host radio show The Hot Breakfast on Triple M Melbourne, so the crack was obviously all in good fun.
"That's an attack on my character!" Darcy laughed during a Triple M broadcast on Saturday.
"That won't end well for Ed. I think he knows who the biggest player in this town is.
"I think he'll regret that. What a ridiculous thing to say.
"You wear one pair of gloves, mate, and it stays with you."
Perhaps McGuire was getting his revenge on Darcy after he and fellow radio co-host Mick Molloy kept ribbing the Collingwood president when a rumour sprung up earlier in the week suggesting former Pies coach Mick Malthouse was in the running to return to the club as director of coaching.
, but for several minutes Molloy and Darcy kept joking he was hiding the truth and there was actually a chance Malthouse would be back at Collingwood.
12.30pm
Sydney sounds a warning
Sydney sounded the latest in a string of ominous warnings to the AFL competition with an emphatic 46-point win over Geelong at Simonds Stadium. In a performance reminiscent of last year's preliminary final display, the Swans blitzed the Cats early on their way to a 16.11 (107) to 8.13 (61) win.
John Longmire's men have now won 11 of their past 13 games and look capable of going deep into September after starting the season with six defeats in a row. They managed Friday night's win without injured skipper Josh Kennedy and with star forward Lance Franklin held to just one goal by Tom Lonergan.
"Right across the board we had a lot of players who contributed at a good level," Longmire said. "There were no real absolute standouts.
"So it was a very even performance but clearly that first quarter was important."
The Cats had won 15 of their past 16 games at their home ground going into the clash, with the Swans beating them last year. But the visitors made themselves right at home, kicking five goals in a row to help set up a 32-point lead at the first break.
The margin stretched to 37 points midway through the second term before Geelong mustered a fightback with three straight goals.
But Sydney regrouped at halftime and was able to keep the Cats at arm's length in the third quarter before finishing strongly.
The Swans host Fremantle next Saturday.
Kennedy will need a strong week on the track to press his claims for a return from a hamstring injury.
"He's definitely not ruled out, which is a good thing," Longmire said. "He ran on Wednesday at training so we're hopeful of getting him back but we're not sure until we see what he does during the week at training."
- AAP
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast, 7.40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs, 4.35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Malthouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne, 1.45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Lonergan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hot Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malthouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton, 2.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Darcy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood, 7.25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Molloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Longmire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
