<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430546274668241</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>http://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/3-ingredient-happy-hour-last-minute-punch/</url>
  <title>3-Ingredient Happy Hour: Last Minute Punch</title>
  <content>
Happy weekend, and welcome back to 3-Ingredient Happy Hour, the weekly drink column featuring super simple yet delicious libations. This week is a very special edition of the happiest of hours, because I am in New York and therefore able to mix a big bowl of booze for my coworkers.

Happy weekend, and welcome back to 3-Ingredient Happy Hour. This weekend we're going to be sipping on a classic cocktail that is, at its core, just a glass of clear, cold, alcohol: The Vesper martini.

Because it was a special occasion, and because there are so many of us, I skipped the individual cocktails and opted for a large format punch. Since we were (as usual) limited to three ingredients, I had to make sure they were three very flavorful ingredients, so I enlisted the help of St Germaine elderflower liqueur, also known as "bartender's ketchup". The video above has the all the details, but the ratios are pretty simple. To make this quick and simple, but flavorful punch, you will need:

1 bottle of St Germain

1 bottle (roughly 750mL) of ruby red grapefruit juice

2 bottles of sparkling wine (anything with bubbles will do you right)

If you know you are going to be making this punch somewhat ahead of time, you can go ahead and make a giant ice block and get that in the freezer. But if you are making this truly last-minute - as I usually am - just grab a bag of ice from the grocery store or whatever. Grab a big bowl and pour your St Germain and juice in there. Give everything a little stir to get the syrupy liqueur into solution and top with bubbles. Gently stir it once more, then ladle into little cup filled with ice.

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ML</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingredient Happy Hour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Minute Punch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vesper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ST-GERMAIN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Germaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
