<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430829742512311</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/real-estate/residential/mcgrath-shares-rise-30-per-cent-as-housing-boom-rolls-on-20170803-gxp4u2</url>
  <title>McGrath shares rise 30 per cent as housing boom rolls on</title>
  <content>
A buoyant housing market and an absence of negative company news has driven a mini-rally in real estate group McGrath, with its shares up more than 30 per cent in the past two months.
After slumping to a new low of 54¢ in early June, McGrath shares moved steadily upwards, hitting a six-month high of 73¢ at the end of July, and lifting its market capitalisation to almost $100 million. They closed on Friday at 70¢, down 2 per cent.
The revival in the share price is especially good news for founder John McGrath, who remains the biggest shareholder with a stake of almost 27 per cent, ahead of institutional backer Perpetual with almost 10 per cent.
However, the mini-rally should be put in context: the shares are still down a whopping 65 per cent f.

Furthermore, the widely-held industry view that McGrath was grossly overvalued at its IPO - when it floated on an earnings multiple of 8.8 compared to the typical multiples of two to three paid for other real estate business - remains.

"If the McGrath organisation can make this float work at these multiples, the rest of the industry would be indebted to them because it would mean real estate practitioners would be able to revalue their businesses under a very different model," noted Century 21 Australia chairman Charles Tarbey last year.
However, with - despite tighter regulation and higher borrowing costs, and auction activity and settlements trending up, investor sentiment has swung more favourably towards McGrath.
Also boosting sentiment has been the absence of any further negative trading updates, the last being in January, when McGrath warned again about low real estate listing numbers and acknowledged it had lost 36 estate agents from its company-owned offices, including some of its best operators.
McGrath CEO Cameron Judson, who guided recruitment firm Chandler Macleod through choppy waters, has steadied the ship since replacing John McGrath a year ago. The revolving door of management departures has slowed, while Mr Judson has made numerous hiring coups, including that of former LJ Hooker head of real estate Chris Mourd, who joined to head up McGrath's franchise business.

Bell Potter analyst Chris Savage maintains a buy recommendation on McGrath up to 80¢ a share. He noted in his March update on the company that McGrath's annuity businesses - property management and mortgage broking - and its franchise business implied a value of 70¢ to 77¢ a share. This means only a relatively small valuation was being applied to the other parts of the company, notably its company-owned sales business, which accounts for two-thirds of its revenue.
However, the likelihood that McGrath will get back to its $2.10 float price remains difficult, given the disruption hitting the sector through low-cost operators like Purplebricks and lead generation websites like OpenAgent, which take a 20 per cent slice of agent commissions.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath CEO Cameron Judson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PURPLEBRICKS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Judson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Mourd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McGrath</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Tarbey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OpenAgent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chandler MacLeod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ Hooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Century 21 Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
