<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430911346891755</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/real-estate/selling/billionaire-james-packers-favourite-exwife-jodhi-meares-new-mansion/news-story/1c71797038884663df0bc9fd543b634d</url>
  <title>Billionaire James Packer's favourite ex-wife Jodhi Meares' new mansion</title>
  <content>
Jodhi Meares loses licence for 12 months
0:44

The former wife of billionaire James Packer, Jodhi Meares has pleaded guilty to high range drink driving, received a $1100 fine and 12 month driving ban.

August 20th 2014
3 years ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Jodhi Meares, ex-wife of billionaire James Packer (pictured together in 1999) has bought a new seaside mansion in Sydney. Picture: Nathan Edwards.

Candace Sutton

Share

BILLIONAIRE James Packer's favourite ex-wife Jodhi Meares has bought a fisherman's cottage in exclusive waterside Watson's Bay in Sydney's east for $2.75m.
The former swimwear model turned Hawaiian-based activewear designer bought the pretty blue weatherboard house after selling two other Sydney properties, reports.
The purchase comes after the sale of her Point Piper apartment, where she holed up three years ago following a spectacular car crash in which she flipped her luxury Range Rover 4WD.
The drink driving accident preceded Ms Meares' breakup with rock musician Jon Stevens and a failed marriage to photographer Nick Tsindos.
But now happily based in Hawaii and with a new Sydney bolthole, Meares is said to be still close to her first husband James Packer.
The pair were pictured out together several times following the breakdown of his marriage to model Erica Baxter, the mother of his three children.

Jodhi Meares' new seaside house at Watsons Bay in Sydney's Eastern Suburbs, bought for $2.75m. Picture: Goodyer RE.Source:Supplied

Jodhi Meares in France on a recent holiday. Picture: Instagram.Source:Instagram

James Packer and Jodhi Meares in 2015. Picture: Christian Gilles.Source:News Corp Australia

One of two bedrooms in Jodhi Meares' new house bought after selling her Point Piper apartment.Source:Supplied
Ms Meares was also photographed with Packer during his ill-fated romance to superstar singer Mariah Carey.
The fashion entrepreneur's new Sydney house is a heritage-listed 1880s cottage with harbour glimpses.
The two bedroom, one bathroom house is one of nine remaining in the so-called fisherman's cottage group of the original Camp Cove village.

The Tigerlily label founder sold her Point Piper apartment for $2.4m in May.

Meares sold her Point Piper flat (above) for $2.4m, doubling what she paid for it in 2004.Source:Supplied

The historic Wolseley Road building where Jodhi Meares lived in 2014 with her then partner Jon Stevens.Source:Supplied

The Point Piper property was under siege by media when police (above) visited Ms Meares following her drink driving accident.Source:News Corp Australia
She paid $1.23 million for the unit in 2004, after her marriage to casino -tycoon Packer ended.
Ms Meares briefly listed the property for sale in 2014, but withdrew it after taking up residence with her then-beau, former Noiseworks frontman Jon Stevens.
The apartment came under siege in June 2014 when Ms Meares rolled her Range Rover and was charged with drink driving.
A media pack camped outside the historic 1907 Danmark building as it was revealed she had been driving more than three times over the legal limit.

Jodhi Meares with ex-husband James Packer and his then new girlfriend, singer Mariah Carey in Italy. Picture: jodhimeares/Instagram.Source:Supplied
Ms Meares pleaded guilty and escaped with a fine and a 12 month licence suspension, her lawyer Chris Murphy saying she had "been punished enough".
Mr Murphy said media pressure after the crash had made Ms Meares want to leave Australia altogether.
Mr Murphy said Ms Meares' two-year marriage to Mr Packer had branded her a celebrity for life.
"It haunts everything that is said about her. She is not a celebrity, she is not a movie star, she is a woman raised by a single mother."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson's Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Stevens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Point Piper</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danmark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meares</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodhi Meares</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Tsindos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Packer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariah Carey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Gilles.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erica Baxter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Candace Sutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Range Rover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Stevens.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Range Rover 4WD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Eastern Suburbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noiseworks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolseley Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Meares</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram.Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaiian-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodyer RE.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHRIS MURPHY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
