<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429966454078868</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/a-way-to-hold-a-public-vote-on-gay-marriage-after-all/news-story/1ad49cef0e5efa0484d2a254c3af5ff0</url>
  <title>A WAY TO HOLD A PUBLIC VOTE ON GAY MARRIAGE, AFTER ALL</title>
  <content>
The Senate has blocked the government's proposal for a same sex marriage plebiscite. There is talk of some kind of postal ballot, but it would not be compulsory and therefore statistically unconvincing. Furthermore, given this impasse the Liberal meeting scheduled for Monday could conceivable lead to the fall of the government. So perhaps an alternative approach is in order.

I believe that there may be a way, without requiring any legislation, for a compulsory plebiscite on the matter.

Note: I am not a lawyer, nor am I pretending to be one. But I shall now present the relevant legislation which I believe gives the government authority to conduct such a plebiscite. In any case, Senator, you are a trained lawyer. If either of you find this of use, you may want to forward it to others who might find it of interest, but who would never even notice an email from a person such as me. I shall ask Sinclair Davidson if he is prepared to publish a version of this on Catallaxy Files. Andrew, you are free to use this, publish it, or whatever, as you see fit.

My proposal involves using the authority of the Australian Statistician. A wag might suggest that he or she owes the community a little something after the recent fiasco.

First, the authority of the Statistician. :

(1) The Statistician may prepare forms relating to the collection of statistical information in relation to any matter referred to in section 8 or 9.

(4) For the purposes of section 8 or 9, the Statistician may, by notice in writing served either personally or by post on a person, direct the person:

(a) to fill up and supply, in accordance with instructions contained in or accompanying a form accompanying the notice, within such period after the service of the notice, being not less than 14 days, as is specified in the notice, the particulars specified in that form; and

(b) to cause the form so filled up to be furnished to the Statistician, or to an authorized officer, in accordance with those instructions.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Statistician</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sinclair Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAY TO HOLD A PUBLIC VOTE ON GAY MARRIAGE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catallaxy Files</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
