<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430481850158220</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/national/cory-bernardi-gets-internal-liberal-party-memo-about-samesex-marriage-meeting-in-leaked-email/news-story/4fface67ecef8435534e3b95084836cf</url>
  <title>Bernardi gets internal Liberal memo</title>
  <content>
DEFECTED Liberal Senator Cory Bernardi is still receiving internal memos being sent to party members, according to a leaked email.
According to  a copy of an email sent by chief government whip Nola Marino to all Liberal Party MPs and senators on Thursday revealed Mr Bernardi was still on the email chain.
The memo was sent to inform then of Prime Minister Macolm Turnbull's emergency meeting which is being held on Monday to debate the marriage equality issue at 4pm.
The email shows Mr Bernardi, who is now an independent on the Senate crossbench, is still receiving the Liberal's confidential emails.
Bernardi's parliamentary email has not changed since he quit the Liberal Party six months ago to set up his own Australian Conservatives party. He now sits on the Senate crossbench. It is unclear if Mr Bernardi has been getting more internal Liberal Party emails than this.
Buzzfeed News reports that it is understood Mr Bernardi did not inform the whip's office he was still receiving Liberal Party information.
The email comes after Ms Marino let a group of senior ministers leave parliament early. Her decision cost the Turnbull government a number of procedural votes in the House of Representatives.
Ms Marino was also under fire when Kelly O'Dwyer accidentally endorsed a Labor bill that criticised the Turnbull government.
According to Buzzfeed, a senior Liberal source said: "No wonder the whip can't maintain any discipline, [she] can't even manage a mailing list."
Mr Bernardi has not responded to questions over whether he has read the email or used the internal party details in any way.
Mr Turnbull is holding the emergency meeting on Monday before the joint party room meeting on Tuesday with the National Party, which will take place the following morning at 9am.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Marino</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bernardi</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernardi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Conservatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Cory Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buzzfeed News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BuzzFeed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Macolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nola Marino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
