<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430911346891785</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/sydney-swans-young-gun-tom-papley-reaping-benefits-of-studying-hawthorn-hawks-star-paul-puopolo/news-story/6ce53828225c10e6e15e0a1f5ba9c354</url>
  <title>Papley happily following Poppy</title>
  <content>
AT LAST something good has emerged from all those Swans losses to Hawthorn over recent years.
It's Paul Puopolo, who has provided the perfect role model for Sydney's aspiring small forward Tom Papley. Even before he arrived at the Swans, their pocket rocket was paying close attention to the 29-year-old Hawks star.
"I watched Paul a lot in my draft year and they year before that," Papley told the Sunday Telegraph.
"I was told to watch him and see just how a small pressure forward works. He's a triple premiership player and I love the way he defends."
The Puopolo training program didn't stop when Papley arrived at the SCG, his coaches and teammates confirmed he was on the right track with his Poppy studies.
"I spent a lot of time watching video of him last year as well," Papley said.
The 21-year-old booted 29 goals in his debut season to finish second in Sydney's goal kicking behind Lance Franklin and he has picked up where he left off with another 25 from his 16 games this season, including three in Friday night's win over Geelong.
All three came in different and creative ways but it was the last which brought the most attention when he drew Mitch Duncan into a silly free kick when he punched him in the stomach.

AFL: Swans coach John Longmire addresses the media following a win over Geelong.

Swans press conference
"I got into him a bit because Hanners was getting a bit of the ball on Duncan," Papley said.
"I wanted to get him off his game and he threw a punch and hit me in the guts right in the good spot and it winded me. We got a goal out of it."
For a player in just his second year Papley is well versed in the dark arts of the niggle and looks like a natural.
"If it puts defenders off their game it's working," Papley said.
"Niggling is part of the job, it's what my teammates want from me and the coaches. Pressure is part of it as well and it creates goals."
If Papley continues his form he will be in the conversation for All-Australian honours. It's a remarkable achievement after a pre-season which included two surgeries, the first for shin splints and the second for his knee.
"I spent a lot of time with AJ (Alex Johnson) and he taught me how to work hard on my rehab," Papley said.
"When he was in the gym I wanted to impress him and do everything I could to earn the trust of my teammates."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Puopolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papley</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puopolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
