<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430700893492481</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/good-weekend/irish-crime-novelist-tana-french-upending-the-whodunit-genre-has-its-rewards-20170731-gxmbne.html</url>
  <title>Irish crime novelist Tana French: up-ending the whodunit genre has its rewards</title>
  <content>
On a blue-sky summer day, three 12-year-old kids run into an ancient forest adjoining a housing estate. Two of the children are never seen again. The third is found near the centre of the forest, his back and the palms of his hands pressed against a large oak tree. He has blood inside his shoes and no memory of what happened. Much later, when the boy has grown up and become a detective, he is assigned to investigate the murder of a child close to the spot where his friends disappeared.
This is the starting point of In the Woods, the first of six related novels that have won a cultish following for Irish writer Tana French. All six books, together known as the Dublin Murder Squad series, are beautifully written. All are hefty. "Big long bastards," as French puts it when we meet in a Dublin hotel. And all are addictive. I was given the series for Christmas last year, and spent the next few months - annoyingly interrupted by work and, you know, life - reading one volume after another. By the time I sit down with French, I know more about the dynamics of her fictional squad-room than the recent activities of my immediate family.Photo: Gaby Gerster/laif
French is small, with pale skin, close-cropped red hair and the cheerful demeanour you would expect of a person whose books have been translated into 34 languages, sold 5.5 million copies worldwide and won a slew of international prizes. She may not get much shelf-space in Australian bookstores - "Tana Who?" say friends to whom I recommend her - but The New York Times critic  as "required reading for anyone who appreciates tough, unflinching intelligence and ingenious plotting". In the , crime-fiction reviewer for The Washington Post, she is "the most interesting, most important crime novelist to emerge in the past 10 years".
For French, 44, a former actor, finding herself cast in the role of literary sensation feels like an extraordinarily lucky break. "I'm still kind of wiping the big grin off my face," she says as we drink tea in the hotel's cosy upstairs bar. Apart from anything else, the success of her books - and the sale of TV adaptation rights to British production company Euston Films - has brought her unaccustomed financial security. As she points out, most actors lead a hand-to-mouth existence: "Unless you're Judi Dench, you don't get back-to-back gigs." 
The idea for the first novel came to French in 2002, when she was paying the rent during a gap between theatre jobs by working on an archaeological excavation just outside Dublin. "I was digging," she says. "The kind that involves a mattock and a wheelbarrow, not the delicate stuff with a trowel and paintbrush." A lovely old forest bordered the site. She remembers thinking: "Great place for kids to play." And then: "What if three kids went in there one day and only one came out, and he couldn't remember what had happened?"
She jotted down the half-formed scenario and forgot about it until a year or so later, when she was cleaning out her apartment in preparation for a move. "There was this bit of paper that showed up under a phone bill, coffee all over it. 'Oh God, that.' " The premise still intrigued French. A keen reader of murder-mysteries, she wondered whether she could write one. "I was fairly sure I couldn't, but I thought I could probably write a scene. And then maybe another scene."

When she got started, she and her husband, actor and film-maker Anthony Breatnach, were living in a tiny flat. While she wrote, Breatnach sat a couple of metres away, playing zombie-killing games on an Xbox. Nonetheless, French's scenes came together - "for some reason I can tune out dying zombies" - and eventually she had a chapter. Then several chapters. Perhaps she could write a book. "I caught myself turning down an acting gig because I wanted to finish it," she says, "and that's when I realised, 'I am serious about this.' " 
Published in 2007, In the Woods established French not only as a wildly talented new novelist but as a clear-eyed chronicler of modern Ireland. "I have a theory that crime writing is one of the places where the crucial issues of any nation's identity get explored," she has said. And recent Irish history has left her little country - one-third the area of Victoria - with what seems to French to be an identity crisis.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Until the mid-1990s, Ireland was a stagnant agrarian society: "A charming bog", as one US travel writer described it. Then the economic boom known as the Celtic Tiger transformed it into the prosperous headquarters of multinational hi-tech firms and pharmaceutical companies. The good times seemed set to roll forever. "The boom is getting boomier," declared Bertie Ahern, the Irish taoiseach, or prime minister, in 2006. But the global financial crisis hit the following year. "And then of course," says French, taking a sip of tea, "it all went completely tits up."
Irish property prices plummeted. Banks teetered on the brink of collapse. In 2010, the government accepted a financial bail-out from the European Union and the International Monetary Fund. It seemed that one minute the Irish had been congratulating themselves on finally emerging from centuries of poverty and creating a successful modern state, the next they were facing the possibility that theirs was a rags to riches to rags story. "They were devastated," French says. "Not just financially and not just in practical terms. They were devastated psychologically."
In her fourth book, Broken Harbour, released in 2012, the action centres on a "ghost estate": the name given to the abandoned, half-built housing estates that have dotted the Irish landscape since a lot of sharp-suited property developers went bust. A man and his two children are found dead, his wife seriously injured, in one of the few finished and occupied houses in a street. The husband had lost his job as a finance-industry recruiter. The value of the house had fallen to the point where the mortgage was "underwater": even if selling the place had been possible, the return would not have covered the amount owed on it. The murder squad detectives find video cameras trained on holes cut in the shoddily built walls, and a large animal trap in the attic.
"It's a depressing bastard of a book," says French. "I always feel like apologising for it." But she wanted to draw attention to the plight of all those people who took out huge loans to buy overpriced houses on the assurance that values would continue to soar. The message coming at them from all sides was that if they didn't get into the property market right then, they never would. "My generation were the ones who really got hit by this - the ones who were in their 20s and 30s when the boom was happening," she says.
I would have fallen for the hype and bought [a house during Ireland's economic boom] - except that we were so broke we couldn't have bought, like, a garden shed.
Tana French

The Irish enthusiasm for home-ownership has always seemed to French to have a desperate edge. She sees it as a legacy of the country's history as an oppressed colony of Britain, when generations of farmers - barred from owning the plots they worked or the cottages that stood on them - were beholden to absentee British landlords. "They could be turfed out for any reason, or none," she says. "So it's really seared into the Irish subconscious that owning your home is the only way you can feel safe, the only way to get rid of that constant low-level panic that you could be on the street at any moment."
French can talk about this stuff with a degree of detachment because she is Irish only by adoption. She has lived in Dublin her entire adult life - since coming here in 1990 as a 17-year-old to study drama at Trinity College - but she was born in the US state of Vermont to a Russian-Italian mother and an Irish-American father. During her childhood, her father's work as a development economist took the family everywhere from Washington DC to Rome to the south-east African country of Malawi. "Lots of international schools," she says. "Lots of movement."
Her peripatetic personal history means she identifies with the Irish desire for a permanent address. "I had an absolute craving for a home of my own," she says. "I think there's a decent likelihood I would have fallen for the hype and bought during the boom - except that we were so broke we couldn't have bought, like, a garden shed." 

 

Tana French is fascinated with the bond between her detectives, likening it to actors on stage. Photo: Gaby Gerster/laif

In a standard crime fiction series, the same sleuth stars in each book, becoming a familiar and trusted figure to readers. Whether we're following Philip Marlowe down the mean streets of 1930s Los Angeles, sitting with Miss Marple in her parlour in the village of St Mary Mead or trudging around some frozen Swedish lake with Kurt Wallander, we confidently expect that, since our old friend is on the case, the villain will be caught in the end.
In the Dublin Murder Squad series, things are less predictable. The books are only loosely connected, and each has a different detective as the protagonist. He or she is also the narrator, and not necessarily a completely reliable one. An event or person will be described in one of the early books in a way that, in a later instalment, when we're seeing the world through another narrator's eyes, we may come to regard as biased or inaccurate. "People's realities can be so different," says French.
And people whose job it is to sort facts from fiction can have the most warped perspective of all. Rob Ryan, the forest-survivor turned cop who narrates In the Woods, says at the beginning: "What I warn you to remember is that I am a detective. Our relationship with truth is fundamental but cracked, refracting confusingly like fragmented glass."
French's detectives are performers, pausing to decide which persona to adopt before they enter an interview room. "They have to know what part to play for this suspect," she says. "What's going to get him interested? What's going to get him talking? What's going to get him off-balance? They have to call on everything they know about people." The detectives work in pairs, and the best partnerships are so close that the bond is almost telepathic. "I'm fascinated by the idea of that teamwork," says French, who compares it with the unspoken understanding two actors can have on stage: "There's this realisation that there is absolute trust and you are making each other better. Very exhilarating."
In her decade-long acting career, she worked mainly in theatre ("I never got very far in film"), particularly relishing Shakespearean roles. In A Midsummer Night's Dream, she was Titania, queen of the fairies. In Twelfth Night, she was the jester Feste. Acting seems to French to have been excellent preparation for her present job: both actors and novelists aim to understand, and convey, what makes people tick. Writing first-person, as she does, "is basically playing a character", she says.
But there's one big difference. In the theatre, she felt she had to nail her performance every night. "This audience isn't going to see it again so you have to get it right for them. There's no second chance." As a novelist, on the other hand, "You only have to get it right once. I can rewrite something 50 times and 49 of them can be utter crap and it's fine as long as the 50th is okay."
If there is a pattern in French's books, it's that the narrator not only has to solve a murder but face a crisis in his or her personal life. Besides being whodunits, her novels are wrenching studies of individuals under intense pressure. As  The New Yorker, "The search for the killer becomes entangled with a search for self. In most crime fiction, the central mystery is: Who is the murderer? In French's novels, it's: Who is the detective?"
Rob Ryan, for instance, is haunted by his past. He has done his best to lead a normal life, but returning to the place where his two friends vanished brings buried memories closer to the surface. The way French sees it, "The real mystery of the book is not, 'What happened to the kids?' It's, 'Is he going to be able to confront what is waiting inside him?' "
The need to come to terms with internalised trauma is one of the themes of the series, perhaps because French worries that Ireland as a nation has never managed to do it. During the boom, she says, the idea took hold that in order to build a shiny future it was necessary for the Irish to collectively turn their backs on their tragic history - banging on about the Great Famine and the Easter Rising wasn't going to get anyone anywhere. "I think there was a huge urge with the Celtic Tiger to go, 'We've done all that,' " she says. " 'We're going to basically chop off our past at about 1994 and push it off into space if we can. Reset the clock and start over again.' And of course it doesn't work that way."
One in every three new novels published in English falls into the crime-fiction category, according to Rachel Franks, the NSW State Library's co-ordinator of education and scholarship, and an authority on the genre. "Then you have all those back-lists - people like Agatha Christie and [Arthur] Conan Doyle, who have never gone out of print," Franks says. "So it is a booming market." To her, the appeal is obvious. "In crime fiction, you can restore the world, or at least a little part of it, to some semblance of order. In a world that is increasingly chaotic and filled with conflict - and strange politicians doing increasingly strange things - crime fiction reminds us that one person can actually make a difference. The detective usually wins."
Stewart King, who lectures on crime fiction at Melbourne's Monash University, points to a growing enthusiasm for novels that not only explore the darkest recesses of human nature but give us the lowdown on specific geographic locations. Donna Leon writes about Venice in such a way that we feel we really know how the city operates. Jo Nesbo does the same with Oslo, and Ian Rankin with Edinburgh. "Crime fiction offers us a view of a place that we wouldn't see as tourists," King says.
Tana French certainly shows us a side of Ireland that is not in the travel brochures. "Corruption is taken for granted, even grudgingly admired," she has a character tell us at one point. "The guerrilla cunning of the colonised is still ingrained into us, and tax evasion and shady deals are seen as forms of the same spirit of rebellion that hid horses and seed potatoes from the British." 
Where French differs from most crime writers is that her books do not always have neatly tied endings: there is the sense that some wounds are too deep to heal, and that some mysteries might never be solved. Faithful Place, set in the rackety working class Dublin neighbourhood known as The Liberties, is utterly down-to-earth, and her sixth book, The Trespasser, is essentially a first-class police procedural. But in other novels in the series - The Likeness, The Secret Place - a hint of the supernatural hovers over the proceedings. "When I was a kid, time-slip books were my favourites," she tells me. "I still love that feeling that there might be something just outside the periphery of your eyesight."
Not all crime-fiction readers like the way French messes with the rules of the genre: a couple of people I know almost threw In the Woods across the room when they got to the last page. French says she sympathises with their frustration: "I can see the argument. There is a contract with a mystery book: 'I'll follow you through this book and you'll give me the bloody answer at the end.' " She sticks by her decision to finish the novel the way she did: any other conclusion would have felt cheap and cheesy to her, she says. "But tell your friends I apologise."
The good news is that things in Ireland are looking up. The austerity measures imposed after the economic bail-out were adopted by most of the citizenry with the calm acceptance of those accustomed to wearing hair-shirts, and the results have been gratifying. Last year, the Irish economy grew faster than that of any other country in the European Union for the third year in a row. "Things are starting to come back together for most people," says French. "Not for everybody. The real casualties of the Celtic Tiger are the people who are left stranded on ghost estates, or who were left with mortgages they couldn't pay. The homeless."
She and Breatnach, who have two daughters, bought a place after property prices fell. "That was sheer dumb luck," she says, sounding slightly apologetic. "We were broke when everyone was getting rich, and we got money when everybody else was sort of crashing." French is now working on her seventh book. "It's slightly different this time," she says, "in that the narrator isn't a detective." I stifle a gasp. What, no one from the Dublin Murder Squad appears in it? "There is no overlap," she confirms. "There's a dead body in there. There is a murder. But the narrator isn't a detective, he's just a guy. A young, nice guy who has always had a pretty charmed existence. But when he is at the lowest point in his life, he suddenly finds himself in the middle of a murder investigation. He has to figure out what to do about it, but also how he wound up there in the first place."
About two-thirds of the way through writing a novel, French tends to find herself desperate for distraction, prepared to do almost anything other than finish it. "I'm having fun with this one," she says, "but I'm expecting that stage to kick in any minute now: 'By God, that wall really needs repainting.' And, 'Do you know, I've got jumpers in my cupboard that I haven't worn in years. I should really tidy out.' "
Motherhood has played havoc with her writing schedule anyway. She used to like to get up at about 11am, start work at noon and go to bed at 4am. These days she is most productive in the mornings, when the girls, aged eight and four, are out of the house. She still has the power of concentration that allowed her to block out the sound of dying zombies while writing her first book, but her daughters have taught her that there are limits: "It is extremely hard to ignore someone who goes, 'Mama, I put a raisin up my nose.' You can't really tune that out."
French admits she sometimes misses acting, but for the moment her priority is meeting her obligation to produce a book every two years. "I can't really say to the publishers, 'Oh by the way, it's going to be three months late because I really want to go back to the stage.' " She puts down her teacup. "I think there's a clause in my contract where they get to poke me with a stick if I say something like that." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW State Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Marple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Ryan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bertie Ahern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Marlowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breatnach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broken Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Nesbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Monash University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Famine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Monetary Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tana French</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easter Rising</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trinity College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Rankin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Franks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euston Films</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French, 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xbox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celtic Tiger</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agatha Christie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Mary Mead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tana Who</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judi Dench</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conan Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midsummer Night's Dream</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edinburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malawi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Leon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian-Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespearean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin Murder Squad</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Breatnach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Wallander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaby Gerster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vermont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oslo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twelfth Night</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
