<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430619289113153</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/tennis/nick-kyrgios-back-on-the-practice-court-after-washington-retirement/news-story/dead83f4cfe57f063458c977b58070d4</url>
  <title>'My girlfriend dumped me, now I can't play'</title>
  <content>
FANS booed him out of the arena at the Citi Open on Thursday but Nick Kyrgios found himself some new supporters after stepping back onto the court in Washington.
It may only be the practice court, but it's a positive sign for the 22-year-old after he retired hurt during the second set of his second round match against Tennys Sandgren. The Aussie star pulled the pin when down 3-6 0-3 to the world No. 106 after being treated for shoulder pain several times during the match.
Kyrgios was dejected upon exiting the tournament, walking off the court with his head down as the crowd voiced its displeasure.
But he went out of his way to make sure some young tennis lovers enjoyed a day they'll never forget, inviting them onto the court as he got back to work.
Whether he was warning the youngsters of the dangers of chasing girls or just making them aware of how damaging karma can be, Kyrgios joked his recent woes were down to his split from girlfriend Ajla Tomljanovic.

"I used to be good, man. My girlfriend dumped me and now I can't play." Kyrgios shooting the breeze with fans. People are loving it.

when she returned from a social media hiatus in July following revelations Kyrgios had partied with two young female tennis players after his time at Wimbledon came to an end.
The world No. 20 was snapped leaving a London nightclub with the girls not long after he retired hurt from his opening round match against Pierre-Hugues Herbert with a hip injury at the All England club.
The early exits from Kyrgios' two most recent tournaments are the continuation of a concerning trend. Prior to Wimbledon, he'd only made it to the third round once in five attempts.
But when he wasn't blaming his breakup for his recent downturn he was admiring the skills of the kids he invited to train with him. Offering them a free racquet if they could return his serve, one boy walked away with a fresh piece of equipment after he moved well to his forehand wing and proved he was up to the task.
Kyrgios' countryman Thanasi Kokkinakis has been having a better time of it, reaching the final four of the Los Cabos Open after a straight-sets quarter-final victory over Taylor Fritz in Mexico. He won 7-6 6-2 on Friday and will play world No. 14 Tomas Berdych for a place in the final.
World No. 454 Kokkinakis overcame being broken in the fifth game of the second set to win the final three games against American Fritz, who is ranked 327 places above him. It's the first time Kokkinakis, a tournament wildcard, has reached a semi-final on the elite ATP Tour.
The 21-year-old started well by breaking Fritz in the third game of the opening set but endured an immediate break back. He fought back from 3-1 down in the first-set tiebreak to win 7-5 before closing out the game in 92 minutes.
Kokkinakis is two months into a full-time world tour comeback after almost two years with crippling injuries.
Meanwhile, Aussie Jordan Thompson came frustratingly close to upsetting world No. 8 Alexander Zverev in the pair's second round encounter at the Citi Open in Washington.
The 23-year-old lost 4-6 6-3 7-6, leading the third set tiebreak 5-4 before conceding the final three points of the match. Two points away from one of the biggest victories of his career, Thompson put a routine backhand into the net and then double-faulted.
- with AAP
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Fritz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thanasi Kokkinakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fritz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATP Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ajla Tomljanovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi Open</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennys Sandgren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Fritz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Zverev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Jordan Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokkinakis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wimbledon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Cabos Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrgios</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Kyrgios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pierre-Hugues Herbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomas Berdych</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
