<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430782497871665</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/superracing/hopes-aloft-for-team-williams-as-stayer-stakes-cup-claim/news-story/cfa90d0a6dea8669311386ce442a1475</url>
  <title>Cup hopes Aloft for Team Williams</title>
  <content>
THE strength of the win and a sense of blue and white deja vu now has Aloft on the fourth line of betting for the Melbourne Cup.

Aloft on Saturday scored a powerful on-pace win in the Nursery Handicap (2000m) at Flemington and is now on a Melbourne Cup campaign.
A year ago, a similarly performed import called Almandin won the same race for Aloft's owner Lloyd Williams and 12 weeks later Almandin won the Melbourne Cup.
Bookmakers undoubtedly responded to the sense of history in Saturday's won, elevating Aloft to $26 for the $6 million Cup.
Almanin, incidentally, is a $21 shot in TAB markets for the Cup and is due to shortly kick off his campaign to go back-to-back.
Nick Williams was wary on Saturday of drawing too many links to Almandin with Aloft.
"It's a long way from August until Melbourne Cup day,'' he said.

"You only have to look at Almandin from last year. No-one was thinking about him with the Melbourne Cup in mind (in August). We'll take it as it is. It's still a long way to go. It's still a winter meeting but we're happy with his return.''
Williams praised the ride of Ben Melham, who secured some cover from the wind before kicking strongly in the straight and staving off the late challenges of Second Bullet and Galaxy Raider.
"It was a great ride from Benny, he's riding in really good form,'' he said.
Melham said Aloft "has got a bit of class about him. He seems to have furnished nicely from last time,'' he said.
Williams said Aloft had no set campaign to the Cup.
"We'll let the horse tell us where he takes us,'' he said.
"We like to get our horses fit as early in the season as possible and keep them ticking over.''
High profile stablemate Bondi Beach settled back in the field at his first start since failing in last year's Melbourne Cup and ground away for ninth.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy Raider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Almandin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Second Bullet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nursery Handicap (2000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Almanin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Melham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
