<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430009403752160</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/entertainment/confidential/jerry-seinfeld-review-comedian-still-razor-sharp/news-story/db7408917befbc1e5625652d641d078a</url>
  <title>Seinfeld still razor sharp</title>
  <content>
IF ABSENCE makes the heart grow fonder, then it's no surprise Perth was happy to see Jerry Seinfeld strut onstage. 
It's been 19 years since Seinfeld last toured Australia, and the comedian has never been to WA before, but that didn't stop Perth audiences from greeting him like an old friend.
After all, his sitcom, a study of the quirks and neuroses of a group of New Yorkers, the show that was famously about nothing, was a huge hit in Australia and despite the final episode airing in 1998, it's popularity seems to have only grown with time. Perth even boasts it's own Seinfeld mural, a wall in Mount Lawley emblazoned with characters from the popular show.
So the anticipation was palpable. Would Seinfeld in the flesh be the same nitpicking, neurotic Jerry we have grown to love on the small screen?
In a word, yes.

Striding quickly onto stage directly after warm up act Mario Joyner, the crowd was momentarily taken aback by the casualness of his entry, but his opening line made it very clear who it was, "Are you kidding me?" Seinfeld asked to rapturous applause. "19 goddamn years and I'm back in Australia!"
He admitted it was hard to get to WA, but also complemented the crowd on bothering to turn up, before embarking on a tirade of the difficulty of doing anything, seeing as leaving the house requires effort of mammoth proportions. It was vintage Seinfeld. You could almost imagine him delivering the monologue to Elaine in his kitchen while downing a bowl of cereal. Perhaps that's the difficulty of his two decade touring gap - an Australian audience is always going to remember '90s Jerry best.
He went on to offer up rapid fire observations on modern life, from the absurdity of trendy restaurants to the quirks of language. "Sucks and great are the only rating you give to anything," he mused.
A tirade on Pop Tarts fell a little short - the American snack not being familiar to many Australians.
Mobile phones came in for the Seinfeld treatment, and he got a massive laugh referencing his recent headline-grabbing hug refusal when he declined an embrace from pop star Kesha on the red carpet.
The second half of his set he got a little more personal. He is, he pointed out, 63 now. And in the years since his small screen fame he has been busy getting married and having three children.
What followed was observations on fatherhood and married life. It's not exactly a unique topic, and Seinfeld doesn't seem to have too much of a different take on the experience of hopeless dad and the politics of marriage, but nonetheless, he's a polished performer, a clever writer and a sharp observer of the human condition - we were all kept laughing.
Seinfeld is one of the best, most polished stand up comedians you will ever see. His observations on the quirks and absurdities of modern life are still razor sharp and his stage presence and performance is second to none. The crowd left buzzing. We hope it won't be another 19 years before he returns again, it was gold, Jerry.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seinfeld</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mario Joyner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Lawley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pop-Tarts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerry Seinfeld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kesha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
