<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430438900484952</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/14/29/former-queensland-soldier-found-guilty-murder-ex-partner</url>
  <title>Former soldier found guilty of murdering his ex-partner inside her Queensland apartment</title>
  <content>
A former Queensland soldier has been found guilty of murdering his ex-partner in a fit of jealous rage.
A jury took just four hours to yesterday convict Dane Andrew Pilcher of the murder of Corinne Henderson in her Townsville apartment in September 2015 after he had pleaded not guilty, citing self-defence.
Graphic police bodycam vision played to the court showed the moment police stormed into the 32-year-old's apartment minutes after she was stabbed 21 times with a kitchen knife.
Confronted by Pilcher in the doorway, who says, "I'm pretty sure she's dead inside", officers find Ms Henderson's body on the floor of her bedroom.
"Get straight to him. Get straight to him," one officer is heard saying.
Earlier in the evening, the former army soldier was captured on CCTV at a service station and in a taxi heading to Ms Henderson's house.
Previously in a relationship, he told the court he broke into the apartment to confront Ms Henderson after seeing photos on social media of her with her rumoured partner, Dwayne Wickham.

Related Articles

He claimed Ms Henderson had stood in the living area holding a knife and that he acted in self-defence - claims the jury dismissed.
The jury also heard a recording of the triple-zero call Pilcher made on the night.
"I have killed my ex-partner. She is not moving at all. I am pretty sure she is dead," he is heard telling the operator.
"There is blood everywhere, blood everywhere ... it is everywhere."
"Oh my God, what have I f----- done?"
CCTV then shows police finding Mr Wickham locked in the bathroom, who only emerges when they assure him Pilcher has been removed.
As police escort Picher into an ambulance, he heckles with Mr Wickham.
"That was a shame Dwayne, wasn't it? Was that worth it Dwayne?" he is heard saying.
Outside the court yesterday, Ms Henderson's family said the verdict was justice for Corinne.
"Corinne was an amazing person... she was a kind-hearted person whom even in her last moments had no other thoughts but to help other people," Sally Jupp, a spokeswoman for the family said,
The former soldier's father maintained his son's innocence but said "he got a fair trial".
Pilcher has been remanded in custody as is facing a possible life sentence where he will be unable to apply for parole for at least 20 years.
He is expected to be sentenced next week. 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corinne Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwayne Wickham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Henderson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Andrew Pilcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilcher</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corinne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wickham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwayne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Picher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Jupp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
