<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430030878588837</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>http://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/this-diy-activity-tin-keeps-kids-occupied-without-an-ipad/</url>
  <title>This DIY Activity Tin Keeps Kids Occupied Without An iPad  </title>
  <content>
It's hard to compete with the convenience of iPads and phones to keep kids busy in cars, planes, restaurants, waiting rooms, and anyplace else where the words, "I'm bored!" are frequently heard. But with a little planning, you can whip out a activity tin for these very situations.

Photo by Eleanor PJ

The front of the tin. Photo by Eleanor PJ

Resourceful mum Eleanor PJ created the play set above for her son to bring to camp, as electronic devices would be banned on the trip. She used an empty pencil tin, and included a variety of toys and games for some old-fashioned, tactile fun: LEGO bricks, coloured pens and Post-It notes. She drew game grids on the inside of the lid using a Sharpie, and then stuck gems onto magnet paper to use as game pieces. Eleanor covered the front of the tin with a sheet of whiteboard paper, and attached a wipe-clean pen with a magnetic lid to it.

"My son loved being able to play games with the friend he shared a tent with," Eleanor says. "He thought it was pretty neat."

BuzzFeed also has some fun ideas for making .

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Post-it</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharpie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BuzzFeed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DIY Activity Tin Keeps Kids Occupied Without An iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleanor PJ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleanor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
