<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429884849699429</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/football/neymar-psg-transfer-news-shirt-sales-debut-pique-photo-money-messi-value-to-double-barcelona/news-story/a393090d93ca2ffa0e71452c4956350b</url>
  <title>Staggering number of Neymar shirts already sold</title>
  <content>
NEYMAR started repaying his mammoth transfer fee on the day he was introduced as Paris Saint-Germain's marquee summer signing with the club selling more than 10,000 shirts bearing his name on Friday.
The 25-year-old Brazilian was signed from Barcelona for a world record 222-million euros ($330m) but with shirts emblazoned with his name and No.10 on the back selling at an average of 100 euros, PSG generated 1 million euros on his first day.
If PSG can keep that up, they would have recouped the transfer fee by mid-March, within the first season of Neymar's five-year deal -- although in reality that revenue is shared with shirt manufacturer Nike, meaning it would actually take twice as long to pay for the player.
Such is the demand for the shirt at one of two PSG stores, on the iconic Champs Elysees boulevard and the team's outlet at their Parc des Princes home, that shoppers on Saturday will be limited to a single jersey each.
Here are some of the big talking points from
WHY NEYMAR MOVED TO PSG
"I wanted to come to Paris and it was only linked to finding a new challenge. It is not because I was not the star at Barcelona, I fitted in very well there," the 25-year-old said.
"This is not what I am looking for here. PSG deserve trophies and I will have new trophies, this is what motivates me, I want to dream bigger."
NEYMAR NOT MOTIVATED BY MONEY
Neymar denied that he had been motivated by either money or the desire to have top billing after being often overshadowed in Barcelona by teammate Lionel Messi.
"This is not what I'm really looking for in Paris - [I'm looking for] new trophies, new challenges, and that's what motivates me," Neymar insisted.
Anyone who thought he moved for money "don't know anything about my personal life," he added. "I was never motivated by money."
"This move is for ambition, they have a similar ambition to mine," Neymar added. "I want something bigger, a bigger challenge and my heart made that decision and made me follow.
"That is why I am here. I want to give my best to help the club win trophies. It was one of the most difficult decisions I have ever taken."

THAT PIQUE PHOTO
Neymar also revealed that he had asked former teammate Gerard Pique not to post a picture of the pair which included the caption: "Se queda" - meaning "he stays".
"He published the picture but I'd asked him not to. I had not yet made my decision."
"He (Pique) wanted to express his feelings and I respect him, he's a great friend. The first person I told I was leaving was the Barca coach (Ernesto Valverde). He was the most important person to tell."

A post shared by Gerard Pique (@3gerardpique) on

NEYMAR 'READY' TO MAKE PSG DEBUT
Neymar said he was fit and ready to make his Paris Saint-Germain debut on Saturday in their Ligue 1 opener against Amiens at the Parc des Princes.
The forward will be presented to fans before Saturday's match, but said he could play a part, despite having not yet spoken to PSG coach Unai Emery.
"I always want to play, so I am ready to do so tomorrow," Neymar said at his unveiling on Friday.
"I have trained in pre-season. I stopped for two days, but I am ready, I've seen the pitch and I want to put the PSG shirt on and play."
"I will speak with the staff, I will wait for their green light."
Neymar is due to be unveiled to the PSG fans at 3.45pm (1345 GMT) ahead of their opening Ligue 1 match of the season against newly-promoted Amiens at 5.15pm.
NEYMAR VALUE WILL 'DOUBLE IN TWO YEARS' - PSG PRESIDENT
Neymar will more than double his value inside two years, PSG president Nasser Al-Khelaifi said.
The 25-year-old's price tag has stunned the football world, more than doubling the previous record Manchester United paid for Paul Pogba.
But Al-Khelaifi, accompanied by Neymar at a press conference in Paris on Friday, said: "There are not two Neymars in the world. I would love for us to meet in two years and see what his value will be compared to today. At least the double."
"When you look at Neymar as a brand with PSG, I don't think that it is expensive actually, because we're going to make much more money than what we paid," the Qatari businessman said.
"For me personally, Neymar is the best player in the world. Our fans have always dreamt of having Neymar here at Paris Saint-Germain."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parc</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al-Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernesto Valverde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>READY' TO MAKE PSG DEBUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEYMAR MOVED TO PSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PIQUE PHOTO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasser Al-Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEYMAR NOT MOTIVATED BY MONEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pogba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Pique (@3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unai Emery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amiens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DOUBLE IN TWO YEARS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEYMAR VALUE WILL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Pique</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GMT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champs Elysees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ligue 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
