<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430310051465076</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/north-korea-could-lose-us1-billion-in-exports-under-fresh-sanctions-20170805-gxq0gj.html</url>
  <title>North Korea could lose $US1 billion in exports under fresh sanctions</title>
  <content>
New York Times: The United States hit North Korea at the United Nations with a proposed set of unprecedented economic penalties, punctuated by a one-third cut in its export revenue, to punish the isolated country for its missile and nuclear tests.
The penalties were contained in a draft Security Council resolution to penalise North Korea that US diplomats have been working on since North Korea launched its first successful intercontinental ballistic missile a month ago, demonstrating an ability to attack the US homeland.Photo: AP
North Korea, which considers the United States its most dangerous and implacable enemy, conducted a second successful ballistic missile test last week.
Under North Korea's leader, Kim Jong-un, the country has boasted of its increasingly sophisticated missiles in rejection of UN prohibitions. The North has also threatened to punish the United States and its other perceived foes -- South Korea and Japan -- with a "nuclear sword of justice."

The US-drafted resolution, which was circulated on Friday to all 15 Security Council members, is scheduled to be put to a vote Saturday afternoon.
It was circulated after US diplomats held extensive discussions about the language with China and Russia, suggesting that the two will back the measure or at least not block it with their veto power.

Support for the draft resolution from China, North Korea's most important trading partner, is considered critical. If achieved, it will partly reflect what diplomats have called China's waning tolerance for Kim's belligerent behaviour.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The draft resolution, which needs at least nine yes votes for approval, would be the most punitive of any resolution over the past 11 years aimed at pressuring North Korea into abandoning its nuclear arms ambitions.Photo: AP
A Security Council diplomat told reporters that the draft resolution's provisions banning North Korea's exports of coal, iron, iron ore, lead, lead ore and seafood, would together lop roughly $US1 billion ($1.26 billion) from the country's $US3 billion in annual export revenue.
The diplomat, who spoke on the condition of anonymity keeping with protocol, said it was the first time that entire sectors of North Korea's export economy would be banned. He called it "the most impactful and expansive set of sanctions to date."Photo: AP
The draft resolution, which "condemns in the strongest terms" the July 4 and July 28 missile tests, would also place new limits on North Korea's joint ventures and Foreign Trade Bank, and prohibit the country from sending more workers to overseas jobs -- another important source of revenue for the impoverished nation of 25 million people.
Nonetheless, the draft resolution did not go nearly as far as what the US ambassador, Nikki R. Haley, had demanded after the July 4 ballistic missile test.
Declaring US exasperation with the ineffectiveness of existing sanctions, Haley called for cutoffs of North Korea's access to foreign money and oil for its military. Those steps were not taken.
New York Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikki R. Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-drafted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Security Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Trade Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
