<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430743843165788</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/music/chris-cornells-daughter-toni-performs-moving-rendition-of-hallelujah-for-dad-and-linkin-park/news-story/2367548c01d55d78c47f32255f06a37f</url>
  <title>Chris Cornell's daughter sings for dad and Linkin Park</title>
  <content>
MERE months after her dad and Soundgarden frontman Chris Cornell committed suicide and weeks after their good family friend and Linkin Park singer Chester Bennington died the same way, 12-year-old Toni Cornell has taken to the stage to perform an emotional tribute for the two talented singers - and it'll leave you bawling.
The spitting image of her late dad, Toni proved she not only inherited Chris' looks, she also inherited his incredible voice.
The musical guest for Friday's Good Morning America was supposed to be Linkin Park however, in the , the band decided not to perform.
Instead Toni and Ryan Tedder's band One Republic took to the stage and performed Leonard Cohen's Hallelujah, leaving the entire crowd bawling.
"It's an honour to perform this for my dad and Chester and sing for them," Toni told the show's host Michael Strahan.
The emotional tribute for the two late singers drew tears from hundreds in the crowd and even one of the band's violinists, but Toni stayed strong throughout the performance as photos of her dad and Chester flashed behind them.
While the song Hallelujah is a common choice in a time of mourning, Toni's reason for performing the popular song wasn't a random one.
At the funeral of her father in late May, Bennington performed Hallelujah for his close friend
Chris Cornell after his suicide on May 18. Two months later, on July 22, the Linkin Park singer died the same way.
The two late singers were extremely close friends. Bennington was the godfather to Cornell's 11-year-old son Chris.
They also toured together in 2007 and 2008 where Bennington joined Cornell for a version of Temple of the Dog's Hunger Strike, and Cornell performed alongside Linkin Park for their 2000 hit Crawling.
And just as the musicians were linked throughout their lives, they will also
Bennington died on what would've been Cornell's 53rd birthday and the two musicians' suicides were eerily very similar.
Just as Bennington often joined the Soundgarden frontman on stage, so too did his daughter.
Back in 2015, Toni joined her father on stage in New York to perform a cover of Bob Marley's Redemption Song.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cornell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linkin Park</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cornell's 53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonard Cohen's Hallelujah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni Cornell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Republic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Cornell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Strahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunger Strike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soundgarden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennington</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Tedder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday's Good Morning America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester Bennington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Marley's Redemption Song</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temple of the Dog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
