<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429798950352564</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/major-rise-online-child-exploitation-rates-alarmin/3209152/</url>
  <title>Major rise in online child exploitation rates alarming</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN police are experiencing a "tsunami" of reports of online child sex exploitation, including hundreds of thousands of images and videos of children, as young as babies, being sexually abused and tortured.

But jail terms for those involved in the depraved behaviour are not keeping pace with the crimes they are committing,

The startling figures, from the Australian Federal Police, come as research reveals that on average, online paedophiles convicted under Commonwealth laws get only two to three years in jail. This is despite the maximum available sentence being 15 years.

As of yesterday, the AFP had received 5700 reports of child exploitation so far this year. In the whole of 2016 there were 8000 reports and this years figures are up from 3500 reports in 2013 and 4500 in 2014.

Police believe Sam may have hidden the bodies of three people
CLAIRE got to experience a week in the RAAF.
Torture trial continues after house of horror claims.
A real estate resurgence hit Nambour in the mid to late 1990s.
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
