<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430825447544983</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/real-estate/foreign-buyer-trumps-downsizers-to-snap-up-bridgehill-residences-penthouse-20170803-gxp0uq</url>
  <title>Foreign buyer trumps downsizers to snap up Bridgehill Residences' penthouse</title>
  <content>
A foreign buyer has bought one of the last two penthouses at luxury apartment tower Bridgehill Residences in Sydney's Milsons Point for just under $8 million, just in time to beat the double stamp duty surcharge on July 1 and trumping cashed up downsizers to the deal.
The new 285 square metre penthouse, unit 1702, has views of the Sydney Harbour and Lavender Bay from every room and occupies half of level 17 at 80 Alfred Street South. No expense was spared in the unit, which comes with Miele appliances, an entertainer's terrace, a study and a guest powder room.
"We were inundated with inquiries from people looking to downsize from the upper north shore, lower north shore and eastern suburbs."
"We received several offers, however, the ultimate purchaser was an offshore buyer looking to buy before the July 1 stamp duty deadline," luxury residential agent Savills' Adam Ross said.

Conrad Taylor

Mr Ross and colleagues Justine Mullane and William Laing handled the expressions of interest sale which hit the market in June.

But this sale was not fully reflective of the foreign buyers' market, especially in apartments, which had "disappeared" since the surcharges came into effect on July 1, foreign property lawyer Apex Lawyers' Chris Sun said.
On June 1,  surcharge to 8 per cent as part of a series of tax changes designed to make . The annual land tax surcharge on foreign home owners will also increase to 2 per cent from the existing 0.75 per cent.
The deteriorating picture of  - which affects both the rental and purchase markets - was apparent in June when Census 2016 figures showed the number of households in Sydney with six or more people jumped 21 per cent from five years earlier.
Separate figures this week from the latest annual Household Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia (HILDA) survey show  from 36 per cent to 25 per cent in the 12 years to 2014.

Supplied

NSW now has the highest foreign buyer stamp duty surcharge in Australia.  and .
"Foreign buyers disappeared after the increased surcharge commenced," Ms Sun said.
"Local buyers are still active but it's going to be disaster for most of the off-the plan-developments.
"It was much worse than we thought. We haven't received a single foreign investor review board (FIRB) application since July 1."

Supplied

At the height of foreign buyer interests in NSW residential properties in 2014 and 2015, Apex Lawyers received hundreds of application in each of those years. Even last year, as house prices continued to rise, there were still many buyers, Ms Sun said.
"I talked to an agent the other day and he said they would start introducing their foreign buyers to Queensland properties because of its lower house prices and surcharge. There are still many buyers but they may not be as interested in NSW properties as they were before," she said.
Apartment project marketer Home789 chief executive Walton Chu has seen the same.
International housing site for g also said she had seen a 50 per cent fall in inquiries in NSW. Many are looking to overseas markets such as South East Asia and the UK.

Conrad Taylor

"These rules will hit the mid-range buyers rather than luxury buyers because in the grand scheme of things luxury buyers are buying for lifestyle reasons not investment," she said.
While there might be slim pickings of foreign buyers, there were plenty of downsizers looking at luxury apartments, Mr Ross said. His team is expecting a scramble for the last Bridgehill 240sq m penthouse, particularly with the number of downsizers flocking to Milsons Point recently.
A downsizer from Castle Cove, north of Milsons Points, snapped up rugby league great Greg Mullane's 345sq m three-bedder with views at 11/1 Northcliff Street for $7.8 million in April.
The 508sq m three-bedroom penthouse at the Mirvac-built "Latitude" tower at 55 Lavender Street sold for $8 million last month.

Conrad Taylor

At between $15,000 to $26,000 a square metre, these penthouses were a "bargain" compared to those exchanged directly opposite the harbour at Circular Quay.
The most recent new penthouses at  headquarters sold for $95,500 a square metre late last year.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castle Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Household Income</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sun</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ross</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walton Chu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred Street South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milsons Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justine Mullane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northcliff Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conrad Taylor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirvac-built</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lavender Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home789</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIRB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Milsons Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridgehill 240</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savills' Adam Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Circular Quay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lavender Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-east Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apex Lawyers' Chris Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Laing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apex Lawyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridgehill Residences</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Census 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Mullane's 345</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
