<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430614994145809</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/more-sports/world-athletics-championships-mo-farah-strikes-gold-again-in-10000m-as-winning-streak-continues/news-story/922cfd1ddd274795c9c62c155faa792e</url>
  <title>Farah going out in customary style</title>
  <content>
TO put it in simple terms Mo Farah is the Usain Bolt of distance running.
The pair have become good friends as they've dominated their respective events over recent years and both are retiring after these world championships.
Farah lived up to his part in this grand farewell party by taking the opening gold medal on offer in the 10,000m, continuing what is an extraordinary - Bolt-like - winning streak.

The British superstar has now won 10 consecutive global track distance titles and will chase No. 11 in the 5000m later in the week.
Farah's medal haul includes four Olympic gold medals and six world titles.
The streak started at the 2011 world championships in Daegu in the 5000m and he hasn't been beaten in either event since.
Farah admitted he was emotional at the start last night in his return to the stadium where he won double Olympic gold five years ago.
He even gestured mid-race to the capacity crowd to get more involved as he made a decisive move to the front of the pack.
"I had to get my head around it," Farah said. "I got a bit emotional at the start and I just had to get in the zone.
"I was trying to play with the guys' heads by getting the crowd in because it wasn't an easy race.
"What a way to end my career in London. Tonight was special because the guys put it out there.
"I knew at 12 laps to go when they went hard from there I knew it was going to be tough. It was about believing in my sprint finish and knowing that I have been in that position before.
"It helped a lot having that experience and it shows that anything is possible if you train hard."
There were some anxious moments for the hometown hero over the final lap as he dealt with three Africans who were determined to take down the champion.
Twice he was clipped and almost fell before once again finding another surge over the final 50 metres to claim victory in 26min 49.51 sec.
Uganda's Joshua Kiprui Cheptegei took the silver medal in 26:49.94 sec with Kenya's Paul Kipngetich Tanui bronze (26:50.60 sec).
"I didn't want to go down," Farah said. "I didn't want to let other people down."
While there is no doubting the British public's love for Sir Mo - he was awarded a knighthood after his London 2012 heroics - it has been a tough year for the distance star away from the track.
His coach Alberto Salazar is under investigation by the United States Anti-Doping Agency over a raft of alleged doping violations, while Farah has been unable to shake off questions surrounding two missed drugs tests in the run up to that London 2012 success.
This year there have been further concerns over the improper documentation of a legal infusion he received before the 2014 London Marathon, and the emergence of an IAAF document from 2015 that features the notation "Likely doping; Passport suspicious: further data is required" next to Farah's name.
A second IAAF file, dated April 2016, appeared to clear Farah of any suspicion and the four-time Olympic champion has angrily refuted any suggestion that he would ever break anti-doping rules, telling the media: "You guys just make something out of nothing."
It's an asterisk which may never go away which is unfortunate because like Bolt, the world is unlikely to ever see a distance runner get anywhere close to the record Farah will have when he bids farewell next week.
Australia's Patrick Tiernan, who had been considered an outside medal chance, had a mid-race meltdown and shuffled over the line in last place.
"It's really disappointing. I knew I was in good shape. It was just bad," he said. "It just started hurting and then I just didn't want to get lapped. It was horrible. I've got the 5000m, though. I'll be back."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Patrick Tiernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London 2012</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Anti-Doping Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya's Paul Kipngetich Tanui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt-like</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Mo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farah</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uganda's Joshua Kiprui Cheptegei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mo Farah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberto Salazar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Marathon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAAF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daegu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
