<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430138252771983</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/12/54/rah-radiologists-deferred-procedures-to-incur-overtime-allowances-colleague-claims</url>
  <title>Royal Adelaide Hospital radiologists deferred procedures to incur overtime allowances, colleague claims</title>
  <content>
9NEWS has obtained emails sent between doctors at the Royal Adelaide Hospital (RAH) which claim stroke specialists were deferring procedures so they could earn massive overtime allowances.
The emails, tendered in coronial proceedings, claim the hospital's two interventional neuro-radiologists (INR), Dr Rebecca Scroop and Dr James Taylor, were regularly scheduling procedures after-hours so they could make more money.
The court has heard each doctor earns $1.1 million a year - more than four times their annual salaries. 
The emails were written in 2015 - 2016 by a colleague in the hospital's radiology team, Dr Suzanne McKee, who said the practice was detrimental to patient care.
"Clearly the system is being manipulated by some proceduralists to ensure maximum remuneration," Dr McKeen wrote.
"Money is being splurged on these two crooks... clearly that is not in the department's best interests."
The SA Coroner Mark Johns granted 9NEWS access to the email correspondence as part of open reporting on the Coronial Inquest into the deaths of two stroke victims.

Related Articles

Michael John Russell, 60, and Leslie Robert Graham, 87, died in April this year while the hospital's only two INR specialists were on leave.
The court has heard the RAH was seemingly "understaffed for emergencies" when the men presented with life-threatening conditions.
The emails tendered to court were sent to the hospital's head of radiology, Dr Jim Buckley, who has been put under the spotlight during his evidence to the fast-tracked inquest.
Dr Buckley has admitted he "inadvertently" signed off on both INR doctors taking annual leave at the same time, leaving a four-day window when there was no specialist on-call.
A radiologist based at Flinders Medical Centre, Dr Steve Chryssidis, instead gave emergency treatment to the two men on April 18, but there were complications and they both died.
The Coroners Court has also heard the INR specialists opposed hiring a third stroke specialist to cover on-call emergencies because it would mean having to share their $2.2 million combined incomes.
An internal review at the hospital in 2013 recommended SA Health employ a third specialist to supplement the two doctors, who serviced a 24-hour roster, and were facing increased demand.
A third specialist was hired at the RAH this week, four years after the recommendation.
Dr Buckley denied that financial return for the INR clinicians was a motivating factor for the delays in the hiring process. 
He told the Coroner, Dr Taylor and Dr Scroop were supportive of hiring a third specialist but that "poisonous relationships" meant there was resistance to certain radiologists joining the team.
Dr Buckley said the two specialists were talented, hard-working, and committed to patient care and claims by Dr McKeen could be malicious because of a soured romantic relationship.
"Dr McKeen has a grudge against Dr Taylor... they had a relationship some time ago that turned sour... I think she was keen to clip Dr Taylor's wings," he said.
He said he believed Dr McKeen was "motivated by a desire to damage him".
The SA Coroner is investigating whether confusion as to who was covering for the doctors resulted in Mr Russell and Mr Graham receiving delayed treatment and whether that contributed to their deaths.
Court documents show that incident was not the first time both stroke specialists had been rostered off on the same day and under-staffing had been an issue at the RAH as early as 2012.
In 2015, Dr McKeen wrote: "There is no justification to allow both Taylor and Scroop to be on leave on the same day."
"It would seem prudent to have at least one consultant available on site for urgent clot extraction during normal working hours.
"The current practice is unacceptable... the expectation is that something be done as a matter of priority."
The inquest into the deaths is continuing.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Buckley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INR</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Coroner Mark Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr McKeen</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Suzanne McKee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Medical Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie Robert Graham, 87</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Steve Chryssidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Rebecca Scroop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael John Russell, 60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Jim Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Scroop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scroop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Coroner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coronial Inquest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Taylor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr James Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coroners Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
