<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430009403752192</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/rwanda-votes-with-paul-kagame-likely-winner-20170805-gxpzqk.html</url>
  <title>Rwanda votes, with Paul Kagame likely winner</title>
  <content>
Nairobi, Kenya: Rwandans went to the polls in an election that was widely expected to extend the long rule of President Paul Kagame, who has guided the country with a steady and at times repressive hand after a genocide two decades ago.
Kagame appears to be hugely popular at home and has been widely praised abroad for bringing stability to his traumatised country after a 1994 genocide left hundreds of thousands dead. But there is no viable opposition in Rwanda, and dissenting views are frequently silenced.Photo: AP
Victory would allow Kagame to remain in power until 2024 and, under recent changes to the constitution, would give him the option of running for two more five-year terms after that, although he has suggested that he would not do so.
With nearly half of Friday's vote counted, Kagame was drawing the support of 99 per cent of those casting ballots, according to preliminary results.Photo: AP
The two opposition candidates -- Frank Habineza of the Democratic Green Party and the independent Philippe Mpayimana, a former journalist, had yet to reach 1 per cent of the vote, according to the electoral commission. A third challenger, Diane Rwigara, who had been considered Kagame's strongest opponent, was disqualified in July.
Provisional vote results are to be announced on Saturday afternoon.

The likely re-election of Kagame has raised concerns that Africa's "forever presidents" club will gain a new member, and that other leaders in the region will feel reassured that they, too, can cling to power.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

David Himbara, who was Kagame's economic adviser until 2010, when the two men had a falling out, has accused authorities of manipulating statistics to make Rwanda appear wealthier and more advanced than it really is.Photo: AP
Rwanda has one of the fastest-growing economies in Africa, expanding by 8 per cent annually, according to the World Bank. But it is still very poor: More than half of the population lives on less than $US1.25 a day. "He says he has built an economic lion, when Rwanda is a midget in the region," Himbara said.
Although Kagame has sought to compare himself with strong leaders in Asia who transformed their economies, "in Rwanda's case, you have the suppression of human rights that is not delivering economic development," Himbara asserted. "That trade-off is not working."
New York Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kagame</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rwanda</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippe Mpayimana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Habineza, of the Democratic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Paul Kagame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Himbara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Kagame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rwandans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diane Rwigara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Himbara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nairobi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
