<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430095303098696</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/where-to-now-for-aru-as-melbourne-rebels-look-after-vru-takes-licence-20170805-gxpz8m.html</url>
  <title>Where to now for ARU, as Melbourne Rebels look after VRU takes licence</title>
  <content>
Melbourne Rebels are believed to be safe from the Australian Rugby Union's chopping block after the Victorian Rugby Union took hold of the licence.
It's understood that Andrew Cox's Imperium Sports Group quietly sold the licence and all shares in the club to the VRU for as little as $1 on Friday in a move which stops the ARU from buying back the Rebels and shutting them down.Photo: AAP
Cox had previously stated he would not sell the licence back if it meant the team was closed down and the Rebels were continuing to sign players for next season.
The Rebels would not comment on the sale on Saturday as it is understood the deal won't be official until the middle of next week and it is further understood that Cox has resigned as a director of the club.
The ARU was in arbitration with the Western Force last week despite owning the Force's licence as the governing body wanted to cut the club but Rugby WA and the Force's management are enforcing an alliance agreement to operate the club until the end of the current television deal in 2020.
So the Rebels sale could give the ARU no way to cut either club for next season.

Earlier this year the ARU agreed to cut one side if South Africa cut two of their teams so to reduce Super Rugby down to 15 sides and South Africa has fulfilled its part of the deal in July.
The Southern Kings and the Cheetahs were "allowed to purse other international opportunities" with both clubs announcing last week that they were joining the European based Pro 12, which now becomes the Pro 14, for the upcoming season.
The Rugby Union Players Association has advocated for a 16-team competition and keeping five teams in Australia.
The ARU released a statement on Friday night saying it had received confirmation of the deal but had not been told of it by the Rebels or Imperium.
"The Australian Rugby Union (ARU) has tonight received confirmation from a third party that ownership of the Melbourne Rebels had transferred from Imperium Group to the Victorian Rugby Union," the statement read.
"The Melbourne Rebels have an obligation under their Participation Deed to inform ARU of any change of ownership. To date, ARU has received no such communication from the Melbourne Rebels despite recent attempts to confirm their position.
"ARU is urgently seeking to confirm the terms on which this transfer occurred."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VRU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Rebels</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRO14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Participation Deed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby Union Players Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Cox's Imperium Sports Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperium Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
