<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430739548198384</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/the-two-players-west-coast-eagles-must-sew-up-for-new-contracts/news-story/003cf8f8c7bf6b1c2351245701aefb93</url>
  <title>The two players Eagles must sew up</title>
  <content>
WEST Coast have been urged to sign Jeremy McGovern and Elliot Yeo to long-term deals to guarantee the club's re-emergence as a premiership force.
Both McGovern, 25, and Yeo, 23, are coming out of contract at the end of next season.
The star duo are considered two of the club's most prized assets, with McGovern rated as the league's best intercept mark and Yeo on track to earn All-Australian selection following a career-best season.
However, The Weekend West understands there has been no significant advancement around new deals that would keep either player at the Eagles beyond 2018.
McGovern will be a restricted free agent at the end of his existing deal. The Eagles are entering a delicate phase following the retirements of Brownlow medallists Matt Priddis and Sam Mitchell, with an aggressive transition of their list planned for the next 12 months.
Eagles adamant on opening stadium

The uncertainty over West Coast's future comes at a time when McGovern's brother Mitch is being targeted by Fremantle and the Eagles.
McGovern has publicly spoken about wanting to play alongside his younger sibling. The stance could yet have a bearing on the future home of both players.
Dual North Melbourne premiership player David King said McGovern and Yeo were the two most important players for West Coast to retain.
"When you compare them to the competition, they're two players who would walk into any team and be in the top half a dozen of most clubs regardless of where they are on the ladder," King said.
"McGovern has been a phenomenon really to be able to play a whole host of different roles for that team. When he's really asked to go and do what his staple is and that's at centre-half back and to intercept mark, he's been brilliant.
"Elliot Yeo has proven to be a real asset as a run-with midfielder, a prime on-baller and obviously as an intercept half back. He's a player you've got to build around."
Adelaide left the door open for their out-of-contract McGovern to be lured home with a modest initial offer to stay, worth about $370,000 next season.
Fremantle are reportedly willing to offer a five-year, $750,000-a-season deal to secure the 22-year-old, who is fresh from a game-saving pack mark and goal to seal a dramatic draw against Collingwood last Sunday.
He is believed to have been invited for a personal tour of Fremantle's Cockburn facilities, but has not yet taken up the offer.
It is understood that if Mitch McGovern leaves Adelaide, the Dockers are favoured to secure his services, following in the footsteps of his dad, Andrew, who played 63 games for the club and was part of its inaugural squad.
King said the younger McGovern was being "over-valued" based on form, but that West Coast had good reason to pay more for the WA product.
"If you get his (McGovern's) brother, you go a long way towards shoring up the pairing," King said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeo, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle's Cockburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekend West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JEREMY McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliot Yeo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
