<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429880554732069</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/joel-selwood-racing-clock-to-be-fit-for-next-week-after-ankle-injury-in-loss-to-sydney/news-story/0d53d71a2dacb397f62ad9a59b84f11f</url>
  <title>Cats skipper waits on ankle scans</title>
  <content>
JOEL Selwood was on crutches at Geelong this morning but remains optimistic about his chances of playing against Richmond next week.
The inspirational Cats skipper left the field twice after hurting his left ankle in two separate incidents in .
"It's sore, just as we probably thought it would be," he told Fox Sports News.
MRP WATCH:
JUMPER PUNCH:
"We'll have some scans and see how it comes up.
"The second one I probably felt a little bit more, I tried to get out for the early bit of the last quarter and just couldn't get it going so I decided to call it a night."
The Cats' spot in the top two is vulnerable after last night's defeat and if Richmond wins against Hawthorn tomorrow, next week's clash will be pivotal in the fight for a home qualifying final.
Selwood rejected an assessment last night from sports medico Dr Peter Larkins that he could miss three weeks with the injury.
"I didn't see Doc Larkins at all last night so I'm not sure how he could come to that, he hadn't seen it at all. We hadn't had it scanned at that stage so we'll just have to wait and see.
"(I'm) definitely hopeful, obviously non-weight bearing for the weekend and it's amazing how they can come up."
Selwood's teammate Daniel Menzel told Fox Sports News Selwood would do everything possible to play against the Tigers.
"He's going to do everything throughout the week and, being Joel, I'd expect him to play."
Selwood sent a major scare through the Geelong camp during Friday night's loss against the Sydney Swans, limping off Simonds Stadium assisted by two Cats trainers after an awkward collision with Kurt Tippett in the second term.
One of the toughest players in the AFL, Selwood was then taken down into the Geelong rooms but was seen doing ball drills and running around in the Geelong rooms during the halftime break before taking his place at the centre bounce for the start of the third term.
But another clash with a Swan, this time Lance Franklin, in the third quarter encouraged Scott to place his star onballer in cotton wool.
However Scott was very optimistic about Selwood's prognosis.
"I'm actually confident enough to say now that he'll be fine," Scott told reporters post-game.
"Clearly in the last quarter, the discussion was around whether we should keep pushing him through, make his chances of playing next week lower. Given that, we sit ere pretty confident that he'll be OK.
Scott Selwood said his brother would push hard to get up for Round 21.
"All I know was that it was an ankle and he didn't finish off the game," Selwood told reporters post-match.
"He'll reassess, he'll ice it - he'll do everything he can. He'll put himself in a position to try and play next week or get back as quickly as possible. That's the Joel I know."
It loomed as a major blow for the Cats, who were already without fellow star on-baller Patrick Dangerfield due to suspension.
Selwood has been one of the most durable players for Geelong during the club's successful past decade. On Friday night, he joined Henry Young in second spot for most games as Geelong captain with 137 games, five behind Reg Hickey.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Tippett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reg Hickey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doc Larkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP WATCH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Menzel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Peter Larkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
