<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430572044472444</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/is-super-rugby-really-worth-saving-ive-got-a-better-idea-20170804-gxpf3c.html</url>
  <title>Is Super Rugby really worth saving? I've got a better idea</title>
  <content>
Super Rugby is done and dusted for 2017 and for the Australian franchises the end of the season couldn't have come soon enough.
But while the season is over, uncertainty still surrounds the future of two Australian teams, the Western Force and Melbourne Rebels. There has been months of speculation about how we fix the Super Rugby model. And it needs to be fixed because it is flawed.

Up Next

Neymar unveiled as most expensive soccer player

01:56

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Hooper steps up as Wallabies skipper

Michael Hooper has been appointed Wallabies captain, with long-serving Stephen Moore stepping down from the role ahead of his international retirement at the end of the season.

The plan at the moment is for the Australian conference to be cut down to four teams - when that comes about is anyone's guess - the Kiwis will keep five sides and there will be four teams from South Africa. Throw in our Argentinian and Japanese friends and there's your make-up for 2018. Back to Super 15.
But are we happy with that? Whoever gets culled out of the Rebels or Force certainly won't be, but I'd say "no" because of a different reason.Photo: AAP
Put simply the whole thing needs a massive overhaul.
By culling three teams all we are really doing is keeping the same convoluted system and rolling out the same product. That just doesn't make any sense.

Fans are losing touch when their teams play in South African and, therefore, losing out. The argument has always been that South Africa has financial clout - largely because it's in a similar time zone to Britain and can deliver content at the right time for pay TV - and that's why we need them.

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The issue for Australian fans is that unless you get up at 3am, you're not going to see our blokes play. So what audience are we targeting?Photo: AP
It's just another reason the game is losing its identity.
We need to change things up, and I like the idea of a trans-Tasman competition, with some support from the South Pacific islands.
It's time for a complete overhaul. We need to cut ties with South Africa and align ourselves with New Zealand and our Pacific neighbours.
Surely, if you have a product that includes the best rugby-playing country in the world it would be an easy sell to broadcasters around the globe? No matter what time of the day it's on.
The idea of an Australia-New Zealand-Pacific islands competition is not new, but it could be just the thing to regenerate interest in the game in Australia.
New Zealand Rugby Union boss Steve Tew has said he would prefer the Kiwis threw their lot in with South Africa, bypassing Australia, if there was to be any change​.
So to keep the New Zealanders happy in a new trans-Tasman competition, their existing five franchises could even be extended to six teams to sweeten the deal. From an Australian perspective, even four teams is ambitious. I would go so far as to say three teams would be ideal, to make sure they are all strong and healthy.
The two Pacific Island teams would need incredible support from World Rugby. Firstly, to lure players back from Europe by making funds available and, secondly, to develop pathways for juniors to make sure their futures are strong. I can just picture the massive support they would receive here and in New Zealand.
Each team in my brave new world would play the others just once with the top four to make the finals. A top four so you don't reward mediocrity. You have to beat the best to be the best. No token top six or a conference leader. Put simply, win and you're in.
The season could run from March to May. Twelve weeks (including finals) and you're done. Short, sharp and snappy. We crown a winner, then roll into Test matches after a short break.
Not enough games, you say? We have to limit the product so that it doesn't become saturated and stale; hold something back so that each week is special, every game has meaning, waiting with anticipation for the whistle to start the match.
My main fear in this rugby revolution is that I may have just hammered the final nail into the coffin for Australian teams. Many people will be thinking that our boys would be no chance against the might of New Zealand. I don't agree.
I think the diluted set-up we have now has hindered growth in Australian rugby and the decision to cull a team is correct, even though I sympathise with those players whose necks are on the line and understand their fears about what will happen with their careers.
Australian rugby needs New Zealand rugby. Not the other way around. So we have to do everything in our power to get an ambitious rugby model like this across the line. If that means using something as simple as geography as the catalyst to get things moving, I say let's jump to it quick smart.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia-New Zealand-Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Rebels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentinian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Rugby Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Tew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
