<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430181202445216</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/lifestyle/the-best-ways-to-reduce-cleaning-time/news-story/4f11a8f0e1e24271111329a6e3436ca0</url>
  <title>The $2 trick that will save you hours of cleaning</title>
  <content>
If you're cleaning the house every weekend, you're doing life wrong.
Yes cleaning is a fact of life and yes, there's nothing better than a job well done, but what if you didn't have to do it so often?
Here are some tricks that will keep your house cleaner for longer:
1. Keep a window wiper in the shower
Wipe away suds and water marks from your shower screens before stepping out. This will stop soap scum from forming and keep your glass cleaner for longer. It only takes a few seconds and will save you from endless scrubbing. Bunnings and IKEA have them for $2.
2. Avoid white grout
Especially on tiled floors. Opt for a darker shade like grey to disguise dust and dirt. Then go ahead and store your broom and mop, because they won't be needed as often.
3. Try a bronze basin
White is a classic choice for bathrooms, but it's not so great for families with full heads of hair, shedding at an alarming rate. If your sink is constantly full of stray hairs, a bronze basin will do a better job at camouflage.
4. Or keep an old towel under your sink
Alternatively, keep an old hand or bath towel under the sink (or hidden away elsewhere) and pull it out after every hair-drying or straightening session to quickly clean up those sticky hairs.
5. Place a shoe holder at the front door
Encourage your family, housemates and guests to take their shoes off as soon as they walk in the door to save you from constant vacuuming. Try something elevated so it's easily spotted.
6. Have a 'dumping zone' for every family member
Designate a hook, storage basket or cubby to each family member so they have somewhere to store their coats, keys, school bags and whatever else they use on a daily basis. This way they can find their items easily each morning and they're out of the way in the evening and on the weekends.
7. Clean your air filters
If your air filters are full of dust, it's no wonder you're constantly wiping surfaces. Remove or clean them regularly, so the dust can be sucked up with the air and save you from death by dusting.
8. Eat at the dining table
Or the breakfast bar - always. Eating atop a surface will keep crumbs in the one spot and you can easily clean up after every meal without it spreading throughout other rooms in the house.
9. Clean out your fridge before your grocery shop
Before heading to the supermarket, take five minutes to check the contents of your fridge. Throw out anything that's expired or unusable, so that there's no chance of finding a mouldy banana or crusty leftovers weeks down the track.
You'll also have a clearer idea of what needs to be purchased and more room for fresh produce when you return.
10. Put your oven racks in the dishwasher every week
Oven spills are much more easily cleaned when the mess is fresh, so if you can remember to pop them in the dishwasher once a week, you won't have to soak and scrub stubborn, baked-on stains.
11. Peel and grate your vegetables cleverly
Vegetable peels seem to escape a surface wipe down every time. So beat them at their own game by peeling straight over your bin or in the compost. And when it comes to grating, do it straight into the bowl you're serving in or recipe you're concocting. No benchtop contact will teach those suckers.
12. Bedtime bath time
If you're a morning shower person, you should switch your habit to night-time or up your dose to twice a day. If you're clean before bed, you won't have to wash your sheets as often. And for the love of laundry, use a top sheet so you can wash your quilt less.
The story was published on  and is republished with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IKEA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
