<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430653648851837</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/world/north-america/the-generals-are-in-charge-at-the-white-house-good-or-bad-20170803-gxoh7h</url>
  <title>The generals are in charge at the White House, good or bad</title>
  <content>
"Send in the Marines."
No, it's not US President Donald Trump's reaction to  but a key element in Trump's political recovery plan.
Six months after telling Turnbull that he - Trump - would be seen as a "weak and ineffective leader" over accepting boat refugees from Australian detention centres on Manus Island and Nauru, the US President is attempting to turn that "weak and ineffective" image around by in effect militarising the White House.
After just a week into Trump's latest political recovery plan, however, the issue is no longer front of mind for those transfixed by the latest twist in the bizarre political drama gripping Washington.

Evan Vucci

In the past few days The Washington Post has dropped another bombshell by publishing transcripts of at times truculent phone conversations between Trump and his Mexican and Australian counterparts, President Enrique Pena Nieto and Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull, which took place in late January, or just a week into Trump's presidency.

This latest dump has meant that by week's end media focus had moved past the week-old Trump recovery plan.
But Trump, who attended a private military high school during his teenage years, has made three highly decorated US military men key political placements in an attempt to turn around his beleaguered Presidency. The White House is under siege from claimed Trump election campaign collusion with Russia, the tangling of Trump's own business interests with government decisions, failure to persuade Congress to repeal Obamacare, and the missile crisis with North Korea.
Whether it ultimately happens or not, impeachment has become part of the conversation about a US political scene marked by a sort of comic-book hysteria.
Counter-hysteria

PABLO MARTINEZ MONSIVAIS

Trump is attempting to overcome confusion, chaos and - yes - hysteria, by appointing retired US Marines general John Kelly . Kelly joins another retired US Marine Corps general, Jim "Mad Dog" Mattis, who is Defense Secretary, and still-on-active-duty US Army Lieutenant-General H. R. McMaster, who has been Trump's National Security Advisor since February.
In the United States the military has a more prominent role in public life than in Australia. For a start the President of the United States of America is also that country's Commander-in-Chief. However, these Trump appointments represent the most militarised peacetime White House in America's 230 years of independence.
It took just hours for the impact of the military-style takeover of key White House functions, with its clear chain-of-command system, to be felt. Kelly, who replaced under-siege White House chief of staff Reince Priebus, hours later fired White House communications director Anthony "the Mooch" Scaramucci, who had been in the position for 10 days.
"The Mooch" was like a meteor lighting up the sky, but soon hitting the earth. He managed to accuse White House chief strategist Steve Bannon of engaging in self-ravishment by oral means, and characterised Priebus as a "f---ing paranoid schizophrenic".

Evan Vucci

As US late night TV host Stephen Colbert put it: "Two weeks ago I hadn't heard of Anthony Scaramucci. Now I have to make an appointment to have the tattoo lasered off."
The outbursts from a soon-to-be-discarded White House "wise guy", who hails from Trump's home town New York borough of Queens, led to comparisons with the obscenity-riddled Joe Pesci character in the Martin Scorsese film Goodfellas, or a bit-part player from any Quentin Tarantino movie, or a cartoon character from Mad Magazine.
They also triggered US media speculation that "the Mooch" had been channelling the roiling resentments of a 3am tweeting, volatile, unpredictable Trump.
Since "the Mooch" left the building, Kelly has taken further steps to introduce order into a chaotic White House. According to US press reports, he has told aides that anyone briefing Trump must show him the information first. So Kelly is now the policy guard dog at the Oval Office door.

World History Archive / Alamy Stock Photo

Alt facts

In the past six months many of Trump's most controversial decisions have been attributed to bad information, partly because Trump is often swayed by the last person he talked to, or "fake news" bruited about by the alt right's alt media.
According to the US Politico site, he "has often posted some of his most controversial tweets while watching [the Rupert Murdoch-controlled] Fox News and stewing". Now Kelly's task is to ensure the information Trump receives is well based.
To achieve this, Kelly knows his raw political power as Trump's chief of staff is greater than that of Mattis, who presides over by far the most powerful military structure in the world, or McMaster, who advises the President every day on such crucial strategic issues as the North Koreans' test firing of intercontinental ballistic missiles, the fight to extinguish the so-called Islamic State as a military force in Syria and Iraq, or Russia's military irredentism in eastern Ukraine.

D. GORTON

Kelly is drawing on the power amassed by US presidents' chiefs of staff in the past 65 years, dating back to the presidency of World War Two military hero, Ike Eisenhower. Eisenhower fashioned the job in the White House after the US wartime military system, where army generals had powerful personal chiefs of staff.
Sherman Adams, a former governor of the north-eastern US state of New Hampshire, and hailing from the by now almost extinct liberal wing of the US Republican Party - one that traces its roots back to Abraham Lincoln - soon became the Eisenhower administration's most powerful figure as Ike's chief of staff. Every piece of paper Eisenhower saw had first to be placed on Adams' desk.
According to a 50s joke, two Democrats were talking and one said "Wouldn't it be terrible if Eisenhower died and [then Vice-President] Richard Nixon became President?" The other replied "Wouldn't it be terrible if Sherman Adams died and Eisenhower became President?"
Given the level of trouble Trump is in just six months into his stay at the White House, however, a more fitting comparison for John Kelly may prove to be Alexander Haig, who was Nixon's chief of staff as the Watergate scandal engulfed his presidency, and Nixon was forced to resign in disgrace.
Former US secretary of state Henry Kissinger has written that "by sheer willpower, dedication and self-discipline" Haig, who served as chief of staff in 1973 and 1974, "held the government together".
Like Kelly, Mattis and McMaster, Haig was a former military man as a US Army four-star general. He was used to a military chain of command. But when he perceived Nixon's presidency was finished, Haig moved decisively.
According to numerous accounts of the Watergate crisis, Haig first raised the resignation issue with Nixon, then urged him towards acceptance that this was the only course. He later instructed Vice-President Gerald Ford to prepare himself for succession.
Whether it falls to Kelly to be an Alexander Haig, or a Sherman Adams, or his own man, he will play a significant part in the continuing Washington drama.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's National Security Advisor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Colbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eisenhower</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commander-in-Chief</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haig</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Scorsese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupert Murdoch-controlled</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ike Eisenhower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nixon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMaster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evan Vucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukraine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abraham Lincoln</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAD Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Republican Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Hampshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alamy Stock Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherman Adams</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quentin Tarantino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-President Gerald Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watergate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Politico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World History Archive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D. GORTON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mattis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War Two</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Nixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Enrique Pena Nieto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Army Lieutenant-General H. R. McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obamacare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marine Corps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>States of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Pesci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Haig</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defense Secretary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodfellas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America's 230</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad Dog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pablo Martinez Monsivais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Kissinger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
