<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430353001138414</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/indigenous/labor-backs-indigenous-voice-referendum/news-story/b29c221621b829f7926a7fb9e80c90a3</url>
  <title>Labor backs indigenous referendum</title>
  <content>
Bill Shorten has declared Labor's unequivocal support for an indigenous voiced parliament, a declaration of recognition and a Makarrata Commission for truth telling of Australia's past, in a powerful appearance at the Garma Festival this morning.
"For us the question is not if we should do these things - but when and how. The parliament needs to start the process of engaging with the Australian people now," the Opposition Leader said.
"It does not come as a surprise to me that following upon the report of the Referendum Council, the parliament's next step must be to consider this report."
Mr Shorten has already faced trenchant criticism from indigenous leaders for his proposal to Malcolm Turnbull on Friday that a bipartisan parliamentary committee be established to consider the Referendum Council's report.
"It is such a miserable scene, the leadership scene in Australia," Cape York identity Noel Pearson said at a forum last night in response to the proposal.
However, Mr Shorten predicted today it would be possible to formulate a referendum question by the end of this year and denied his suggestion was for "a committee for the sake of a committee; it is not a mechanism for delay."
He intimated, however, that the parliamentary consideration would include dealing with the constitution's "race powers" - an element dismissed by the Referendum Council's deliberations as being irrelevant because it carried no guarantee against racially discriminatory laws being passed.
Some indigenous parliamentarians have been pushing for changes or deletions to the words 'race' in the constitution an approach now being regarded as "minimalist" and therefore inadequate.
Malcolm Turnbull said the Referendum Council's report left a number of unanswered questions that must be considered by the parliament.
These included: "What would the practical expression of the voice look like? What would the voice look like here for the Yolngu people (of north eastern Arnhem Land)? What would it look like for the people of western sydney? The largest population of Aboriginal peoples in Australia? Is our highest aspiration to have indigenous people outside the parliament providing advice to the parliament?"
"Or is it to have as many indigenous voices elected within our parliament? What impact would the voice have on issues like child protection and justice, where the legislation and responsibility largely rests with state and territory governments? These are important questions that require important consideration, but the answers are not beyond us."
"I acknowledge that indigenous Australians want deeper engagement with government and their fellow Australians, to be much better consulted, represented, in the political, social and economic life of our nation."
Gumatj clan leader and Garma festival host, Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu warned both leaders that their words had been "wonderful words indeed but they must say the same things in Canberra."
"I know it's hard - and it can be hard because there are other educated parliamentarians who are sitting listening to what the prime minister and the opposition leader are saying," he told them at the morning tea forum. "They are saying maybe to the liking of the politicians, (or) maybe to the disliking of the politicians, we don't know."
"Please be saying the same thing to the politicians and let them listen. Because this country has to listen to the Aborigines once and for all or they have to listen one hundred times more."
Having recently had his left foot amputated as a result of renal disease, Mr Yunupingu by the time he had a prosthetic fitted and was able to stand again - within a month, he hoped - he expected the joy of that recovery to be joined by the joy of seeing Mr Turnbull and Mr Shorten having taken the current proposals back to parliament.
"We have to be together" he said "we have to make a noise together. We have to sing out to the parliament together. We will carry the name Makarata together. As one people."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makarrata Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolngu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aborigines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makarata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumatj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
