<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431516937285377</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/adelaide/how-the-duel-between-paddy-ryder-and-sam-jacobs-will-set-up-showdown-43/news-story/a674ff1b76945256361474293d510f54</url>
  <title>Battle of two very different rucks</title>
  <content>
ALL-Australian ruck contenders Paddy Ryder and Sam Jacobs will be crucial in shaping Sunday's Showdown, and it can't come quickly enough for either of them.
The towering hitout contestants spent a little bit of time together this week to promote the game and there was a sense of urgency.
As ruckmen, they are different beasts.
FITNESS TEST:
Jacobs is big and strong, whereas Ryder is on the wrong side of 200cm but can leap like no other ruckman in the game and is more comfortable scooping up the ball below his knees.
The last time Jacobs and Ryder faced one another - in the Crows' 17-point win in Round 3 this year - there wasn't much between them.
Ryder had 48 hitouts and 11 disposals while Jacobs had 42 hitouts and nine disposals.
Ryder expects a similarly close duel on Sunday.
"He's certainly one of the best and I'll have to work really hard to try and beat him," Ryder said.
"I've just got to really work on what I've been doing and what I've been executing, playing my role."
Ryder said much had been taken from the close loss to the Crows in Showdown 42 earlier this year.
Chief among them was that the Power needed to lift when the game-deciding moments arrive.
"The main thing is the moment when the pressure rises in the game ... we came out of that knowing that we have to better in those situations," Ryder said.
"As a player, this is what you want to be involved in - big games.
"The pressure of the big games is what comes your way in finals and that's what you want to be good at."
To Jacobs, Ryder is the immediate challenge - stopping his high-leaping ways and giving his midfielders first look.
But he said the challenge from the Power came from several fronts.
"He's been one of the best ruckmen this year so it's going to be a another challenge," Jacobs said. "We're contrasting players, in a way - he's obviously very athletic and I've got to quell his influence.
"I'll try to play the game on my terms but I've got to understand his strengths as well. It's going to be a really-high pressure game again.
"Port Adelaide is really strong around the contest and they've actually got a really good contribution from all areas. I think they're a really well balanced team."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday's Showdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacobs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryder</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
