<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431211994604900</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4835707/vanity-fair-stands-by-angelina-jolie-audition-story/?cs=2372</url>
  <title>Vanity Fair stands by Angelina Jolie audition story</title>
  <content>
September's issue of Vanity Fair is set to become a keepsake, as it will most likely be the last time Angelina Jolie ever appears on the cover.

The Oscar-winner and the publication have been at loggerheads since the issue hit stands last week. The cover story centres on Jolie promoting her upcoming Netflix film, First They Killed My Father, about the Cambodian genocide, which is based on a true-life account of a survivor of the Khmer Rouge's regime as told through the eyes of a child.
The story described a  that casting directors of the movie played with Cambodian orphans.
According to the story written by Evgenia Peretz, crew gave money to children, many of them homeless, before taking it away and forcing them to explain why they had stolen it.
After the process was widely criticised, Jolie, via , accused  of taking the casting process out of context and demanded a retraction.
Jolie came out and denied the children were tricked, saying last week the report was "upsetting" and that "every measure was taken to ensure the safety, comfort and wellbeing of the children."
The filmmaker's team then reportedly asked Vanity Fair to remove the original paragraph from the online version of the story, and to run an apology in print and online that read, in part: "the children were not tricked as some has suggested."
Despite Jolie's legal team demanding something resembling a 72-point-size public apology,  is standing by its reporter and the story after publishing a transcript of the interview. It shows that Jolie was not present at the auditions but the crew told the children: "A camera's coming up and we want to play a game with you."
"In response to these requests, V.F. reviewed the transcript and audiotape of Peretz's interview with Jolie for the story. Peretz had recorded it on two devices. After reviewing the audiotape, V.F. stands by Peretz's story as published," an article online states.
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanity Fair</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khmer Rouge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolie</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evgenia Peretz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelina Jolie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V.F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peretz</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Killed My Father</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar-winner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
