<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431319368788153</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/people-are-immortalising-their-dead-loves-ones-in-stuffed-animals/</url>
  <title>People Are Immortalising Their Dead Loves Ones In Stuffed Animals</title>
  <content>
Yesterday, a video capturing a tender if somewhat eerie moment surfaced on Reddit, allegedly showing a woman listening to the voice of her late husband emanating from a Build-A-Bear. The title of the post suggests that she was married to her husband for 32 years before he died of cancer, and the bear was a gift to her from her children.

Photo: Getty

Surprisingly, this isn't the first (or second or even third) instance of the living using technology to preserve the memory of a dead loved one in a stuffed animal.

In December,  with a Build-A-Bear equipped with the voice and laugh of their grandfather who died of a stroke. When two of a girl's best friends each lost a parent, she gifted each of them a bear  for their birthdays this autumn. While he was still alive, a man got his girlfriend a toy monkey with his voice in it for her birthday. . And in June of last year, a woman repaired a stuffed bear with a recording of her grandmother's late husband who died of lung cancer. The message said, ""

And users shared similar stories in the Reddit thread, signalling that this isn't just an isolated instance of a Black Mirror coping mechanism - many are apparently implanting humble stuffed animals with reminders of their loved ones. :

While such mementos of the dead may seem strange now, one day they might be as common as an urn on the mantel.

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Mirror</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immortalising Their Dead Loves Ones In Stuffed Animals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Build-A-Bear</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
