<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651429876259764744</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/nrl-super-league-rangi-chase-cocaine-positive-test-indefinite-suspension-for-troubled-playmaker/news-story/ccdee8139469d182f78400e4d78202f5</url>
  <title>Ex-NRL star snared in double cocaine bust</title>
  <content>
EX-NRL star Rangi Chase has been suspended indefinitely after testing positive for cocaine, his Super League club Widnes have announced - in one of two player busts.
The New Zealand-born former England international, 31, failed a drugs test after playing for Widnes in their 36-8 home defeat by Wakefield on July 14.
"Widnes Vikings received notification from UK Anti-Doping and the Rugby Football League today that Rangi Chase tested positively for cocaine in a drugs test, following the recent fixture against Wakefield Trinity," Widnes said in a statement released on Thursday (UK time).
"As a consequence, under Rugby Football League anti-doping regulations, he has been suspended from all training and playing activity.
"The club fully respects this suspension and are currently reviewing this matter. There will be no further comment at this time."
Chase's infraction, which some Super League pundits are predicting may end his career, follows a raft of cocaine-related incidents in the NRL earlier this season.
Shaun Kenny-Dowall was forced out of the Roosters after pleading guilty to cocaine possession; Sharks chairman Damian Keogh quit after pleading guilty to possessing the drug; New Zealand Test stars Jesse Bromwich and Kevin Proctor were banned from this year's World Cup, and also copped club sanctions from Melbourne and Gold Coast respectively, after being outed for cocaine use after the Anzac Test; while Cronulla Holden Cup player Jesse Savage was also busted for cocaine possession.
Chase, who started his career in the NRL with Wests Tigers and St George Illawarra, was named Super League's Man of Steel with Castleford in 2011, but he has led a chequered career.
He courted controversy in 2011 when he switched allegiances to England, less than a year after playing against England for the Maoris.
He left Castleford in acrimonious circumstances and also cut short subsequent spells at Salford and Leigh before returning to Castleford last year.
But he was the subject of two separate internal investigations by Castleford, who loaned him to Widnes.
Chase has made six appearances for Widnes and signed a permanent two-year contract on July 7, just a week before his positive cocaine test.
Meanwhile, Adam Walker has tested positive for cocaine and has been banned from all training and playing activity, his club Wakefield have confirmed.
UK Anti-Doping and the Rugby Football League informed the club of Walker's results, which came from a post-match test following Wakefield's game against Widnes.
A statement from Wakefield read: "The club fully respects this suspension and are currently reviewing this matter."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wakefield Trinity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castleford</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super League's Man of Steel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JULY 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Widnes Vikings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rangi Chase</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla Holden Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wakefield</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damian Keogh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Bromwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby Football League</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Widnes</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK Anti-Doping</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Kenny-Dowall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Proctor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
