<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431598541664812</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/exblockheads-were-in-hot-demand-but-turned-down-an-opportunity-with-a-major-radio-station/news-story/dd0e34e479fbb45e1e08abb78da14d5c</url>
  <title>Ex-Blockheads turn down radio gig</title>
  <content>
EX-BLOCKHEADS Ben Toyne and Andy Sunderland may be back this year with a Channel 9 podcast but industry insiders say it comes after the pair turned down a huge opportunity with a major radio station.
Sources told Confidential that the 2016 fan favourites, who are based in Melbourne, were in hot demand off the back of their appearance on the show, during which they were pegged as "the pranksters".
They say the duo, who put their careers as school teachers on hold to shoot the reality renovation series, were offered a show with Southern Cross Austereo after The Block finale but turned it down.
However, when contacted by Confidential for comment Toyne and Sunderland said they were "never officially offered a position" but that they were excited about their new podcast.
Both Toyne and Sunderland had previously publicly expressed their interest in staying in the media with an on-air gig or television presenting opportunity a number of times, with the pair claiming late last year they would take a break from teaching to focus on pinning down a new gig.
Our contacts say the boys, who won a cool $510,000 for their time on The Block, were at odds over the offer, with one of them keen to go back to teaching while the other wanted to snap up the radio show.
But, when approached by Confidential with this information, the pair reiterated that they would "love" a radio gig.
Toyne and Sunderland's new podcast, The Block Unlocked, will premiere tonight following the reveal of the main bathrooms on the current season.
It remains to be seen where the venture will take the duo, who were being touted as "the next Hamish (Blake) and Andy (Lee)" by fans and industry insiders last year.
Their first podcast will feature Brisbane winners Will Bethune and Karlie Cicero being interviewed by Shelley Craft.
This year, Queenslanders Hannah and Clint Amos have already expressed their interest in pursuing a media career after getting a taste for television.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunderland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-Blockheads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint Amos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karlie Cicero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Bethune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Sunderland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block Unlocked</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Cross Austereo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelley Craft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EX-BLOCKHEADS Ben Toyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders Hannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
