<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431083145584899</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/what-multimillionaires-were-doing-in-their-20s/news-story/34565ced26db33ebeffd2484cb47f963</url>
  <title>What multi-millionaires were doing in their 20s</title>
  <content>
Amazon boss briefly world's richest man
0:36

Amazon.com Inc chief executive Jeff Bezos briefly unseated Bill Gates as the richest person in the world.

July 28th 2017
8 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Finance - syndicated/

Alyce Tran never predicted that her fashion blog would turn into a $15 million business.

Share

MANY people spent their 20s in dead-end jobs, playing X-Box and breaking hearts (or having their hearts broken).
Some lived with their parents, some carved out a meagre existence in crummy sharehouses and others went globetrotting.
But other, arguably more ambitious people were paving the way for a successful future. At the time they may have thought they were missing out on a lot of the fun, but boy, has their sacrifice paid off.
This is what super successful people were doing in their 20s.
Sheryl Sandberg, 47, COO, Facebook,
Net worth: $1.7 billion

Sheryl Sandberg. Picture: AFPSource:AFP
In her 20s, Sandberg was getting her MBA at Harvard. When she graduated, she was offered a job at Google. At the time, the position wasn't what she was looking for. But she took it anyway, after talking with chief executive Eric Schmidt. As : "... He said, 'Get on a rocket ship. When companies are growing quickly and they are having a lot of impact, careers take care of themselves. And when companies aren't growing quickly or their missions don't matter as much, that's when stagnation and politics come in. If you're offered a seat on a rocket ship, don't ask what seat. Just get on.'"

Roxy Jacenko, 37, Director, Sweaty Betty PR and The Ministry of Talent
Net worth: Unknown. In 2015, rumoured turnover was $13 million

Roxy Jacenko.Source:Supplied
"In my 20s I was working as a receptionist at Diesel, the Italian jeans company and pretty much head of rubbish bin emptying and coffee making.
"I realised soon that I needed to make myself available and busy in each and every department of the business in order to learn given university was not an option for me due to poor grades. I found myself working as the PR and Marketing "director'' for the brand in Australia some two years into my reception role, leaving at 24 and starting Sweaty Betty PR.
"Pre my 20s I started at McDonalds Drummoyne at 15 working in the drive through, then moving at 17 to be a florist at The Flower Man in Double Bay by day and by nights I was working at Kodak developing photos.
"I was never given hand-outs, my parents instilled in me that if you "want", you work. While at the time I was not particularly appreciative of the mindset, it set me up for where I am today. I will do the same with Pixie and Hunter - nothing gets handed to you, there is no silver spoon waiting. At 5, Pixie already has an active role in."
Jeff Bezos, 53, Amazon founder and CEO
Estimated worth: $88 billion

Jeff Bezos.Source:AFP
Bezos started his professional career flipping burgers at McDonald's when he was a teenager.
After graduating from Princeton he turned down positions at several established companies, including Intel, Bell Labs and Anderson Consulting. He spent his early 20s job hopping, then in his late 20s he made a list of 20 products he could sell online. Bezos decided that books were the most viable option. When he couldn't get his current employer hedge fund employer D.E. Shaw on board with the idea, he decided to branch out on his own.
"I knew when I was eighty that I would never, for example, think about why I walked away from my 1994 Wall Street bonus right in the middle of the year at the worst possible time," he says in The Everything Store, a biography by Brad Stone. "That kind of thing just isn't something you worry about when you're eighty years old.
"At the same time, I knew that I might sincerely regret not having participated in this thing called the internet that I thought was going to be a revolutionising event. When I thought about it that way ... it was incredibly easy to make the decision."
In 1994, Amazon was born and made Bezos one of the richest people in the world.
JK Rowling, 52, author of the Harry Potter series
Estimated net worth: $1 billion

J.K. Rowling.Source:AP
Rowling was 25 when she came up with the character of Harry Potter while stuck on a delayed train, .
Rowling was working as a secretary for the London office of Amnesty International at the time - to stave off boredom she began writing chapters on her work computer and daydreaming about the characters. When she was made redundant her severance payout allowed her to focus on the book full-time.
According to J.K. Rowling: The Wizard Behind Harry Potter, Rowling didn't have an easy time making her dreams a reality. After being fired, Rowling was married, divorced, had a child, endured the death of her mother and was diagnosed with clinical depression, all while living in relative poverty. She finished the first book in the series in 1995, and Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone was published in 1997. It has made her the world's richest author.
Alyce Tran, 31, Co-Founder - The Daily Edited
Last financial year The Daily Edited turned over $23 million

Alyce Tran.Source:Supplied
"In my 20s I was working as a lawyer and was trying very hard to progress up the ladder in the firm I was at. In my late 20s I co-founded  with a colleague. We founded TDE as a passion project on the side of our legal careers and when it was taking off we were still working two jobs, essentially by day as lawyers and by night in every function of the growing TDE business (dispatching customer orders, dealing with suppliers, working on our website etc between the hours of 8pm -1am every night!) before resigning from our roles as lawyers at 30 June 2015 and we really haven't looked back since."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everything Store</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonalds Drummoyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheryl Sandberg, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philosopher's Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweaty Betty PR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell Labs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ministry of Talent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Bezos.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amnesty International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Finance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyce Tran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TDE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy Jacenko.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JK Rowling, 52</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Double Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-Founder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheryl Sandberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bezos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy Jacenko, 37</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Edited</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J.K. Rowling.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Bezos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D.E. Shaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flower Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-Box</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Potter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anderson Consulting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyce Tran.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Bezos, 53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyce Tran, 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowling</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wizard Behind Harry Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J.K. Rowling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Gates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kodak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
