<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431602836632148</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/cody-simpson-is-broadening-his-horizons-by-releasing-new-music-and-acting/news-story/aa2a4454a79ea653afe14360034001b7</url>
  <title>Cody trying hand at movies</title>
  <content>
CODY Simpson has proven himself a man of many talents.
The 20-year-old Gold Coaster, who is one of the faces of the new Bonds Homegrown Tees campaign, has also just shot his first foray into film acting and is about to release a new music.
Speaking to Confidential from home in LA, Simpson revealed he was set to release a new single - his first in two years - with his band Coast House Collective next month, followed by an album early next year through his label Coast House Records.
"It's starting to get pretty full-on - I'm at the next stage in my career and I'm really comfortable and confident in it and excited to see what people think," he said.
While Simpson remained relatively tight-lipped about his upcoming tracks, he said the album was sure to bring him back home.
Simpson, who has only dabbled in acting in the past, just wrapped shooting a support role in new Bret Easton Ellis (American Psycho) thriller Smiley Faced Killers in Las Vegas.
"I like to try my hand at everything and take every opportunity," he said.
"I stay as open as I can and this (film) could lead to more work like that in the future."
Simpson described the Bonds campaign, which he appears in alongside Disney star Maia Mitchell and indigenous model to Charlee Fraser, as the "icing on the cake" of an exciting time in his life.
"As an Aussie growing up seeing the Bonds campaigns, it's one of those pinnacle moment so I am super stoked to be involved," he said.
The shoot was originally meant to take place in Sydney but was shot in LA.
"It wanted to come home and was looking forward to it but there were a lot of Aussies on set so it made it feel like home anyway," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bret Easton Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smiley Faced Killers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast House Collective</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coasters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlee Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cody Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Psycho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maia Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast House Records</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonds Homegrown Tees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
