<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431164749964273</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/brisbane-roar-marquee-massimo-maccarone-bags-a-double-as-roar-run-over-peninsula-power/news-story/a27fad631e2bc4736b4c65443453578c</url>
  <title>Roar score four in trial hitout</title>
  <content>
MARQUEE man Massimo Maccarone scored a brace on his Brisbane Roar debut as the three-time A-League champions twice fought back from a goal down to beat Peninsula Power 4-2 at AJ Kelly Park Saturday.
The veteran Italian striker entered the contest in the 70th minute, and scored with a quarter of an hour remaining from the penalty spot after a handball offence from Power defender Myles Carseldine.
Maccarone's spot kick put the Roar ahead for the first time in the trial. He then sealed the contest with two minutes remaining from close range.
His double ensured the Roar avoided what would have been an embarrassing result against the spirited Brisbane Premier League outfit that led 1-0 and 2-1.
Taking advantage of Roar coach John Aloisi's to field a second-string 11 - apart from defender Luke DeVere - in the first half, the Power dominated the opening stanza.
The hosts took a shock third-minute lead via a speculative 35m angled free-kick from Dean Briggs that bamboozled everybody, particularly Roar goalkeeper Tom Bilic, on its way into the net.
Largely unimpressive early, the Roar finally woke from their slumber after half an hour, equalising through triallist Peter Skapetis.
However, Power were to have the final say of the half, regaining the lead in the 38th minute through Thomas Strickland.
Roar changed their entire team at halftime, with most of their first-choice players getting 45 minutes under their belt ahead Wednesday night's FFA Cup clash against Melbourne Victory
An unmarked Nick D'Agostino should have equalised in the 58th minute but directed his shot straight at advancing Power goalkeeper Jake Reesby.
But D'Agostino redeemed himself 11 minutes later, rising high to head past Reesby. He was replaced a minute later by Maccarone, who made an immediate impression for his new club.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Roar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maccarone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke DeVere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Bilic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Strickland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Victory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massimo Maccarone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reesby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roar</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Skapetis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myles Carseldine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agostino</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Briggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Aloisi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Reesby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AJ Kelly Park Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
