<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431254944278172</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-match-report/essendon-bombers-v-carlton-blues-cale-hooker-helps-drag-bombers-to-crucial-win-20170805-gxpy8u.html</url>
  <title>Essendon Bombers v Carlton Blues: Cale Hooker helps drag Bombers to crucial win</title>
  <content>
The Bombers arrived at the MCG on Saturday hoping to continue the style they showed against the Western Bulldogs last weekend. Admittedly, that contest would end in defeat, but it was an example of the free-flowing manner they want to play.
That continued in the opening minutes against the Blues on a sunny afternoon, the weather representing the Bombers' style. However, when all was said and done, the Bombers got  the crucial four points care of an eight-point win but there was little reason for a side eying a finals berth to have a sunny disposition.
The Blues were able to turn this contest into a grind, one that the Bombers clearly did not enjoy. The Dons will also need to work on their goalkicking. Cale Hooker regained the lead - for the final time - with minutes remaining from a set shot from 40 metres but he would finish with 2.5. Admittedly, he was superb in the final term, lifting at time when Joe Daniher's influence had waned.
Anthony McDonald-Tipungwuti, a pressure-machine inside their attacking 50-metre arc, and skipper Dyson Heppell (34 disposals) also had a major hand in a victory that meant plenty in such a tight season.
"We stuck together. We stayed pretty composed all day. We were getting plenty of opportunities," Heppell said.
"We snuck through by the skin of our teeth. That would have completely burred us if we had lost."

Daniher had laid the platform with the opening two goals of the match, reinforcing what the Blues lack up forward. The first drew the highest of praise from Wayne Carey, the greatest forward to have dominated a football field. Having won a free kick from Liam Jones just outside 50 metres, Daniher essentially played on, swung on his to left foot and floated the ball through. It had Carey immediately comparing him to arguably the greatest forward, and certainly entertainer, of the past decade. 
"That's why the comparisons to Buddy Franklin aren't far off," Carey said on Triple M.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The platitudes only grew when Daniher, with the zest of Usain Bolt, soon dashed off from centre wing, took two bounces and drilled a goal from 30 metres.
The Bombers had the opening two goals on the board, and that would be the first five come the 20-minute mark of the term when Hooker also got in on the act. For the Blues, there was nothing sunny about this, for their prime movers couldn't get their hands on the ball. By comparison, Brendon Goddard, Zach Merrett and David Zaharakis found plenty of it, although it wasn't all good news when Orazio Fantasia strained a hamstring.
The Blues would have two goals by the first change but the question was whether they were determined to avoid the rout that came against Geelong last week. The answer was emphatic, to the point their tactics should be a blueprint for any side hoping to curb the Dons.
They would slow play, enjoy possession for as long as possible and seek to counter-attack from half-back - as had been successfully done earlier in the season. The Bombers were forced to kick more over the mark. Matthew Wright, one of the more successful pick-ups by the Blues over the past two years, would contribute the only two goals of either side in the second term.
The Bombers were unable to adjust in the third term, and ill-discipline didn't help. A free kick at half-back was reversed against Tom Bellchambers, gifting Wright his third.  Merrett, who may be cited for a jumper punch, drifted out of the game. The Dons' run and dash completely disappeared, and this became a slog the Blues wanted.
Jones emerged as one of the best afield. He took strong marks, put his body on the line and kept Daniher quiet. The Blues, as was their plan, rebounded from half-back. Matthew Kreuzer benefited from this when he marked and goaled from 45 metres - giving his team its first lead. He also took charge in the ruck.
Marc Murphy, Sam Docherty and Bryce Gibbs, the latter after a quiet start when tagged by David Myers, were influential. Sam Petrevski-Seton also got involved.
Ben Howlett would end almost two goalless quarters for the Dons when he snapped after a quick Jobe Watson handball. While Watson was involved in that play, he had no impact on this contest and would have only 11 touches. Heppell would provide a steadying goal from 50 but the Blues quickly responded, the first an example of their blueprint - Docherty storming through half-back, finding Jack Silvagni, all alone in the middle of the ground, who turned and dashed to 30 metres from goal and converted.
The momentum continued in the final term. A goal from Levi Casboult and a gem from Gibbs along half-forward got the Blues going, but Daniher's long goal threatened to provide the inspiration his team needed. The contest appeared to be in the Blues' grasp but the Bombers wouldn't let go. They would boot the final three goals, with McDonald-Tipungwuti contributing two and Hooker, having missed two earlier attempts, finally converting from 40.
The Bombers' finals hopes would remain alive for another week.

Votes:
8: Dyson Heppell (Essendon)
8: Anthony McDonald-Tipungwuti (Essendon)
8: Cale Hooker (Essendon)
8: Marc Murphy (Carlton)
8: Bryce Gibbs (Carlton)
Best:
Essendon: Heppell, McDonald-Tipungwuti, Hooker, Merrett
Carlton: Murphy, Kreuzer, Gibbs, Jones, Docherty
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce Gibbs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Silvagni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Zaharakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Howlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dyson Heppell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniher</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dyson Heppell (34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Bellchambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orazio Fantasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon Bombers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddy Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi Casboult</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gibbs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heppell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Docherty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Docherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Goddard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cale Hooker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
