<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430524799831549</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/television/kylie-jenners-attempt-at-stopping-trolls-has-backfired-badly-for-the-reality-star/news-story/89f21ce26f840d3c12154f1a231989d0</url>
  <title>Reason why every Jenner photo is mercilessly trolled</title>
  <content>
IF YOU happen to follow Kylie Jenner on Instagram or just enjoy a cheeky scroll through her photos every now and again you might've noticed one glaring detail in the reality star's photos.
Every single one of Jenner's pictures is flooded with the letters "lb" - and there's an interesting reason why.
The letters are an abbreviation for "like back" with "cb" also meaning "comment back" and it's the way her 96 million followers have chosen to mass-troll the reality star.
Generally, the abbreviation is used to tell someone that you've liked their photo and they should do the same back but, it was Jenner's complaint about the two letter word that has made things exponentially worse.
Back in August, 2016, the reality star tweeted to her 22 million followers to stop with the comment.
"So I'm trying out disabling my comments on Instagram because I'm done w people self promoting & the 'LB's," she wrote.
And it wasn't just in 2016 that Jenner asked her followers to stop - the weird comment has been happening for years - with the reality star also taking to Twitter way back in 2012.

STOP WRITING LB ON ALL MY INSTAGRAM PHOTOS AND USING ME AS A WAY TO ADVERTISE YOURSELF.

But, as is often the case with the internet, the tweets backfired and ever since, Jenner's Instagram comment section has little more in it than the letters "lb".
Obviously, a like from Kylie Jenner herself can lead to a wealth of opportunities - whether it's a barrage of extra likes or even thousands of followers - but clearly, the reality star was fed up with the self promotion.
Instagram finally let users disable comments on their posts back in December, with stars like Paris Jackson using the censorship tool, but clearly Jenner must be used to the endless "lb's" on her Instagram.
And, considering the amount of money the reality star gains for each Instagram post depends on her number of "engaged followers", Jenner is probably laughing all the way to the bank.
Speaking back in 2015, CEO of Talent Resources Mike Heller stressed the importance of "engaged followers", the ratio of likes/comments to followers.
"Engaged followers are more important - it shows that their followers are not just taking a look at their Instagrams but are actually participating," Heller said.
"They are touching the brand. They are getting involved. The convergence of the fans buying the product is when the celebrity has a loyal engagement."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenner's Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resources Mike Heller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USING ME AS A WAY TO ADVERTISE YOURSELF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenner</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WRITING LB ON ALL MY INSTAGRAM PHOTOS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Jenner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Talent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
