<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430653648851841</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/mum-24-jailed-for-worst-driving-judge-has-ever-seen/news-story/5dd945e91332a615d70f114192f9274d</url>
  <title>Mum jailed over 'worst driving ever'</title>
  <content>
A SPEEDING motorist has been jailed in the UK after leading police on a car chase where she exceeded 193km/h, with the judge branding it as the worst case of dangerous driving he had ever seen.
British mum-of-two Megan Nolan, 24, hit the high speeds on the motorway in order to evade capture, and only stopped when her VW Scirocco car engine blew.
Nolan, from Wythenshawe, Manchester, was jailed for one year on Friday after a judge at Manchester Crown Court told her it was the worst he had seen in his 15-year career,  reported.
Judge Martin Rudland told the uninsured driver that her driving was "selfish and ludicrous", and to not send her to custody would be "wildly wrong".
Nolan, who planned to take a job as a teaching assistant in September, had been out drinking with friends on June 4 before making her way home at around 1am, where her speeding caught the attention of a Greater Manchester Police patrol on the M60 motorway, who gave chase to the vehicle.
The patrol car lost her after she ploughed through two red lights into oncoming traffic, but a second police patrol caught up to her again rejoining the motorway, and made attempts to get her to stop.
She had pleaded guilty at Manchester and Salford Magistrate's Court at an earlier hearing to dangerous driving and driving without insurance.
In CCTV played to the court, Nolan's black Volkswagen can be seen weaving between the light traffic on the motorway, before taking an exit and leading the police round residential areas at speeds exceeding 80km/h.
She ran multiple red lights and drove on the wrong side of the road before her engine began smoking and she had no option but to abandon her vehicle after more than 20 minutes of police pursuit.
When watching the footage back, Nolan had her head in her hands and began to cry, looking at her mother who was in the public gallery.
Prosecuting, Andrew Mackintosh told the court: "The police pursuit lost sight of the vehicle but another vehicle was nearby and spotted the car going back on to the motorway.
"The pursuit continued and the cause was travelling in excess of 120mph [193km/h] on this occasion.
"The vehicle was forced to come off at the Wythenshawe junction where she ran a further three red lights.
"Police continued pursuit efforts and in the residential area the car was going in speeds excess of 50mph [80km/h].
"It was a pursuit for over 20 minutes, where no one was hurt, no damage was caused except to her own vehicle.
"She was forced to pull the car over after it began smoking, when she alighted from the vehicle and tried to run but was arrested a short way away."
He said when questioned by police, Nolan admitted she had been drinking in the town of Bury, and "had been driving home when the officers put their lights on and she panicked".
"She admitted the quality of her driving was as shown on the footage. She had no insurance and she said she was a stupid idiot who was lucky that no one had been hurt."
Defending, Mike Harman argued that Nolan had "broken down" because of an upcoming court case where she was to be a prosecution witness, which was of great stress to her.
He said: "She has two young boys ages five and three, from a good family and is quite softly spoken."
Nolan sobbed as she was sentenced to a year in prison, while Judge Rudland told her: "You have no previous convictions. I note that you are a mother with two children aged three and five.
"You have pleaded guilty to the offence of dangerous driving and driving without insurance.
"I have to tell you Megan Nolan that this was the worst piece of dangerous driving that I have ever witnessed in my 15 years on the bench.
"It would be wildly wrong of me in the public interest not to mark driving of this sort with a custodial sentence.
"For over 20 minutes you indulged in the most brazen and sustained piece of driving, with police chasing you, sirens and bells going, and three following you.
"You gave no thought to anybody including yourself or the two children you have who were asleep in bed at home."
He continued: "You had been drinking, which I suspect was the reason you were attempting to evade the police by jumping red lights, negotiating junctions, travelling at excessive speeds and weaving throughout traffic without any thought to the approaching traffic.
"You attained speeds on English roads, Miss Nolan, in excess of 120mph [193km/h]. No amount of thoughtful and well-put-together mitigating can justify that.
"It is only by the largest fortune that no person was injured, but there are those people who would have been woken by the sirens and lights of the police in their own homes as they chased you in the course of your risky, selfish and ludicrous driving.
"You will be deprived of your liberty for a substantial period of time. I take no pleasure in depriving your children of your company and your care, but in light of the offences you committed, a custodial sentence must follow."
Nolan will serve half of her sentence in custody and the remainder on licence, with supervision for six months after that, and pay a £140 [A$230] surcharge.
She was disqualified from driving for three years on her release, her licence will be endorsed with penalty points and she must take an extended driving test.
Judge Rudland also commended the police officers in the pursuit, adding: "I would like to pay particular commend to the police officers driving the vehicles for their calmness, competence and care in dealing with what they were confronted with that day in their line of duty.
"They were terrific and professional. In the various circumstances they were presented with, they dealt with them brilliantly."
This article originally appeared on  and was reproduced with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wythenshawe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Nolan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salford Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nolan</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Rudland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester Crown Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Manchester Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Mackintosh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Harman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VW Scirocco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Martin Rudland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
