<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651430052353425422</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/shari-tagliabue-opinion-the-bus-stops-where/news-story/fff625e991d04f95451bd0d3aa9120a4</url>
  <title>The bus stops where</title>
  <content>
THEY say that all publicity is good publicity, but does this always apply?
Good PR is everything to an organisation, especially an entity that relies on the goodwill of the people it serves to remain in business.
Despite this, our Townsville City Council seems to be doing a great job in alienating ratepayers with baffling moves that either infuriate, irritate or both.
Slugging pet-owning pensioners 10 bucks to register their dogs? Soft target, pensioners, they're not usually the type to rant, rage or protest, the most we might expect is a deep sigh, a shake of the head, and a ruffle of the ears of their trusty companion.
Just how badly does the council need the piffling amount of money this fee would generate? Or a more pertinent question - how low is the level in the barrel being scraped for the council to need this revenue raiser?
It's not the only questionable idea trotted out this week. Who else thought the only occasion we would be revisiting the bus interchange issue would be to give a weary cheer when it was finally completed?
This is not that occasion.
To any newcomers: an explanation. Never has the concept "bus interchange" been a better barometer for bureaucracy.
We had one once, it was nothing flash, not much shelter to speak of, located in the centre of town next to the stage (yes, we had one of those) in the tree-shaded mall (yep, we had one of those too).
Great minds decided it was far better to axe the stage, open the mall to traffic and move the bus interchange a good couple of blocks from the shops, introducing extra parking meters for good measure.
Faced with either lugging shopping to the bus or to wherever they'd parked their car, people unsurprisingly chose their suburban shopping centre.
After endless consultations a new location was sourced and in 2015 the State Government committed $4 million to build it, but the council wouldn't agree on the location, leaving the state to call for "community consultation".
Chairman of the Planning and Development Committee Tony Parsons said at the time that there'd already been extensive consultation on the Ogden Street site: "We did 12 weeks of public consultation for the City Plan, three months for the CBD Masterplan and four weeks for the Waterfront project - the public consultation has been done to death ...". And yet this week, two years on, Cr Les Walker announced more community consultation on the same bus interchange that has already been put to the community for consultation.
Add to this the questionable quick fix second pipeline, the proposed closure of the waste transfer station with no hard rubbish collection in sight and photo opportunities with Jamie Durie, sent to help us clueless regionals manage our water woes, and you would be forgiven for losing faith.
I've ended countless columns with the sentiment, "If they can't get a bus shelter sorted, what hope is there for other projects?"
Help us out, TCC; the public will applaud a good outcome.
All you have to do is actually deliver one.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ogden Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD Masterplan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman of the Planning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Durie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Les Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development Committee Tony Parsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
