<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431078850617540</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-life/canberra-hosts-annual-gammacon-pop-culture-event-20170805-gxq2et.html</url>
  <title>Where can you buy a foam battleaxe or a corset while dressed as a stormtrooper?</title>
  <content>
Gamers, local artists and cosplay enthusiasts from across the region converged on Canberra for the annual Gamma.con pop culture convention.
Organisers expect four to five thousand people to attend the event at the AIS arena across the weekend.Photo: Jamila Toderas
Walking the rows between stalls you might bump into classics like Obi-Wan Kenobi or Halo's Master Chief while characters from Overwatch and Rooster Teeth productions were also popular this year.
Around every corner a new weapon, costume or game was being spruiked by local vendors and artists, promoting the work that locals are contributing to the genre.

Despite not being close to the size of Oz-Comic Con or Supernova.,the friendly environment has kept people coming back year after year.
Lewis Turner, or Taako from Adventure Zone on the day, appreciated having somewhere to feel accepted and comfortable to have some fun with cosplay.

"It's the best feeling in the world when someone recognises your character and asks for a picture," Ms Turner said.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It's just nice to have a more positive vibe in regards to all this."Photo: Jamila Toderas
This sentiment is exactly what organisers hope visitors walk away with, according to event convener Daniel Davis.
Gamma.con took nine months of work, Mr Davis said, kicking off as soon as last year's event was completed.
Photo gallery
"There's been a lot of meetings, a lot of late nights," he said.
"We're all volunteers, Gamma.con is a not-for-profit so we don't get paid to do any of this.
"We just do it because we love it and love to give back to the Canberra people."
The people of Canberra have embraced the event allowing this year's instalment to entertain more people than ever and spread across the complex rather than just the arena floor.
Chris Schofield epitomised the commitment of visitors in his Reinhardt (Overwatch series) costume created from foam floor mats. It took Mr Schofield and a friend a month to put together and no, it wasn't too hot he assured.
The feeling on the day was that many hope the event can continue to grow and return bigger and better for the people of Canberra.
"You can make a lot of new connections for group activities or you can bounce ideas off people," Mr Schofield said.
Taylor Hogan said, "Gamma is really the only event in Canberra to celebrate this so it's really nice to have this event here." .
Gamma.con continues on Sunday with .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halo's Master Chief</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Schofield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oz-Comic Con</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obi Wan Kenobi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Overwatch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adventure Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taako</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rooster Teeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reinhardt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
