<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431856239704952</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/former-olympian-elka-whalan-helps-queanbeyan-tigers-dive-into-afl-canberra-finals-charge-20170803-gxotp8.html</url>
  <title>Olympic swimmer helps Queanbeyan Tigers dive into finals</title>
  <content>
The Queanbeyan Tigers have called on a former Olympic Games swimming star to help them dive head first into their AFL Canberra finals run.
The Tigers brought in two-time Olympian Elka Whalan to deliver a presentation to the playing group as they gear up for the final two rounds of the regular season.Photo: Michael Goiser
The Tigers will look to force their way into a home elimination final when they play the Eastlake Demons at Manuka Oval on Sunday.
Whalan, who swam under har maiden name Graham, was a star in the pool and brought home medals from the Olympics, Commonwealth Games and world championships.
The Tigers have relished the underdog tag in recent years, springing an upset against unbeaten Belconnen to win the flag two years ago followed by another grand final appearance last year.
It's that mentality they've used to springboard a promising young list into premiership contention and Whalan's talk hit the mark in Tigerland.

"At the end of the day, talent and gifts are one thing, but character is what sustains you through life," Whalan said.
"It's not just your effort, but it's who you are off the field. We can celebrate athletes and people for doing amazing things but it's actually being an incredible person and having a strong moral compass, letting your yes be yes and your no be no, and being someone that is reliable, dependable, teachable, lovable.
"The whole crux of it was not only inspiring and motivating, but being a first rate you and not a second rate somebody else."
Whalan follows in the footsteps of director general of military strategic communication, brigadier Dan Fortune, and  in presenting to the Tigers.
All three have spoken to the Tigers as part of the club's leadership and development program, which is the brainchild of sports chaplain, Scott Minchin.
Whalan said, "I spoke about the amount of times I counted when races didn't go my way and having to deal with disappointment, having to deal with resilience and challenges.
"Talks are now are resonating people not about how wonderful you are and what great achievements you made, but what about those times when the swimming races didn't go my way and how did I react.
"How do you get yourself up the next day and dive in the water again?"
A host of players in the 100-strong crowd made the effort to tell Whalan how much her speech meant after she finished but they weren't the only ones feeling a little bit star struck.
Whalan saw the names and faces of Tigers legends hung up on the walls in their rooms and got to meet some of those same club greats.
She even had her daughter Nevada with her, who was "sky high" when she left with a Tigers jersey and beanie that she hasn't stopped wearing since.
"I just felt so humbled to be talking in their locker room and sharing with them. It was a blessing for me to be there," Whalan said.
AFL CANBERRA ROUND 16
Sunday: Ainslie Tricolours v Tuggeranong Hawks at Alan Ray Oval, Belconnen Magpies v Gungahlin Jets at The Nest at Kippax, Eastlake Demons v Queanbeyan Tigers at Manuka Oval. All matches at 2pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian Elka Whalan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigerland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Minchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL CANBERRA ROUND 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Ray Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Goiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kippax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whalan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong Hawks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nevada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Tiger</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastlake Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Fortune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ainslie Tricolours</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belconnen Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belconnen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
