<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431770340358064</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/19/34/aussie-retail-sales-on-the-rise-this-winter-amid-doom-and-gloom</url>
  <title>Aussie retail sales on the rise this winter amid  'doom and gloom'</title>
  <content>
Australians are spending more this winter with retail sales rising for a third straight month.
Blaming booming house prices for an increase in consumer confidence, economists are pointing to homeowners who are leading the charge.
"While we are feeling a lot of doom and gloom in the economy, homeowners are feeling more confident and they are certainly putting more money into their home to make it more comfortable and more valuable as well," consumer advocate Christopher Zinn told 9NEWS.
Across Australia, retail spending grew by 0.3 percent in June to $26.2 billion, with New South Wales seeing a 0.5 percent rise.
The biggest surge was in household goods (0.9 percent), followed by clothing and footwear.
Heavy discounting is also likely to be behind the trend, with shoppers taking advantage of widespread sales.
And when it comes to luring shoppers through their doors, retailers are being forced to think outside the box.  

Related Articles

At Rhodes Shopping Centre, free shopping nannies are now available to parents for two hours.  
"It makes shopping a whole lot easier so we'll definitely be doing it again," mother Katie Moses told 9NEWS mid-shop. 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Moses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhodes Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Zinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
