<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431770340358058</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/youth-justice-crisis-fearful-staff-overlooking-bad-behaviour-report-finds-20170805-gxq0bz.html</url>
  <title>Youth justice crisis: fearful staff overlooking bad behaviour, report finds</title>
  <content>
Fearful staff in Victoria's youth justice centres are overlooking poor behaviour such as swearing, graffiti and gambling which can lead to critical security problems including riots, a major review of the system has found.
The comprehensive assessment into the Victorian youth justice regime declared that the system was in "crisis" with significant structural and cultural reform needed before it could improve, including better training for staff to deal with misbehaving inmates.Photo: Nine News
The report, conducted by former Department of Justice secretary Penny Armytage and Swinburne University professor James Ogloff​, uncovered multiple examples of guards being desensitised to misdemeanours or unwilling to address them. 
Acts witnessed by the reviewers included defiance of staff, damage to property, excessive swearing, and gambling. Failing to crack down on bad behaviour had critical security implications, the report found. Photo: Paul Jeffers
"Youth justice custodial staff are not comfortable in responding appropriately to negative behaviours from young people," the report authors wrote. "They do not appear to have a robust understanding of the critical security implications of their role."
Fear of being hurt was one of the main reasons staff were not taking control. One told the report that these concerns were relatively new: "Years ago they were more mature. If I restrained a young person alone, the other clients would protect me and [there would be] no further risk. Now I get kicked from behind and harmed. Fractured skull."

Victoria's youth justice system has been plagued with unrest, including at the Malmsbury and Parkville youth detention centres. There have been several riots, leading to huge amounts of damage. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

More than 120 recommendations form part of the wide-ranging review, with the state government pledging to accept all of them. Funding of $50 million has been set aside over four years to help pay for it.
Part of the funding will go towards better training and a targeted recruitment campaign for new staff. There will also be 21 additional highly-trained critical response guards.
The report also found there were a lack of offence-specific programs to address the explosion in certain crimes, such as violent assaults and car thefts. 
It also recommended that inmates be given a "structured day", with clear expectations around behaviour, routines and participation in activities.
Another suggestion was to urgently remove a legislative requirement to separate 10 to 14-year-olds from 15 to 17-year-olds and introduce a new assessment and clarification system.
"This is a system in crisis," the report found.
"The system can, and should, undertake significant structural and cultural reform during the upcoming machinery of government change, making it the leading youth justice system in Australia, and informing best practice across the world."
Minister for Families and Children Jenny Mikakos​ said it was the most comprehensive review of Victoria's youth justice system in 17 years.
"This is going to see the most sweeping reforms of our youth justice system, this is a very significant investment," she said.
"There is no silver bullet; everything that we have done is about looking at the broad spectrum of issues." 
Shadow attorney-general John Pesutto​ said the review had become necessary because there had been nearly 40 youth justice riots since october 2015
"That's the worst record of any state government ever," he said. 
A new youth detention facility is expected to open at Cherry Creek in 2021 at a cost of $288 million.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swinburne University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Children Jenny Mikakos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Pesutto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malmsbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Armytage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ogloff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
