<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431469692644684</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/18/34/review-slams-vic-youth-justice-system</url>
  <title>Review slams Vic youth justice system</title>
  <content>
A major review of Victorian youth justice has found the the system is in "crisis" and has failed to identify and respond to problems.
The report, conducted by former Department of Justice secretary Penny Armytage and Swinburne University professor James Ogloff , uncovered issues with staff training, poor infrastructure and the need for significant cultural and structural reform.
It noted many examples of staff failing to crack down on misbehaving inmates.
"Custodial staff do not appear to have a robust understanding of the critical security implications of their role and are not comfortable in responding appropriately to negative behaviours from young people," the report noted.
It also said the system has, until recently, remained shielded from government and public scrutiny,.
The report, released on Saturday, made 126 recommendations to the Andrews government, which accepted all of them "in principle".
The system has been plagued with incidents causing major damage, including a riot and breakout at the Malmsbury centre in January.

Related Articles

Youth Affairs Minister Jenny Mikakos said $50 million had been set aside over the four years to implement the changes needed.
"This is going to see the most sweeping reforms of our youth justice system, this is a very significant investment," Ms Mikakos said on Saturday.
"There is no silver bullet; everything that we have done is about looking at the broad spectrum of issues."
The funding will be put towards better training, more critical response guards and a new custodial operating model.
"Achieving the vision we've outlined will require a commitment to sustained improvement, strong leadership and a willingness to confront head-on some of the limitations of the current system," Professor Ogloff said in a statement on Saturday,
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swinburne University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malmsbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Armytage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Affairs Minister Jenny Mikakos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mikakos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Ogloff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ogloff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
