<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431645786305499</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/domain/domain-news/latest-news/derelict-lilyfield-house-covered-in-warning-signs-sells-for-126-million-20170805-gxpz2q.html</url>
  <title>'It's shocking': Rundown Lilyfield home sells for $1.26 million </title>
  <content>
Damaged walls, broken floors and a collapsing ceiling weren't enough to deter buyers from a rundown home in Sydney's inner west on Saturday. 

Ten groups registered to bid on the three-bedroom Lilyfield home, on the market for the first time in almost 30 years. 

The long-held investment property at  was one of more than 503 Sydney homes scheduled to go under the hammer on Saturday. By evening, Domain Group had recorded a 70 per cent clearance rate from 324 reported auctions. 

The back half of the property was in poor condition. This kitchen, unused for about five years, had missing floorboards, damaged walls and debris scattered throughout. Photo: Fiona Morris.

The house was divided into two separate residences. While the front part, tenanted until recently, was in decent condition, the back section was a different story. 

"It's shocking, I've never seen anything like it," said one would-be buyer, as she passed through rooms marked with signs warning people to watch their step and mind their head. 

The three back rooms, last home to a hoarder about five years ago, had fallen into a derelict state.

The ceiling in one room was starting to cave in. Photo: Fiona Morris.

Despite the challenges of the home, it took just seconds for auctioneer  of Savills Cordeau Marshall to take an opening bid of $1 million. 

Bidding on the 180-square-metre block jumped up in $50,000 and $25,000 increments until hitting the $1.2 million reserve.

From there it went up in $10,000 and $5000 jumps, with five bidders making offers before the hammer fell at $1.26 million - $60,000 above reserve.

Auctioneer Craig Marshall from Savills Cordeau Marshall in action.

It was well above the $88,000 vendor David Adams bought the property for in 1988.

The Gladesville resident and his daughter, Jane Ramsey, were delighted with the result. "We were always hoping for $1.2 million, to get over that is just great," said Mr Adams. "[Prices in Lilyfield] have gone off the charts."

Selling agent , also of , said it was an entry-level property for the suburb. 's median house price, now at $1.73 million, has risen 22.1 per cent in the last year.

The three-bedroom home a 239 Lilyfield Road, Lilyfield, last sold for $88,000. Photo: Supplied

He said the effort and cost of the extensive renovations required put off many young buyers interested in the property.

"People were talking of spending anywhere from $100,000 to $800,000 to fix it up, depending on the scope of work they wanted to do to the place," he said.

"It was a bit too overwhelming for [young buyers], it's really for somebody who is not afraid of renovating."

The rooms in the front half of the house were in much better condition. Photo: Fiona Morris.

That person was the opening bidder, a buyer from nearby Rozelle, who did not wish to be identified. 

She was delighted to nab the home - which will be her third renovation project - after missing out at several auctions. She plans to respectfully renovate it before moving in.

In nearby , a tightly held three-bedroom terrace owned by the same family for more than a century, sold for $1,666,000.

Auctioneer Craig Marshall sold the home for $1.26 million. Photo: Fiona Morris

Despite six parties registering to bid on the 130-square-metre corner block, it came down to a two-man race for . 

After an opening offer of $1.2 million was knocked back for being too low, a vendor bid of $1.6 million was made.

From there bidding jumped to $1.62 million, then $1.63 million and $1.65 million. It then dropped to smaller $5000 and $1000 increments until it sold. 

A three-bedroom terrace at 1 Darghan Street, Glebe, sold for $1,666,000. Photo: Supplied.

Selling agent  of  said the buyers were a local family who planned to renovate the original-condition home before moving in. 

In , there were roughly 140 bids for a modern three-bedroom terrace at  before it sold under the hammer.

Bidding on the 158-square-metre block started at $2 million and went up in $50,000 and $25,000 increments, quickly passing the $2.2 million reserve, as six of seven registered bidders vied for the keys.

A modern Surry Hills terrace at 619 Bourke Street sold for $1,551,000 Photo: Supplied.

By the time bidding reached about $2.45 million it was down to just two parties, who tried to outbid each other with $1000 jumps until the property sold for $2,551,000 - $351,000 above reserve. 

The home, which records show last traded for $454,000 in 1996, sold through  of to a young family upsizing from Redfern. 
Elsewhere in Sydney...

87 King Street, Manly Vale NSW 2093. Photo: Supplied

SOLD $2.91 million
Manly Vale
87 King Street
5 bedrooms, 4 bathrooms, 4 car spaces

This  broke the suburb record by $10,000. Bidding on the home, which last traded for $1.74 million in 2013, opened at $2.4 million. It went up in $50,000 increments, quickly reaching the $2.7 million reserve. A young family relocating from the inner west outbid six other groups to secure the house. It sold through  of . The previous suburb record of $2.9 million was set earlier this year by 50 Sunshine Street, which had DA approval for a subdivision.

40 Eastern Avenue, Kingsford. Photo: Supplied.

SOLD $3.29 million
Kingsford 
40 Eastern Avenue
4 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms, 2 car spaces

More than 200 people gathered for the auction of this , which opened with a bid of $2.85 million. While bidding went up in $50,000 increments to start, it dropped down to $5000 jumps before the hammer fell, as two of six registered bidders competed for the home. It sold for $290,000 above the $3 million reserve, through  of . Records show it last traded for $2.15 million in 2010.

96 North West Arm Road, Gymea. Photo: Supplied

SOLD $1,085,000
Gymea
96 North West Arm Road
3 bedrooms, 1 bathroom, 1 car space

An upsizing young family outbid four other registered groups to nab this  owned by the same family for several generations. The auction for the 910-square-metre block in a bush setting opened with an offer of $950,000. Bidding went up in $10,000 jumps before dropping to smaller increments. It sold for the reserve price through  of , who showed about 70 groups through the property.

13 Douglas Street, Stanmore NSW 2048. Photo: Supplied

SOLD $1,705,000
Stanmore
13 Douglas Street
3 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms, 2 car spaces

It was a two-man race for this  which records show last sold for $1,111,000 just over four years ago. Bidding started at the $1.6 million price guide and went up in $20,000 and $10,000 bids, quickly passing the $1.65 million reserve. The property was snapped up by an investor, who bought the home for their young child to live in when they grow up. It sold through  of . The vendors plan to upsize to another home in the inner west.

Quarterly house price report

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rozelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lilyfield Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North West Arm Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lilyfield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Vale NSW 2093</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gymea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Marshall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savills Cordeau Marshall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Douglas Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redfern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanmore NSW 2048</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Ramsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glebe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladesville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darghan Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Morris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Avenue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rundown Lilyfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
