<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431813290031464</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-match-report/brisbane-lions-v-western-bulldogs-dogs-find-bite-to-edge-past-lions-20170805-gxq4pb.html</url>
  <title>Brisbane Lions v Western Bulldogs: Dogs find bite to edge past Lions</title>
  <content>
For the first half of this season, the Western Bulldogs struggled to find the two defining qualities that took them all the way to last year's premiership: their dominance of contested possessions and at the clearances.
It's made them look like a team in the grip of a fierce hangover. Was that ferocity, that sheer desire, still there? Since round 14 against North Melbourne, they've found it again, ranking second in the league in both categories, to reinvigorate their finals chances. Photo: AAP
Against the Brisbane Lions, they dominated at ground level, smashing the home side 45 - 30 at the clearances and entering their attacking zone 64 times to 37. 
So how was the result of this game so close? In the first quarter, the clearance differential was a whopping 17-4, and the Dogs shot out to a 28-point lead. The game looked set to be sealed early. But these Lions, still last on the ladder with four wins, are increasingly a different proposition, especially at home. 
In the end, the Dogs didn't do much more than fall over the line, taking the game by 14 points after kicking six goals to two in the final quarter. They reclaimed a space in the final eight, for now, but it was anything but convincing, and came with a heavy price tag. 
That was the loss of last year's premiership captain Easton Wood, who suffered what looked like a nasty tear to his left hamstring in the first quarter. Wood was ripped to ground in a tackle by Jarrod Berry, immediately grabbed at his upper thigh and signalled to the bench to leave the ground. 

That's a potentially devastating loss on top of Dale Morris, already out with a broken arm. And with the Dogs facing Greater Western Sydney, Port Adelaide and Hawthorn from here, their premiership defence is hanging by a thread, regardless of Saturday's result. 
From the 13th minute of the third quarter to the third minute of the final quarter, the Bulldogs didn't manage a goal. And the Lions had something the Bulldogs lacked - in  their daring transfer of play and their astonishingly improved skills, they were ruthlessly efficient. From 37 entries into attack, they scored 24 times. 
The Dogs, conversely, butchered their opportunities, both in their delivery inside 50 and in front of goal. Marcus Bontempelli, who still finished the game best on ground, sprayed his first shot out of bounds and hit the post with three others before finally kicking truly to lift his side with the first goal of the last quarter. 
Bontempelli all but closed the game with his second late in the last quarter, after the Dogs were given an almighty scare by the unlikely Ryan Bastinac, who gave his side back the lead with a second of his own with just minutes to play. But the neat Toby McLean came back with the quick reply, and Liam Picken's third added the icing. 
In between, Brisbane chipped away at their opponents, often battling against the run of play, kicking five goals to two in the second quarter to grind their way back into the contest. Senior players - Daniel Rich, Tom Rockliff, Dayne Zorko - and younger ones, such as Jacob Allison in his second game, were all prominent. 
Rockliff, having another excellent game, kicked the Lions first goal of the third quarter to draw the Lions within four points; Lewis Taylor, the buzzing fly, gave them the lead. When Daniel Rich ghosted around the back of Berry to bomb home his second, the Lions entered the last quarter with an improbable lead. 
But Bontempelli, as he does so often, lifted to bend the game to his will. Even if he was below his usual silky self, his game is all timing and impact. His team, however, may have timed its run too late.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bontempelli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Rich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Picken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Allison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Bastinac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Zorko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
