<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431774635325389</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/cricket/big-bash/chris-lynn-looking-on-the-bright-side-to-missing-half-of-bbl-season-after-latest-shoulder-reconstruction/news-story/1d4b05ea544f1417c62222a6d18b14ad</url>
  <title>'Career-ending': Real threat to Lynn's future</title>
  <content>
BIG Bash specialist Chris Lynn has admitted another shoulder injury could end his career but he is not about to change his six-smashing ways.
Lynn has commenced his rehabilitation after last week undergoing a shoulder reconstruction which will see him miss at least the first half of the upcoming BBL.
The operation has robbed Brisbane Heat and the BBL of its biggest drawcard after Lynn smashed 26 sixes last summer to be named the player of the tournament.
But at 27 it was a decision he had to make with the opportunity for Lynn to make millions in the back end of his career as a T20 specialist.

If Lynn makes a full recovery his batting will not be hampered, but the energetic fielder admitted he had to cease diving.
"It has been frustrating but it was the right decision to get it done," he said.
"I want to play through tournaments and hopefully make a mark and be fully fit for 12 months. I want to put the shoulder injury to bed. I want to go back to enjoying my cricket and being pain-free.
"I have to change my dynamic slightly but I won't be changing the way I bat.
"I need to be more cautious in the field. Running around on the boundary is not an option. I might have to stop a few with the boot."
It is the second time Lynn has had his troublesome shoulder reconstructed and the long-term outlook is not good if he injures it again.
"Longevity was why I took that' option to have the operation. Is a short-term loss for a long-term gain," he said.
"They (career-ending) are words you don't want to hear but they are down that path. I've got to be more cautious and have more smarts about how I go about things.
"I am zero or 100 but there are times I have to reel it back and get another 10 years out of my career. We'll see how smart I am in the next 12 months.
"I'd love to get back (for the BBL) and walk out in front of the Gabba again. It's something I get really excited and nervous about as well.
"My fingers are crossed for the Big Bash."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynn</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Heat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Lynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
