<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431684441011507</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/northern-pride-take-intrust-super-cup-top-six-side-souths-logan-to-the-death-at-barlow-park/news-story/696ee4c2cf284803e26bb454739c0a73</url>
  <title>Nailbiter again at Barlow Park</title>
  <content>
THE Northern Pride have once again fallen just short of an Intrust Super Cup win at home, taking Souths Logan to the wire in an Intrust Super Cup thriller at Barlow Park.
Ryan Ghietti was left out of the side after Ben Hampton was sent back to Pride, but it didn't seem to affect the home side as they started strongly.
Javid Bowen scored in the fourth minute on Saturday night to continue the Pride's new trend of solid starts.
The visitors then started finding holes in the Pride defence and Souths Logan halfback Sam Scarlett was the beneficiary, dotting down under the posts to draw level.
Metres were coming easy for the Magpies and it was the little No. 7 who put his side in the lead in the 33rd minute, before a late penalty goal had his side 14-6 in front at halftime.
A halftime rev-up from Ty Williams appeared to work wonders for the Pride, who struck through Gideon Gela-Mosby in the 43rd minute but they fell into the same old bad habits and once again drifted out of the game.
The Magpies took advantage and scored two tries in four minutes, but the home side didn't give up and got it back to 24-18 after Ben Hampton burrowed over in the 63rd minute.
A penalty goal gave Souths Logan some breathing space but another Javid Bowen try five minutes from time ensured the match would go to the wire.
A Ben Hampton break threatened to put the Pride in tryscoring position the next set but a bone-jarring tackle jolted the ball free.
The push to force an error for the Magpies was perhaps a bit overzealous from Darryn Schonig, who was sent off for flooring a rival with an elbow.
Another Magpies penalty goal made it 28-24, leaving the Pride thinking what might have been had they played the full 80.
Schonig might not be the only one in trouble with the judiciary this week after Troy Kapea was also placed on report during the match.
The Pride have a bye next weekend.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ty Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Kapea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Souths-Logan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schonig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Ghietti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darryn Schonig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gideon Gela-Mosby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barlow Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Scarlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javid Bowen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hampton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Pride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
