<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431864829639605</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/05/security-overhaul-considered-australian-domestic-airports</url>
  <title>Security overhaul considered at Australian domestic airports</title>
  <content>
Security measures for Australian domestic flights could be tightened after two Sydney men were charged over an alleged terrorist plot to bring down a plane.

9 HOURS AGO  UPDATED 11 MINS AGO

Tighter security checks could be introduced for Australian domestic flights following an alleged terror plot to bomb a plane.

Senior ministers are believed to be preparing to take to cabinet a proposal to introduce identity checks, full-body scanners and restrictions on liquids similar to security measures for international flights.

Two Sydney men have been charged over the alleged plot to bring down an Abu Dhabi-bound plane on July 15 using an improvised explosive device.

Transport minister Darren Chester said Australia's aviation system was world class and its safety and security remained the government's highest priority.

"Aviation security settings are constantly monitored and evaluated by experts in the field who provide advice to the government," he told AAP on Saturday.

"Security measures are kept under constant review to ensure they remain effective and proportionate to the Australian security environment and respond to new and emerging threats."

The security clampdown could also include a ban on people passing through domestic security barriers without a boarding pass, The Australian reports.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 11 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
