<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431684441011467</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/05/18/45/vietnam-baby-siezure-hospital-treatment</url>
  <title>Melbourne dad desperately trying to raise money to save sick baby daughter</title>
  <content>
The birth of your child is something every parent remembers.
It's something every parent holds dear, but for an Australian father, the excitement was short lived.
Tim Maclatchy and his partner Tram Doan knew something was wrong on their first night home from hospital in Vietnam.
Daughter Caroline had a seizure. Mr MacLatchy recalls that terrifying moment.
"After a minute or two we weren't too sure then another one happened an hour later that was stronger."
So they rushed her back to hospital.
"Then she was having seizures about every hour as we were going through all the hospital stuff. She had maybe four, five for the whole day," Mr MacLatchy.

Related Articles

Tests would take weeks. Tiny Caroline's body was being dealt a cruel blow. Her parents were anxious, and sleepless. Each hour dragged by, they felt no closer to an answer.
Tram, a Vietnamese-born mother, knew the ins-and-outs of the medical system. But for her partner, Melbourne teacher Tim, it was something very different. He didn't understand the language, and got lost in translation when it came to her care.
"It's been really scary. Not knowing what's happening, the language barrier it's been very frustrating trying to figure out what the problem is, what the treatment is. Getting different answers from different doctors, then researching it on Google is helpful, but also makes it even scarier."
But eventually the couple learned she had been diagnosed with a rare chromosomal defect, called DiGeorge Syndrome, that leaves her suffering congenital heart disease but also poses a range of other medical issues.
At the moment, her windpipe is too narrow. That's going to require an operation.
She can't breathe on her own, and requires constant supervision. Her parents want her to have treatment in Australia, and a medical evacuation flight will be on standby.
But that could cost the family about $60,000.
"Oh, it's horrible. You have hopes and dreams. You have to reassess everything about it. We still don't know what sort of life she's going to have. The symptoms are so varied, it's a huge spectrum of disorders, she could have a relatively normal life, or she could be highly disabled. We don't know."
As Mr MacLatchy talks to Nine News from his Ho Chi Minh apartment, he's just returned from work. He's about to head back, while Tram is packing for the hospital. It's her daily 30 minute visit. That's all the hospital allows.
Sometimes, Mr Maclatchy says, they allow an extra visit, and he sneaks in on his way home from work.
But he's burning the candle at both ends, and the anguish and worry for his daughter is etched all over his face. Then, he sheds a tear.
"She's a fighter. Her will to survive is there. She's smart, she looks at me I can tell, she wants to know what's going on. She knows who we are and, the nurses have told us she gets quite excited when we come in to see her. She knows exactly who we are."
As we continue to chat via Skype, Tram walks in to the room. She beams from ear to ear, all smiles. But then I ask about her daughter, the girl she describes as a "beautiful angel", and she sheds a tear.
"We're really frightful", she says.
"That hospital (in Vietnam) is really, really crowded. Lots of patients. If she had a chance to go to Australia she would have more life opportunity. The Children's Hospital is the best."
The Children's Hospital she speaks highly of is the Royal Children's Hospital in Melbourne. Mr MacLatchy shares his love for the place and the staff. He's been in discussions preparing, and hoping his daughter can be treated there.
"The heart operation she needs is quite risky, and the best surgeons are in Melbourne. She also needs ongoing treatment with, to stabilise her calcium levels. She has no parathyroid gland, she needs that to absorb the calcium more effectively."
An online crowd funding bid, has already raised more than $50,000. That number has doubled, in the last 24 hours.
"A huge thank you we really appreciate everyone's help. It really just it's made our day. 'Good on ya mate to all the Aussies', and zing ga mon to all the Ting Viets." says Mr Maclatchy.
Or as Tram says, "cam on ban", or "thank you" in Vietnamese.
As for Caroline, she's now 6 months old. She's spent almost all of that time, in the intensive care ward of a hospital. But she could be on her way.
"She's strong, we believe she will get better. Day by day she will get well soon," Tram says.
Mr Maclatchy smiles at his partner, "yeah, she's getting there. She's getting stronger day by day and soon she'll be in Australia."
The family hopes she can be placed on an emergency flight, that will also be fitted with a ventilator to aid her breathing, then the surgery and road to recovery can start.
As proud dad Tim says, "We can bring her home."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnamese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DiGeorge Syndrome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skype</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnamese-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Maclatchy</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Maclatchy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tram Doan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ting Viets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ho Chi Minh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
