<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432247081732120</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/moneysaverhq/new-superannuation-obstacles-need-ninja-warrior-skills-to-climb/news-story/e373285768668d47403ff71ddf42587f</url>
  <title>Ninja warrior skills needed for super</title>
  <content>
YOUNG workers today have plenty of financial obstacles popping up in front of them, and another big one is approaching quickly on the horizon.
They already are being saddled with high housing debts, if they are able to afford a house at all. They enter the workforce with much larger student debts than their parents and grandparents did, and surging household bills eat into a greater slice of their income.
And now, the changing make-up of Australia's workforce is throwing a super spanner at them, and many will need ninja warrior skills to dodge it.
There's a broad misunderstanding among workers that every dollar they earn attracts compulsory payments from their employer. It doesn't.
The 9.5 per cent super guarantee payments are only required to be made to employees earning more than $450 a month. So a part-time worker juggling a few jobs each paying a few hundred bucks may receive zero super.
And people who work as contractors - a growing proportion of the workforce in today's fragmented and so-called gig economy - get no super unless they proactively pay it themselves.

The Association of Superannuation Funds of Australia (ASFA) has been campaigning for the $450 threshold to be scrapped. It says as it stands, hundreds of thousands of workers are missing out on super payments each year, a majority of them women.
ASFA's CEO, Martin Fahy, says 750,000 Australians now work more than one job. "Wages are now spread across more work, which can mean you slip between the cracks," he said.
"Everyone needs super - it's time to level the field."
Missing out on superannuation payments at the start of a career can dramatically slash future savings, because the power of compound interest on investments works best over 40 or 50 year time frames.
Perhaps the biggest obstacle for super savers is not the law, but a lack of interest. You can't blame a young graduate from paying little attention to money they won't be allowed to spend for several decades, but it's not only the young who don't care.
Millions of people in their twenties, thirties and forties don't focus on their super until they are closer to 50. By then they have missed out on potentially huge gains that are created by many years of earnings being reinvested.
Ask most people near 60 what's their biggest financial regret, and you can expect an overwhelming majority to say they wished they started saving sooner.
It's a slippery problem for any age, but a potential financial knockout blow for a generation who are less likely to own a home, e and for many their super will be their biggest asset.
Super specialists say young workers - or their parents or grandparents - can build a stronger future by combining multiple funds into one to save money on fees, using salary sacrifice to build balances faster and save tax, and taking advantage of the $500 super co-contribution scheme for workers on low incomes.
Have a look at your super online, even if only for five minutes a month. It's your money, and a small burst of ninja action today will multiply your savings at least tenfold later in life.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninjas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Association of Superannuation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASFA's CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Fahy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Funds of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
