<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431388088265388</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/sweet-honey-and-that-book-20170804-gxp8py.html</url>
  <title>Snap out of the Punch and Judy political  mindset</title>
  <content>
The best thing about being a media commentator, apart from all the free stuff, is that everything represents total and utter vindication.
We saw how this works in the aftermath of the terrible fire at the Grenfell Tower flats in London last month. To commentators on the Left, the fire vindicated their long-held opposition to deregulation under post-Thatcher British governments; to those on the Right, it demonstrated the human cost of so-called green-tape.Photo: Bloomberg
Likewise the UK election. Depending on whom you were reading, Theresa May's near-death experience in what started out as an unlosable election was due either to her ideological Thatcherism, or the fact she stood for nothing.
That's the beauty of being in the media. Back when I regularly attended morning conference at a daily newspaper, I heard all of the world's problems solved cleanly and crisply - and generally in retrospect. Everything becomes so much simpler when you don't have stakeholders, don't have to submit yourself to the judgement of electors, and, when you do make a balls-up of things, get to shape how the public will hear about it.
But never mind. I'll claim my own slice of vindication on the UK election result. Doesn't it demonstrate once again how jaded the public has become with the Punch and Judy version of statecraft, where everything is about party politics? From the moment May called an election three years ahead of schedule, patently for no other reason than that the polls were dire for her opponent, she was wedded to an impression of political gamesmanship, which was like an anchor around her neck from that moment forward.
It's rife. Our politicians can't stay off the media, and once on there, can't stay off the subject of them versus the other side. The advent of 24/7 television news stations - unwatched as they are - plus social media platforms has just made the situation worse. They don't realise how little ordinary people with actual lives care about the political contest.

Some minor recent local examples:
In June, when Pauline Hanson made some typically dumb remarks about autistic children in the education system, Bill Shorten tweeted the following (and reasonably enough too):  "Heartbreaking and upsetting for parents of children with autism to hear [Pauline Hanson] say their kids don't deserve the same opportunity."  The following day, however, he couldn't resist this: "More than 24 hours later and Malcolm Turnbull still silent. Disappointing to say the least. "

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

OK, we get it -- Turnbull is so desperate for One Nation preferences at the next election, he won't publicly criticise Hanson. But the underlying mindset Shorten demonstrates - and I believe the entire political class is infected with it - is that nothing, not even the education opportunities of kids with special needs, is immune to the political tit-for-tat.
The other side thinks precisely the same way -- everything is refracted through the prism of the political dynamic. When NSW Labor leader Luke Foley recently called off a trip to China, some shadowy Liberal twitter account claimed it was over allegations of Chinese interference in local politics on Four Corners. In fact, as he pointed out, Foley postponed the trip in order to attend the funeral of a colleague. Silly political point-scoring gone wrong yet again, and providing a free kick to the "enemy".
This partly reflects the narrowing gene-pool of the political class.
Former Hawke government minister Barry Cohen liked to tell a story that when he was first introduced to his new Labor party-room comrades, arriving in Canberra as a young MP in 1969, he was struck by how many of the hands he shook had fingers missing: these men (and yes, they were all men) had worked on railroads, construction sites and in factories.
Now, MPs on both sides have the smooth hands of those who have worked entirely within the political system itself, as ministerial advisers or similar. Even worse, they generally came to that work via the respective political parties. Ministerial offices these days are stacked with party members, many of whom have come up through Young Labor or the Young Liberals. Like the footballer who won't "lift his eyes" and look for options other than a long shot at goal, these people have been focused on party politics so long they can barely see past it.
The first mob to snap out of this mindset wins big.
First, do less media, and, when you do it, address the needs and concerns of voters, not the claims and weaknesses of your opposition.
More trickily, clear the party hacks out of your offices: apart from anything else, they are likely to focus on their own political ambitions and faction games, rather than the main game, and will have a tendency to get you in trouble with their cunning schemes. Those around you should be professionals who believe in what you are trying to achieve for the community. Whether they believe in your silly political party is beside the point.
.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grenfell Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thatcherism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theresa May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thatcher British</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
