<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432118232712148</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/as-prince-philip-waves-goodbye-perhaps-its-time-for-queen-elizabeth-too-20170803-gxoo9f.html</url>
  <title>As Prince Philip waves goodbye, perhaps it's time for Queen Elizabeth, too</title>
  <content>
Lean forward a little, would you? We can only whisper this to a trusted few. Don't want word getting out just yet - nudge, nudge, wink, wink and all that. But it's time we talked about convincing someone that their time is up and the moment has come to say goodbye.
It's a delicate dilemma in so many workplaces. Someone hangs around for so long they believe they are indispensable. Truth is, they instead become set in their ways. A little long in the tooth. Predictable. You know the type. Thinks everything will fall apart if they move on and the world is left to others.Photo: CP
Anyway, enough about Tony Abbott.
Instead, let us examine the case of another who believes they were born to rule. How to tell the boss of a family business to relinquish control? For the past 65 years Queen Elizabeth II has presided over a business royal insiders have long referred to as "The Firm". This week her 96-year-old husband, Prince Philip, stepped down from his official duties, many of which, in his own words more than half a century ago, were devoted to "the science of opening your mouth and putting your foot in it, a science which I have practiced for a good many years".
But a gaffe-prone husband turned out to be the least of the Queen's problems. In the 1990s she endured a series of crises not uncommon to so many families - financial difficulties, adultery, divorce and then the unexpected death of a difficult but beloved member.
It would have been enough to ruin most clans. But using the time-honoured royal approach of a stiff upper lip and an innovative public relations strategy, Elizabeth helped reinvent The Firm's image to the point where, if you have succumbed to the latest rash of cleverly engineered spin from Buckingham Palace as the 20th anniversary of Princess Diana's death approaches, the Windsors are nothing more than the Waltons - with a little more jewellery.

Her supporters - and she herself - remain adamant she should rule until death. But if the Queen wants the world to believe the royals are a truly modern family that can adapt, innovate and show true leadership, surely the greatest step she can take is a backward one and hand over the business to that up-and-coming whippersnapper, 68-year-old Charles.
True, we live in a time where many are working to reinvent workplace culture and ensure roles exist for the ageing employee. Australia has a prime minister who is 62, the United States a president almost a decade older. But there is no escaping the awful truth that, if you are lucky enough to make it into your 10th decade, cognitive and physical functions are considerably eroded. The only thing that quickens is the deterioration of memory and judgment.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Other blue bloods around the world are already dealing with this. Japan's 83-year-old Emperor Akihito said last year his advancing years might begin to affect his ability to serve. The Japanese government quickly moved to propose a law allowing him to abdicate. In Norway, speculation grows that 76-year-old Queen Margrethe II may abdicate because she misses her husband who retired more than a year ago. And let's not forget it was only four years ago that Pope Benedict stepped down because of declining health "due to old age" - the first time the papacy had been willingly vacated in 900 years.
But constitutional monarchy means never having to say you're leaving. Elizabeth's strident supporters point to her ability to guide the royal family through an age of unprecedented social upheaval. Her popularity remains at record levels, despite the inevitable mistakes. And there have been moments when even the most ardent monarchist had wished she could show a few deeper glimpses of humanity. After all, what grandmother would sit by and allow her grandchildren - one of them only 12 and still reeling from the sudden death of his mother - to be forced to walk behind her coffin under the unblinking gaze of the entire world? Ask Prince Harry. He's still looking for an answer.
By staying on in her advancing years, inevitably retreating from public life and official duties, speculation will mount and swirl around the Queen's mental and physical health and her succession planning. Remaining because she believes it maintains stability for The Firm will lead to greater instability.
It matters not whether you are a republican or monarchist. If the Queen wants an enduring legacy then standing aside is the only reasonable option. Her image cannot be enhanced by refusing to release her grip on the throne. Instead, by stubbornly extending her rule she has only one destiny.
Does the Queen really want to be remembered as the incredible shrinking royal?
Garry Linnell is co-presenter of The Breakfast Show on Talking Lifestyle.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talking Lifestyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emperor Akihito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Margrethe II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breakfast Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Linnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope Benedict</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
