<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431641491338176</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/john-worsfold-to-seek-a-please-explain-from-zac-merrett-for-punch-20170805-gxpy81.html</url>
  <title>John Worsfold to seek a please explain from Zac Merrett for punch</title>
  <content>
Coach John Worsfold will ask Zach Merrett to explain his undisciplined action which could yet result in a suspension and almost contributed to the Bombers paying the "ultimate price" in an eight-point win over Carlton.
The Bombers remain firmly in finals contention but were made to work over-time after appearing to have the contest firmly in hand with a four-goal lead at quarter-time at the MCG on Saturday. However, the Blues tightened through a "team-first" defence and stopped their opponents from enjoying the run they had craved.
Led by skipper and brilliant onballer Dyson Heppell and three goals to defensive small forward Anthony McDonald-Tipungwuti, the Dons would erase a two-goal deficit and regain the lead in the final term and help erase the memory of the loss to the Blues earlier in the season.
Worsfold, though, wasn't entirely happy, and the Bombers could be without Merrett for Saturday's key clash against Adelaide at Etihad Stadium should he be cited by the match review panel for a punch to the stomach of Lachie Plowman in the second term.

"I am expecting the MRP will look at that and grade it ... I don't know how they will grade it but some of those gradings are a fine. If they are really high gradings, they may roll into a suspension. But Zach has a good record. It's not like the (Luke) Hodge incident where he got a fine but it rolled into a suspension," Worsfold said.
"You just wonder why it happens. What are they thinking? It's easy for us fresh and enjoying the contest, generally enjoying it (but) players are under under enormous pressure .... I am sure Zach is disappointed with his action, especially because, again, we sit here wondering if it is going to affect the team. We want to be better than that."

The incident seemed to weigh on Merrett and his input diminished for a while although he would finish with 26 disposals.
"I am not sure of that ... if you are saying it looked like his impact on the game diminished, it's a great opportunity for him as a young player. We will certainly talk through it and ask him, one, why it happened and then what happened after that - resilience and experience is something he can learn from," Worsfold said.
The Bombers are set to be without Orazio Fantasia for up to three weeks after he strained his hamstring in the first term and did not return to the field.
The Bombers' resilience was highlighted by Heppell, who had a game-high 34 disposals. However, Jobe Watson was quiet and finished with only 11 touches at a time when his future has been questioned.
"Jobe, he struggled a bit today but he wasn't the only one that was a bit off. I think four players, their output was below what we expect of them," Worsfold said.
"Jobe's a super footballer, super competitive and he won't have too many games like that."
Cale Hooker would finish with 2.5, including a pivotal goal late in the final term which regained the lead for good. He had botched two earlier attempts in the final term but showed strong character when it mattered the most.
"I must admit generally with set shots for goal I try to not take too much interest in them. That's just another reason for your blood pressure to go up and it was high enough anyway," Worsfold said.
Blues coach Brendon Bolton said the loss "hurt" and lamented his team's inability to close out another tight match. He said his team had "shown great character" to fight back after the Dons initially took control.
"When you are young, you have to learn what's required in moments because you look at the three or four goals they kicked in the last, they are just little fundamental errors. We get stepped, you spill a ball in congestion that you probably should contain, there is not one thing - they are just little moments. You have got to be in them - really seasoned players know what to do at the right times," he said.
The old firm of Matthew Kreuzer (38 hit outs and a goal), Marc Murphy (32 disposals) and Bryce Gibbs (29) willed their side back into the contest, while Liam Jones held Joe Daniher to three goals after the key forward booted the opening two goals of the match.
"He was fantastic for us. That's a big win out of our year. I think you need to look at this as a collective. We have found a key defender that can match it with the real big forwards. Often you have got to go and recruit that or you have to grow it, like a (Jacob) Weitering from a young age and it takes time but we unearthed one and that's a win," Bolton said.
He said Weitering (20) also "stepped up" on Hooker, after a quiet night against Geelong last week. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Worsfold</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce Gibbs (29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weitering (20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dyson Heppell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Murphy (32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer (38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orazio Fantasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weitering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heppell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Plowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Worsfold</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cale Hooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
