<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431121800290934</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/teams/essendon/james-hird-will-return-to-essendon-sooner-rather-than-later/news-story/58d95b74bba14ce139badcbb0fca77ab</url>
  <title>No 'fake Hollywood circus' for Hird return</title>
  <content>
JAMES Hird will return to Essendon "sooner rather than later", according to Bombers chairman Lindsay Tanner, who insists the club great was welcome back at the club at any time.
But Tanner said neither he nor Hird wanted "some sort of fake Hollywood razzle dazzle media circus exercise" to accompany the return of the premiership skipper, Brownlow medallist and former coach.
LIVE BLOG:
JAMES HIRD:
"Early on in my time as president, I certainly made it plain to the AFL that it was my intention to do everything I could to foster that (Hird's return)," Tanner said on ABC radio.
"But these things, you've got to allow a bit of time. There's a healing process that's got to be allowed to occur naturally and the last thing I'm sure James wants, and certainly I don't want, is some sort of fake Hollywood razzle dazzle media circus exercise, so these things need to be dealt with in a low-key and careful way.
"I'm very confident that we'll see James back in the fold in some form, sooner rather than later."
Hird recently attended a club coterie function with the Herald Sun also revealing last month .
He hasn't been back to the club since he left as coach late in the 2015 season.
Hird was coach of the club during the 2013 sports supplements saga that saw 34 players receive doping bans in early 2016.
Tanners said Hird appeared to be overcoming his personal issues after he was.
"From everything that I can discern, his situation is sort of improving and it's great that he's already had that involvement with the coterie group function, for example," Tanner said.
"But it's important from our point of view, he's obviously welcome at any time and there's still enormous emotional warmth for James right throughout the club but he's had his own issues to deal with.
"We don't want to intrude in that or put undue pressure on him, so that's an evolving story, but I'm very confident that as time passes, you'll see those sort of difficulties fade away."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsay Tanner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanner</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hird</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hird</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
