<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431684441011508</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/qld-racing/new-proposal-for-eagle-farm-track-gets-tentative-thumbs-up-from-participants/news-story/6076f8d77a30d6b38cededb0999380db</url>
  <title>On the surface, new proposal accepted</title>
  <content>
GUARDED optimism with a hint of scepticism is probably the best way to sum up the feelings of racing participants who were canvassed for their thoughts on  on Saturday.
Those who had digested Dale Monteith's 71-page report felt it offered a sound explanation for the failings of the existing surface.
But there are understandable reservations from many about the sand profile, with some openly ''hoping'' the angular sand cannot be sourced, which would therefore lead to Plan B, which is mixing a component of sandy loam into the profile.
The April timeline is also treated with some trepidation, but when asked on Friday, Racing Queensland chief executive Eliot Forbes said "the advice we have from the consultants is that is a reasonable time frame to work to''.
"It is the right time of year to grow new grass," he said.
There may still be more to be played out in the saga of the former track. Forbes gave a somewhat cryptic response on Friday when asked whether any legal action would be taken over the failure of Eagle Farm.
"Racing Queensland will examine all options going forward in relation to the performance of the contract," he said.
The $1.5 million mooted to fix the track seems light, but Forbes is adamant early investigations suggest the fix will fall within that figure.
Monteith's report found one of the key failings of the existing Eagle Farm surface was the fact it was stolonized, or sprigged, rather than having turf laid (the sections of the track over tunnels where turf was laid, produced stronger results than the rest of the track).
It was suggested sprigging was used as a cost-cutting measure in the initial project, with the mooted savings figure in the vicinity of $600,000.Yankee in the running
QUEENSLAND'S Horse of the Year shapes as an interesting tussle this year, with a potential anomaly on the cards.
Buffering finally passes the baton after five consecutive years of being named the winner. Finalists this year are Group 1 winners Capital Gain and Yankee Rose, Magic Millions winner Houtzen, warhorse Rudy and summer star Most Important.
David Vandyke's Yankee Rose won the Group 1 Spring Champion Stakes and placed in the Cox Plate. She has never raced in Queensland, with her lone public appearances being a couple of Sunshine Coast trials.
Has there ever been a Queensland Horse of the Year winner not having had a run here?
In recent times, Shoot Out won his second Queensland Horse of the Year title having not raced in the Sunshine State that season, while Buffering's fourth win in 2015 came in a season where he didn't race in Queensland either.
Both had raced here at other times, but not in those winning years - so Yankee Rose is a worthy entry in this year's awards, with Vandyke a welcome addition to the Queensland training ranks last year.
Vandyke is aiming Yankee Rose at a first-up tilt on the Memsie Stakes after she won her latest trial at the Sunshine Coast on Tuesday. The daughter of All American has not raced since she came through the VRC Oaks with bone chips last November.
Vandyke's ultimate goal this spring will be the Cox Plate again, or the Caulfield Cup.Care To Think spelled
MATT Dunn says promising four-year-old Care To Think is likely to be spelled after his win in Saturday's Highway Handicap at Royal Randwick.
The Highway has become known as the Matt Dunn benefit and he guessed this was his 12th win in the race. Care To Think was also an acceptor at Doomben, but Dunn opted for Sydney when he drew wide in Brisbane.
"He's a horse that can overrace, so I didn't want to fire him out of the barriers here, so we went to Sydney where he was able to settle and run home. I think he will run 2000m in time. He just needs to learn to settle a bit better, but he's a pretty nice horse."Fradd fastest on foot among hoops
THE handicapper was summonsed before stewards after the running of the annual jockey foot race at Doomben on Saturday, where Robbie Fradd was a runaway winner from fellow "veterans" Damian Browne and Jim Byrne.
As the most ''experienced'' riders in the field, the trio were afforded a 20m head start on the rest of the field and Fradd showed a clean pair of heels.
He was unwanted in ''betting'' though, fetching just $150 (the cheapest price in the race) in the fundraising auction during the National Jockey Celebration Function.
Fradd was twice a winner of the corresponding race in Hong Kong.
"I did have some form ... I kept it quiet," Fradd said with a laugh. "I wasn't sure if the body was going to hold up!"
Earlier Matt McGillivray had declared himself the likely winner and brought $400 at auction.
That figure was later topped when Tegan Harrison made more than $500.
But giving away the big start (McGillivray off scratch and Harrison off 10m), the pair never looked like catching the front- running trio.
Organisers estimated yesterday's event would raise somewhere in the vicinity of $40,000 for the National Jockeys Trust, which was in addition to the $33,000 raised by the Radio TAB appeal on Tuesday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yankees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care To Think</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Vandyke's Yankee Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tegan Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt McGillivray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eliot Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yankee Rose</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vandyke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGillivray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doomben</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoot Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Jockeys Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memsie Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio TAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUEENSLAND'S Horse of the Year</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Fradd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VRC Oaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EAGLE Farm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Dunn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1 Spring Champion Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield Cup.Care To Think</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houtzen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Gains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fradd</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monteith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox Plate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Millions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday's Highway Handicap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plan B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damian Browne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Jockey Celebration Function</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
