<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431211994604860</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nbl-hot-property-nba-teams-lining-up-to-play-aussie-squads-in-preseason/news-story/3372a28e4be9cd0da03bbbca98cafed1</url>
  <title>NBA teams lining up to play NBL clubs</title>
  <content>
UP to four more NBA franchises have expressed interest in playing Australian teams following the NBL's historic agreement to play pre-season matches in America this October.
Years of hard work came to fruition last week when the NBL announced a historic NBA triple-header involving Sydney, Brisbane and Melbourne.
The Kings will take on the Utah Jazz in Salt Lake City on October 3, pitting Australian internationals Brad Newley and Kevin Lisch against fellow Boomers Joe Ingles and Dante Exum.
Melbourne will play Oklahoma City Thunder on October 9, who will feature MVP Russell Westbrook, while the Brisbane Bullets will play the Phoenix Suns on October 14.
The NBL's momentous partnership with the NBA has sparked significant interest in America, according to CEO Jeremy Loeliger.
Speaking on ABC News on Saturday, Loeliger revealed more NBA teams have expressed a desire to take on Australia's best club teams.
"I can tell you since the announcement I've had interest from at least four other NBA clubs who have said, we'd love to play an NBL team next year," Loeliger said.
"Of course those decisions are made by the NBA and not the clubs, but there is a huge amount of interest.
"I can tell you that plenty of them have an interest in playing a match here in Australia.
"That is a conversation to be had with the NBA.

If it were to be organised exclusively with the teams it would have happened by now."
Loeliger also confirmed a number of NBA franchises would like to play an NBL team in Australia.
The NBL has already started preliminary discussions about hosting an NBA game in Australia prior to the 2019 World Cup in China, which starts in late August.
However, Loeliger admitted an NBA game Down Under may arrive sooner.
"It could be as soon as next year or the year after," he said.
"I know the NBA is trying to confirm their global games calendar at the moment and hopefully with a bit of luck one of those games might be scheduled here in Australia."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVP Russell Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dante Exum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Newley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma City Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Lake City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boomers Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loeliger</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Lisch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Jeremy Loeliger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
