<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431250649310852</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/history-may-produce-another-cup-for-williams-20170805-gxq350.html</url>
  <title>History may produce another Cup for Williams </title>
  <content>
The burning question at Flemington on Saturday was, would history repeat itself later in the spring after the imported Aloft was successful in the Nursery Handicap?
Last year, multiple Melbourne Cup-winning owner Lloyd Williams took out the Nursery Handicap with Almandin who went on to give Williams  another Cup to add to his amazing collection three months later.Photo: AAP
And Aloft, who earned a powerful form line during his time in Europe, could well be another likely candidate for the rich Spring Carnival.
Nick Williams, the son of Lloyd Williams, said that the stable was confident Aloft would have a successful spring campaign.
"It's a long way from August to November but he's a nice horse and he'll continue to improve. We like to have our horses ready and fit come the big Spring races," Williams said.
"We'll have a look for a race in the next two or three weeks."

Aloft started at $4.80 and defeated Second Bullet at $5.50 with Galaxy Radar at $8.00 in third position.
And Stuart Webb's talent at uncovering a gifted racehorse continued on Saturday at Flemington when the trainer produced Lodge Handicap winner Crown Witness.
Webb, who only has a small team at his Caulfield base, said that he was excited about the future for Crown Witness who could now be groomed for a Spring carnival preparation.
While Webb admitted that Crown Witness may have to press on in the coming months against tougher company, he's confident the three-year-old filly will cope.
"She was a little bit difficult at first but we've ironed out those problems and we'll probably push through now to some better races.
"She's been in the system for a fair while but she's got excellent ability. In fact, I'd love to see her racing at Caulfield over 1100 metres," Webb said.
Webb was joined in his praise for the youngster by apprentice Ben Thompson who managed to land a winning double when Crown Witness emerged to grab victory in the final stages of the race.
"She gave me a really good feel and she was strong through the lines. I think she's got a really good future," Thompson said.
Crown Witness looked to be struggling to rein in the early leader Madeenhey who led until close to the line.
Crown Witness started at $3.60 and was too strong for Madeenhey at $3.40 with the favourite Chateau Griffo​ third at $3.30.
Earlier in the day, trainer Tony McEvoy believes that Azel the winner of the Pavilion Handicap could also be bound for a Spring carnival preparation after his solid win.
McEvoy said that he had ironed out any problems that Azel had and he believes the horse is a real talent.
"He's really improved, I loved the way he did it today and I think he's now earned a look at the spring.
"He was a bit colty when he was last in work, but he's better now and he trialled well at Flemington during the week and he really concentrated on the job,' McEvoy said.
McEvoy believes that 1400m and 1600m races are not beyond the horse with the three-year-old having his next outing at Moonee Valley leading up to the more important Spring races.
When asked if Azel will clash with the trainer's brilliant three-year-old Royal Symphony, he replied: "There's nothing wrong with getting the quinella."
Azel started at $5.00 and was too good for the $5.50 hope Wait For No One with Cao Cao third at $5.00 with the favourite Indian Thunder missing a place at $4.40.
Trainer Ben Hayes believes that his tough race mare Hell Or Highwater​ can continue winning similar races run during the winter months after the mare scored in the New Season Hcp.
Hell Or Highwater raced on the pace for most of the event but proved too strong in the closing stages for her rivals.
"She's a tough mare and a good mare. It was a huge win and she's so honest that I think she'll keep winning races during this preparation," he said.
Hell Or Highwater started at $5.50 and defeated the favourite Dulverton​ at $3.60 with Domino Vitale​ at $8.00 in third position.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wait For No One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cao Cao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy Radar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dulverton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hell Or Highwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Cup-winning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webb</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Azel</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domino Vitale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Season Hcp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Almandin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Symphony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lodge Handicap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highwater</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nursery Handicap</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Second Bullet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Witness</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeenhey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pavilion Handicap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chateau Griffo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd Williams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McEvoy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
