<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431383793298042</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/competitors-make-splash-in-high-water-levels-at-avon-descent/news-story/abfdf3a47aa658d1736bb5a6b1ad1597</url>
  <title>Competitors make splash at Avon Descent</title>
  <content>
BRENDAN Rice paddled the 'dream team' with partner Josh Kippin to line honours on Day 1 of the 45th edition of the Avon Descent white-water classic.
Kippin, last year's single kayak winner and South African-born Rice, covered the 53 kilometre stretch from Northam Weir to Cobblers Pool west of Toodyay in relay in 3 hours 29 minutes 25 seconds.
The pair, who are heading to the World Championships in South Africa in four weeks' time, decided to compete as a team this year to keep up their paddling speed rather than their endurance.
"The race in South Africa is only 30km long, so doing the full length of the Avon (124 kilometres) solo would take too much to recover from this close to the World Champs," Rice said.
The hot pace that Rice and Kippin set even put the first double kayak of Matt Dean and James Morphett 13 minutes behind them in their wake. Dean and Morphett were the first paddle craft to Extracts Weir near Toodyay but were overtaken in the second half of the race.
The volume of water that forced its way down the Avon River during the February flood has altered the course and river bed in places, affecting the water channels and challenging the river knowledge of competitors.
"The ti-trees are still tricky though but the water level this year is certainly a lot better than we were expecting a couple of weeks ago," Rice said.
Ben Carrick put WA into a solid position to defend the Interstate Challenge covering the distance in 4 hours 13 minutes 2 seconds. Rob McIntyre faded but kept NSW in second place, seven minutes behind Carrick, after being only a minute in arrears at Extracts.
"I am normally a sprint paddler so it was tough towards the end," he said.
Brea Roadley's effort to be the first female across the Day 1 finish line put Victoria into third place.
Jay Branson and co-pilot David North were the first power craft to earn a rest and hot shower at Cobblers Pool. The pair covered the course from Northam Weir in a touch over 55 minutes.
Hot on their rudder were defending champions Michael Prosser and Perrin Franks just 11 seconds behind, with Justin Green and Scott Goodbody third.
The 370 competitors in this year's 143km white-water classic enjoyed an excellent river level thanks to more than 70 millimetres of rain in the Darling Range in the past ten days.
However, the higher level at Extracts Weir proved just a little too tempting for some power craft to resist shooting the rocky wall at speed, with several competitors coming to grief and falling out of their boats.
Renee Bijl fell heavily from the boat piloted by her father Alan and gashed her leg on the large sharp rocks of the weir-wall. Rescue teams swung into action quickly to remove her from the water and transfer her to Northam Hospital for treatment.
The first paddlers are expected at the Riverside Gardens finish line in Bayswater about after 11am this morning (Sunday) with power boats soon after.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perrin Franks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Dean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Prosser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon (124</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Champs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African-born Rice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kippin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kippin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brea Roadley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northam Weir</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob McIntyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toodyay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northam Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverside Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Goodbody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Rice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Carrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Extracts Weir</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon Descent</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Bijl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Interstate Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Branson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Morphett 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cobbler Pool</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayswater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
