<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431856239704956</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/brisbane-broncos/brisbane-raise-the-bat-in-540-cakewalk-over-horrendous-gold-coast-titans-20170805-gxq3f4.html</url>
  <title>Brisbane raise the bat in 54-0 cakewalk over horrendous Gold Coast Titans</title>
  <content>
If the Titans were supposed to be a late-season trip wire for the finals-bound Broncos, then it did little but blow up in their face. Queensland's only geographic derby continues to be a one-act affair after the Broncos crushed the Gold Coast 54-0 to remain established in the top four.
Three first-half tries set up a 16-0 lead and sucked the life out of a contest that had been difficult to hype, even with the best efforts of Wayne Bennett, who was happy to suggest he coveted Titans halfback Ash Taylor once he was on the market.
The longer it went on, the worse it became for the home side. Playing like a team with a point to prove, to themselves as much as anyone, Brisbane might have encountered some sterner opposition in the Intrust Super Cup as they tore the Titans to shreds.
Taylor did his best but was outplayed by his opposite number Kodi Nikorima, while Ben Hunt was a roaring success in his new role at dummy half, crossing late in the first half and twice in the second to ease concerns about the loss of Andrew McCullough (knee) for the season.

To make matters worse, Taylor would leave the field in the second half with concerns about his knee (suspected meniscus). The dressing room was probably the right place to be, given the way things were unfolding on the park. At least he could turn off the TV.
The only real blemish for Brisbane was the booking of forward Joe Ofahengaue, who was perhaps lucky to stay on the field after a nasty lifting tackle on Titans lock Max King.

It was retro round and this was the type of spearing tackle that had mostly disappeared from the game. Brisbane should plan on the youngster being on the sidelines for at least a few weeks.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But it would be tough for Bennett to be in a bad mood after that sort of performance. He conceded during the week that the Eels ambushed them and they needed to lift their intensity heading into the final rounds, then the finals themselves.
They played their part but the Titans, already out of the post-season running, failed to play theirs. Jarryd Hayne had an unhappy night, making some poor decisions with the ball, while coach Neil Henry would struggle to find a solitary positive from that mess.
There was nothing but smiles from Bennett in his coaching box. Maybe it was the scoreline, maybe it was the sight of Sam Thaiday playing a cameo at hooker to start the show, then again with five minutes to play. Maybe it was James Roberts having potshots at goal from the sidelines.
Maybe that showed a lack of respect but you could equally argue the Titans didn't deserve a great deal. With 21,000 fans at Robina, this should have been their showpiece game. Instead, they were the ones who failed to show up to the party.
By the end, Brisbane were more concerned about cracking the half-century than anything the Titans might throw up at them. They were still throwing themselves around in defence and high-fiving Gold Coast errors like it was a grand final.
They would get their prize right on full-time, when Josh McGuire crashed over next to the posts to allow his team to raise the bat. That would be the 10th try to Brisbane, who were clearly stung by the Eels and went out to do some damage of their own.
During the week, Titans chief executive Graham Annesley said it was vital to continue to play well to ensure Taylor wanted to stay. After that, he might reconsider if he wanted to put pen to paper, although Brisbane hardly needed his services.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Thaiday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Hayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Annesley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kodi Nikorima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ofahengaue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McCullough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
