<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431254944278225</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/teams/gws/gws-giants-return-to-top-form-with-win-against-melbourne/news-story/c2b8e4399a5347be8e459ad94e120af0</url>
  <title>Be afraid, the Giants are back</title>
  <content>
THE Orange Tsunami is back and in a big way and swamped Melbourne by 35 points in Canberra.
This tidal wave was different because it was driven by defence as the Giants out-tackled the Dees 110-85.
MATCH CENTRE:
"Our tackle count told the story," GWS coach Leon Cameron said.
"Our tackling has been worse than up and down the last month. It was good that everyone bought in and to keep Melbourne to 12 shots was really pleasing. Our back seven played really smart with and against the wind."
The tactics were perfect against the Demons, whose great strength this year has been their contested footy, which they again won (172-161).
As good as the Giants were, Melbourne was equally disappointing.
After a poor performance against North Melbourne in Tasmania last week the clash in Canberra was supposed to be the stage for a statement from the Demons. Unfortunately, it came in the negative as they were blanketed from the outset when the Giants kicked a record first-quarter score of 8.6.
The eight goals came unanswered as GWS broke their previous high score for a first quarter by three points. The domination was comprehensive in the end, with the Giants producing 27 scoring shots to 12.
"I've said this a lot, it's not where you are now it's where you are at Round 23," Melbourne coach Simon Goodwin said.
"We've got a great opportunity next week to respond and another two after that and where we sit that will be it. This club still has a lot to play for."

But it could come at a heavy price with big man Shane Mumford set to come under scrutiny from the match review panel for two incidents. The first was a high bump on his direct opponent Max Gawn and the second a heavy tackle on debutant Corey Maynard.
The clash with Gawn will be the biggest worry after he chose to bump rather than tackle and collected Gawn flush on the jaw with his shoulder.
The knock flattened Gawn, who took plenty of time to recover but managed to continue without any serious problems which will work in the big Giant's favour.

AFL: GWS ruckman Shane Mumford sparks a brawl with an errant elbow on Max Gawn

Mummy lines up Gawn
The tackle on Maynard will also be a concern after Mumford buried the Demon's head into the Canberra turf. Like Gawn, Maynard wasn't seriously hurt and played out the match without any problems.
In a week when Brownlow Medal favourite Patrick Dangerfield was severely punished, there will be some nervous moments in the next 24 hours for GWS.
Melbourne's Jake Melksham will also come under review for a high bump in the third quarter.
The win moves GWS into second spot and will most likely see Melbourne fall out of the top eight.
The alarming thing for the rest of the competition is the Giants did it without their star forwards Jeremy Cameron and Jonathon Patton, who were both out with hamstring injuries, and the suspended Toby Greene.
They will also gain improvement from debutant Brett Deledio who will be better for the run. He finished with nine disposals, five tackles and a goal.
He contributed," Cameron said.
"He was nervous on his first shot on goal. He and Steve (Johnson) directed their teammates and positioned our defence, which really helped."
Cameron himself was the only injury concern when he punched a wall in the coaches box after Lachie Whitfield missed from close range.
"I thought Lachie should have gone through his routine better," Cameron said.
"I let emotions flow over the top and hit an innocent wall."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Whitfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawn</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orange Tsunami</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Maynard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Goodwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maynard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Jake Melksham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
