<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431942139051676</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/rugby/junior-laloifi-set-to-make-the-most-of-big-stage-on-offer-in-club-semifinals/news-story/044bb5721adf5bbd9f7dafb0f8588b3c</url>
  <title>Fullback banks on Sunny result for Dragons</title>
  <content>
QUICKSILVER fullback Junior Laloifi is back where it all began for "The Ballymore Kid" with a hunger to propel Sunnybank into their first grand final since 2014 and make talent spotters take notice.
The lightly-framed finisher with jets in his boots and a lush pop star hairdo is today's danger man who can ignite the Dragons in a testing minor semi-final against Wests at 5.05pm.
Still just 22, Laloifi is one of the pin-up boys for what the National Rugby Championship can do for unheralded players when given a shot.
Sunnybank's rise to the 2014 grand final and two bumper seasons for Brisbane City (2014-15) earned him the novel "Ballymore Kid" contract with the Reds in 2016, which he turned into six Super Rugby appearances and feelers from a Japanese club.
"You can definitely make a strong impression in the club finals with a team that performs when the pressure is on because you never know who is watching," Laloifi said.
Laloifi singled out young fly half Jake Strachan, 20, as a talent on the rise who can steer a win over a Wests team in their first finals series since 2006.
"Jake has the game to play at higher levels and his game management shows the benefits of the advice he's got from the other Jake (McIntyre) when he wasn't at the Reds," Laloifi said.
In the 3.05pm major semi-final at Ballymore, a rib injury will keep centre Campbell Magnay out of action for GPS while Wallabies squad prop Sef Faagase will play off the bench for University.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Strachan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McIntyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sef Faagase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballymore Kid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballymore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Magnay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunnybank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junior Laloifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laloifi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Rugby Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quicksilver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
