<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432169772320133</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-05/season-in-doubt-for-dogs-premiership-skipper-wood</url>
  <title>Season in doubt for Dogs' premiership skipper</title>
  <content>
Dog Easton Wood clutches his hamstring following his injury

WESTERN Bulldogs premiership captain Easton Wood could miss the rest of the season after sustaining a bad hamstring injury against the Brisbane Lions on Saturday night. 

Wood was helped from the field by trainers in the first quarter after a strong tackle by young Lion Jarrod Berry.

"It's probably more likely it's a bad one than just a two or three-weeker," Bulldogs coach Luke Beveridge said following his team's 14-point win over the Lions. 

"I can't confirm anything, they always scan it and we'll give more during the week, but it appears as though he's hurt pretty badly."

 

Wood has a history of hamstring problems and immediately grabbed high up on his left hamstring after the tackle.

With just three matches left before the finals, it appears Wood's only chance of making it back this season is another deep post-season run by the premier. 

It soured a gritty win by the Bulldogs, who overturned a three-quarter time deficit to record their fourth straight win. 

Beveridge did not blame Wood's absence for a second and third quarter fadeout that saw the home team kick nine goals to two with some exciting football. 

"It always destabilises you a little bit but I think the second quarter was a combination of Brisbane's good play and us, skill-wise, not being as good as we were in the first quarter," Beveridge said. 

"They rebounded hard and we couldn't stop some of their transition. 

"I wouldn't link it to Easton coming out of the game, it was more they won the quality aspect of that quarter."

Easton Wood immediately came from the ground and is getting his leg assessed after this incident.

 

It's the second significant injury to a Bulldogs defender in the past three matches following Dale Morris' broken arm against Gold Coast in Cairns two weeks ago. 

Beveridge said Morris was back running and could be set to return "in a couple of weeks". 

Of more immediate concern is who will step in to play in Friday night's huge clash against Greater Western Sydney at Etihad Stadium. 

Beveridge said Fletcher Roberts and Kieran Collins could come into contention in the key posts, while Matthew Boyd would also come into consideration. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton Wood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beveridge</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion Jarrod Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
