<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431813290031461</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4835618/valentine-coach-tips-eagles-to-soar-again/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Valentine coach tips Eagles to soar again</title>
  <content>
Edgeworth goalscorers Brody Taylor and Daniel McBreen

Valentine coach Darren Sills believes Edgeworth will power to their third consecutive Northern NSW NPL premiership double after they made his side "look second-rate" in a 5-0 drubbing on Saturday.

Fifth-placed Phoenix were desperate for a win in the penultimate-round game at Cahill Oval to keep their finals hopes afloat but they paid the price for errors in the first half to trail the ladder leaders 2-0 at the break.
Brody Taylor put the Eagles ahead in the 32nd minute with a header off a Dom Bizzarri cross, which was put over goalkeeper Scott Carter who had rushed out of his area.
Dylan Holz then hit a shot from an acute angle which came off Carter's hands into goals as he dived back towards the goalline at his near post.
Will Bower made it 3-0 in the 84th minute after Carter spilled a cross, Daniel McBreen hit a powerful strike on the run from range in the 90th and Keigo Moriyasu cleverly chipped the keeper in the 94th. 
The win and third-placed Lambton Jaffas' 2-1 loss to Maitland at Edden Oval on Saturday means only Hamilton Olympic can now stop Edgeworth from claiming the minor premiership. Olympic, who are away to Lake Macquarie on Sunday, are five points behind the Eagles. Hamilton play Broadmeadow in the last round, while Edgeworth host Lakes.

Regardless of what Hamilton can do, Sills believed the Eagles were on track for another title double. Valentine must now rely on Broadmeadow losing against the Jets Youth on Sunday at Magic Park and again next week to make the top four.
"There were a couple of mistakes in the first half that meant we had to change game plan and that didn't help," Sills said.
"But, in the end, we were totally outclassed and on that performance I can't see anyone beating them. They made us look second-rate today."
To make matters worse for Valentine, their league-leading goalscorer and player of the year contender, Jalon Brown, went down late with a hamstring tear and looks unlikely to feature again this year.
Edgeworth coach Damian Zane could just about touch the premiership trophy.

"It sort of half feels like we've won it, but we haven't," Zane said.
"But gee, it would be hard to see us losing it from here."
Zane said he could sense his side were up for the contest on Saturday and he was thrilled with the performance.
"I never really felt they threatened us, and that's a credit to our defence," he said.

"We were superb. The defence laid the base and we looked threatening all the time. I knew the goals would come."
The result means Edgeworth are now 12 goals better than Hamilton, meaning a draw next week should be enough to guarantee the premiership.
At Edden Oval, the Jaffas went ahead in the second minute when the ball fell in the box to an unmarked Ryan Griffiths, who buried his left-foot shot.

Lambton were in control for the rest of the half without extending their lead. Ryan Griffiths had a shot from a failed clearance in the 28th, Pat Brown missed a one-on-one chance in the 30th and Maitland keeper Matt Trott made a great diving save to deny Joel Griffiths' strike in the 39th.
But Maitland took over in the second half and led in the 59th minute after Liam Thornton's header from a corner and Jye Mackellar's finish from a rebounded shot. 
The win keeps Maitland's slim finals hopes alive and moves them to 31 points, one behind Valentine and two shy of Broadmeadow.
Maitland coach Phil Dando said his side rolled their sleeves up and got the job done.

"The strong wind made a difference and we ran with it second half," Dando said.
"But we were really sloppy two minutes in to concede and we just weren't desperate enough.
"But as the half went on I thought we coped with the bumpy pitch and defended well, even though they had some good chances.
"We had to take Matt Sokulsky off in the first half and we changed from 4-4-3 to 4-4-2 and it worked quite well.
"We defended well and created some chances in the second half.
"Then we hung on and didn't concede a late goal as we've been prone to do. We grafted hard which we don't always do as well as we might.

"We're dependent on other games now, but we've kept ourselves in with a chance."

Dando was full of praise for Trott, who made a crucial save late, and centre-backs Shane Cansdell-Sherriff and Zac Hill.

Also on Sunday, Charlestown host Weston at Lisle Carr Oval.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cahill Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Holz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Dando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keigo Moriyasu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaffa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisle Carr Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edden Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Griffiths</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel McBreen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Sills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jets Youth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Trott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jye Mackellar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Thornton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jalon Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brody Taylor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edgeworth</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Sokulsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern NSW NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Cansdell-Sherriff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damian Zane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dando</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Bizzarri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
