<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431319368788141</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/clothing-items-guys-should-have-before-30-2017-7</url>
  <title>22 clothing items every man should own before he turns 30</title>
  <content>
When a man turns 30, he starts to look back at his life. But he should also turn around and look back at his wardrobe because, chances are, it's been neglected.

We've rounded up 22 of the most important essentials that every guy should have by the time he turns the big three-oh.

If you're approaching or over 30, it might be time to go shopping.

Getty/Hannes Magerstaedt

There are no more excuses. You're an adult now. You need at least one suit, preferably in navy or grey.

Really, you should have both by now. What have you been doing all this time?

As American dress skews more informal, blazers have become more important than ever.

A nice blazer will make sure that you don't overwhelm a room with a full suit when the occasion doesn't call for it. But it can also separate you from the crowd a bit.

iStock

Even if you're not a watch guy, you should realise the importance of wearing a watch on occasion.

Drop a few hundred to have a timepiece that you can call your own.

Shutterstock

Quality dress shoes are always worth the investment. Make sure that you're set for the next decade by doing some research, and get some basic yet bulletproof shoes that you can wear with your suits.

Though you seldom wear shorts these days, you should be prepared for the few times that you'll need them.

And we don't mean , either.

Boots aren't just for lumberjacks anymore. They're an essential part of every man's fall and winter wardrobe.

A quality pair that can last your entire life is something that every guy should have at this stage.

Rancourt & Co

Whether it's crisp white sneakers or a pair of trusty moccasins, you should have a signature summer shoe.

Shutterstock

For colder climates, everyone knows that there's no substitute for a parka.

A parka isn't always appropriate to wear, however, and a gentleman knows that.

Jeff J Mitchell / Staff / Getty Images

Sure, you can carry a collapsible around with you forever, but after 30 it starts to look a little silly.

When you're 30, you should stop using your old college luggage and buy grown-up stuff. You're an adult now.

Shutterstock

Because when was the last time you were jealous of a man who took a backpack to work with him?

iStock

If you're still using a Pac-Man wallet, then it's time to upgrade.

Instead of going through belts every year like usual, invest in an expensive one that you can wear for years.

Pascal Le Segretain / Getty Images

Never be unprepared for a black-tie wedding again.

Jeans are an important part of every man's wardrobe, and by this time, it's pretty important to have a trusted pair that you really enjoy wearing.

Shutterstock

The perfect T-shirt is not a myth. You just have to find it.

A perfectly fitting T-shirt is something that every man should have before he leaves his 20s.

It doesn't matter what style it is as long as it fits well and you absolutely love it.

Maybe it's a henley. Maybe it's an Oxford cloth button-down. Maybe it's a sweatshirt.

Whatever it is, people have come to identify you by it when they see you on the weekends.

http://www.solidandstriped.com/collections/mens-swimwear and http://www.uniqlo.com/us/product/men-swim-active-shorts-135772.html#68~/men/bottoms/shorts/swim/~ and https://www.jcrew.com/mens_category/swim/trunks/PRDOVR~A4316/A4316.jsp?color_name=MOROCCAN%20RED&styles=A4316-RD5527

A bathing suit that is actually flattering is one of the biggest tell-tale signs that you've grown up.

Dan Kitwood / Staff / Getty Images

Buy a few ties for yourself. When your collection isn't 100% gifts from family members, then you'll actually have some ties that you'll like to wear.

Getty/Ron Sachs

The wire-frame glasses that don't quite fit your face correctly aren't going to cut it anymore.

For help with finding the right shape for your face, check out .

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iStock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Kitwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty/Hannes Magerstaedt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shutterstock</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRDOVR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rancourt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pascal Le Segretain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty/Ron Sachs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pac-Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOROCCAN%20RED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RD5527</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff J Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
