<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432247081732136</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/canberra-raiders/nrl-canberra-raiders-stun-cronulla-sharks-with-ricky-stuart-masterclass-20170805-gxq1xt.html</url>
  <title>NRL: Canberra Raiders stun Cronulla Sharks with Ricky Stuart masterclass</title>
  <content>
A Ricky Stuart masterclass has inspired the Canberra Raiders to a 30-12 victory over the Cronulla Sharks to keep their NRL finals hopes alive.
No, it wasn't a case of Stuart pulling on the No.7 jersey, but ringing some line-up changes that played a massive role in the outcome of the match.Photo: AAP
He brought Josh Hodgson back to starting hooker, threw Joe Tapine onto the right edge and thrust Elliott Whitehead into the middle to click the Green Machine into gear at Shark Park on Saturday night.
With St George Illawarra losing to South Sydney, the top-eight door snuck a little wider to heap a bit more pressure on Penrith, who play Wests on Sunday.
The Raiders still need to win all four of their remaining games, but will take plenty of confidence across the ditch to face the struggling New Zealand Warriors in Auckland.
Their forwards were brilliant, with Whitehead, Junior Paulo, Shannon Boyd and Josh Papalii all starring.

But it was the Sharks who put the Raiders under pressure early, off the back of a penalty and a scrum, and they were ahead inside the first five minutes.
They created the overlap with good hands from Cronulla five-eighth Fa'amanu Brown putting Sosaia Feki over for the opening try.
With Andrew Fifita and Paul Gallen rolling up through the middle with plenty of intent, they made it an eight-point lead from a penalty.
But it sparked the Green Machine into life, with Hodgson back to his brilliant best at dummy half.
He looked one way, went the other, and found a charging Papalii to barge over from close range.
Then a precise Blake Austin cross-field bomb was too hot for Feki to handle and it fell into the arms of the waiting Jordan Rapana, who was happy to dive across for his first try.
He doubled his account not long after when his partner in bromance, Joey Leilua, flicked a great ball out of dummy-half for him to dive over in the corner.
Stuart also switched England international Whitehead into lock, with young gun Tapine starting in the second row.
Whitehead was hungry for work in the middle and his offload found Hodgson who dummied his way to the line to set up a 24-8 half-time lead.
But the Sharks were never going to give up.
Despite producing more errors than any other team in the NRL, they've found a way to stay in the contest, and it took just 10 minutes for them to get back into this one.
Off the back of a scrum, the Sharks spread it wide and centre Jack Bird threw a brilliant pass to a wide open Gerard Beale on the wing.
Those footsteps became louder when Papalii was sent to the sin bin for a professional foul as Cronulla pressed the Raiders line. But Canberra were brilliant when a man down.
A combination of Jarrod Croker's super boot and a massive break created by Hodgson - that would've led to a four-pointer but for a try-saving tackle from Holmes - whittled down the clock and allowed the Raiders to extend their lead to 30-12 with just 12 men on the park.
They wound down the clock expertly to take the two points.
AT A GLANCE
CANBERRA RAIDERS 30 (Jordan Rapana 2, Josh Papalii, Josh Hodgson tries; Jarrod Croker 7 goals) bt CRONULLA SHARKS 12 (Sosaia Feki, Gerard Beale tries; Valentine Holmes 2 goals) at Shark Park. Referees: Gerard Sutton, Adam Gee. Crowd: 11,639.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tapine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Sutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehead</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey Leilua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodgson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shark Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Croker 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Rapana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott Whitehead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Rapana 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Papalii</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Croker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Beale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Raiders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Gallen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papalii</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla Sharks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junior Paulo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine Holmes, 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tapine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Gee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREEN MACHINE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRONULLA SHARKS 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Bird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CANBERRA RAIDERS 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sosaia Feki</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hodgson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
