<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432126822646817</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/pearls-a-happy-puppy-playing-with-bubbles-not-balloons/news-story/20bcae6b9e50a675a3820a5ae3092e71</url>
  <title>Pop goes the puppy hazard</title>
  <content>
PEARL the puppy is the latest face of Melbourne Zoo's Bubbles not Balloons campaign.
The 11-week old mastiff cross is enjoying her time surrounded by bubbles while recovering from a near-fatal accident.
After eating two deflated balloons, Pearl was saved by veterinarians at Lort Smith - Australia's busiest animal hospital.
The hospital regularly treats pets who have ingested balloons and similar objects, and has got behind Melbourne Zoo's campaign.
Bubbles not Balloons wants the public to blow bubbles instead of inflating balloons at events in order to help protect wildlife.
While seabirds are the most common victims of digested rubbish, Pearl is a reminder even pets need to be kept safe. Lort Smith doctors hope their support reminds pet owners that balloons and other rubbish can be harmful to their furry friends.
"It's really important to keep a close eye on what your pet is playing with or eating, particularly for inquisitive puppies like Pearl," Lort Smith head of hospital services Dr Russell Harrison said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Russell Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lort Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Zoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Zoo's Bubbles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearl</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
