<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431856239704981</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/bidding-frenzy-for-highprofile-melbourne-properties/news-story/b450688a6fa25bf3a12f529d21041ebe</url>
  <title>Bidding frenzy for high-profile Melbourne properties - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Marshall White, Stonnington, Justin Long auctions off former Qantas and Spotless Group chairwoman Margaret Jackson's Armadale mansion. Picture: Tim Carrafa

BIDDING soared sky high at the auction of former Qantas chairwoman Margaret Jackson's mansion yesterday, while a former Olympic sprinter scored a buyer for his Cheltenham renovated california bungalow.
There were 846 auctions scheduled in Melbourne this week.
CoreLogic recorded a preliminary clearance rate of 71 per cent.

RELATED:
RELATED:

sold under the hammer for $5.84 million.

Two bidders fought fiercely for the stunning property owned by Ms Jackson and her husband, Roger Donazzan, at -9 Avalon Rd, Armadale, with $20,000 and $50,000 bids flying from both parties.
Marshall White Stonnington auctioneer Justin Long opened with a vendor bid of $4.8 million, which was quickly upped to $5 million and declared on the market at $5.42 million.
Bids continued to soar, with a young couple scoring the keys with a winning bid of $5.84 million.
The four-bedroom house spans three floors and has formal and informal living areas.
It is surrounded by lush gardens and has a four-car garage, home theatre and cellar.

sold under the hammer for $1.33 million

Meanwhile in Cheltenham, about 200 people packed into the front yard of former Olympic sprinter Adam Basil's property at 15 Bernard St.
The renovated 1920s four-bedroom weatherboard attracted five bidders, who pushed the sale price close to $50,000 more than Basil's reserve.
Buxton Hampton East agent Matthew Pillios said it sold under the hammer for $1.33 million.
He said a young couple from Craigieburn who planned to start a family won the keys.

sold for $3.7 million, despite passing in at $3.4 million.

Australian Supercars driver Rick Kelly also scored a buyer for his beachfront beauty in Carrum yesterday, despite it passing in at $3.4 million.
Ray White Chelsea agent Janine Foy said there was strong interest in the two-storey house at 708 Nepean Highway, with more than 100 people attending the auction.
She said there was only one strong bidder and they negotiated up to win the keys for $3.7 million.
Ms Foy said the buyers were a local mature-age couple who planned to call Amanpuri their home.
The resort-style property features three bedrooms, a swimming pool and a big balcony with panoramic views of the bay.

2/41 Dally St, Clifton Hill, is still on the market, with an asking price of $960,000.

Meanwhile, a musician's inner-city converted warehouse apartment failed to hit the right note with prospective buyers at its auction, passing in after just one bid.
Owned by one half of the indie pop duo, Gypsy & the Cat, the two-bedroom townhouse at 2/41 Dally St, Clifton Hill, only notched one bid of $860,000 from a young family in front of a crowd of 20 before it was passed in.
Nelson Alexander Fitzroy auctioneer James Pilliner said the bidder negotiated up to $870,000 but the offer was rejected by owner Lionel Towers. It is now on the market for $960,000.
hayley.goddard@news.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Jackson's Armadale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernard St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janine Foy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marshall White Stonnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marshall White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nepean Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifton Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Basil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buxton Hampton East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Pillios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanpuri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armadale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheltenham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Foy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Supercars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pilliner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigieburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Carrafa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Donazzan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Towers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avalon Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Alexander Fitzroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dally St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Long</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
