<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431340843624772</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/treasurer-promises-transparency-at-the-pump-in-effort-to-lower-qld-fuel-prices-20170805-gxq2tq.html</url>
  <title>Qld petrol stations banned from showing discount fuel prices</title>
  <content>
The Queensland government has announced new laws to stop petrol stations from displaying discounted fuel prices on their boards.
However, the Opposition has been left fuming, after they announced the same policy 18 months ago, which was rubbished by Labor at the time.Photo: Thinkstock
The new laws will come into effect on January 31, 2018, with the RACQ having called for them for the past five years.
Treasurer and Acting Energy and Biofuels Minister Curtis Pitt said the new "what you see is what you pay" regulations were about improving transparency in the industry.
"As we know, some fuel operators have been putting a discounted price on the board, which only relates to those people who can get that through a vouchering system," Mr Pitt said.
"These strict regulations mean fuel retailers will still be able to promote discount fuel price schemes, but only the full price available to all motorists can be displayed on the price boards.

"The LNP failed to deliver these reforms when in government despite the RACQ calling on the changes since 2012.
"The Nicholls-Newman government were all talk and no action, promising petrol price board reform for Queenslanders but did absolutely nothing about it in three years."

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

However, Opposition treasury spokesman Scott Emerson accused the government of having no understanding of Queenslanders' concerns regarding the rising costs of living.
"This is a policy we announced 18 months ago and at the time, the government said it wouldn't make any difference," he said.
"They have ripped off our policy and now they're putting it out, but they still say they won't do it until next year."
The government's announcement also drew support from the Motor Trades Association of Queensland, which said the policy provided a practical and commonsense resolution to an issue which had been confusing drivers.
"From February, fuel retailers must not display a discounted fuel price on any price board. Parallel with this, price changes (increase or decrease) to a fuel type displayed on the price board must correlate with the price displayed on the fuel pump," deputy chief executive Kellie Dewar said.
"MTA Queensland has been advocating for regulation on this issue for many years and we see this as a significant win for our members and consumers."
.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellie Dewar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thinkstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biofuels Minister Curtis Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acting Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Emerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Motor Trades Association of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTA Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholls-Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
