<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431727390684778</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/west-coast-track-probe/news-story/f87329891cd84047044f6883a7964c6a</url>
  <title>West Coast track probe</title>
  <content>
THE Wilderness Society has welcomed an investigation into illegal track use in the Tarkine region, but concerns remain about a barge it says has been giving 4WD motorcycles access to closed coastal tracks between the Pieman River and Sandy Cape.
The society took video footage of two all-terrain vehicles being ridden through an area closed to 4WDs in April and reported the barge.
A Parks and Wildlife Service spokeswoman said investigators were "following a specific line of inquiry relating to two suspects and the alleged use of the barge to obtain illegal access to the Arthur Pieman Conservation Area".
In a recent letter to the Wilderness Society's Vica Bayley, Environment Minister Matthew Groom said the investigation would determine whether there was enough evidence to prosecute the alleged offenders.
"A considerable amount of time and effort is directed towards the Arthur Pieman Conservation Area compliance program each year by PWS staff and it has generally been very successful, with a large number of drivers approached, any breaches of the legislation investigated, and offenders charged/issued with infringement notices," Mr Groom said.
"Unfortunately, it appears however, there still remains a small group of people who choose to do the wrong thing."
Mr Bayley said he was pleased an investigation was under way, but said nothing had been done about the barge.
The Parks and Wildlife Service spokeswoman said it was premature to suggest the service had not acted to confiscate the barge.
"PWS must ensure that appropriate evidence has been obtained to support such an action," she said.
Mr Bayley also said the Government's desire to reopen tracks in the area to 4WDs - which it cannot do unless the Federal Court rules to overturn the current ban - created a "permission" in some people's minds to flout the ban.
The Government has argued it supports "sensible recreational access" to the areas.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Matthew Groom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildlife Service</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Groom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Pieman Conservation Area</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WDs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarkine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilderness Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilderness Society's Vica Bayley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bayley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pieman River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Cape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
