<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431731685652124</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/ffa-centre-of-excellence-deliver-biggest-win-of-season-as-premiership-decision-looms-20170805-gxpzkv.html</url>
  <title>FFA Centre of Excellence deliver biggest win of season as premiership decision looms</title>
  <content>
The FFA Centre of Excellence has delivered a stunning 12-0 thrashing of the Riverina Rhinos at the AIS on Saturday as they remain in limbo as to whether they're still in the NPL Capital Football minor premiership race.
Capital Football approved a decision to postpone a round 14 game between the FFA COE and Canberra Olympic because FFA players and coaches were in Thailand on international duties.Photo: Dion Georgopoulos
It is understood the governing body  to inform officials they were being forced to forfeit the match and in the process handed Olympic the minor premiership.
The second-placed FFA COE were left seething as they were denied the opportunity to win a maiden premiership in their final season of existence.Photo: Dion Georgopoulos
The academy is keen to play the game before its doors close on August 25 after the FFA decided it was not producing enough talent to justify its $1.6 million price tag.
Capital Football has delayed an official decision on the match as it waits to see if Olympic will clinch top of the table honours when it plays against Gungahlin United on Sunday.

Coach Tony Vidmar said all his boys could do was let their football talk, and they did just that at the AIS on Saturday with a whopping nine goals in the second half.
"It was an onslaught. I was expecting a strong performance but I wasn't expecting that many goals, the boys were really, really good today," Vidmar said.Photo: Dion Georgopoulos
"You score 12 goals and it goes up there with one of the best performances we've ever had, I think you could say it's been a couple of years in the making.
"We're finishing off the season really well, we've got a few more games to go and I hope we can continue on with strong performances until the end."
Vidmar said he is anticipating Capital Football will change their tune when a decision regarding the forfeit it made on Monday.
"I think they're going to back track and we'll end up playing them but that stuff is out of our control, the performance was really good today and that's all the matters right now," Vidmar said.
Meanwhile, Belconnen United secured their place in the finals with a 6-0 thumping on the road against the Monaro Panthers.
Jason Ugrinic scored a hat-trick to take his season tally to 20 as he closed within one of league-leader Stephen Dominici who can add to his total for Olympic on Sunday.
AT A GLANCE:
FFA Centre of Excellence 12 beat Riverina Rhinos 0
Belconnen United 6 beat Monaro Panthers 0
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA COE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belconnen United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vidmar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL Capital Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Ugrinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Vidmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaro Panthers 0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Centre of Excellence</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belconnen United 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverina Rhinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dion Georgopoulos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverina Rhinos 0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaro Panthers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Dominici</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
