<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431469692644679</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/woman-tries-to-help-homeless-man-with-motor-neurone-disease/news-story/9d9fc987dab9ae58e02213c57630eb43</url>
  <title>Woman tries to help homeless man with Motor Neurone Disease</title>
  <content>
Bill and Emma met in Melbourne and now she wants to help the homeless man. Picture: GoFundMe

Share

EMMA was rushing through Melbourne's CBD when she was stopped by a dishevelled man holding crutches while clutching a cup.
As he asked her for some change, she did what many of us do, and said she didn't have any.
As she continued to be buried by busy office workers and commuters, she stopped and turned around. She offered to buy the homeless man, Bill, some food and he told her a heartbreaking story about how he ended up on the streets.
"I spent an hour talking to him and crying my eyes out in the middle of Melbourne Central food court," she wrote on a  page to raise money for Bill.
"I couldn't believe what a hopeless situation he found himself in and how unlucky he has been over his entire life."
Bill, 51, told Emma, who did not reveal her last name, he had Motor Neurone Disease and grew up in children's homes in Victoria and was separated from his family.
"He has worked for the majority of his life and paid his taxes. His last job was working for a transport company when he became sick and was unable to do this job anymore," Emma wrote on the page.
"He applied for the pension and was told by Centrelink that he had too much money saved in his bank. He was given a payout by his company and was told he wasn't eligible for the pension until May 22 2018 (eight years later).
"Bill has been without income for nearly eight years and during this time has had throat cancer and osteoarthritis in his hips. In the last year, he was diagnosed with Motor Neurone Disease and is unable to afford the medication he needs to manage the symptoms of this illness."

Emma said he was donated an electric wheelchair, but it was vandalised while he was charging it at the Melbourne Central train station. He can't afford to have it fixed.

Bill is one of many homeless people on the streets of Melbourne. Picture: Mark WilsonSource:News Corp Australia
She said Bill stands outside Melbourne Central shopping centre and begs in the hope of making enough money to find a bed for the night.
"If he is unable to raise enough money he sleeps on the street," she said.
"I have set a goal for this GoFundMe as $25,000 based on weekly medication costs ($250 per week) for MND and enough money for Bill to live comfortable ($300 per week) in Melbourne until May 2018 when he's eligible for the pension (45 weeks from now).
"However the first action to be taken will be repairing his electric wheelchair."
People suffering from MND are usually given a life expectancy of two years and just 10 per cent live more than five years. The medication helps relieve symptoms for those battling the disease and can prolong their lives by two to three months.
"When I started to speak with Bill I quickly realised that he is like any other person that I might know or be friends with," Emma said.
"He's smart, funny and kind and does not deserve the misfortune that he has experienced. I hope that other people like me would like to give him some luck.
"I work in Melbourne Central and Bill comes to visit me or I go to the area where he begs for money. I have recently organised for him to have a working phone so I can now contact him.
"This GoFundMe is linked to my bank account which I withdraw cash from an ATM and give Bill money for accommodation and basic necessities. I will also be buying things which he can't get access to otherwise with this money such as a second hand electric wheelchair which I'm currently in search of on Gumtree."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MND</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 22 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark WilsonSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumtree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Central</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill, 51</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Motor-Neurone Disease</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
