<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431516937285393</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/more-sports/ella-nelsons-journey-from-life-in-the-fast-lane-to-struggle-street/news-story/9b90db92543a0626a1c5ca9d35e3f56b</url>
  <title>From Rio hero to struggle street</title>
  <content>
IT was hailed as the night a star was born.
Ella Nelson put her hand up to be the next Australian sprint queen after going within a whisker of making the 200m Olympic final in Rio.
At 22 and making her Olympic debut, she missed a spot in the final by just .01 sec.
The accolades came flooding in for the Sydney sprinter given the last Australians to feature in an Olympic 200m final were a couple of all-time greats, Cathy Freeman and Melinda Gainsford-Taylor, at Sydney 2000.
Fast forward 12 months and Nelson is sitting in a meeting room at the Australian team's training camp in Tonbridge, on the outskirts of London, trying to explain what has happened to her career.
"It's been tough, I'm not going to lie but every year is different," she says. "Well, that's what everyone keeps telling me.
"The end goal still remains the same and that is to run well at the world championships. All the stuff at the beginning and the middle doesn't matter as long as the end goes well."
There were signs of troubles during the Australian domestic season where she was surprisingly beaten in the national 200m final by Papua New Guinea's Toea Wisil.
Nelson ran a personal best 22.50 sec in the Olympic semi-finals. Her best this season is 23.00 sec in Canberra in March which comes in equal 90th on the IAAF's world ranking of 2017 times.
She's reticent to go into too much detail about her issues.
"For me there has been a lot of stuff going on behind the scenes and off track that looking back has played a bigger part than I initially realised," Nelson says.
Australian head coach Craig Hilliard believes Nelson has fallen into a trap which has grabbed many good athletes over the journey.
"For whatever reason it hasn't worked, her preparation hasn't worked this year and it is what it is," he said. "It's sad and it's hard.
"It's hard for athletes when you have such a jump and a spike and you think it will go on but you've seen it before, sometimes you get to here and plateau or drop down a fraction."
Nelson has again spent most of the year at her US base in Phoenix with the ALTIS training group that includes Canada's 100m Olympic bronze medallist Andre De Grasse.
"This year after a really big Olympic campaign we identified areas that I needed to work on more, we tried to a lot of different things," Nelson explains.
"We tried to work on some weaknesses in the off-season and sometimes that just takes longer to adapt, sometimes it takes a whole year.
"I've been working on my acceleration, trying to get myself stronger. We talked about being bulletproof this year and avoiding hamstring tears and that kind of thing.
"Unfortunately I started the year with a sesamoid bone stress reaction so I was in a boot for eight weeks right after Rio.
"I just felt there was this never-ending injury cycle but it has ended, I'm injury free but just dealing with some other stuff."
The memory of Rio is still strong and she'll regularly look at clips from the Olympics on her mobile phone to help her through the dark times.
"It was insane, it was crazy," she says.
"I've spoken to quite a lot of athletes and well known Olympians and they all say the year following is really difficult, sometimes subconsciously, sometimes consciously.
"But it was the most amazing thing. I still have people coming up to me saying how cool that was, to see someone they knew do so well.
"Young girls coming and asking me for advice, it was just the best thing in the world.
"I had the most fun there, even though I was so close to something so great there. It's a really good memory to look back on that I will cherish for the rest of my life."
A recent training camp in Monaco with the ALTIS group has Nelson confident a turnaround isn't far away.
"Everyone keeps reminding me that I'm going to have a really long career and that every year is going to be different, sometimes you will be injury riddled for a whole year, some years will be tough and you might not be racing as well," she said.
"But knowing that I can achieve that (Olympic semi-final), I believe I can do better whether it's this year or next year on the Gold Coast or Tokyo. I just don't know but I'm going to keep working hard.
"The thing is you only have to run fast once a year at a major championships and that can still be at the worlds this year."
Nelson will be joined by 17-year-old Queensland schoolgirl Riley Day in the 200m heats which are on Wednesday August 9 (4.30am AEST).
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Hilliard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonbridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andre De Grasse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea's Toea Wisil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday August 9 (4.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney 2000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada's 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Altis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melinda Gainsford-Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ella Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
