<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432298621340069</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-05/dogs-not-playing-ducks-and-drakes-with-bob-and-jj</url>
  <title>Dogs not 'playing ducks and drakes' with Bob and JJ</title>
  <content>
Bevo defends Bob's late inclusion
Bulldogs coach Luke Beveridge says Jason Johannisen's extremely late exclusion was because of injury, not pre-planned

Bob Murphy and Luke Beveridge leave the Gabba together

LUKE Beveridge admitted it looked a little "orchestrated" but said there was no funny business behind Bob Murphy's late inclusion for Jason Johannisen on Saturday.

Beveridge got the football tongues wagging on Thursday after naming Murphy the "travelling emergency" - a first for most - to take on the Lions.

He said the Bulldogs skipper was sore and would only play if someone didn't get through the warm-up.

Then, lo and behold, Norm Smith medalist Johannisen was ruled out with a hamstring niggle just moments before the first bounce, rushing Murphy into the 22.

"He's just bent over to pick up a ball before we even started the warm up and felt a bit uneasy in the top of the hamstring, but he wasn't sure, so we warmed him up," Beveridge explained.

"He looked like he was going OK but he still felt a bit compromised.

"We just couldn't take the risk with him in the end.

"It looks a bit orchestrated doesn't it?"

Beveridge said he saw Lions coach Chris Fagan - a former mentor in their days at Hawthorn - walking across the Gabba and told him what had happened.

"We don't normally play ducks and drakes, but had a quick chat to him.

"He knew about it at that point in time."

Fagan said he had no problems with the lateness of the change, describing Beveridge as an "honest man".

"I actually thought it was genuinely an injury," Fagan said.

"We were watching the warm-up, Johannisen was out there, suddenly he came off the oval.

"I think Bevo was genuinely telling the truth. I guess everyone will speculate about it.

"I know Bevo pretty well, I think he's an honest man."

Murphy had a strong game, finishing with 17 disposals.

Beveridge said he "may be" in doubt to play Greater Western Sydney on Friday night, with a second successive six-day break.

"We'll see. Hopefully he's all right.

"Hopefully he comes up better this week than he did last week, but he played all right."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fagan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johannisen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bevo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beveridge</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murphy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norm Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
