<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431426742971413</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4830899/lord-mayor-hits-the-decks-to-dj-party/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Lord mayor hits the decks to DJ party</title>
  <content>
Lord mayor Nuatali Nelmes.

IT'S arguably the most surprising gig since the Beastie Boys played the Cambridge Hotel under the name Quasar in 1997.
Newcastle lord mayor Nuatali Nelmes has been unveiled as the DJ for The Family Hotel's August 24 first birthday celebrations.
Cr Nelmes said she was at the Newcastle West pub a few weeks ago celebrating a friend's birthday when the Forbes brothers asked if she would spin a few tunes.
"It sounded great after an espresso martini," Cr Nelmes said. "I'm looking forward to it - I've never played a DJ set before. 

"There is a science behind it, normally a DJ gets everyone moving, brings them up and then back down again.

"I can assure you it will be good exercise."
Cr Nelmes said she has reached out to numerous friends for their suggestions and tweeted Labor MP Anthony Albanese or DJ Albo, whose stint guest programming Rage in 2013 led to DJ sets in Sydney, Brisbane, Canberra and Melbourne.
He responded by sharing a snap from a recent set in Victoria. 

Mixed bag: Anthony Albanese tweeted this playlist to lord mayor Nuatali Nelmes.
"Albo has form in this area - he has hipster prowess and is a political rockstar," she said. "I like Yothu Yindi's  and Spiderbait's Shazam! - they're playing at the Supercars."
Cr Nelmes said she was unlikely to include any politically charged numbers, or nods to the upcoming council elections.

"I have to discount music that is not going to make people dance or is going to be depressing, it needs a decent beat," she said. "I don't know of any dance music that references local government off the top of my head. But I am going to have to include Beyonce's and some iconic feminist songs.
"I grew up in the 90s with house music and grunge music and don't mind some hardcore house. I'll have Fatboy Slim, the Red Hot Chilli Peppers, Salt and Pepa - the first female R&B artists to reach Australia that I knew of -  and the Violent Femmes.

"I like Bob Marley because my parents used to play him and my friend has got some remix versions.

"My daughters are 10 and 12 so I also love a bit of One Direction, although they're so much better solo. I'll have to slip in a song from one of them - my favourite at the moment is [Niall Horan's] Slow Hands. It will be an eclectic mix for sure."  Which bangers should the lord mayor play?

BOWIE MURAL MAY GO

Shrine: The mural was created during the Hit the Bricks street art festival in 2014.
More than a year after Valley Kitchens' controversial decision to paint over artist Guido Van Helten's Stewart Avenue mural, the city may be about to lose another one of its iconic public artworks.

Colliers International has sold 484-486 Hunter Street, which is also known as the property hidden behind hoarding that boasts Dan Prestage's 2014 mural of David Bowie as Jareth, the Goblin King in Labyrinth. Agents did not return calls before publication about the future of the mural, which still bears remnants of messages posted after Bowie's death.  It raises an interesting question: should we protect our street art, or celebrate it as a temporary gift?
ESCAPE TO EVERYWHERE

Explore: Jewells Primary staff member Katie Clarence reading at Uluru.
AUTHOR Roald Dahl wrote in Matilda that reading transported the lead character "into new worlds and introduced her to amazing people who lived exciting lives".

Jewells Primary School staff took this year's Book Week theme, Escape to Everywhere, another step further, by physically escaping to a range of locations - from in front of a fireplace, to the beach, a hairdresser's appointment, State of Origin, skifields, Port Macquarie, Laurieton, Tasmania and even a hammock in Borneo - and photographing themselves with their noses buried in a book.  The images were posted on Facebook and users asked to guess the identity of each staff member.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borneo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley Kitchens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jewells Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Prestage's 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fatboy Slim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Clarence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yothu Yindi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jareth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jewells Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colliers International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Anthony Albanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roald Dahl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hot Chilli Peppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Violent Femmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Book Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spiderbait's Shazam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Direction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guido Van Helten's Stewart Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ Albo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Hotel's August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nuatali Nelmes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goblin King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slow Hands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Albanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Marley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Niall Horan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pepa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurieton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Nelmes</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beastie Boys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOWIE MURAL MAY GO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
