<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432895621800302</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/this-donald-trumps-the-bird-world/news-story/80749b696caf275833a9d04ed17aa888</url>
  <title>This Donald trumps the bird world</title>
  <content>
NORMALLY it would be headline news across the world - Donald Trump in Huonville - except in this case the famous tweeter is a bird, which bears a remarkable resemblance to its more famous namesake.
With a streaming mane of golden feathers adorning his head, the golden pheasant was quickly christened Donald Trump by owner Rowen Carter.
Mr Carter, who is part-owner of the Huon Valley Caravan Park, said when he got Donald two years ago the bird soon started fitting the persona of the US President.
"He even has a girlfriend named Melania but adding to that, he has a roving eye for the females and chases them fairly hard. He really ramps up the tweeting during mating season," Mr Carter said.
"Our Donald Trump thinks he's quite beautiful and delights in showing off his golden mane and plumage.
"We even asked him his opinion of Malcolm Turnbull, and Donald our pheasant turned his head away."
Mr Carter said his golden-feathered friend is not domesticated either.
"Our Donald has quite a high opinion of himself, expecting others to feed him the best grain and clean his pen.
"He is also a prolific sire with about a dozen offspring."
Mr Carter said the golden pheasant bird is native to Malaysia but has been in Australia for many years.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowen Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Carter</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huon Valley Caravan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huonville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
