<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431598541664841</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/att-jockey-corey-brown-full-of-admiration-for-kokoda-heroes-after-pushing-through-pain-barrier/news-story/7ae9c630097cddcdcb3e4776a2dfe03c</url>
  <title>Brown admiration for Kokoda heroes</title>
  <content>
COREY Brown has given an insight into what it's like to walk the Kokoda Track after doing so with a host of jockeys including Hugh Bowman and Kathy O'Hara last week to raise money for charity.
"Three-and-a-half-days to walk 100km and the terrain now is still very tough but you can imagine what they [soldiers] went through," Brown said.
SUNDAY RACES:
MISSILE STAKES:
"They would have had to clear it themselves and the weather wasn't always on their side. We had a bit of rain the last two to three hours but we were walking on flat land (then) and it was just a mess. What they must have experienced would have been 10-fold."
Brown admits it was tougher than he expected and said O'Hara led from the front.
"The star performers were Kathy and Stephen Baster, more so Kathy and she was on the leader's heels the whole way, the bloke who was showing us the way," Brown said.
"(Celebrity) Kris Smith and I were back at the tail of the field with broken down knees like old men going downhill. It was very tough and I'll be honest, I underestimated it.
"It was a bit of a surreal feeling when you are looking down to Kokoda, where the memorial set up is, and it was quite moving."
Bowman didn't let the arduous task stop him from piloting Winx, , in a track gallop on Saturday morning.Bennett won't rush return
FORMER Scone trainer Greg Bennett is set to go back into pre-training and breaking in horses but won't be an official trainer again for at least 12 months.
"I'm in the early stages of negotiating to get a place to lease in southeast Queensland (at Canungra) and just re-establish myself with a bit of breaking in and pre-training," Bennett told At The Track. "I'm not going to renew my (trainer's) licence yet and I handed it in, so I'm going to remain that way for 12 months at least."
Asked whether he will train racehorses next season, Bennett was uncommitted.
"I will think about it then, I'll never say never," he said.Time for reflection
SATURDAY marked National Jockey Celebration Day at Royal Randwick and let's face it without their courage and efforts, we wouldn't have a sport.
A minute's silence was held at Randwick to remember all jockeys who lost their lives while riding, in particular Darren Jones, Donna Philpot and Roger Booth, who lost their lives this year. On behalf of the entire racing community, we thank each and every jockey.
*****
BOOKMAKER Mick Sullivan sponsored a race (Cindy Sullivan Memorial) and held a function at Royal Randwick on Saturday in his late wife's honour in a bid to raise funds for cancer research.
"Cindy died of cervical cancer (in March) and the foundation that we've got the function upstairs for is the Australian Gynaecological Cancer Foundation and they struggle for funds basically," Sullivan said.
"Racing is my passion and the way I could bring people to the races was to have the fundraiser. We've owned a lot of horses together and Cindy has had a lot of success actually and she won six Group 1s (as an owner). We have 660 people upstairs and hopefully we can raise funds."
*****
MEMES' little sister Lucere didn't live up to hype on Saturday when she finished last as an odds-on favourite on debut at Kembla Grange.
HORSES TO FOLLOW: Admiral Jello (ready now), Invincible Gem (stick with her), Tango Rain (great return), Pro Consul (just needs a barrier).
ONES TO SACK: Labdien (too many chances), Zayam (just battling).
RIDE OF THE DAY: Corey Brown (Invincible Gem).
QUOTE OF THE DAY: "Kris Smith and I were back at the tail of the field with broken down knees like old men going downhill." - Corey Brown on walking the Kokoda Trail.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tango Rain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canungra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Jockey Celebration Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labdien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LUCERE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy O'Hara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Gynaecological Cancer Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cindy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUNDAY RACES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro Consul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Philpot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cindy Sullivan Memorial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokoda Track</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokoda Trail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Brown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Booth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokoda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Admiral Jello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zayam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Hara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Baster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Gem</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
