<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431684441011459</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/equal-love-wa-hold-rally-in-forrest-chase-for-free-vote-on-samesex-marriage/news-story/6d56a78a1a8facae7c724fb1c779938d</url>
  <title>Gay marriage supporters to PM: 'It's time'</title>
  <content>
HUNDREDS of marriage equality supporters gathered in the Perth CBD, demanding a free public vote on the issue be passed in Parliament as soon as this week.
Convener of Equal Love WA, Sam Cavallaro, said the entire lesbian, gay, bisexual, trans and intersex (LGBTI) community wanted a commitment for marriage equality from our politicians.
"In 2004, the Howard government put a ban on same-sex marriage, which was nothing more than discrimination and it created a second-class citizen," he said. "We've had a consistent campaign that has dogged Malcolm Turnbull the entire time he's been Prime Minister. It's time he listened to the majority of Australians."
Labor Senator Louise Pratt addressed the crowd, before predicting the issue would trouble the Federal Government at the next election.
"More and more people in the coalition are realising they can't go to the polls with this issue unresolved," she said.
"I wanted to stand here proudly today and help send a strong message to Canberra."
Director of the Anglican Parish of Darlington Bellevue, Father Chris Bedding, believes many Christians had been misrepresented on the issue.
"There's a perception that Christians are largely opposed to marriage equality, but that's untrue," he said. "There are some very vocal Christian voices which dominate the media and give the indication that all Christians are filled with hate, fear and rejection.
"So it's important that clergy, church leaders and individual Christians speak up in favour of marriage equality so that our voices are heard, and so the media can't be dominated by voices of negativity."
When asked why marriage equality was important, rally attendee Sonia Gurrin said: "Because no one should have the right to tell you that you can't express your love in the highest form possible - marriage. Love matters."
The rally was organised by local community group Equal Love WA.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equal Love WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Parish of Darlington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellevue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Cavallaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bedding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Senator Louise Pratt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonia Gurrin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
