<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432672283498739</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/world-travel/europe/up-close-with-the-russian-woodpecker-the-scary-soviet-antiballistic-missile-radar/news-story/08d7863317d16e114cd75e220fb225d1</url>
  <title>Up close with the Russian Woodpecker, the scary Soviet anti-ballistic missile radar</title>
  <content>
UKRAINE:    Drones Explore Chernobyl 30 Years After Nuclear Disaster   Multiple
5:16

Marking 30 years since the Chernobyl nuclear disaster, this drone footage, captured at various times between 2013 and 2016, shows the nearby city of Pripyat and the nuclear facility, still uninhabitable due to high radiation levels. In the video, a Ferris wheel and bumper cars in a fairground are seen lying unused, and churches and homes are unoccupied. The hammer and sickle, the symbol of the former Soviet Union, remains standing, albeit rusted, atop a deserted apartment block. Credit: Philip Grossman/ExploringTheZone.com

April 29th 2016
a year ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Technology - syndicated/

It's hard to imagine people didn't know this imposing structure was there. Picture: Richard PJ Lambert

Julia D'Orazio

Share

ON MAPS, this site was marked as a children's playground. That couldn't be further from the truth.
When the Chernobyl nuclear explosion happened in 1986, it shook the world in many ways. Not only did it put the now , it also exposed the world to what was really at this site in Ukraine - the dreaded Duga radar, also known as the Russian Woodpecker.
A Soviet engineering and scientific feat of its time, the Russian Woodpecker was an over-the-horizon radar system designed to provide early detection of an intercontinental ballistic missile attack.

The Russian Woodpecker is a Soviet-era anti-ballistic missile system that remains in current day Ukraine. Picture: Julia D'OrazioSource:Supplied
It represented how the world was standing anxiously on knifes' edge during the Cold War. All it would take was a positive detection of an incoming missile and a button pressed for this structure to play its role in turning a cold war to a fully fledged one.
But while it once had a role in detecting disruption, it now remains useless and unkempt as it sits within the 2600 square kilometre Chernobyl Exclusion Zone.
As if being in the exclusion zone wasn't eerie enough, standing in the shadows of this hellish and imposing top-secret military creation was.
I had to bend my neck far back to take in this eyesore sight. Ironically, this largely forgotten Soviet-era landmark wouldn't be easily obliterated from anyone's mind.

The radar network played a major role in the Cold War. Picture: Julia D'OrazioSource:Supplied
Built in 1976, this monstrous steel-woven structure was designed to detect missiles within
seconds. Standing taller than the Sydney Harbour Bridge at 146 metres and stretching 500 metres wide, it's hard to fathom how this radar was unknown to those beyond the Red Curtain - even though it emitted a frequency of 10 Hz that could be heard from around the world.

Air traffic controls, television and radio broadcasters would be irked by the mysterious pecking noises it emitted, hence its nickname, the Russian Woodpecker.
Built just outside the city of Pripyat, it was completely off limits and unknown to outsiders.
It was erected near Chernobyl due to its high power demands. On maps, it was marked as a summer camp for children hidden in the depths of the forest. Locals were told that the imposing skyscraper was a radio tower.

The Russian Woodpecker can be found inside the Chernobyl nuclear exclusion zone. Picture: AFP/Sergei SupinskySource:AFP
Its staff of technicians, scientists, military personal and their families lived nearby in a sealed section under extreme conditions of protecting Cold War secrecy.
Officially known as the Duga 3 Radar, this giant steel yard was the last of a trio of similar radar installations dotted around Ukraine. It was between the Chernobyl blast and the fall of the Soviet Union that the missile detector was slowly decommissioned and ceased to operate.
This also shone light on the source of the mysterious frequency that irritated many and, above all, revealed the structure's true purpose for missile detection.
This colossal structure now remains derelict into in the depths of the Ukrainian forest.
The site of the Duga-3, known as Chernobyl 2, had remained closed off to visitors long after the Exclusion Zone was relaxed to allow tourists to get a glimpse of Ukraine's melancholy and destructive past in 2002.

It's hard to imagine people didn't know this imposing structure was there. Picture: Richard PJ LambertSource:Flickr
Some daring BASE jumpers have scaled to the top of the derelict web of steel and calling the radar detector 'the best man-made object we had to jump" before plummeting off the apocalyptic
structure and hovering over the Ukrainian forest.
It is only in recent times the Ukrainian administrators relaxed admission into the site of the Duga-3 and now permits tourists to glance at what remains of its' steel skeleton structure.
Upon closer inspection, it is quite an impressive architectural marvel. By no means is it pretty but one has to admire the engineering legwork to create such a structure of such epic proportions.
Its steel framework features cage-like devices stacked on top of one another with a series of wires connecting each tower. It would not be so far-fetched to expect some Hollywood superhero villain to come climbing down from the antenna to question your intentions for being there.
This skyscraper is hardly one that would feature on a postcard but it does highlight an other side of Ukraine's textured past. For those who like to feel out of their comfort zone, taking a trip to the infamous exclusion zone to take sight of the Russian Woodpecker will have you feeling just that.
Follow Julia's travel adventures through her website, , or on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Curtain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exclusion Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soviet Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drones Explore Chernobyl 30 Years After Nuclear Disaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chernobyl 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flickr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duga-3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orazio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chernobyl</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia D</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukraine</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukrainian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold War</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OrazioSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pripyat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard PJ Lambert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP/Sergei SupinskySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Harbour Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard PJ LambertSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duga 3 Radar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soviet-era</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Grossman/ExploringTheZone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chernobyl Exclusion Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Woodpecker</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
