<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432509074739843</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/cancer-council-sa-urges-schools-to-enforce-sun-protection-policies-in-august/news-story/032384e369209b7a7c89ef4afdbfb01c</url>
  <title>Slip, slop, slap - in August?</title>
  <content>
SCHOOLS are being urged to slip, slop, slap, sleek and slide - despite the best part of a month of winter remaining.
The Cancer Council says UV levels rise from August onwards, putting students and staff at risk of skin damage.
, every public school must have sun protection policies in place for Terms 1, 3, and 4, and any other day the UV radiation level is three or higher.
The Education Department did not made hats mandatory but provided schools with the Cancer Council's SunSmart guides, which say students and staff should wear hats "whenever they are outside".
Gilles Street Primary principal Gyllian Godfrey said her school community was initially reticent about enforcing hat-wearing in August, but some research into Bureau of Meteorology UV records proved convincing.
"(We) unexpectedly discovered that there were more days in August where the UV level peaked at three or higher than not," Ms Godfrey said.
"By enforcing the no hat, no play policy in Term 3, we are providing a safe learning, working and play environment for everyone."

Childrenas vision experts say the sooner parents start protecting childrenas eyes from the sun, the lower the risk of developing future eye problems. Dr. Dawn Hartman joins Lunch Break with Tanya Rivero discusses what parents need to know. Photo: Gett

Why children need UV protection for their eyes
Cancer Council SA's cancer education and information manager Joanne Rayner said winter could be deceptive because temperature and UV levels were not related.
"Even though it is cold in August we will receive UV radiation at levels well above three from now until the end of April," she said.
The SA Primary Principals Association has previously said the department should have made hats mandatory all the way to Year 12.
High school leaders have said some might make hats compulsory from Years 8-10, but others would decide the battle to make students wear them would not be worthwhile.
Four in every five cancer diagnoses are for skin cancer, which kills 2000 Australians each year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UV</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cancer Council's SunSmart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya Rivero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Dawn Hartman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilles Street Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Primary Principals Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Godfrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gyllian Godfrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lunch Break</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Childrena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Rayner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terms 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Term 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cancer Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
