<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432629333825344</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/rendezview/im-willing-to-try-sexting-but-i-dont-have-high-hopes/news-story/815be9809bd51fafb8c86eb3786c76e8</url>
  <title>Sexting: I'm not doing it right</title>
  <content>
AT a lunch recently, a friend asked me if my husband and I ever sexted. "Oh, all the time," I responded. "You know, just the usual stuff about who's picking up the children, and reminders to get milk on the way home, that sort of thing."
"That's texting," she replied, rolling her eyes, "I said sexting - honestly, Frances, I really do worry about you sometimes."
Maybe, but not as much as I was worried where this conversation was going.
The thing is, I'd heard her correctly the first time, it's just that I've never been comfortable discussing my sex life with other women, mostly because it would only make them feel jealous and horribly inadequate.
But the truth is I have never sexted, but apparently other people are at it all the time, especially those in the 18-24 year age group, with a recent survey of several hundred undergraduates in the United States finding that 49 per cent of them said they had sent or received a sext at least once.
The survey also said that people in the older age bracket of 45 and over sexted far less, mostly because they did not understand the technology.
This, of course, is not true.
This is just the reason the old people gave the survey staff, because they did not want to tell them the real one, which is they don't sext because they are very tired, have grown-up children who refuse to leave home, and they have just discovered Netflix.
Anyway, all of this got me thinking about this new way for couples to communicate, and what would happen if I actually tried this myself, and sent John a sext. I think it would go something like this...
"Hey, Big Boy... are you thinking what I'm thinking?"
"Sorry, I think you have the wrong number."
"No, it's me, Frances.''
"Have you been drinking?"
"No."
"Who's Big Boy?"
"You, you idiot. Anyway, Stud Man, are you thinking what I'm thinking?"
"Are you sure you haven't been drinking?"
"Yes, I'm sure. Stop asking that. Now, what are you thinking about?"
"My footy tips for the weekend, why?"
"Goodbye."
Similarly, if John were to attempt to sext me, I'm fairly sure it would go like this...
"What are you wearing?"
"What?
"What are you wearing?"
"Why?"
"Just tell me..."
"Fine, my tracksuit pants."
"Anything else?"
"A T-shirt. And some bed socks."
"OK. Bye."
"Bye. Can you remember to pick up some milk on the way home?"
Yes, I think I'll leave this form of communication to the professionals... and Shane Warne.
Other than that, C U L8R, GTG, XOXOXOXO.
Love, Hot Stuff.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stud Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XOXOXOXO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hot Stuff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GTG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C U L8R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Warne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Boy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
