<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432848377159558</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/north-hobart-community-could-reopen-voula-delioss-grocery-shop/news-story/0a5dfbfa69de52ffd7dd665c410a7886</url>
  <title>Ultimate tribute to Voula</title>
  <content>
NORTH Hobart locals are banding together in a bid to pay late shopkeeper Voula Delios the ultimate tribute by reopening her grocery store.
A meeting next weekend will discuss how the community could take control of the shop and open its doors again.
The Sunday Tasmanian reported last weekend on the gutsy suburb's struggle after the shock of Mrs Delios's stabbing death 12 months ago.
Locals spoke of their sadness and fear, but also of the loss of the iconic deli run by the Delios family for three decades.
Uniting Church minister Jeff Savage will host Saturday's meeting, which will discuss co-op models and the potential for the community to become a shareholder in a store.
The shop was only listed for lease again in recent weeks.
Meeting organiser Hobart City Alderman Helen Burnet said some locals who were expressing an interest in reopening the store had business experience, including State Cinema owner John Kelly.
"We're looking at suitable models for how it might fly," Ald Burnet said.
"We're keeping a community model at the heart of this, so it's about what sort of social good we can do.
"It was tragic circumstances but when you lose a deli you kind of lose a community space.
"It's that incidental meeting of your neighbours."
A memorial is being planned for Mrs Delios, considered a local institution, with a plaque and olive tree being considered for the Swan St park.
The meeting will take place at the Uniting Church in Swan St, North Hobart, at 11am on Saturday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniting Church</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Cinema</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ald Burnet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Delios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart City Alderman Helen Burnet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Hobart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Delios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voula Delios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
