<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432410290490977</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/channel-nine-launches-new-local-footy-qld-show/news-story/ad8b88e1e835a568452e8834395088ea</url>
  <title>Nine takes punt on local footy</title>
  <content>
CHANNEL Nine launches its new locally produced NRL program today but station bosses say it's the start of greater things to come for Nine in Queensland.
The panel show, Footy QLD, which features rugby league greats Gary Belcher and Scott Sattler on hosting duties alongside Scott Prince and Brent Tate, is filmed at Channel Nine's Mt Coot-Tha studios and will premiere at 1pm today.
Nine Queensland's production and programming manager, Geoff Cooper, told Confidential the network's decision to take a punt on a local show was part of his ongoing strategy to focus on locally produced content.
"Over the last couple of years, we have been trying to change our approach with local productions," Cooper said.
"And, if we cannot produce it ourselves, we partner with other companies we know can make good products and use our local facilities."
Cooper said the network was "testing the market" with Footy QLD, which Nine is making in conjunction with production company Crocmedia.
"We know anecdotally people are saying 'it would be nice to have more local content and sports (shows) in Queensland'," he said.
Cooper said the plan was to "do even more" with Footy QLD if it was the "right fit" for the local market.
"We also have a few other ideas we will be investigating in the off-season for next year."
And Crocmedia executive director, Chris Giannopoulos, said he was "expecting big things" from the show because of the passionate nature of Queensland league fans.
While Nine's local production slate for the second half of the year includes their telethon and exclusive broadcast of the Sunsuper Riverfire, Cooper revealed a new television series was going into production later this month and would air nationally in 2018.
Meanwhile, Footy QLD host Belcher said the program had been a long time coming.
"We'll be covering off on all the big topics in the game - there will be some serious stuff and some lighthearted stuff," he said.
"It has been a long time since Queensland had its own footy show - I was involved in the one in the '90s and it's great to be involved again now.
"But my wife won't let me bring back the moustache."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footy QLD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Tate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Giannopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crocmedia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Sattler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Belcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunsuper Riverfire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine's Mt Coot-Tha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
