<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431856239704941</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/opinion/joe-spagnolo/joe-spagnolo-wa-the-winner-in-the-battle-for-hearts-and-minds/news-story/bd27f7ecf789979e002cb712b8a9bccd</url>
  <title>WA winner in battle for hearts and minds</title>
  <content>
ONE of my favourite photos of Malcolm Turnbull's tumultuous visit to WA this week was of a flock of seagulls fighting over a piece of bread.
I'm referring to a picture of State and Federal politicians, including the PM and WA Premier Mark McGowan, jostling for position at a ribbon-cutting ceremony to mark an extension of the Mitchell Freeway.
The story behind the picture is delicious, and insightful of the relationship between the Federal coalition and the WA Labor Government.
I'm reliably told that both the McGowan and Turnbull administrations wanted their pound of flesh, in terms of who got credit for this piece of road.
Indeed, both sides of politics did their every best to ensure that they were front and centre when it came to the "smile for the camera" bit.

From a WA Labor perspective, McGowan made sure he and Transport Minister Rita Saffioti were well and truly in the view of the cameras, and Turnbull made sure he and in-trouble Federal MPs Christian Porter (Pearce) and Ian Goodenough (Moore) were easily seen.
The Turnbull Government then made sure that the press release issued to the media on the day was in no way ambiguous in regards to who paid for what.
The second paragraph reads: "The $236 million project is 80 per cent funded by the Turnbull Government and 20 per cent funded by the McGowan Government".
The issue of who takes credit for State-Federal initiatives has been, and will be, a recurring theme between the McGowan and Turnbull administrations in the coming months and years.
Both sides, for example, desperately wanted to take credit for the recent decision to re-allocate $1.2 billion of Commonwealth Perth Freight Link monies to new WA road and rail projects.
Among all this pontificating and jostling for "poll position" there are, however, some positive signs that the Turnbull-McGowan relationship is actually better than the Turnbull-Colin Barnett relationship before it.
One senior Federal Liberal recently commented to me that from a Commonwealth perspective, doing business with McGowan was decidedly easier that doing business with the stubborn Barnett.
Privately, the Turnbull administration was - and still is - furious at Barnett for dilly dallying on the PFL and not committing to the second stage from Stock Road to the Stirling Bridge.
The Turnbull administration believes Barnett's reluctance to commit to stage two of the PFL left the door open for Labor to scrap the project - which it did in March.
It is also said that Barnett was not keen on projects, under the guise of so-called "city deals", put to the WA Liberals by the Turnbull administration.
For all the theatre that went on in public between Turnbull and McGowan over GST this week, what I'm told is that even before their much hyped 90-minute meeting there was a healthy level of respect between the two political leaders and that their previous meetings had been friendly and cordial.
Turnbull and McGowan are realists: They need each other.
Turnbull needs to win back the respect of angry West Australians who feel neglected by Canberra.
McGowan needs to build things - and for that he needs not just millions but billions and the Feds have made it clear they have plenty of cash.
During the Kevin Rudd era, there was a feeling by the WA Labor Party that the Federal Labor government was doing them no favours by continually "doing business" with Colin Barnett's Liberal-National government.
As Turnbull cosies up to McGowan and offers him billions, I just wonder what Liberal leader Mike Nahan is thinking?
Regardless, the undeniable truth is this: The biggest winner in this new love fest between the Federal coalition and Labor is WA, which badly needs more roads, more rail and more GST dollars.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Goodenough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull-Colin Barnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Labor Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Perth Freight Link</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal MPs Christian Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull-McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Rita Saffioti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnett</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Nahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA's Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stock Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State-Federal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Labor Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Barnett's Liberal-National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
