<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432801132518792</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/theres-more-than-one-way-to-run-a-business-20170803-gxok5k.html</url>
  <title>There's more than one way to run a business</title>
  <content>
Business generates extensive economic and social benefits. It can also be dreadfully damaging. By making informed, conscientious choices about consumption and investment, each of us can back the good and shun the bad.
First, an example of the bad. Crown Casino is an ostentatious palazzo raking cash, often from the vulnerable and addicted, in the certainty that the house always ultimately wins. Walk through the place at any time of day or night: the jarring sights and sounds of this cavernous trap baited by thousands of gaming machines and hundreds of gaming tables trigger alarm - and support for advocates of stricter protections for punters.Photo: JOE CASTRO
Instead of regulating rigorously, our governments have for decades gifted widely reported manifold special treatment to this gaudy gem. It happened again in February, when the Victorian government invoked a special exemption clause in the planning act and  Crown's plan to build a 90-storey tower. In the very same week, the  the state's alcohol and gambling regulator is too lenient on Crown Casino, amid well-reported concerns criminals have been given too much freedom to launder money in what is one of the world's biggest casinos.
Gambling is, and should of course continue to be, legal. But is hard to escape the conclusion Crown and its ilk have undue legal freedom, at the expense of the significant number of problem gamblers they prey on. Last financial year alone, Crown clients lost $1.8 billion. The annual Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia (HILDA) , released last week, found that as many as 1.4 million Australians are directly harmed by gambling. A staggering 41 per cent of monthly punters reported detrimental effects to themselves and their loved ones.
 Photo: Illustration: Andrew Dyson

Ahead of the 2014 election, Crown founder Lloyd Williams was recorded appearing to offer Andrews  for the Labor campaign. "I'm very pleased that, you should probably know I am the executive of the Packer estate, and James is going to kick every goal he can for you," Williams is recorded as saying, his hand on Andrews' back.
Crown is a business in which those who care about consequences should not invest. Yes, it employs people and pays the state government billions, but its net effect is needlessly negative. Many people had profound misgivings when it was approved more than a quarter of a century ago by the financially desperate, debt-laden Labor government of Joan Kirner.

One of the protesters at its opening was actor and activist Rachel Griffiths, who last week helped put the spotlight on another menace that can be mitigated by consumers and sharemarket investors - and by businesses, governments and community organisations. , behind drugs. As many as 45 million children, women and men are treated as commodities (average price about $90), criminally and cruelly bought and sold for sex work and fishing and construction and textiles and pretty much across all forms of labour. Most of it is happening in our region. 

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Griffiths is the patron of an organisation called , which works predominantly with women and children who have survived trafficking and abuse in Cambodia, Afghanistan and Vietnam. On Wednesday she appeared before Federal Parliament's joint standing committee on foreign affairs and trade, which is  establishing a Modern Slavery Act in Australia, in line with a recent move in the UK, to compel companies to report on slavery in their supply chains. Some businesses are resisting the proposal on the grounds of over-regulation. Instead, as Griffiths pointed out, they should be backing it on the grounds of enlightened self-interest; Australians are becoming increasingly aware of the slavery scourge, and are likely to prefer products they can be confident have not involved evil exploitation.
Investors are increasingly using their power to encourage companies to purge their supply chains of slavery. Australia's superannuation pool is the world's fourth-biggest. Hagar's support for an anti-slavery law is in line with the Australian Council of Superannuation Investors, which urged the committee to recommend "mandatory reporting, with provision for board approval, public disclosure, independent oversight and civil penalties".
"The issue of slavery is present, endemic and global," ACSI chief executive Louise Davidson stated. "It warrants urgent action by the Australian government." A number of businesses are also in favour. Miner Fortescue Metals, for example, argues all large businesses should be required to publish annual slavery statements.
This crucial humanitarian move also makes financial sense. A report released in recent days in the Responsible Investment Association Australasia's annual  revealed ethical investment funds outperform mainstream competitors, year after year. Economically and socially, investors, managers, employees, customers and suppliers benefit. Everybody wins.
That is something really worth betting on.
Michael Short is The Age's chief editorial writer. @shortmsgs
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACSI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Kirner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Council of Superannuation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hagar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Responsible Investment Association Australasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Dyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Short</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modern Slavery Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOE CASTRO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Casino</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Metals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
