<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432715233172093</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/brisbane-singer-ellen-reed-tipped-to-represent-australia-at-eurovision/news-story/e3612b9dd168a9e7c552ef502e9629bc</url>
  <title>Is this our next Eurovision superstar?</title>
  <content>
COULD powerhouse Brisbane singer Ellen Reed be Australia's next Eurovision star?
The rumour mill is churning after the fire-haired beauty, who was a grand finalist on The Voice last year, was interviewed by Blair Martin - a long time Eurovision correspondent - about her latest single Favourite Mistake on 4ZZZ Queer Radio last week.
When asked by Martin, who Confidential understands is well connected in the song contest circle, if she would be keen to be Australia's fourth competitor in 2018, Reed said she would be "honoured".

Dami Im sings for Australia at Eurovision 2016

Dami Im sings for Australia at Eurovision 2016
While our Eurovision performers, such as fellow Queenslander Dami Im, are chosen by SBS and Sony Music and not by a public vote, it's not entirely impossible the Firebirds ambassador could be picked for the gig.
While we've seen a string of emotional ballads from the rising star, her latest single, which is distinctly more poppy and upbeat, has all the hallmarks of a Eurovision hit, which Martin pointed out on air.
And with Universal having failed to snap her up following her appearance on Nine's reality singing show last year, the independent artist is up for grabs should Sony spark an interest.

Isaiah Firebrace performs for Australia in the Eurovision semi final 1.

Isaiah Firebrace performs for Australia in the Eurovision semi final 1.
It's also worth noting the return of Seven's X Factor - which sees its winner signed by Sony and, like Isaiah Firebrace, shipped off to Eurovision - has been ruled out for the foreseeable future.
Confidential's insiders understand Martin may even throw Reed's name in the ring himself should Australia be offered the chance to compete again - which is not guaranteed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven's X Factor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blair Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaiah Firebrace</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eurovision</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eurovision 2016</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Firebird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslander Dami Im</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Favourite Mistake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dami Im</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ZZZ Queer Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellen Reed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
