<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431521232252717</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-05/hunted-demons-wont-dwell-on-lost-opportunities</url>
  <title>Simon Goodwin post-match press conference</title>
  <content>
Goodwin: 'We butchered the ball'
Simon Goodwin conceded his side was too sloppy with its ball use and were outtackled by an impressive Giants outfit

Jack Watts failed to provide a good target up forward

MELBOURNE failed another huge test when they dropped their second consecutive game but coach Simon Goodwin has refused to think about blown opportunities and will keep his players focused on the rest of 2017.

The Demons looked hot when they booted the opening three goals of the game against Greater Western Sydney on Saturday, but meekly surrendered the next eight of the first quarter in a stunning display, and eventually lost by 35 points.

The Giants showed an intensity they've been missing for the past few weeks and coach Simon Goodwin admitted after the match that the Demons couldn't handle the pressure.

"I thought the Giants tackled us incredibly well early in the game and fundamentally they got on top of us around the footy," he said.

"They really hunted us around the footy and we turned the footy over a lot, I think they got six goals from turnovers in the first quarter alone.

"The momentum that they got was really difficult to stop.

"We were happy with our start but really disappointed with that 15 to 20 minute patch in the first quarter."  

A bad fortnight has ruined a chance for Melbourne to consolidate a position in the top eight, but Goodwin was determined to maintain a positive vibe within the camp.

"I've said this a lot and I'll continue to say it, it's not where you are now, it's where you are at (the end of) round 23," he said.

"We've got a great opportunity to respond next week and another two opportunities after that, so this club has a lot to play for."

One of the Demons' biggest issues was their inability to score, with leading goalscorer Jeff Garlett and fellow forward Jack Watts unsighted against the Giants.

Both players failed to get a kick until the third quarter, and with tall target Tom McDonald also quiet before half-time, the visitors managed just 12 scoring shots from 55 inside 50s for the afternoon.

"That was one of the reasons we couldn't connect forward of centre, we got beaten in our forward half," Goodwin said.

"In a lot of ways they responded after half-time, and that's probably taking the glass half full approach heading into next week, but at the same time, in the first half we got beaten badly across our half-forward line." 

Shane Mumford and Max Gawn collided in this incident.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Garlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Watts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Goodwin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
