<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432887031865593</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/asia/russian-president-vladimir-putin-poses-topless-in-siberian-holiday-fishing-photos/news-story/5e9d288a765c54991ee88c7aef496375</url>
  <title>Russian president Vladimir Putin poses topless in Siberian holiday fishing photos</title>
  <content>
Vladimir Putin let it all hang out while on holiday in Siberia. Picture: AFP/Sputnick/Alexey Nikolsky

WiresNews Corp Australia Network

Share

RUSSIA'S President Vladimir Putin, who loves to cultivate a virile man-of-action image, was shown on Russian TV Saturday spearfishing in a camouflage wetsuit, piloting a powerboat and catching some rays while on a Siberian holiday.

Vladimir Putin and Russian defence minister Sergei Shoigu kick back in Siberia. Picture: AFP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AFP
Mr Putin's affinity for the tough guy pose has been documented with shots of him bare-chested on horseback, diving in a submarine in Lake Baikal - the world's deepest - and flipping a Judo opponent.

Vladimir Putin headed to Siberia for a break. Picture: AP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AP
These latest images, provided by the Kremlin, captured his two-day stay in the remote Tuva area of southern Siberia.

Vladimir Putin gets some fishing in. Picture: AFP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AFP

Vladimir Putin shows off his fishing skills. Picture: AP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AP
Mr Putin "fished in a waterfall near a mountain lake, indulged in underwater fishing, sunbathed, went rafting in mountain rivers, piloted ... motor boats, went hiking and four-wheeler riding in the mountains," said Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov.

The Kremlin press service released pictures of Vladimir Putin on holiday. Picture: AP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AP

Vladimir Putin is clearly fond of fishing and of wearing no shirt. Picture: AFP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AFP
The images broadcast on public television, which insisted on "the physical fitness of the president", show Putin catching a pike in a camouflage wetsuit or sunning his bare torso with Defence Minister Sergei Shoigu, who is originally from the region.

The man kills fish with his bare hands. Picture: AFP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AFP
His trip comes days after Mr Putin said the US would have to cut 755 diplomatic staff in Russia and warned of a prolonged gridlock in its ties after the US Congress backed new sanctions against the Kremlin.

Vladimir Putin fancies himself quite the action man. Picture: AFP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AP
Mr Putin's previous made-for-TV exploits, however, have not been without controversy.
During a 2011 dive in the Black Sea he allegedly discovered two 15th century amphoras, but the find was mocked in independent media because the vessels were suspiciously without algae or other sea life.

He can swim, too. Picture: AFP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AFP
Mr Peskov admitted several months later that the scene had been staged.

Vladimir gets set for a dive while on holiday in Siberia. Picture: AP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource:AP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>wiresNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladimir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergei Shoigu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dmitry Peskov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siberian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siberia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian TV Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Putin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Peskov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Baikal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Minister Sergei Shoigu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP/Sputnick/Alexey NikolskySource</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP/Sputnick/Alexey Nikolsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
