<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431091735519605</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-05/five-talking-points-greater-western-sydney-v-melbourne</url>
  <title>Five talking points: Greater Western Sydney v Melbourne</title>
  <content>
Giant Shane Mumford and Demon Max Gawn had a mammoth battle in the ruck

1. 'Mummy' has given the Match Review Panel plenty to look at
Just days after Brownlow Medal favourite Patrick Dangerfield lost his chance to go back to back, GWS big man Shane Mumford will have his own worries. The Giant dumped debutant Corey Maynard in the first quarter with a bruising tackle that saw the Demon's head bounce off the cricket pitch area in the middle of the ground. Mumford was penalised, but Maynard got straight up to take his free kick. Not content with one incident, Mumford then dropped Max Gawn in the third quarter with a crude shoulder to the jaw, but incredibly, the 2016 All Australian didn't even get a free kick. Leon Cameron got a good look at back-up big man Dawson Simpson last week and he'll be calling on him again, with his No.1 ruckman set for a stint on the sidelines.

Shane Mumford and Max Gawn collided in this incident.

2. Slow and steady for Deledio in long-awaited return
The former Tiger played his first senior game since round 17, 2016, after overcoming a disastrous run with injuries to both calves, and while he wasn't a big factor in the result, his confidence will be better for the run. Deledio showed his class with footy in hand on a couple of occasions throughout the afternoon, and while he missed a set shot sitter from 30m out dead in front in the second term, the 30-year-old made no mistake when he got another chance in the last quarter. It was a memorable moment when he was mobbed by his teammates, and capped off a successful return to the big time. Deledio has another three games to continue to work on his form and fitness, and by the time the finals series begins, he should be cherry ripe to have a real impact for the Giants. 

The Giants get right around Brett Deledio as he kicks his first goal in an orange guernsey.

3. GWS finds a way to cover the loss of star forwards
The Giants went into the game with their leading goalkickers Jeremy Cameron (hamstring), Jonathon Patton (hamstring) and Toby Greene (suspended), and the 111 goals they've kicked this season, missing from the side, but they spread the load brilliantly. Star onballer Josh Kelly led the charge with three, one of 10 Giants to hit the scoreboard in an extremely important win. On the flip side, the Demons were also without a gun with Jesse Hogan (broken collarbone) not in the team, but their best forwards might as well have stayed in Melbourne. Jack Watts didn't get a kick until 10 minutes into the third term, while Jeff Garlett took even longer to bother the statisticians. Christian Petracca and Tom McDonald were also well held by the GWS defence, as shown by the fact the Dees managed only 12 scoring shots from 54 inside 50s for the game, one more than the Giants.

 

Pure wizardry from Stephen Coniglio!

4. Dees' top-eight hopes take a dive after first-quarter disappearing act
Simon Goodwin's men entered the round in seventh after a disappointing result against North Melbourne last week, and blew another chance to consolidate a spot in the top eight against GWS. They booted the first three goals of the game and dominated the home side, but once Dom Tyson gave them a handy 16-point lead, the Giants found their fanatical tackling pressure and the Demons couldn't handle the heat. GWS booted eight straight goals to take a 36-point advantage at the first change. When you consider the final margin was only 35, it was a costly and disappointing display. Melbourne's effort certainly couldn't be questioned, but their skill level and decision-making under the Giants' pressure didn't exactly look like that of a side capable of doing some damage in September.  

Alex Neal-Bullen puts on the moves and kicks a classy goal for the Demons.

5. The Kelly/Tyson/Salem trade, where are they now?
The Dees were howled down back in 2013 when they traded selection two to the Giants, which snared them gun midfielder Josh Kelly, in return for Dom Tyson and pick nine, which ended up being Christian Salem. The deal also involved some later picks with Jayden Hunt (Melbourne) and Rory Lobb (GWS) finding a home once that year's NAB AFL Draft was over. Kelly's 27-possession, three-goal effort only reaffirmed his status as one of the competition's brightest prospects, but Tyson and Salem weren't Melbourne's worst contributors and have really bright futures of their own. This seems to be a situation where both clubs are winners, well at least the Giants will be if Kelly is still in the orange and charcoal in 2018.

Christian Salem left the field after injuring his leg in this tangle.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Salem</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Garlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demon Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly/Tyson/Salem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Tyson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayden Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Neal-Bullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Watts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Maynard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dees</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Lobb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Petracca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawson Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Goodwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maynard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
