<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432891326832945</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/footscray-apartment-proposal-knocked-back-by-vcat-for-not-being-big-enough/news-story/9486d0a7a46e6d7dd3e17eb90f0ed6ba</url>
  <title>VCAT orders developer: 'go bigger'</title>
  <content>
THE state planning tribunal has told a developer to design a bigger apartment building, declaring an $18 million seven-storey proposal did not "exploit" a Footscray site enough.
Developer Jabala Pty Ltd appealed to the Victorian Civil and Administrative Tribunal after Maribyrnong Council last year knocked its proposal back because it exceeded its preferred four-storey height limit for the property at 6 Cross St.
Responding to the council's concerns, the developer scaled back the size of some of the upper floors in a redesign submitted to the tribunal.
But the tribunal told Jabala to go back to the drawing board, saying both the smaller design and original plans were an "underdevelopment" of the site, which currently contains a single-storey warehouse, home to The Potter's Church.
The council's infrastructure services director Nigel Higgins said while it was rare for VCAT to refuse an application on the basis of underdevelopment, it wasn't unprecedented, citing a ruling in Manningham in 2004 as the highest-profile such -ruling.
The council argued any development needed to be respectful of the "low-scale" homes in the area.
But tribunal members Rachel Naylor and Ann Keddie said the fact the property was opposite West Footscray Railway Station and only had one direct neighbour meant it was a prime location for "intense development" that could "easily absorb the seven-storey height".
Jabala was given a deadline of last Friday, August 4 to declare whether or not it would submit a new design.
The tribunal said it would reject the development if new plans were not submitted.
Jabala could not be reached for comment.

Demographer Bernard Salt on the growth of the west for Future Melbourne

BERNARD SALT ON THE GROWTH OF THE WEST FOR FUTURE MELBOURNE
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jabala Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GROWTH OF THE WEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ann Keddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Footscray Railway Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Potter's Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCAT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footscray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maribyrnong Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BERNARD SALT ON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cross St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jabala</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Naylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernard Salt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
