<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651431555591991413</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/dustin-fletcher-says-hed-love-to-see-james-hird-back-at-essendon-and-that-hes-not-angry-at-the-club/news-story/a2038f10b6ffaf5ee6590fa430447aa8</url>
  <title>'I'd love to see him back at Essendon'</title>
  <content>
ESSENDON great Dustin Fletcher says he would love to see former coach James Hird return to the club in some capacity.
Hird has kept a low-profile in the football community since stepping down as the Bombers' senior coach late in the 2015 season, off the back of the club's long-running supplements saga.
And Fletcher - who recently spent time with Hird and Kevin Sheedy in Tasmania - says his premiership teammate from 1993 and 2000 is in a good place after recent health troubles.
"We had a good trip," Fletcher told 3AW prior to Essendon's game with Carlton.
"I still text him and give him a ring every now and then.
"I know he went overseas with his wife and kids the last little bit before school holidays and he has been enjoying himself.
"Hopefully he's on the right path.
"I'd love to see him back at Essendon."
Fletcher retired at the end of 2015 before receiving a year-long ban like 34 of his former teammates in January last year.
And the key defender says he has no regrets over the way his career ended despite the dark clouds which hung over the club.
"Nah, I'm not really angry at the club," he said.
"There's no doubt mistakes were made by various parties and different people and to be honest, it wasn't the best time, but I'm pretty easygoing.
"The footy club have been fantastic to me."
Fletcher said he was happy to see the club back on track, saying a successful Essendon side was good for football.
"My old man played 260-odd games and it's a big part of me," he said.
"I'm well and truly happy that it (the saga is over and that Essendon can get out there and play footy.
"Because I think the competition is better when Essendon is playing well, Carlton's playing well and Collingwood and Richmond - it's just good for the AFL."
The now 42-year-old played 400 AFL games, breaking Simon Madden's club record of 378 games in Round 1, 2014.
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hird</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Madden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Sheedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
