<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432371635784809</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4835829/avondale-reignite-fire-with-crushing-victory/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Avondale reignite fire with crushing victory</title>
  <content>
Finals bound: Uni's Andrew Rae celebrates during the Illawarra rugby victory over Shoalhaven on Saturday. Picture: Adam McLean

IT TOOK just minutes for Avondale to deliver the response coach Murray McDonald wanted.
With the Illawarra rugby minor premiership already firmly in their keeping, McDonald was concerned the Wombats were in cruise control still two weeks out from the finals campaign. 
So a trip to Camden presented McDonald an opportunity to demand Avondale to flex the kind of muscle they'll need later this month in search of the title. 
Not only did they overpower Camden, they beat the clock, finishing 81-3 winners in a relentless demolition. 
"I gave them a bit of a rocket during the week," McDonald admitted. 
"We only played about 40 minutes of good footy the previous week (a 46-28 win over Shamrocks, when they had led 34-7 at half-time).
"I just wanted us to be consistent and put a full game together and we did that really well."
Piling on early points against the last-placed Camden, Avondale never looked back and are now one victory away from a perfect 18-0 record.
Forwards Tuumuliileuao Taiti-Taanoa and Steve Fuka were among the standouts.

However, their final round opponents Tech-Waratahs will prove a tricky assignment, given they are the competition's most improved team. 
Tahs succumbed 31-7 to third-placed Bowral on Saturday, but only after trailing 12-7 at the break. 
Regardless of the outcome, Avondale are destined to meet Vikings in the major semi-final in a fortnight's time. 
Vikings outlasted Kiama with a 40-29 victory, with second place already locked in. 
While Vikings coach Sean Barrett said last week there were enough similarities between Kiama and Avondale to work on their finals plans, McDonald has lowered his eyes. 
"I'm not worried about Vikings yet," he said. 
"We didn't set out at the start of the season to finish unbeaten, we just want to go out and win next week.
"It would be a great reward for the boys and the club, but I just want us to play well going into finals."
Meanwhile, University ensured it will have a shot at defending their premiership, beating Shoalhaven 36-24. 
Uni travel to Vincentia to take on Kiama in the final round, while Bowral are up against Campbelltown on Saturday.
Bowral will play the Mallee Bulls in a cut-throat semi-final next week.

Charles Curry

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Fuka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Curry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Barrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vincentia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avondale</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech-Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuumuliileuao Taiti-Taanoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowral</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vikings</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uni's Andrew Rae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shamrock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mallee Bulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
