<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432500484805204</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/shogun-sun-rises-to-the-occasion-to-cause-boilover-at-randwick-20170805-gxpz6s.html</url>
  <title>Shogun Sun rises to the occasion to cause boilover at Randwick</title>
  <content>
The Golden Rose bubble might have burst for a couple of highly touted Sydney colts, but it's very much intact for an unheralded Queenslander after Shogun Sun stormed to a surprise victory at Randwick on Saturday.
Kelly Schweida's colt, the most experienced in a crack field of which some will harbour hopes of making the stallion-making race of the Sydney spring, caused a boilover when he dived through under Christian Reith to beat favourite Addictive Nature by one-and-a-quarter lengths.Photo: AAP
Peter and Paul Snowden's impressive Brave Song, which launched a late challenge to Addictive Nature for favouritism, laboured in the ground and beat just one runner home.
"It was just the ground and he couldn't let down," Kerrin McEvoy said. "He might have come to the end of it as well."
But it was all smiles for connections of Shogun Sun - and to a lesser extent those attached to Addictive Nature - who have set their sights on the Golden Rose despite the imminent arrival of the better three-year-old cavalry in coming weeks.
Sportsbet trimmed Shogun Sun's Golden Rose price to $26, the same line of betting as Addictive Nature.

"If he keeps going like that I wouldn't be surprised to see him in a Golden Rose," Shogun Sun's rider Reith said. "The gap opened for him and it took him a little bit to get through because he wasn't quite sure about it.
"But he was very impressive once he got through there and he really put the foot down and knuckled down. And they always look good when they go past the post first."
Added trainer Bjorn Baker on Addictive Nature: "We've got to press on. I'm happy with that effort, I'm not sure if the inside will be the place to be, and we'll look at the Ming Dynasty in three weeks' time."
Schweida, one of the most astute trainers north of the border, wasn't trackside at Randwick and it was left to Shogun Sun's part-owner Mark Gray-Spencer to sing the praises of both his colt and trainer.
"Kelly Schweida is a great trainer and he's very underrated," Gray-Spencer said. "It gives us some hope going forward. I think Kelly is thinking about the Golden Rose.
"We bought [the colt] at the Magic Millions [for $80,000] and I've had a few horses with Kelly over the years and we got a few people including my brother into this one. We're having a great time."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shogun Sun</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schweida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shogun Sun's Golden Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gray-Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sportsbet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ming Dynasty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Reith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Snowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brave Song</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bjorn Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Millions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Schweida</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Rose</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addictive Nature</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Gray-Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
