<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432633628792661</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/rendezview/vips-partners-should-not-be-reduced-to-plus-ones/news-story/d893fb341a6395abf85dd7da7812906b</url>
  <title>Let's end the sneering at VIP's partners</title>
  <content>
NOW Prince Philip has retired with a tip of his bowler hat, perhaps we can also wave goodbye to the notion that male partners of alpha females are somehow emasculated.
For the 70 long years he's walked by the side of the Queen, he and other partners of female leaders have been subject to sneer campaigns.
It's so boring.
On Wednesday, a raincoat-clad Prince Philip carried out his lwith the Royal Marines Charity at Buckingham Palace.
With a cheery wave to the crowd, the Duke of Edinburgh, at 96, finally packed it in.
Well he's only carried out 22,220 solo engagements and made 5496 speeches as the Queen's Consort. I would imagine he simply wants a good sit down.
He was the poster boy for husbands of women in power - and despite his notorious gaffes, I'd say he's supported the Queen very well throughout their marriage. At least he's made her laugh.
To be fair, when Philip married Elizabeth in 1947, he knew what he was getting into. Admittedly he threw a bit of a wobbly when Winston Churchill insisted the Royal Family take the name Windsor not Mountbatten (even though that wasn't his real name anyway) complaining, "I'm nothing but a bloody amoeba. I am the only man in the country not allowed to give his name to his children."

He also had to give up his naval career, which must have been challenging, but then, nobody would expect anything less had the roles been reversed, especially in that era. Prime minister and presidents' wives around the world are still expected to do little more than look pretty alongside their husbands, even if they continue to have careers of their own.
So it's disheartening that 64 years after The Queen's coronation, we're still treating the male partners of female leaders with suspicion and derision.
Back in 1979, when Margaret Thatcher came to power as the UK's first female prime minister, her husband Denis - a highly successful businessman and millionaire, was publicly portrayed as henpecked and stupid.
When Margaret Thatcher was asked in an interview if her career had emasculated Denis, she replied, "My husband has his own life, his own work, his own personality and his own interests. He isn't playing second fiddle. We are each playing first fiddle."
But tell that to Julia Gillard, who got the same silly questions about her hairdresser partner Tim Mathieson when she became Australia's first female prime minister 31 years later.
In 2013 radio shock jock Howard Sattler asked the Prime Minister on air if Tim was gay. "Don't be ridiculous," she replied with great dignity. He was later sacked.
British prime minister Theresa May is also copping the same old bigotry, as her husband Philip, a city fund manager, is criticised for having crumply suits and outrageously suggesting he does "boy jobs" like putting the bins out.
And what would we have made had Hillary Clinton got into power and installed her old Bill as the First Gentleman? I'm pretty sure he would have escaped mockery, but then, we never found out did we, as instead we got the most testosterone-fuelled egomaniacal president the USA has ever seen.
As Prince Philip once said at a banquet in Brazil, "Balls to you sir."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winston Churchill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke of Edinburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Thatcher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Sattler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountbatten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Marines Charity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Consort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Family</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Mathieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Gentleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theresa May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
