<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432500484805196</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/corey-brown-lands-missile-stakes-on-invincible-gem-after-swift-kokoda-trek-20170805-gxq1k6.html</url>
  <title>Corey Brown lands Missile Stakes on Invincible Gem after swift Kokoda trek</title>
  <content>
MISSILE STAKES
Corey Brown hobbled off the Kokoda Track and then out of the winning stall after the Missile Stakes. If he was a horse, he might not have passed the morning vet check. Yet while the body might be slowing, the brain - and tongue - remain as sharp as ever.Photo: AAP
"I was always planning on riding [at Randwick on Saturday] because I was just going to outdo [Hugh] Bowman to show him who's tough and who's not," Brown quipped seconds after Bowman, also part of the Kokoda trekking team, had passed him en route to the jockeys' room.
His great mate wasn't riding on the day because of suspension. But Brown's aching knees and unlikely gait were still there, less than 24 hours after returning to Australia following a Kokoda mission done in three-and-a-half days.
Brown won the Missile on Invincible Gem, upsetting  stablemate Le Romain in the group 2 feature, by   planting Le Romain's rider Glyn Schofield in the cheap seats and then easing off his back to run him down late.
Invincible Gem won by a widening one-and-a-quarter lengths from Le Romain, which touched off The Monstar for second. Yet it was just numbers and, in reality, just another race. Brown, Bowman, Kathy O'Hara and Melbourne jockey Stephen Baster know that more than ever after their Kokoda trek..

"I underestimated the challenge I was up for, let alone to think what they went through 50-odd years ago," Brown said. "I'll be honest, I struggled the third day with my knees. A few of us all went through stages where if we could have got an Uber up the mountain we would have called one.
"But it was a great experience and when you get to the Anzac Memorial at Kokoda, which overlooks the two mountains ... it's a bit of a surreal feeling. It's definitely a place that means something.
"I loved every minute of it even though it was very, very hard. I would have loved to have done it over seven or nine days to learn a bit more about it - not just because of the personal and physical challenge - but to learn more about it. It was a bit rushed. It's definitely a bucket list thing to do for sure."
Newcastle trainer Kris Lees couldn't lose. Some suspected he would get the Missile Stakes quinella, but maybe not in the order that eventuated. And just when he thinks he might have got to the bottom of Invincible Gem, she tricks him again.
It was only when Schofield rode Invincible Gem to a midweek win last prep Lees thought he might have something with the  filly, but  Schofield was cursing her all the way around this time.
"[Le Romain] was exposed the whole way, which was always a chance of happening," Lees said. "And he probably just ran out [of condition] the last 50 metres. He's in for a good preparation.
"Last preparation [Invincible Gem] just kept surprising me and I was looking to spell her and she would do so well after a win I just kept raising the bar and she handled every step. She's a great advertisement for that stallion [I Am Invincible], he just improves mares incredibly well."
Lees will ponder whether to take Invincible Gem to the Sheraco Stakes next start.
The Monstar's trainer Brett Cavanough tinkered with his horse's gear adding a near cupped blinker after he threw away the Ramornie Handicap and he's got a group 2 placing on his resume now.
​"He probably just got beat by two really good horses," Cavanough said. "He's has had two attempts at weight-for-age and he's been really good both times.
"I'll talk to the handicapper and see what weight he gets and we'll look at the Tramway, trying to dodge all the real sharp horses. If it rains and turns into a mudheap we can do anything. He's just versatile, he's fit and he's a good eater. I think we've got to stay in work because of the wet tracks."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tramway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Romain</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheraco Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glyn Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramornie Handicap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schofield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Memorial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy O'Hara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cavanough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokoda Track</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokoda</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monstar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Lees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Cavanough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Baster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invincible Gem</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
