<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432891326832973</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/richmond-changes-as-popularity-sees-property-prices-rise/news-story/0b5a74327b674aa58b652e9d2d0b2363</url>
  <title>Richmond changes as popularity sees property prices rise - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Spotlight on Richmond.

LIVING in the heart of the action with everything on your doorstep in Richmond appeals to a diverse mix of people, according to developers.
Icon Developments senior development manager Brinn Tavener said Richmond's gentrification from an industrial area to a "vibrant urban hub" over the past 20 years made it a wish list location for many buyers.
"As part of this change, we've seen the suburb experience steady price growth," Mr Tavener said.

Spotlight on Richmond.

Median house prices in Richmond have grown 8.4 per cent to $1.22 million in the 12 months to April, according to CoreLogic.
Mr Tavener said the growth was coming from the changing demographics of home buyers in the area.
"Historically younger professionals wanted to be closer to the CBD and then would move out to the suburbs when they had a family," he said.
"However, these days people are wanting to stay in areas closer to the CBD with all the amenity that they are used to and enjoy.
"This change, coupled with limited new supply coming into the market, has supported the growth in house and apartment pricing."

Richmond is the ideal suburb to live in if you love sport.

Beam Projects director Paul Myers said Richmond was highly sought after because it was just 4km from the city centre and on the doorstep of Melbourne's sporting precinct.
"Richmond is a culmination of all the best Melbourne has to offer," Mr Myers said.
"The revitalisation of Swan St has turned the strip into one of Melbourne's pre-eminent food precincts - with the addition of restaurants by celebrity chefs Shannon Bennett and George Colombaris - which appeals to a broad range of buyers.
"There are green spaces all around the neighbourhood.
"A variety of parks and gardens within walking distance means people can choose their favourite spot for sprawling picnics, walking the dog, group exercise or relaxing with a
book and takeaway coffee."

, is in the Farmer Cutter & Swan development.

Icon Developments and Beam Projects have partnered to deliver Farmer Cutter & Swan, a six-level level apartment project, including ground floor retail space.
Mr Myers said the project had been popular with owner occupiers.
"When buyers compare the type of house they can purchase with their budget, young families have recognised that the larger format apartments (three bedroom, two bathroom, two car spaces) offer more and are better value than a run-down weatherboard that is more expensive and offers less," Mr Myers said.
"Farmer Cutter & Swan has apartments from $380,000 to top floor penthouses starting at $3 million," Mr Tavener said.
"The diversity in pricing has allowed us to offer a range of apartments to quite a wide demographic of the market, all of which appreciate the benefits Richmond has to offer."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brinn Tavener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Colombaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Myers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tavener</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmer Cutter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Icon Developments</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beam Projects</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
