<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432887031865608</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/football-technique-australia-running-soccer-as-an-elective-subject-at-carwatha-college/news-story/1a954b4e90daee7f7302165e3b8e2c3f</url>
  <title>School's footy subject ready to kick off</title>
  <content>
IMAGINE taking your most beloved sport as an elective subject at school; how good would your studies be?
For soccer fans at Carwatha College in Noble Park that dream will soon be reality. In 2018 the school will partner with Football Technique Australia (FTA) to introduce a football program.
The aim is to keep young students engaged with school and improve other areas of their education.
The FTA Academy will deliver a high level football program for years 5-11 as part of the school curriculum.
With limited places in its inaugural season, students will need to apply but if successful they will replace their regular PE classes with football and also participate in before school soccer programs.
Principal Pat Mulcahy said the program would start with 25 places with a view of expanding it by 25 more each year.
"It's about engaging kids in their education - if kids have something to look forward to everyday they engage a lot more in all other aspects of their education as well," Mr Mulcahy said.
FTA football director Ljuban Palinic said the football academy would give students the opportunity to pursue their passion while at school.
The program will feature the latest training methods and include skill acquisition, conditioning, mental preparation, game intelligence and football awareness.
Mr Mulcahy said he introduced basketball and dance academies when he was working at Berwick College and both had gone on to attract hundreds of participating students. He envisaged Carwatha's football academy would be just as successful.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Mulcahy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mulcahy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ljuban Palinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTA Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carwatha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Technique Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carwatha College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
