<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433149024873405</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/apple-custom-badge-reader-photo-2017-8</url>
  <title>BEHOLD: This is what Apple's custom badge reader looks like</title>
  <content>
Photos of what looks like a badge reader for Apple's internal use were posted by the FCC in July.

Behold:

According to the  included with the filing, it's for granting access to restricted areas to people with a company-provided credential.

"The reader will indicate granted access by briefly changing colour to green and playing a sound. Declined access is indicated by red colour and a second sound," according to the filing.

The filing was the second in a series of three mysterious Apple FCC authorization filings describing devices with Apple-style model numbers that popped up over the past year. Photos of the device from the first filing were published in March , 180 days after authorization was granted, and showed a door assembly with a NFC-capable badge reader.

This badge reader, codenamed A1846, has wireless NFC capability as well.

There are off-the-shelf badge readers available on the market, but Apple Park, Apple's $US5 billion campus opening this year, has  spearheaded by Apple's design head Jony Ive, including custom-built door handles, tables, and even banisters. Apple didn't immediately respond to a request for more information.

We don't know much else about this badge reader, but we're sure the sound it makes when it unlocks is amazing.

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jony Ive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFC-capable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple FCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
