<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433110370167361</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-06/pies-likely-to-lose-wells-greenwood-to-injury</url>
  <title>Pies likely to lose Wells, Greenwood to injury</title>
  <content>
Buckley: 'It was a perfect tackle'
Nathan Buckley asks the question what else was Brodie Grundy supposed to do

Collingwood tagger Levi Greenwood is helped from the field

COLLINGWOOD is likely to face Port Adelaide at Adelaide Oval next Sunday with a recast midfield missing Levi Greenwood and possibly Daniel Wells.

Pies tagger Greenwood hyperextended his left knee in a collision with North Melbourne ruckman Todd Goldstein during Collingwood's 54-point win at Etihad Stadium on Saturday night.

Magpie coach Nathan Buckley said the club's medical staff believed Greenwood had sustained damage to the medial ligament, which could rule him out for the last three rounds.

"The doc's really confident that there's no significant structural damage outside that. But we're still thinking that there's damage to maybe a medial ligament or the like," he said.

"We'll do the scan and we'll see, but we don't expect that he'll get up for a couple of weeks."

The Pies are already missing skipper Scott Pendlebury for the rest of the season with a finger injury, and Wells' potential absence with a corked left thigh would rob them of another classy playmaker.

Buckley revealed Wells had carried the "corky" into the game after copping it during a best-afield performance in the draw against Adelaide the previous week, and he had aggravated the problem.

Wells had a team-low five possessions against his old club.

"He trained pretty well during the week, so we went in clean and clear. He had an incident during the second quarter where he stretched for a ball and I think it went from pretty good to not great," Buckley said.

"He was able to play the game out but we'll wait for the dust to settle before we see what sort of damage he did in that incident.

"I think he's disappointed with his output for the night, and the fact he wasn't able to contribute as much as he would have liked against his old side.

"We've got eight days, so we've got a little bit of time into Port to see whether he's available for us next week."

The Pies' engine room could also be missing gun ruckman Brodie Grundy, who will attract Match Review Panel scrutiny for a tackle that .

Fellow Pies Tyson Goldsack and Adam Treloar copped knocks to the head but played out the game seemingly without any ill-effects.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Goldstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pies Tyson Goldsack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Pendlebury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi Greenwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenwood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Treloar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
