<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432625038857981</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/rendezview/gay-marriage-saga-exposes-our-governments-obsession-with-itself/news-story/e8684d83377d1b0e1251f8a74f8c53c1</url>
  <title>Proof our government is obsessed with itself</title>
  <content>
WHEN the Parliament resumes tomorrow the Coalition will decide if it's going to keep faith with the Australian electorate or let a handful of activist backbenchers hijack the government.
Christopher Pyne gave the game away with his "winners' circle" triumphalism to the Liberal left at the federal council meeting in June. It's now obvious that the Leader of the House of Representatives and his like-minded colleagues have been planning a  ambush for a very long time indeed.
It's noteworthy that Pyne's declaration that -sex marriage would happen very "soon" didn't trigger any rebuke from the Prime Minister; at the very least he should have lost his job as chief parliamentary strategist.
Colleagues say privately that Pyne has been verging on the hysterical in his advocacy of -sex marriage. When the issue was discussed by the Coalition joint party room back in August 2015, Pyne interjected that it was, somehow, a "National Party branch stack" even though he himself had said before the 2013 election that any change to the Coalition's opposition to -sex marriage would be a matter for the Coalition party room (and not just the Liberal one).
This follows the precedent set under John Howard when the Marriage Act was first amended in 2004 as well as the overarching rule that policy is for the Joint Party Room.
What's more, at a private dinner in Adelaide in August 2015, Pyne was told by then PM Tony Abbott of his plans for a plebiscite and Pyne expressed strong support as well as declaring it was important to "lock in the Nats".
What changed between the dinner and the subsequent Party room has a lot to do with leadership manoeuvring against Abbott but that's for another time.
For the record, let's be clear. After a six hour joint party room meeting had resolved that this issue should be determined by the people rather than MPs, Abbott declared that this was the last parliament where MPs would be bound on the issue of -sex marriage (because it was to be decided by the people, not politicians). But they certainly were bound on the process: there would not be any change to the Marriage Act without a people's vote first.
Every single one of the Liberal MPs this week demanding that this matter be decided by a free vote in the parliament went to last year's election on a clear platform that the parliament wouldn't touch it until after the people had had their say.
If you listened to the views of Trevor Evans, Dean Smith, Tim Wilson, Warren Entsch and others, apparently, only MPs can be trusted to have a mature debate about this. The people, by contrast, would descend into ignorance and even homophobia if it were left to them.
This is the kind of patronising nonsense that gives politicians a bad name.
These MPs who now say that they must support -sex marriage because of "conscience" are actually betraying the commitment they made to the people at the election to let them exercise theirs. It's reversals like this that are adding to the trust deficit in politics today.
But this issue is no longer just about same-sex marriage. It's about keeping faith with the electorate. And it is also about Turnbull's leadership.
What many commentators have missed is the PM's growing loss of support among his own "moderates" faction. Turnbull only remains in the Lodge because conservatives like Peter Dutton and Mathias Cormann continue to support him, for now.
All of this is a diabolic problem for Malcolm Turnbull and it's hard to avoid the conclusion that he wants it both ways.
While a handful of Liberal Party backbenchers are intent on dragging down their struggling PM to make history on gay marriage, it just highlights yet again for ordinary voters that this is a government obsessed with itself.
In the real world, there's far more pressing concerns facing households such as their winter power bills, poor wage growth that isn't keeping pace with a rising cost of a living and ongoing job insecurity.
Is it any wonder the polls keep telling us that people think the government is not focused on the things that matter?
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader of the House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Party Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
