<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432380225719481</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/world/man-who-tore-out-girlfriends-intestines-when-she-cried-another-mans-name-during-sex-gets-life/news-story/a791b169621dd5fb7cde579632df7825</url>
  <title>Life for man who disembowelled girlfriend</title>
  <content>
A FIEND who disembowelled his girlfriend after she called out her ex-husband's name during drunken sex in a closet said "sorry" as he was jailed for life without parole.
Fidel Lopez, who tore out his girlfriend's intestines after she screamed her ex-husband's name during tequila-fuelled sex, will spend the rest of his life in prison.
The 26-year-old has avoided the death penalty in Florida for killing and disembowelling Maria Nemeth in a grisly episode which shocked investigators,  reported.
Lopez admitted leaving Ms Nemeth, with whom he planned to marry and have children, to die on the bathroom floor of their apartment two years ago.
He admitted he had became a "monster" and carried out bizarre acts on her body as she lay bleeding on the tiles.
Florida's Broward County Court sentenced Lopez to life without parole after he pleaded guilty to murder and sexual battery to escape execution.
Police attended Lopez's apartment in Sunrise, north of Miami, in September 2015 after he called 911.
Lopez told the operator that 31-year-old Nemeth was having trouble breathing and was going to die.
Officers found Nemeth's naked body amid blood and body tissue in the bathroom of the apartment the couple had moved into only a week earlier.
Lopez was next to the body, crying.
It was just before 4am. The bathroom door was ripped off its hinges, a sliding-glass door was shattered and they found an empty tequila bottle and cut limes in the kitchen.
Lopez told them the couple had been having rough sex when Ms Nemeth went into the bathroom, vomited and collapsed.
He said that Ms Nemeth had urged him to use beer bottles as sex toys, but when officers challenged him he confessed to ripping out Nemeth's intestines in a jealous rage.
Police released crime scene footage of Lopez's interrogation, CBS Miami reported.

"Fidel, this was not a case of rough sex," one of the detectives can be heard telling Lopez.
Later in the interrogation the detective advised him: "You have to do the right thing and tell the truth."
Lopez had told cops he turned into a "monster" after Ms Nemeth, who had moved to the US from Peru in 2004, twice shouted her ex's name.
"She changed my name," he said. "She called me the name of the other (expletive) guy. And she said it twice and she was wrong and she was confusing me with him.
"At that point, I get mad," he said. "I get really, really mad."
He said he flew into a rage, shattered the glass door, punched holes in the wall and ripped a wardrobe door off its hinges.

He eventually ripped out part of her intestines with his hands, according to disturbing details in a report by US cops.
Lopez washed his hands and went outside for a cigarette before starting to panic and calling 911.
Ms Nemeth, who had originally arrived in the US at the age of 20 on a student exchange program, was working as an administrator in Miami.
She had married an American man from whom she had separated but remained in contact with, and constantly quarrelled with Lopez about it.
The couple had plans to marry and have children before the murder by Lopez, who has been dubbed "the Florida Monster".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria Nemeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida Monster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIAMI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fidel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS Miami</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fidel Lopez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida's Broward County Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lopez</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Nemeth</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nemeth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
