<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432809722453437</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-05/fighting-but-failing-suns-frustrate-eade</url>
  <title>Fighting but failing Suns frustrate Eade</title>
  <content>
Eade: 'Hard to win when playing kids'
Rodney Eade admits wins are hard to come by as the injury toll robs his side of experience

PERTH, AUSTRALIA - AUGUST 05: Aaron Hall of the Suns leaves there field limping with an injury during the 2017 AFL round 20 match between the Fremantle Dockers and the Gold Coast Suns at Domain Stadium on August 05, 2017 in Perth, Australia. (Photo by Daniel Carson/AFL Media)

RODNEY Eade praised the spirit of Gold Coast but was again left to bemoan skill errors after his side's 23-point loss to Fremantle at Domain Stadium on Saturday night.

The undermanned Suns led at quarter-time before Fremantle took control with a four-goal to one second term, which proved decisive.

"Stats aren't everything but when you are winning the contested possession by 37 it shows a real intent," Eade said.

"I think it shows the effort the players are putting in.

"It was galling the other way, the kicking disposal differential where we went at 57 per cent. That's the thing that hurt us.

"We had some good attacking forays but just turned the ball over.

"All our effort going forward and working hard at the contest we just couldn't make it effective. That was disappointing."

Gold Coast, which already had 14 on its injury list, lost David Swallow before the bounce and Aaron Hall to a hamstring strain before half-time.

Eade said Swallow had a tight groin.

"He trained on Thursday, but with the flight over we just had a little bit of a run yesterday and it just wasn't worth the risk," Eade said.

"He probably could have got up but we didn't think it was worth the risk, especially with the flight back."

Hall injured the other hamstring to the one he hurt earlier in the season.
"I haven't had an update, but you'd think it will be a minimum two weeks", Eade said

However, the under-seige coach remained upbeat despite the Suns' seventh loss in eight games, and said they would be attacking the last three rounds of the season at full tilt.

"Obviously we'd like to get a win," Eade said.

"That's the main thing, but certainly we are playing a lot of kids and some individuals being able to get some confidence out of that for pre-season.

"As much too, the spirit and effort we're showing. We are training pretty hard at being able to use the ball pretty well."

WATCH: Rodney Eade's full media conference

However, he didn't sugarcoat the injury crisis at the club and likelihood of a thorough review of another wretched season in that regard.

"We lost two players before quarter-time against Collingwood and three players by half-time last week so it makes it difficult when you are playing kids all the time," he said.

"I have been really pleased with our effort over the past month, including today.

"I think there are some really good signs, the spirit and the effort of the players have been terrific. We just haven't connected well as far as our use of the ball."

What a spoil from Joel Hamling! Unfortunately for him, Darcy MacPherson was there to crumb & kick the goal.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy MacPherson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eade</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Swallow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Hamling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Carson/AFL Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 05</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Hall of the Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eade</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
