<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433273578926130</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/workplace-relations/walking-the-talk-about-death-20170802-gxnpv1.html</url>
  <title>Walking the talk about death </title>
  <content>
When was the last time you talked openly about death? It is a topic that most of us remain uncomfortable with, despite it being a natural part of our lives.
One person who is very comfortable talking about death is Zenith Virago.Photo: Cathy Zheutlin
"We are all walking towards our own death," says Virago. "Well, some people are trying to run backwards but there's no hope."
Virago, 60, knows what she is talking about, having "walked alongside" hundreds people who have died. She coined the term Deathwalker to describe her work, which sees her accompanying a dying person and their family through the journey of death into bereavement.
This can involve talking about death, preparing for death, completing Advanced Health Plans, caring for those who are dying, assisting with the practicalities when someone dies suddenly or at home, creating ceremony, and ritual, and assisting families with loss.
Virago is often called in once a person has died, however she prefers to start the conversation well before that time. She notes that some people contact her when they are completely well but, perhaps after seeing a loved one die, are thinking about their own death. As well as work with individuals, Virago provides community education through the Natural Death Care Centre in her home area of Byron Bay as well as across Australia and internationally.

The centre's work includes Day of the Dead ceremonies as well as intensive training for others who wish to become Deathwalkers. "I've spent the last 15 years training people, enhancing their existing skills and encouraging them to walk that role in their community."
Virago's career has been accidental, gradually formalising her knowledge since finding herself "walking beside" friends who were dying during the HIV/AIDS epidemic in the 1980s.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I didn't plan it as a career ... I was lucky to learn on the job, at the bedside."
Previous paralegal training was valuable in understanding the legal aspects of death.
Some people use the term "midwife to the dying" or "death doula" to describe similar work but these titles do not sit well with Virago, who uses birth as a parallel to explain. "A lot of people think the midwife delivers the baby but it is not - it's the mother who gives birth. I'm walking that journey with the dying person or with their family - I'm accompanying them but it is their journey. Everyone has to do it for themselves."
Virago sees her role as one that harks back to old traditions. "There was always someone that held knowledge around death and dying in a community,' she says. 'I'm reviving something that always was."
Ultimately, she sees herself as a community resource. If you need a prompt to start a conversation, Dying To Know Day, on August 8, is a national day of action, with more than 350 events around Australia, including online, listed on dyingtoknow.org.
Talking honestly about death, even once a year, can make a difference to how we die. "It is a big and beautiful subject," says Virago. "Everyone has the capacity and courage to do death well. Most people who die well have lived well." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natural Death Care Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy Zheutlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV/Aids</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advanced Health Plans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deathwalker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day of the Dead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Know Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virago, 60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zenith Virago.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virago</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
