<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432887031865602</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/lifestyle/a-farewell-to-comfort-zones/news-story/01f6b55afabf9448ef2a0edf0c5d8131</url>
  <title>A farewell to comfort zones</title>
  <content>
Gee this dating gig. Phew!
I feel like I'm walking around with no clothes on. I'm raw, skittish, still sore but starting to function like a normal human being. I even cooked a meal Sunday night, and ate it.
My first proper date was with a really nice bloke, but it was too early and I pretty much just sat there like a mute and my mate came to the table and rescued me. And by rescued, I mean she did most of the talking for me. Then I pretended I needed to go to the bathroom and rang my mum like a loser.
I'm dating a different bloke. (I know, fast. Trust me I am freaking out.) And to make it worse, his personality is bigger than Ben Hur: All or nothing. Decisive. Confident. No games. No bull. Spontaneous. And most importantly, funny.
He says exactly what he thinks. I'm used to owning the floor, so I'm being pushed right out of my comfort zone. I am not in the driver's seat, and it's great.
My mate Katie met him, and she said afterwards, "Well, well, well Jessica. You have met your match with this one."
He likes motorsports, fishing - you know, man stuff. He sent me a picture of a motorbike wheel (apparently it was beautiful) and I laughed, because that's pretty much his version of sexting.
Mate, the last time I got on a bike it wasn't motorised and it had streamers on the handlebars and a basket on the front.
He keeps making me watch all these motocross race videos. I make all the appropriate sounds but mostly ask questions like "Doesn't your butt hurt sitting on that seat for hours on end?"
I know, look at me go! I am so nailing this dating thing.
I put up a picture of us up on social media. We were at the races and it's not often I blow-dry my hair and wear matching underwear so it needs to be recorded. The internet exploded.
It was my own fault, I suppose. I made sure it was black and white because we had matched our outfits.
Yes, that's right. We matched colours. Nerds.
He did look a little bit handsome though and has the best smile. I get a tiny bit weak when he laughs, so I am weak a lot.
I know, steady on there Jessica.
Ten seconds later, I watched my phone turn into a firecracker and I yelped a little.
Turned all the notifications off, peaked early and went home.
A few hours later I was told I'd had enough rest, and to get my arse into gear because we were going to his mate's who'd just ordered 2541 pizzas for everyone. And well, I do like pizza.
I have absolutely no idea what I am doing, so I am just rolling with it.
As my best mate Katie said "Throw your hat in the ring and see what happens." I just hope it doesn't catch fire.
Although, he's on notice. He still hasn't learnt how to make a Bloody Mary yet.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloody Marys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
