<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432586384151862</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/how-a-dose-of-puppy-love-is-helping-south-australian-veterans-live-with-posttraumatic-stress-disorder/news-story/ab9601f2841be8a98205b9462bfe324b</url>
  <title>New dogs of war saving our soldiers</title>
  <content>
WHEN Peter Checkley went shopping he'd scan the aisles for bad guys - that person in the crowd who wanted to do him harm.
Of course there was no such person, but a lifetime spent in urban combat zones meant Mr Checkley could never turn off his training.
Since teaming up Operation K9 assistance dog Ruby three-and-a-half years ago he's stopped scanning for terrorists and now scans the aisle for scraps of food that might distract his four-legged friend.
The PTSD survivor says it's no exaggeration to say that Ruby saved his life.
Sam Hooper tells a similar story. He went from waking up disappointed that he'd made it through the night to waking up from a whack in the face from the tail of his best mate Wallace, the dog who's given him the strength to embrace life again.
Ruby and Wallace are just two of the dogs trained by the Royal Society for the Blind to help ex-soldiers cope with post traumatic stress disorder.
The dogs can do everything from waking up people suffering from night terrors by turning on lights and removing blankets to fetching water bottles from the fridge for people suffering from panic attacks.
Mostly, however, they provide company, love and healing.
Retired Army Major Mr Checkley was in his late teens when he signed up to serve in Britain.
As a Royal Marine Commando, he was deployed to The Troubles in Northern Ireland where he did a number of tours attempting to keep a lid of the sectarian violence that was tearing the country apart.
He also served in Cyprus and Malaya, before emigrating to Australia in 1992.
Here he joined the Australian Army, where, at the age of 58, he led a team of specialists in Afghanistan.
Mr Checkley's first realisation that a life spent in war zones may have taken a mental toll came during an officers' night out.
"It was a movie night," he said.
"I had no clue what movie it was. I sat down with senior officers on both sides, and it was Saving Private Ryan. I was a wreck. I was wet through, but I couldn't leave. I was in a really bad place."

Drugs used to treat soldiers' physical pain is exacerbating post-traumatic stress and other emotional issues, Thomas Catan reports. Photo: AP.

For Veterans With PTSD, A New Demon: Their Meds
He struggled on, but became increasingly reliant on alcohol to get him through each night. He could go through a cask of wine a day.
Before Ruby came into Mr Checkley's life he was at a point where he was "seriously thinking (wife) Jenny might be better off without me".
"When I got Ruby I was able to socialise again. I stopped being hyper-vigilant and scanning for the bad guy
"It's got me back out there. It's like having another person with me, looking after me. I'm not one million per cent, and I never will be, but Ruby helps me get close."
Mr Hooper was deployed to East Timor in 1999, shortly after the country, in his words, "tore itself apart"
Attached to a field hospital in the capital of Dili, Mr Hooper said nothing could have prepared him for what he experienced.
"It was shit, just quietly," Mr Hooper said.
"The militia had done a good job of destroying the capital - pretty much everything was burnt. There was sewerage everywhere."
Sent home after sustaining an injury, it wasn't long before he noticed his behaviour changing.
"My ex probably said it best when she said, 'I want the Sam who went away, not the Sam who came back'," he said.
"I was fine for six months. I started drinking heavily, became loud and abusive, became violent towards things, rather than people - I'd throw things around or punch walls."
Mr Hooper wasn't actually diagnosed with PTSD until after he was discharged in 2002. He struggled to adjust to past-Army life, until Wallace came into his life 15 months ago.
"I'm brighter in myself now," he said.
"I'm happier, certainly not as depressed and anxious.
"I'm certainly not suicidal, which I was for a long time. I go out now, because I want to, not because I have to.
"It's hard to lay around in bed all day depressed when there's a dog jumping on you telling you to fill up his food bowl. Assistance dogs are something that should be available to every veteran with PTSD."

The U.S. Army is researching an anesthetic injection​ called a stellate ganglion block ​that could relieve symptoms of post-traumatic stress disorder. Here's how ​it works. Illustration/Video: Heather Seidel/The Wall Street Journal

Could a ​Simple Injection Treat PTSD Symptoms?
It's a sentiment Nick Xenophon Team Senator Skye Kakoschke-Moore agrees with.
Senator Kakoschke-Moore is petitioning the Senate to urge the Federal Government to fund a trial through the RSB to get more dogs with veterans.
"If the Federal Government is serious about finding ways to support our ex-service personnel then it should wholeheartedly support this trial," she said.
"Assistance dogs not only transform the lives of veterans, they also save lives.
"The RSB are the gold standard when it comes to training and placing assistance dogs for veterans. The evidence gathered through this trial will support the already overwhelming anecdotal evidence of the transformational effect of PTSD assistance dogs."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Med</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruby I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Checkley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PTSD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Timor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation K9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Team Senator Skye Kakoschke-Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simple Injection Treat PTSD Symptoms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saving Private Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heather Seidel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Catan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallace</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyprus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Marines Commando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruby</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Kakoschke-Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Demon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hooper</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Checkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Veterans With PTSD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S. Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Army Major Mr Checkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
