<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432715233172116</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/15000-and-you-thought-your-afl-tickets-were-expensive/news-story/5bb3dcdac5c651c10192b71438a316c1</url>
  <title>SA council's China footy junket</title>
  <content>
A SECOND Adelaide council is in hot water after documents revealed it spent $15,000 of ratepayer's money to send its mayor and two staff to China to watch the Port Adelaide versus Gold Coast Suns AFL game.
Playford Council was forced to release documents detailing the cost of Mayor Glenn Docherty's 10-day trip to China in May after an application under the Freedom of Information Act.
Tickets to the Port v Suns AFL game were not paid for by ratepayers but they will have to fork out $15,281.74 for other costs - including $1800 for a "travel allowance", $3,253 for accommodation, $4,393 for flights, $994 for meals, $938 for "miscellaneous" items and $1,190 for tickets to a gala dinner.
A similar trip was taken by Onkaparinga Council, but neither council represents ratepayers in Port Adelaide's AFL home base of Alberton.
Opposition spokesman for Primary Industries and Regional Development David Ridgway, who exposed the cost of the trip through an FOI application, said Playford Council was already unpopular with ratepayers after planning a rate rise of over 200 per cent for some residents.
It was rejected after widespread protest.
"Growers on the Northern Adelaide Plains have been devastated by the recent flooding and are working tirelessly to make ends meet and get back on their feet,'' he said.
"These growers and other ratepayers will be understandably angry their money has been used to send local government representatives overseas to watch a game of footy.
"The council's focus should be on driving down rates for these families and small businesses, not attending footy matches in China."
Mr Docherty said the council was striving to generate new business opportunities, including with China, in preparation of the close of the Holden factory in the area this year.
"The trip is already creating business benefits, including a recent visit from a Chinese delation to look at business opportunities,'' he said.
"In September the state and federal governments have a trade delegation coming over and they will visit our Stretton centre where they will be able to look at dozens of local businesses."
Meanwhile, Local Government Minister Geoff Brock has signalled that he expects councils to be more open about sporting sponsorships.
Under questioning in State Parliament this week, he ruled out criticising councils for signing up to sponsorship deals but said: "What I expect councillors to do, whatever decision they make ... is to have it fully disclosed to the public''.
Playford Council also defended the spending as part of a plan to increase trade with China.
In a written statement the council said: "Both Playford and PAFC strongly believe that through sports diplomacy, there is a great opportunity to build a bridge for business to business, government to government and people to people relationships between Australia and China''.
On the trip the mayor also attended other events including trade fairs and met Chinese government officials.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stretton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Docherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government Minister Geoff Brock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedom of Information</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Playford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SECOND Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide's AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suns AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Adelaide Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Development David Ridgway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Onkaparinga Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Playford Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
