<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433187679579406</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/national/public-service/ip-australia-reveals-plans-for-40m-upgrade-of-woden-headquarters-20170801-gxn8fd.html</url>
  <title>Room for yoga classes part of $40m upgrade to IP Australia </title>
  <content>
Public servants at Australia's intellectual property agency are set to benefit from a multimillion-dollar upgrade of its headquarters in Woden.
Work is set to begin in early 2018 on an estimated $39.7 million refurbishment of IP Australia's office at Discovery House, which is currently the subject of a parliamentary standing committee.Photo: Jamila Toderas
Details for the upgrade were released in IP Australia's submission to the committee, made public in late July, which include a new 60-place childcare centre, the construction of a 'health and well-being room' for yoga and pilates classes, as well as reconfiguring conference rooms and office spaces.
A multi-puprose amenities room is also planned for the redesign, which can hold more than 200 people, as a business centre that can fit up top 20 visitors.
The planned upgrades are subject to the approval of the standing committee, as well as the successful negotiation of a 15-year lease of the site from the building's owner.
In its submission, IP Australia said the proposal is designed to future proof the agency, with some of its current facilities in Woden "no longer entirely fit for purpose".

"The accommodation refresh will create an efficient, adaptable and sustainable workplace desuigned to support flexible work practices," the submission read.
"It is anticipated that at the conclusion of the works, 2000 square metres of office space will be freed and become available to sub-let to another government agency."

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The government department, which administers trade marks and patents in Australia has more than 1150 workers based out of Woden, making up 10 per cent of all public servants based in the suburb.
The proposed development of IP Australia's headquarters comes after the agency developed a report in 2015 looking into the accommodation of its workforce.
The report found several limitations with the current workplace arrangements, with the accommodation being "not only dated, but no longer entirely fit for purpose".
Other findings from the report included the current workplace density at IP Australia was 13.2 square metres per person, below the 14 square metre per person target mandated by the Department of Finance.
As part of the proposed upgrade, the ratio of meeting rooms at Discovery House would be improved and more shared spaces would be added.
IP Australia was the only body to make a submission to the committee
Public hearings on the multi-million dollar proposal are expected to be held some time this month.
If approved, the redevelopment is expected to be completed in 2019.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IP Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Finance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discovery House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
