<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433574226640092</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/adele-hosts-private-movie-screening-in-london-of-despicable-me-3-for-kids-of-the-grenfell-tower-fire/news-story/151b85722fb79e3ce1c485f3198decd0</url>
  <title>'Generous' Adele treats Grenfell kids</title>
  <content>
ADELE hosted a private screening of the movie Despicable Me 3 for survivors of the Grenfell Tower blaze.
the superstar organised the event at a cinema in London, inviting real-life Minions to meet kids who survived the blaze late last week.
Adele has raised hundreds of thousands of dollars for those affected by the tragedy.
Just five days ago she was spotted at a local learning centre in the area helping disadvantaged kids in an effort to give back following her global success.
A source said: "Adele sees her work in the community as a full-time priority now her touring days are over for the foreseeable future.
"Being a local Londoner, she's made no secret about how personally affected she was by the Grenfell Tower blaze and wants to help in every way she can.
"While she's working hard behind the scenes to raise cash, she wanted to treat residents to a night of fun and help take their minds off what happened and organised a private viewing of the brand new Despicable Me 3 movie.
"Everyone was overwhelmed by her generosity."
London-born Adele, 29, was one of the first stars to visit Grenfell Tower after the fire tragedy killed 80 people in the June blaze.
She also dropped in on a group of firefighters who tackled the fire for a "cup of tea and a cuddle".
Last weekend she was seen at Kensington's Into University chatting with youngsters and signing autographs in a rare sighting since she axed the final two dates of her World Tour at Wembley due to vocal cord damage.
Before pushing her voice to the brink during her 123-date tour, Adele had already indicated she would quit touring forever to spend time being a mum to son Angelo, four, with husband Simon Konecki, admitting she was a "homebody" and life on the road did not suit her "particularly well".
She signed off the first night of her Wembley gig asking fans to dig deep for Grenfell.
She said: "I've been down to Grenfell Tower. They are being neglected now.
"I promise any money that we raise will get to them. I am not leaving them.
"I'm involved now. I'll be banging on for this for days, weeks, months and years. I want everyone to donate.
"I didn't have a social conscience that long ago. You can grow one. I grew one. It comes with age."
The next day she told the crowd at her Wembley gig, that fans had helped raise over $165,000.
and is reprinted with permission
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grenfell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wembley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Konecki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington's Into University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Despicable Me 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London-born Adele, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grenfell Tower</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Londoners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
