<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432496189837888</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/fremantle-dockers-youngster-luke-ryan-stars-again-in-win-over-gold-coast/news-story/a7671c366d990eff1d3d33f449fc0fb3</url>
  <title>Dockers youngster Ryan stars again</title>
  <content>
HERE'S who impressed for Fremantle - and who didn't - as the Dockers returned to the winners' list with a comfortable victory against Gold Coast.
WHO IMPRESSED
Luke Ryan
This young man can play. It wasn't all perfect from Ryan, but the defender had a huge influence in just his eighth AFL game. The 21-year-old's marking ability is supreme for a player of his size and he just knows where to run to intercept the ball. With Gold Coast pressing early in the third quarter, Ryan stepped up to take several critical marks down back and pushed forward to set up the play. He finished with 28 disposals and a game-high 16 marks. It's time for Fremantle to finally get their first NAB Rising Star nominee for the year.
Cam McCarthy
McCarthy or Messi?

It has been a tough apprenticeship for Cam McCarthy in his first season at Fremantle, but he finally got some reward for effort tonight. McCarthy has lost his way over the past two months in terms of running at the ball carrier and leading to the right positions. Against the Suns, he found himself moving into better spaces and got the better of a quality defender in Steven May. The former Greater Western Sydney forward booted three goals to half time and finished with four overall. With another pre-season under his belt, he should be a significantly better player next year.
Nick Suban
Looked like a dead man walking early in the season, but has remarkably forced his way back into the discussion for a one-year deal. Suban has been used successfully as a run-with tagger. Against Gold Coast, he was allowed more freedom to play off a wing and relished the space and opportunity. Suban set up both of Fremantle's opening two goals. The first was courtesy of two bounces through the middle of the ground and a deft handball to McCarthy. The second was again a handpass, this time in a one-two exchange with Crozier. Suban has always been a penetrating kick, but has too often made the wrong decisions with ball in hand. He's made a strong case to be kept on and is still young enough that he should probably now be retained.
Griffin Logue
Having been critical of Logue several weeks ago, the club's top-10 draft pick duly deserves a vote of confidence now. Logue is starting to read the play better in defence and is showing a real capacity to mark strongly. His effort to take a brave grab going back with the flight of the ball in the first quarter will no doubt please coach Ross Lyon and was a gusty act. When he wasn't taking an intercept mark, the teenager was keeping the ball in front of himself at every opportunity. His ceiling is high and Fremantle should benefit from getting so much game time into Logue early.
Hayden Crozier
The 23-year-old has played every game since round three, but has been a modest contributor until tonight. Crozier showcased all the best parts of his game. He snapped a smart goal in the first quarter and was lively across the half-forward line in gathering seven disposals to quarter time. Crozier showed a selfless attitude with a chip pass to David Mundy in the second quarter where he had the right to have a ping at goal. He has also become the team's best tackler in the forward half. The main criticism has been his inability to find enough of the ball to be a dangerous player. If Crozier can produce more games like his one against Gold Coast, he can still become the player Fremantle were expecting.
AND WHO DIDN'T
Ballantyne breaks through

Jonathon Griffin
Brought in for a rested Sean Darcy and looks like he is just going. Griffin boasted far more experience than opponent Daniel Currie, but lowered his colours in his AFL return. The 31-year-old finished with two fewer hit-outs. It is clear Darcy has already gone past Griffin. It will be interesting if the veteran chooses to retire at the end of this season or is kept on as ruck insurance.
Danyle Pearce
Still contracted for next season, but Fremantle should consider the merits of keeping Pearce on. The 31-year-old was guilty of two glaring turnovers kicking out of Fremantle's defensive 50m arc - one which cost his club a goal to Peter Wright in the third quarter. He also went to ground too easily on several occasions. With a disposal efficiency of just 57 per cent for the night, it is worth asking what Pearce can still bring to the senior team. It wouldn't surprise if he didn't survive another list cull at the end of the season.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logue</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballantyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Mundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Darcy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Currie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suban</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffin Logue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Suban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB Rising Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam McCarthy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danyle Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCarthy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crozier</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayden Crozier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
