<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432895621800283</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/hero-huskies-on-the-map/news-story/e157b5882dbbab077975bae158b6ead0</url>
  <title>Hero huskies on the map</title>
  <content>
EVERY step into the icy unknown, their dogs were with them.
The heroic age of polar exploration owes so much to the huskies - the tireless workers that pulled the sleds and dreams of their masters.
The dogs hauled the food, the medical supplies and the science equipment. They were companions and, at times of desperation, they became a sustenance of last resort.
The work of huskies in helping early explorers traverse and map the icy continent is often overshadowed by the staggering ordeals of the expeditioners themselves.
But now the huskies are getting the recognition they deserve, for their part in the heroics.
The dogs that led Sir Douglas Mawson through Antarctica more than 100 years ago have been immortalised after a decision announced last week.
The names of Mawson's dogs have been bestowed on 26 prominent landmarks across Antarctica, ensuring the canine crew will never be forgotten.
The Australian Antarctic Division Place Names Committee has, for the first time, recognised the deeds of animals in choosing place names for islands, rocks and reefs.
Huskies were first used in Antarctica by the British in 1898. The dogs, from Greenland, were chosen because of their familiarity with snow and double layer of fur.
The dogs proved themselves lifesavers for the British explorers, who survived a four-day blizzard by having the dogs lie on top of them to keep warm.
The dogs were also prized for their strength, with a crew of six sled dogs able to haul hundreds of kilos of supplies across treacherous terrain.
According to former Antarctic expeditioner and dog handler Rod Ledingham, huskies were the "mainstay of exploration".
Mr Ledingham, who worked with huskies after joining the British Antarctic Survey in 1966 as a meteorologist, said the dogs were also keen navigators.
He said they could pull sleds across crevasses that would have otherwise been unpassable.
Mr Ledingham estimated thousands of huskies worked in Antarctica last century, before they were removed in 1993 after the Madrid protocol banned all non-native animals.
He said the dogs were not only the main form of transport but an important form of companionship on the isolated continent.
"They were companionship and some were like pets, but you had to be careful not to pat one more than any other because the others would attack that one."
They were fed only every second day, mainly on seal meat.
During his work with huskies during the 1960s and 1970s, Mr Ledingham found the female huskies to be the most reliable.
"Most of the leaders were female because they were easier to train and didn't spend their time growling at each other like the males did."
He said Mawson ordered 50 huskies from Greenland for his Australasian Antarctic Expedition of 1911-1914.
But the travel south did not agree with many of the dogs, who succumbed to disease - believed to be a type of distemper - and died during their voyage to Hobart.
When the expedition left Hobart on the Aurora, only 36 dogs were left.
Life in the Antarctic was harsh for the explorers, and their dogs.
Many of the dogs perished in the extreme conditions, and even though they bred, the pups were often eaten up by the hungry adult dogs. When the dogs' condition became too poor for them to work, they were shot.
When Mawson, Belgrave Ninnis and Xavier Mertz left Cape Denison and headed east in November 1912, they took two teams of dogs.
Tragedy struck on the Antarctic Plateau in December when Ninnis and six of the best dogs fell to their deaths down a crevasse. They took with them most of the food, their tent and supplies.
In Mawson's Antarctic Diaries, he ponders how to survive after losing "all dog food, and almost all man food".
"We considered it a possibility to get through to winter quarter by eating dogs ... May God help us," he wrote.
Mawson and Mertz turned around and raced back to Cape Denison - feeding the weakest dogs to the other dogs, before finally eating dog themselves.
Tragically, eating the dogs gave the pair Vitamin A poisoning, contributing to the death of Mertz.
The role of dogs in such tales of tragedy and survival have always been known, but never fully honoured.
Australian Antarctic Division Place Names Committee Chair Gillian Slocum said Mawson's dogs played a critical role in Australia's heroic era of exploration.
"Given their important contribution to Antarctic exploration, it is appropriate to name Antarctic landmarks in their honour with most prominent features named after the most important dogs," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninnis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctic</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xavier Mertz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Antarctic Division Place Names Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Douglas Mawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vitamins A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctic Plateau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mertz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasian Antarctic Expedition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Ledingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mawson's Antarctic Diaries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Antarctic Division Place Names Committee Chair Gillian Slocum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgrave Ninnis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ledingham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Denison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mawson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Antarctic Survey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 1912</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctica</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
