<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432367340817496</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/dissenting-clubs-could-veto-salary-cap-deal-in-new-twist-to-pay-war-20170805-gxq5b4.html</url>
  <title> Dissenting clubs could veto salary cap deal in new twist to pay war</title>
  <content>
It would  take just five dissenting clubs to jeopardise any salary cap agreement struck between the NRL and the Rugby League Players' Association in a fresh twist to the protracted pay war.
We can reveal that under the game's funding arrangement, 75 per cent of clubs must agree to the new collective bargaining agreement, which includes the salary-cap figure. That would require 12 of the 16 clubs to sign off on the cap for it to be ratified. However, a couple of the clubs under most cap pressure have been trying to raise the support required to scupper a deal that wouldn't suit them. Photo: AAP
As it stands, the clubs agitating for a significantly higher salary cap don't have the numbers. At the most recent meeting of club chief executives, the vast majority supported the indicative figure the parties are working towards.
However, that hasn't stopped a couple of clubs from hitting the phones in an attempt to gather the numbers needed to put upward pressure on player payments. Should they be successful, it would effectively render more than a year's worth of CBA negotiations pointless and potentially leave the game in limbo.

The governing body and the RLPA have made progress in recent weeks after NRL boss Todd Greenberg involved himself in talks. The salary cap is likely to be about $9.2 million, although there is argy-bargy over several potential inclusions.
Some clubs have overshot the mark and have been shopping their stars around ahead of what is predicted to be a frenzy of market activity. There are fears players will be made to pay for the sins of clubs who have blown the budget, leading to tactics such as threatening to drop them to reserve grade if they don't move on. The RLPA is keeping a close eye on the situation to ensure the rights of  players are protected.

"We are not aware of any current cases in which players are being 'bullied' or 'forced' to move on from a club whilst under contract," RLPA boss Ian Prendergast said. "We are hoping to reach an outcome for the collective bargaining agreement as soon as possible, however we also need to ensure that this next deal truly represents the value of the players."
Some clubs have been working towards a $10 million salary cap, but the final figure will be much lower.
"The starting point in any discussion of this nature has to be that the player has a valid and enforceable playing contract, which he is entitled to have honoured," Prendergast said.
NRL in a league of its own - sadly

The AFL has pocketed almost $20million more than the NRL from fundraising, leaving rugby league lagging behind even equestrian when it comes to tapping into a rich source of revenue.
Just a week after we revealed Greater Western Sydney will oppose plans to transform ANZ Stadium into a rectangular venue, Australian rules football has enjoyed a big financial win over rugby league.
The Australian Sports Foundation, the only body that offers donors tax-free donations, has just released its funding figures. Top spot was taken out by the AFL, which attracted $20million of the record $44.75million splurged on sport. While league doubled its funding to $429,312, the sum places it as the 12th-ranked sport, behind 11th-placed equestrian. Several AFL clubs raised more than $1million each - more than double what rugby league raised as a code.
At a time when NRL clubs are lobbying for government grants for high-performance centres, stadium upgrades and junior development, the figures show league officials are ignoring a potentially lucrative revenue stream. The discrepancy with Australian rules should be a huge 
concern. "Given the popularity and profile of [league], we believe further substantial growth is possible to assist the game at all levels," said foundation chief executive Patrick Walker.
Not easy being Green - or Mary, or Sticky

The pressure is mounting on the NRL's coaches if their performances at recent press conferences are anything to go by.
North Queensland coach Paul Green is the latest to lash out at whistleblowers following his side's loss to the Storm. Green risked a $10,000 fine after declaring "that was the worst refereeing display I have seen" and claiming the whistleblowers  "ruined the game".

Frank: Paul Green at the post-game media conference where he took aim at referees. Photo: AAP

His spray follows the comments of mild-mannered Dragons counterpart Paul McGregor, who was handed a breach notice and $10,000 fine for his description of officials as "embarrassing" and "incompetent" after the Dragons' loss to the Knights. Canberra's Ricky Stuart, the most fined coach of the lot, used his experience in such matters to give the refs a bake without sanction because he didn't question their integrity.
The outbursts are becoming more prevalent at the pointy end of the season and raise a bigger question: Are the fines money well spent?
Plenty of club powerbrokers we've spoken to actually encourage their coaches to spray the refs - regardless of the cost - in the belief they are more likely to win a penalty count in the weeks that follow. We're not suggesting that was the case in any of the above instances, or that the referees are swayed by such tactics, however, it shows the lengths some will go to get an edge at the business end of the season.
Watson's cause

Newcastle have nabbed themselves more than just a good footballer in Connor Watson.
The Roosters utility is just as impressive off the field. Watson is looking to establish his own charity after losing his cousin, Parker, six months ago at the age of just 17.
Watson is proud of his Aboriginal heritage - "My dad is from Walgett, so on his side I've got Kamilaroi and Wiradjuri in me" - and is passionate about preventing youth suicide in rural communities.
"That's one of the biggest things in society for me, the suicide rate of teenagers," Watson said. "Especially Indigenous suicide in those country communities. There are some pretty confronting statistics. My little cousin passed away a little while ago. It was very tough when it happened. It still hasn't sunk in. It's someone I'm definitely playing for every week. I'm thinking of him and the family out in Dubbo."
Watson is 21 but shows a maturity beyond his years. He is studying business at UTS and wants to build on the fundraising ventures his parents have begun through their business. The Newcastle-bound pivot and Roosters teammate Latrell Mitchell have already spoken to the NRL about their intentions to visit regional and remote Indigenous communities at the end of the year. 
New world order

Melbourne has emerged as a potential host for the World Club Series as the odds shorten on the fixtures being played locally.
Brisbane remain interested in hosting the WCS, potentially as a double-header, at Suncorp Stadium. There are plenty of logistical challenges involved regardless of where the games are played, with the travelling teams earning a $400,000 fee to help cover costs. It will prove extra tricky for organisers given the World Cup will eat well into the pre-season of the top sides.
Brisbane and South Sydney are interested in being involved if the matches stack up commercially, while Melbourne are a big chance of participating given they are short-priced premiership favourites.
Dog eat Dog

Canterbury have been discreetly trying to offload some of their players without any luck, but rivals are eyeing off one of the stars the club doesn't want to lose.
Several clubs would love to have David Klemmer on their books and are keeping a close eye on the situation at Belmore. The Bulldogs are under pressure after overestimating what the salary cap will be for next season, but there has been little interest in the players they are shopping around.
It would be a much different story if Klemmer, arguably the game's form prop, was to suddenly become available. The NSW and Australian forward remains under contract and, compared with some of his teammates, is on a relatively modest deal.
The Bulldogs are hopeful someone will pick up some of his teammates, who are on heavily back-ended deals, but the few clubs with cash are keeping their powder dry.
Shark patrol

Cronulla are considering making a play for Aidan Sezer if disgruntled playmaker James Maloney leaves the Shire outfit.
Maloney is contracted to the premiers for another season but believes he isn't being paid his market worth. Several clubs are watching the situation with interest and the Warriors are firming as a potential destination should a release be granted. The Sharks won't part with the NSW pivot unless a suitable replacement can be found and it remains to be seen whether Sydney-bound Cooper Cronk is a viable alternative.
Canberra will be one of the clubs under immense salary-cap pressure after overestimating the figure for next season, which is likely to be about $9.2 million. If the Green Machine is forced to jettison players, Sezer could be one of the men it  reluctantly parts company with. That would free up the Sharks to make a play for the Raiders half in what would be a new-look halves combination with Chad Townsend.
Maloney has enjoyed success across the Tasman and the Warriors are keeping their options open after losing Kieran Foran to Canterbury.
Welcome Matt

He's spoken of his intention to abandon his NRL dream and return to Sydney, although we're hearing Matt Lodge may yet stay put in a bid to play for Brisbane next year.
Lodge has been plying his trade for Broncos feeder side Redcliffe, his version of purgatory following the wild night in the US that threatened his league career. A New York judge ordered the former Wests Tigers prop to pay $1.2 million in damages to his victims after his infamous Manhattan rampage.
The 22-year-old has indicated he will likely return to Sydney next year after facing bankruptcy, and several NRL clubs have been inquiring about his services. We've been told the Broncos haven't given up hope of changing his mind and are a big chance of signing him if the NRL integrity unit clears him to resume his first-grade career in 2018.
Badge of honour

Congratulations to Gavin Badger for notching 300 NRL games in the most thankless job of all. "The Badge" will become just the fifth referee to reach the milestone on Sunday, a tremendous achievement given the increasing scrutiny and criticism of the whistle-blowers. Hopefully his wife, Kasey, will soon   also control first-grade games.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Prendergast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-bound Cooper Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiradjuri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra's Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aidan Sezer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prendergast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latrell Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WCS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sezer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redcliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kamilaroi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Badger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Klemmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Foran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RLPA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Greenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Green</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walgett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sports Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maloney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Players' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Klemmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Club Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREEN MACHINE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Townsend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Maloney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kasey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Lodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
