<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432586384151832</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/canberra-raiders/nrl-canberra-raiders-produce-complete-performance-against-cronulla-sharks-20170805-gxq1y4.html</url>
  <title>The Canberra Raiders statistic that could guide them to the NRL finals</title>
  <content>
It's the new statistic that can potentially guide the Canberra Raiders on winning streak to the NRL finals: 77 per cent.
Get above that and the Raiders haven't lost all season.

Up Next

Broncos deal Titans record loss

01:30

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Judiciary charges loom as Cronulla slip to Canberra

In a night of ugly tackles from Graham, Fifita and Gallen, the Ricky Stuart masterclass inspired the Raiders to a 30-12 victory over the Sharks to keep their NRL finals hopes alive.

Not only did the Green Machine do that, but they smashed it with a completion rate of 91 per cent.
It was almost a case of Canberra out-Cronulla-ing Cronulla and was especially crucial during a 10-minute period when they were a man down.Photo: Craig Golding
On the back of their most complete performance of the season, it means the Raiders have now won two on the trot, heaping pressure not only on a stumbling St George Illawarra but Penrith as well.
But they still need to win their last four games to push their way into the eight.

If they can produce another complete performance like that across the ditch against the New Zealand Warriors, then there'll be a few teams looking over their shoulders.Suspended animation

Josh Papalii of the Raiders is tackled by Chad Townsend. Photo: Craig Golding

Any Raiders team is going to be better with the injection of Josh Papalii and Jordan Rapana.
The pair have been outstanding this season for the Raiders and their returns from suspension had an immediate impact for the visitors.
Papalii hated every second of his two-game vacation, with the powerhouse itching to get back out on the field, but it allowed him to freshen up after a gruelling State of Origin campaign for Queensland.
Both crossed for tries in the opening half, Papalii's starting the ball rolling for the Green Machine, with Rapana then chiming in with a first-half brace.
His second was a case of getting the band back together with Rapana teaming up with Joey Leilua, who produced a great ball from dummy half to allow Rapana to dive over in the corner.
Rapana's first came from a pin-point cross-field kick from Blake Austin, who's kicking game played a crucial role as they wound down the clock to victory.Stuart's Midas touch

Ricky Stuart at the post-match press conference. Photo: NRL Imagery/Scott Davis

The Raiders coach made some crucial decisions involving his England internationals that had a massive impact on the game.
In recent weeks, he's started Kurt Baptiste at hooker with Josh Hodgson at lock, but he opted for Hodgson in his more usual role at dummy half.
Hodgson was sharp in the No.9 jersey, getting back to the form he produced at Shark Park last year.
He set up Papalii's try and then showed-and-goed his way through the Cronulla line for one of his own.
That came off the back of an Elliott Whitehead offload.
Whitehead was brilliant in his switch from his usual spot on the right edge into the middle.
He worked tirelessly at lock, both trucking it up the guts and his usual tackling as well.
It also allowed Joe Tapine to move to the right edge after a great game on the left edge filling in for Papalii in last week's win over South Sydney.Nu ill effects

Fa'amanu Brown of the Sharks leaves the field injured last week. Photo: David Rowland

Sharks five-eighth Nu Brown's selection raised eyebrows, with the versatile back playing a week after a sickening concussion.
He copped an accidental knee from New Zealand Warriors prop Sam Lisone and was sent to hospital for scans such was the concern after he was knocked out.
But he passed all the concussion protocols to be cleared for action and he showed he was clear headed with his performance.
His quick hands played a role in the Sharks' opening try, getting the ball to a wide open Sosaia Feki on the wing.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tapine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Lisone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey Leilua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodgson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rapana</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shark Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Rapana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Baptiste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott Whitehead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Papalii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Golding</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Raiders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla-ing Cronulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papalii</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL Imagery/Scott Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nu Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREEN MACHINE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Townsend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney.Nu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Papalii of the Raiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sosaia Feki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown of the Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hodgson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
