<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433144729906066</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/what-a-waste-victorias-rubbish-pile-projected-to-hit-20-million-tonnes-a-year-20170803-gxot6x.html</url>
  <title>What a waste: Victoria's rubbish pile projected to hit 20 million tonnes a year</title>
  <content>
Decaying food that emits greenhouse gases as it rots; shredded old cars and white goods that can't be recycled; vast quantities of construction spoil; discarded televisions and computers that if mishandled could leach harmful chemicals into the environment.
This is the stuff Victoria's mountains of landfill are made of, and it's growing by hundreds of thousands of tonnes a year, mostly at a handful of mega-tips on Melbourne's urban fringe.

Up Next

Dumped: Melbourne's waste management scam

01:36

More Environment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Tip of the iceberg

Victoria's waste management is becoming a serious problem. With several tips closing and the sheer volume of rubbish being produced by Victorian's increasing, the problem will only get worse before it gets better.

Victorians produced 12.8 million tonnes of rubbish in 2015-16, a new report by government agency Sustainability Victoria shows, and are projected to generate more than 20 million tonnes of waste each year by 2043.
On that projection, the giant waste pile will grow by about 240,000 tonnes a year.

It's growing even though Victorians are producing slightly less waste per person than 10 years ago.

Sustainability Victoria estimates it will cost between $3.6 billion and $5 billion in the next 30 years to manage the increase in waste and improve the state's recycling regime so that less rubbish goes to landfill.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

About two-thirds of the 12.8 million tonnes of waste was recycled, the agency says, with the remaining third going to landfill.Photo: Graham Tidy
It says a "paradigm shift is required" in how Victoria processes waste, including more effective recycling and the conversion of wasted food into energy.
Victoria's waste management, where one-third of what is thrown out becomes landfill, compares poorly with some European countries where up to 99 per cent of waste is recycled.
In an  that awaits the Andrews government's final approval, Sustainability Victoria has identified five tip sites on Melbourne's urban fringe that will handle the city's waste over that time, in Ravenhall, Werribee, Wollert, Bulla and Lyndhurst.
Junkyard dogs minister

But one earmarked site, at Ravenhall, is the subject of a looming legal challenge that, if successful, will force the government to find a new dumping ground for much of Melbourne's growing waste pile.
Melton and Brimbank councils have joined resident groups to challenge at VCAT the Environment Protection Authority's recent approval of an expansion of the Ravenhall landfill.
A hearing is scheduled for October 2.
Planning Minister Richard Wynne also approved the tip's 96-hectare expansion in June, which will give it space to handle waste for another 21 years.
In its report, Sustainability Victoria says the outcome of the VCAT challenge is critical to the state's future waste management plans.
"If this site does not receive land use planning approval, the metropolitan region is at risk of having inadequate landfill capacity to meet expected needs and a new landfill hub of similar capacity may need to be scheduled by 2021, and built and commissioned by 2026," the report says.
Harry van Moorst​ is president of lobby group Western Region Environment Centre, which has joined the councils' court action.

Harry van Moorst, president of the Western Region Environment Centre, at the Werribee tip. Photo: Luis Ascui

He argued Sustainability Victoria's plan lacked ambition or any binding targets to cut waste.
"We are just not getting real traction or incentives to make these alternatives [to landfill] a reality," Mr van Moorst said.
"This report has tonnes of mentions of resource recovery but there is no scheduling and policy for utilising the landfill levy even to help pay for it."
The landfill levy is a tax on rubbish that has raised almost $500 million.
The waste management plan sets a target to increase the proportion of waste that is recycled from 67 per cent now to 73 per cent in five years and 76 per cent in 20 years.
It says recycling more food, which accounts for 35 per cent of the state's waste, is the best way to reach this target.
Food fight

Barely any food that is thrown out in Victoria is recycled - 92 per cent went to landfill in 2015-16 - and the report predicts the city will need more landfill capacity to handle it all within one to five years.
Rotting food in landfill produces methane gas that is a source of greenhouse gas emissions.
"Decomposition produces odours, leachate and greenhouse gases which can adversely impact on community amenity, the environment and public health," the report says.
"Managing these issues at landfills is a long-term imposition on current and future generations."
E-waste - electronic junk such as discarded computers and televisions  - is also a big contributor to Victoria's growing junk pile.
In 2014, 106,000 tonnes of e-waste entered the Victorian waste system, less than half of which was recycled.
It is projected that this could grow to 259,000 tonnes by 2035.
The Andrews government says it will ban e-waste from landfill next year.
Sustainability Victoria's report sounds a warning that a market will need to be found for the digital detritus "to ensure stockpiling does not occur". 
Stockpiling of recycled materials "can have negative community, environment and public health impacts", the report says.
Environment Minister Lily D'Ambrosio​ said Victorians were producing less waste per person now than they were 10 years ago - about 2.1 tonnes each, compared with 2.3 tonnes - and more was being recovered and recycled.
"But as Victoria grows, we need to keep investing in recovering and recycling waste, and protecting our environment," she said.
The government put $7.6 million in the current budget into a fund for making commercial products out of waste, including recycling rubber and plastic waste into road materials.
Nina Springle​, Greens waste spokeswoman, said the government should tackle society's throwaway culture, by supporting the Greens' bill to ban plastic bags.
"It's time to stop the production of easily disposed of waste products at its source, because people are not regulating themselves," Ms Springle said.
"We are consuming so much and we are not thinking about the end product."
Sustainability Victoria's Statewide Waste and Resource Recovery Infrastructure Plan, 2017-2046, is open for consultation until August 31.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorst</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Tidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Lily D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ravenhall</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCAT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E-Waste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyndhurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Statewide Waste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Ascui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nina Springle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brimbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resource Recovery Infrastructure Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Richard Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Region Environment Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sustainability Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Springle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambrosio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
