<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433788975006932</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/03/32/liberals-plot-path-forward-on-gay-marriage</url>
  <title>Liberals plot path forward on gay marriage</title>
  <content>
New polling figures and a United Nations ruling highlight some of the key issues confronting Liberal MPs as they prepare to plot a path forward on same-sex marriage.
The Liberals will hold a special partyroom meeting in Canberra on Monday to debate whether to hold a plebiscite, postal or parliamentary vote before changing marriage laws.
Polling released days out from the meeting shows a majority of voters in six seats held by Liberal MPs - whose positions on marriage equality are undeclared - support same-sex marriage and a free vote in parliament.
However Liberal voters in each electorate were significantly less inclined to believe same-sex couples should be able to wed or that the government should resolve the issue through a free parliamentary vote.
The ReachTel poll commissioned by activist group GetUp examined the views of voters in six seats across Queensland and Western Australia.
More than 50 per cent of respondents in five of the six electorates supported same-sex marriage.
In Sterling, a metropolitan Perth seat held by Justice Minister Michael Keenan, 48 per cent supported gay marriage, with 42 per cent opposed and 10 per cent undecided.

Related Articles

A majority of voters in each electorate believed the government should hold a free vote in parliament as soon as possible.
Liberal voters were far less likely to support marriage equality and were generally split over holding a free parliamentary vote.
GetUp is urging the six Liberal MPs - Mr Keenan, Trade Minister Steve Ciobo, Assistant Health Minister Jane Prentice, Aged Care Minister Ken Wyatt and backbenchers Steve Irons and Ben Morton - to back a free vote.
Respondents were not asked about holding a same-sex marriage plebiscite.
Meanwhile, the United Nations has found Australian laws barring same-sex couples who married overseas from getting divorced violate international obligations.
The UN Human Rights Committee ruled an Australian woman has been denied equal protection of the law because Australia does not allow her to end a legal Canadian same-sex marriage.
The case was taken to the UN by Fiona Kumari Campbell, who travelled to Canada to marry her ex-partner in 2004 before the couple separated later that year.
As same-sex marriage is not legal in Australia, Dr Campbell's marriage is not officially recognised and therefore cannot be subject to divorce proceedings.
She cannot get divorced in Canada either because she did not live there for at least a year.
The UN found the differential treatment Dr Campbell was subjected to regarding divorce proceedings was discriminatory.
"This is another nail in the coffin of Australia's prohibition on marriage equality," Dr Campbell said afterwards.
Ahead of Monday's meeting, federal cabinet has reaffirmed support for a national vote to decide on same-sex marriage.
However Western Australian Liberal MP Dean Smith describes the plebiscite as a "tool for delay" and says the time has come for a parliamentary vote.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Kumari Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sterling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN Human Rights Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian Liberal MP Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Minister Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care Minister Ken Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Campbell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Steve Ciobo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Health Minister Jane Prentice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ReachTEL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GetUp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Morton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Irons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
