<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433015880885944</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/nato-soldiers-stop-afghan-insider-attack/news-story/a2b22504f2257c1cfae5df6139b27e73</url>
  <title>NATO soldiers stop Afghan insider attack</title>
  <content>
Romanian soldiers from the NATO-led Resolute Support mission in Afghanistan have killed an Afghan policeman who was trying to carry out an insider attack after a training session in the southern province of Kandahar.
A Romanian was wounded in the attack on Saturday while an Afghan policeman was wounded in the crossfire, a statement from Resolute Support headquarters in Kabul says.
"The advisers had completed a scheduled law enforcement training and were preparing to return to base when they were attacked by a member of the Afghan National Civil Order Police," the statement said.
Romanian soldiers providing security returned fire and killed the attacker, it said.
The attack, which came as the US is considering increasing the number of troops it has in Afghanistan, is the latest in a series of so-called "green-on-blue" incidents.
In June, three American soldiers were killed and seven wounded in two separate incidents, a week apart.
In May last year, two members of the Romanian special forces were killed and a third was wounded when a local policeman opened fire on them.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan National Civil Order Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kandahar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resolute Support</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATO-led Resolute Support</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KABUL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romanian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
