<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432582089184531</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-05/big-win-giants-over-dees-as-pies-freo-bombers-dogs-get-points/8777510</url>
  <title>GWS pushes for top two spot after beating Melbourne, while Collingwood, Fremantle, Essendon and Western Bulldogs also win</title>
  <content>
The Giants consolidated a top four spot, the Lions gave the Bulldogs a big fright, and an injury to Kangaroos star Ben Brown was another big headline on a big Saturday of AFL football.

Quick navigation

Giants far too strong for Demons in the wind

The Greater Western Sydney Giants have consolidated their spot in the AFL's top four with a 35-point victory over Melbourne.
GWS outclassed the Demons, winning 14.13 (97) to 10.2 (62) in front of 14,274 fans on Saturday afternoon at Manuka Oval.
It was a costly loss for Melbourne, who could drop out of the top eight by the end of the round, while GWS jumps to second.
The Giants' tackling was sensational, with their high-pressure game choking a Dees side who lacked creativity in attack.

External Link:

Giants v Demons summary
There were concerning signs for GWS early, with Melbourne booting the first three goals of the match.
But the momentum was arrested by two freakish goals, with Stephen Coniglio's left-foot banana from the boundary opening the Giants' account before Tom Scully benefited from a wicked off-break.
That sparked an avalanche, with GWS using a favourable breeze to pile on eight majors to give them their highest-scoring first quarter in the club's short history.
The Giants switched their focus to defence in the second term without the aid of the breeze, playing with an extra man in the backline as the pace disappeared from the contest.
Despite dominating possession, the Dees struggled to break them down and went into the main break trailing by six goals.
GWS kept Melbourne at arm's length in a dour second half, with any hopes of a comeback snuffed out by the Giants' strong defensive efforts.
The Demons' forwards had a miserable day with Jack Watts and Jeff Garlett not registering a kick in the first half.

External Link:

Giants v Demons stats
Giants midfield star Josh Kelly played stints up forward and finished with three goals and 27 disposals, while veteran Steve Johnson and Devon Smith kicked two apiece.
Callan Ward and Dylan Shiel showed toughness at the contest, while racking up 29 and 25 touches respectively.
Former Richmond star Brett Deledio celebrated his AFL comeback with a last-quarter goal in an otherwise quiet return.
To add to the Demons' pain, Jake Melksham could face a suspension for a high bump.
Giants ruckman Shane Mumford will also come under scrutiny from the match review panel over two incidents.
He flung debutant Corey Maynard into the turf in a heavy tackle in the second quarter, before collecting Max Gawn with his shoulder in the third.
AAP
Magpies win, Brown hospitalised in bad night for North

Collingwood has been far too strong for North Melbourne, running out 54-point winners at Docklands on Saturday night.
North Melbourne managed only one goal to half-time, and although the Kangaroos kicked six in the second half, they still went down 16.15 (111) to 7.15 (57).

External Link:

Kangaroos v Magpies summary
The bad result was made worse for the Kangaroos, who had star forward Ben Brown hospitalised on a disastrous night for Brad Scott's side.
The match was stopped for several minutes in the second quarter after Brown was knocked out in a Brodie Grundy tackle.
The Magpies' ruckman received a free kick for holding the ball, but Brown's head hit the turf in the tackle.
It will draw comparisons to the one that led to Geelong superstar Patrick Dangerfield being suspended.

External Link:

Kangaroos v Collingwood stats
Tackling will be in the spotlight again this week.
Adam Treloar also hit his head on the turf in a Jack Ziebell tackle, but the Pies' star was able to continue the game and was important with 34 possessions and a brilliant goal.
To make matters worse for North, midfield bull Ben Cunnington (28 disposals) will come under scrutiny from the match review panel for a high bump on Tyson Goldsack.
Collingwood had injury concerns as well, with former Kangaroo Levi Greenwood leaving the game with a knee injury in the second term.
Daniel Wells (five possessions) did not fare well in his first game against his old side, the veteran midfielder finishing on the bench with a leg injury that restricted him for most of the night.
With skipper Scott Pendlebury still sidelined with a broken finger, Taylor Adams was influential with 30 touches and two goals.
AAP
Dockers get job done against Suns at Subi

Fremantle has increased the pressure on the struggling Gold Coast Suns with a 23-point win at Subiaco Oval.
The Dockers trailed early, but soon rebounded and went on to score a solid victory, 12.18 (90) to 10.7 (67).
The Suns easily won the contested possessions and had one more inside 50 than the home side, but could not convert enough chances.

External Link:

Dockers v Suns summary
Cam McCarthy led the way for Fremantle with four goals, while Suns spearhead Tom Lynch and fellow forward Peter Wright each kicked three for the visitors.
The Suns are going through a club-wide review, after another disappointing season.
The Queenslanders have won just six games so far in 2017, and there is speculation that coach Rodney Eade's job could be under threat.

External Link:

Dockers v Suns stats
While the visitors kicked the opening two goals of the game, they could not get closer than 11 points down from early in the second quarter.
Despite the fact they were beaten on the scoreboard, the Suns also registered 34 less tackles than the Dockers.
Fremantle will face Sydney, Richmond and Essendon to round out the season, while Gold Coast will face Brisbane in the Q-Clash next week, before finishing 2017 with games against Essendon and Port Adelaide.
Bulldogs hold on against brave Lions

The Western Bulldogs have overcome an injury to skipper Easton Wood to edge past Brisbane by 14 points and move into the AFL top eight.
After enjoying a 28-point lead at the first break, the Bulldogs were 11 points down at three-quarter time but battled back to win 14.19 (103) to 13.11 (89) in front of 16,148 fans at the Gabba.
Marcus Bontempelli, who was as culpable as anyone for kicking inaccuracy, booted two majors in the final term to help the Bulldogs to victory over the Lions.

External Link:

Lions v Bulldogs summary
Early on, it seemed like the Bulldogs would romp to a win as a tame Chris Fagan side slipped 6.6 (42) to 2.2 (14) behind.
Despite losing the clearance battle 45-30 and the inside-50 count 64-37, the Lions dominated the scoring in the middle quarters.
A big contributing factor to the Lions' 23 scoring shots from their meagre inside-50 total was the absence of the Bulldogs premiership captain Wood.
He limped off the ground with a hamstring injury midway through the first quarter after a tackle from Jarrod Berry.

External Link:

Lions v Bulldogs stats
The Lions took the lead in the third quarter as Lewis Taylor came to the fore creating one goal for Tom Rockliff and then kicking one from 50 metres.
Daniel Rich's big boot from outside the 50, after a handball from Berry on the mark, gave the hosts an 11-point lead going into the final term, but it was to prove in vain.
With their season on the line, the defending champions rallied in the final quarter, with Jack Redpath and Liam Picken kicking their third goals of the game.
AAP
Bombers scrape a win over Blues

Essendon has nearly blown a chance to jump into the top eight, eking out an eight-point win over Carlton at the MCG.
The Bombers had an opportunity to move up the ladder after Melbourne's defeat by the Giants in Canberra, but John Worsfold's men were pushed all the way before beating the Blues 11.18 (84) to 11.10 (76).
Essendon could have almost put the game away in the opening term, kicking a wasteful 5.8 to Carlton's 2.1 to lead by 25 points at quarter-time.

External Link:

Essendon v Carlton summary
The Blues steadied, holding the Bombers goal-less in the second quarter to reduce the margin to 10 points at the long break.
Carlton was winning the clearances against Essendon's midfield, and the Blues kicked five goals to two in the third term to take an unlikely three-point lead at three-quarter time.
In a tight final quarter, the Blues edged ahead before goals in time-on to Cale Hooker and Anthony McDonald-Tipungwuti sealed the win for the Bombers.
Joe Daniher and McDonald-Tipungwuti were the standouts for Essendon with three goals each, while Matthew Wright also booted three for Carlton.

External Link:

Essendon v Carlton stats
There was some bad news for Essendon, with a hamstring injury for forward Orazio Fantasia which could keep him out for several weeks, while star midfielder Zach Merrett could be in trouble with the Match Review Panel after he punched Lachie Plowman in the stomach in the second quarter.
AFL ladder

External Link:

AFL 2017 ladder

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday of AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Garlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callan Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Pendlebury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Rich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Picken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Cunnington (28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lions' 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devon Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson Goldsack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Shiel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Redpath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blues 11.18 (84</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Ziebell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Watts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Treloar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q-Clash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Scully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Maynard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dees</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orazio Fantasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Levi Greenwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Plowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's 2.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Melksham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Worsfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cale Hooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
