<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433320823566852</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4833341/phoenix-move-away-from-signing-new-zealand-players/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Phoenix move away from signing New Zealand players</title>
  <content>
Until the A-League breaks for international windows, Wellington Phoenix are all but giving up hope of becoming football's answer to the New Zealand Warriors. Fairfax Media understands the club will not fill the remainder of its roster with New Zealanders this season as they are close to giving up on their policy of prioritising local talent due to the disadvantages of playing in a competition without international breaks.

Club sources suggest the Phoenix are turning their attention to signing Australian players and those who are not eligible to represent their home country, after suffering for availability during the three international windows that impact as many as four A-League matches in the 27-rounds of the regular season.
Unlike most competitions around the world, the A-League doesn't break for FIFA international windows, which historically has meant Wellington suffers considerably as the only New Zealand club in the competition.
Football Federation Australia, which faces difficulty in its scheduling and does not break for internationals due to broadcast commitments, made attempts to accommodate Wellington's situation with as many home games around those windows. A Phoenix insider said, "it's like we start every season with at least a nine-point suspension" due to the difficulties during international windows. The club's football department is now tailoring its roster to the competition's regulations.
However, it could have more serious ramifications for the club than competition points. In a market where identity and composition is key to its appeal, a lack of local talent is making it difficult for the Phoenix to establish itself as the team of the nation. While the Warriors boast Roger Tuivasa-Sheck, Shaun Johnson, Simon Mannering, Ben Matulino and Issac Luke among their ranks, Wellington have only 13 New Zealanders contracted and five of those are youth players.
The Phoenix's licence is up for renewal again in three seasons and the club must meet specific off-field performance criteria to automatically trigger a three-year extension.
Their attendances and memberships continue to dent the average of the league. In four of the last five seasons, Wellington had the lowest crowd figures in the competition and most concerning is the significant decrease in their average as they attempted to establish a national footprint last season. Wellington experienced a 22 per cent drop in attendances to just 6224 last season, the lowest in the league.
However, there is some positivity for the club's hopes of reaching targets of metrics. Coming from a low base, Wellington's broadcast ratings soared considerably last season with an increase of approximately 140 per cent, according to the FFA.
In particular, the Phoenix witnessed a major rise in New Zealand-based audiences with coverage provided by Sky Sports and meetings are scheduled for later in August to introduce magazine shows for the club and the A-League on the Pay TV network. The lack of non-match coverage of football in New Zealand has proven difficult for cross-promotion of Phoenix games.
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Matulino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Issac Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Phoenix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Mannering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Tuivasa-Sheck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pay TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
