<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433402427946380</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/etihad-stadium-meltdown-against-collingwood-wont-haunt-eagles-in-clash-with-st-kilda/news-story/c43f0ed2288f201c3ab41cdc8040f0c4</url>
  <title>Etihad meltdown won't haunt Eagles</title>
  <content>
WEST Coast will be inspired rather than daunted as they return to Etihad Stadium a fortnight after their final-term capitulation against Collingwood, according to emerging midfielder Dom Sheed.
The Eagles coughed up a four-goal last-quarter lead against the Magpies to send the club into a tailspin which triggered a retirement announcement from Matt Priddis.
The Brownlow medallist has travelled as the emergency and will be left out of the team to face St Kilda today, barring a late injury or illness to another player this morning. West Coast, who drifted to $2.20 outsiders with TABtouch yesterday, must submit their 22 by 9.40am WA time.
Priddis, 32, is expected to sit in the coach's box and may play a mentoring role with the midfield unit during the breaks.
The Eagles slipped out of the eight following yesterday's results and they will likely finish the round in 10th position if they lose today's high-stakes clash. However they will jump to seventh on the ladder with a victory.
West Coast host lowly Carlton at Domain Stadium on Saturday night before finishing the regular season with testing assignments against Greater Western Sydney (Spotless Stadium) and Adelaide (home).
Sheed, who looms as a pivotal next generation midfield plank as Priddis and Sam Mitchell prepare to hang up their boots, said the round 18 loss to Collingwood had become an important learning experience.
"We've really learnt a lot from that game so we're keen to get over to Melbourne and play on Etihad again against the Saints. We know it's going to be difficult but we're up for it," he said.
Eagles adamant they'll open new stadium

Sheed shared best-on-ground honours with forward Josh Kennedy in the coaches' votes when he gathered 29 disposals and kicked two goals in the big win over Brisbane last Sunday.
"I'm just happy to be in the team and playing my role at the moment. I think my form's still been a bit up and down and inconsistent. But yeah, building," he said.
While his focus was on the clash with the Saints and the remainder of this season, the 22-year-old Kalgoorlie product said he was conscious he would be required to step up next year following the departures of Priddis and Mitchell.
"It has crossed my mind. I'm in my fourth year now and fifth year next, so I feel I can," Sheed said. "I think our midfield will hopefully stand up going forward."
Sheed said Priddis had played a critical role in his development since he arrived at the Eagles.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheed</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TABtouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
