<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433406722913725</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/a-quarter-of-aussies-take-sickies-for-sleep-deprivation/news-story/a902368f7493c1470a325391824cf6b1</url>
  <title>How sleep deprivation is a huge public issue</title>
  <content>
UP TO half of us sleep poorly on a nightly basis and our 24/7 lifestyle, love affair with technology, anxiety, insomnia and undiagnosed medical conditions are mostly to blame.
Not getting enough shut-eye is a huge public health issue that we keep turning a blind eye to, according to experts, and it's increasing our risk of heart disease, obesity, diabetes and depression.
Sleep deprivation is causing more people to seek treatment in hospital, turn to cognitive behaviour therapy and hypnotherapy, and sign up for home-based sleep studies in order to change their behaviour and catch the quality Zs they require.
Dr David Hillman, a sleep physician at Sir Charles Gairdner Hospital and deputy chairman of the Sleep Health Foundation, said the problem was right up there with national health issues such as smoking, alcohol consumption, sensible diet and exercise - it's just not as visible.
"Sleep is a state that perforates into all of our organs. Its fingers stretch widely and impact on a lot of health issues," he said.
"As a nation, we are undisciplined about creating good sleep routines.
"Some people wear short sleep as a badge of honour, but it's not smart or tough to go without sleep."
His comments come ahead of Federal Health Minister Greg Hunt releasing a Deloitte Access Economics Report the Sleep Health Foundation commissioned, Asleep on the Job: Costs of Inadequate Sleep in Australia, on Tuesday.
"Some of the numbers in there are huge," Dr Hillman said. "People think losing sleep doesn't penalise anyone but themselves. Well, it does."
A quarter of working Australians may take one sick day per month as a result of poor sleep, according to a recent survey.
Alarmingly high rates of internet use just before bed (44 per cent of adults reportedly do this every night) were identified as a major problem in another study the Sleep Health Foundation commissioned last year. Dr Hillman attributed this to the pervasiveness of mobile phones and social media.

"Social media is a growing issue for us and convincing teenagers and young adults, who are vulnerable to exclusion, to disengage is difficult," he said.
Perth-based clinical psychologist Melissa Ree, of Sleep Matters Insomnia Solutions, which operates north and south of the river, has seen an increasing incidence in sleep problems. She offers a sleep-related form of psychology.
"Many people are living in circumstances that prohibit time for sleep, such as working long hours, FIFO workers and having kids who wake through the night," she said.
Dr Ree said stress, anxiety and depression all caused insomnia, and each of these disorders was on the rise.
"People are becoming aware that the most effective long-term treatment is not a pill, it's cognitive behaviour therapy for insomnia (CBT-I)," she said.
"Treatment guidelines around the world recommend CBT-I as the first-line treatment for insomnia. About 80 per cent of those treated with CBT-I will benefit and the benefits are long-lasting."
Clinical hypnotherapist Christine Carter, of Advanced Clinical Hypnotherapy & Counselling in Scarborough, said she worked with people who were "absolutely desperate to get a good night's sleep".
"We live in a very high-pressured society at the moment and it's causing people to be more stressed and anxious," she said.
"If you get into bed stressed, you put a lot of fear into your subconscious mind that you can't sleep. If people get into bed with their phone, they'll be even more stressed."
Sleep Clinic Services chief executive Brett Chamberlain said snoring, waking up tired, daytime sleepiness and mood swings were warning signs that your sleep was impaired.
"Most sleep apnoea sufferers are undiagnosed and consequently untreated," he said. "When we see a person snoring while asleep, we laugh it off. Snoring is not normal. It is just very, very common. One in three Australian adults suffers from some sort of sleep-disordered breathing.
"Anyone with concerns about their sleep should ask their GP for a sleep study referral."
Former paediatric nurse turned sought-after sleep consultant Tara Mitchell says sleep deprivation doesn't have to be part and parcel of parenting a newborn or toddler.
"I just don't believe that children shouldn't sleep well," she said. "The whole family suffers and so many parents think it's just the way it is, but they're on the brink and then get to points where they never pictured they'd be."
Mrs Mitchell, aka The Gentle Sleep Specialist, said she, too, was in the grips of sleep deprivation after her first child, Scarlett, now three-and-a-half, was born when she started studying to become a qualified consultant on the matter.
"I spent so long trying to get my daughter to sleep, but it was a completely different journey with my second child," she said. "Sleep is the pillar of health and I'm passionate about providing people with support and guidance to make effective changes throughout their days and nights. Once you prioritise sleep, you thrive instead of just survive."
Mrs Mitchell said a lot of people think sleep can be sacrificed for other things, but it can't.
"It's not a stagnant state, the brain does amazing things during this time," she said. "Once we get sleep sorted, some babies are able to come off medication required for reflux."
SLEEPING TIPS
PARENTS WITH YOUNG CHILDREN
Create well-established routines (regular wake-up and meal times, balanced diet, daily physical activity and a clear game plan leading up to bedtime).
Turn off any screens an hour before bed.
Keep gaming consoles and TVs out of the bedroom.
If your child is a bit fearful, encourage the use of night lights and/or comfort toys/objects and check in on them to make sure they stay in bed (the emphasis is on staying quietly in bed rather than going to sleep).
Many children love to be read to or, if older, read to themselves as a nice transitional activity before bed.
Make time to talk with and cuddle your child.
TEENAGERS
Teens may not feel sleepy and ready for bed until later in the evening because their circadian rhythm often shifts and they become "night owls".
Establish a regular, screen-free, wind-down routine in the 30 to 60 minutes before bedtime. Screens may hamper sleep because they stimulate brain activity.
Watch stress levels. Is the teen over-committed (or under-comitted) or under excessive pressure to achieve? Are they experiencing friendship or family difficulty? Stress can make falling asleep difficult. A balanced lifestyle is important.
Limit caffeine (including energy drinks) to the morning.
Spend time outside. Exposure to sunlight, especially in the morning, helps ensure the body clock is working well.
Start the day with breakfast outside. Bright light at night interferes with sleep; bright light in the morning assists it.
SOCIAL MEDIA/SCREEN ADDICTS
If your sleep is suffering because of a screen, dim it. You can download apps to make your screen adapt to each time of the day.
Stop close-screen activities that activate your brain (social media use or games) at least one hour before going to bed.
Limit the amount of time you use the device.
Read an old school book or listen to gentle audio for your pre-sleep wind down.
WHAT YOU NEED
0-3months: 14 to 17 hours
4-11 months: 12 to 15 hours
1-2 years: 11 to 14 hours
3-5 years: 10 to 13 hours
6-13 years: 9 to 11 hours
14-17 years: 8 to 10 hours
18-25 years: 7 to 9 hours
26-64 years: 7 to 9 hours
Over 65 years: 7 to 8 hours
Source: Sleep Health Foundation
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Carter, of Advanced</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleep Health Foundation</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinic Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Hillman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinical Hypnotherapy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Health Minister Greg Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costs of Inadequate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Children</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Mitchell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIFO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte Access Economics Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Chamberlain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Charles Gairdner Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleep Matters Insomnia Solutions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Ree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Ree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gentle Sleep Specialist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MEDIA/SCREEN ADDICTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr David Hillman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBT-I</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
