<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433445377619905</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4834371/carmageddon-and-the-grey-ghosts-of-the-apocalypse/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Carmageddon and the grey ghosts of the apocalypse</title>
  <content>
OH, THE HORROR: Get your ticket to The Cars That Ate Newcastle.

CARMAGEDDON. And it's going to get worse, Newcastle. Much, much worse.
The opening of the new university campus hasn't seen the end-of-world scenario that some had predicted, but I reckon it's been harder to get a carpark at Marketown in the past fortnight - not impossible, but harder. Three hours of free parking - while shopping at the centre (cough cough) - is just enough time to park the personal steel chariot, skip down to Hunter Street and jump on the free bus to NeW Space for a couple of hours.
While Aldi in Cooks Hill has outsourced enforcement for overstaying in their carpark to Newcastle City Council's grey ghosts who roam the earth armed with authority, chalk, camera and a book of tickets, you'd be unlucky to currently cop a "fine" at Marketown. And given NSW passed legislation in 2012 that prevents private car park operators from gaining access to motorists' personal information to send out demands for payment, you might want to check your rights before paying any "fine".
About the grey ghosts. NCC's 10 parking officers do a great job while copping abuse from people who do not comply with parking restrictions. I'd increase their numbers and put them on commission. Can you imagine the absolute hell if there was not proper enforcement of parking restrictions in Newcastle?
Remember late 2012 when former Lord Mayor Jeff McCloy rescinded his support for the short-lived free parking trial that was lobbied for by the Newcastle Alliance and supported by the Liberals and the Greens?  On abandoning the trial, McCloy said free parking was "being abused by members of the public ... parking is a more complex issue than I really understood and you need to be mindful of all the things you affect when you make these changes."
Well, der. And that was nearly five years ago. So much has changed in Newcastle in that time. But not the attitude to private car usage.
The poll in last Monday's Herald is telling. A whopping 77.5 per cent of respondents claimed that neither parking restrictions nor fines encouraged them to use public transport. That comes on top of the previous Saturday's Herald reporting that Hunter drivers are racking up $17k a day in parking fines. And then there was last Tuesday's Festival of Urbanism where researchers revealed attitudes of Australian drivers suggest that cost and convenience may not outweigh individualist notions of privacy and autonomy.
Why Carmageddon? Why is car parking about to get worse in Newie?
The staged development application from Iris Land on display at NCC seeks consent for four high-rise buildings in and around the mall. Iris want to start the whole project rolling by firstly knocking down the David Jones carpark and knocking out 389 car parks. There's no reason - other than it's not what the developer wants - that the NCC and the Joint Regional Planning Panel cannot require Iris Land to commence and complete the other three sites first, thereby leaving the 389 car parking spaces available during construction of the other three sites.
Last Monday's poll must be very depressing reading for those charged with getting more people in Newcastle out of their cars and onto public transport. If fines and parking restrictions won't change behaviour, and with the loss of even more car spaces and increased numbers of people living in the city in buildings not required to provide car parks, Carmageddon beckons.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday's Festival of Urbanism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iris Land</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Jeff McCloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooks Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCC's 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmageddon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cars That Ate Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday's Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday's Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Regional Planning Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NeW Space</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marketown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
