<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432981521147152</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/smh-editorial/shooters-party-want-to-give-10yearolds-legal-access-to-guns-20170804-gxpb0o.html</url>
  <title>Shooters Party want to give 10-year-olds legal access to guns</title>
  <content>
The sight of 13-year-old Sean Donato peering down the barrel of a loaded rifle is a confronting one.
But despite the jarring image of such a young child wielding a deadly tool, the Firearms Act 1996 (NSW)  allows a youth from the age of 12 to legitimately use such a weapon. The youngster needs to have obtained a "minor's permit" that requires training in gun safety procedures and they must supervised by an adult holder of a firearms certificate. This allows for target shooting or, perhaps, hunting of game.
There are now, however, calls to lower the age at which a child can obtain a minor's permit. The Sporting Shooters Association of Australia backed by the Shooters, Fishers and Farmers Party would like to see the age reduced to 10. This is an age considered way too young for alcohol, sex, smoking, voting or driving.
The proposal is likely to be met with some controversy. These are, after all, times in which our security seems to face regular challenges. 
Some will cite the example of Lindt cafe siege gunman Man Haron Monis and his access to illegal weapons to argue that availability of firearms should be tightened rather than relaxed.  
That there are already too many guns in the community does not seem to be disputed. Only last month federal Justice Minister Michael Keenan announced a three-month gun amnesty enabling weapons to be handed in "no questions asked". He argued that of five terrorist attacks on our soil, most involved the use of an illegal firearm.

Roland Browne, vice-president of Gun Control Australia, argued the amnesty would do nothing to combat terrorism. Gun Control Australia, calling for "smarter regulation", seeks to abolish the minor's permits, saying they are a breach of the firearms agreement made in the aftermath of the 1996 Port Arthur massacre. 
Our current gun laws, introduced by John Howard, are a legacy of the attack by gunman Martin Bryant, aged 28, who murdered 35 people and wounded 23 others at the historic site in southern Tasmania.
If we look at the US experience, the figures are alarming.  A study released in June into childhood firearm injuries found nearly 1300 children die each year. Fifty-three per cent of these were homicides, 38 per cent suicides, 6 per cent were unintentional firearm deaths and 3 per cent due to other reasons. 

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

On the other hand, girls from the New England Girls School in Armidale engage in target rifle shooting made available to students aged 12 years and above. They are evidence that powerful rifles can be handled responsibly with the correct training and supervision.
That such capable supervision is also available in gun clubs and from parents such as Sean's father, Philip Donato, the Shooters, Fishers and Farmers Party member for Orange, is not disputed. The risk of problems may arise, however, where a child of 10 is not sufficiently mature to be entrusted with such responsibility. Or where the supervision is less than of the highest standard.
The death of one child arising from use or access to a firearm will be one death too many. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Donato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armidale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gun Control Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roland Browne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Bryant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Minister Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Firearms Act 1996</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Donato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man Haron Monis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifty-three</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sporting Shooters Association of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmers Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New England Girls School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Control Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
