<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432899916767612</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/push-for-lowered-speed-limit-outside-hugely-popular-chocolaterie/news-story/50111abe7f4b2c3f653abf70e4a1dc9a</url>
  <title>Sweet success leads to push for speed drop</title>
  <content>
AN influx of 800,000 visitors a year to the Yarra Valley Chocolaterie has led locals to petition to axe the 100km/h speed limit on Old Healesville Rd.
Concerned residents say the road has become more congested and dangerous since the popular chocolaterie opened and they can't get in and out of their properties safely.

Diana Viggers, who has lived on the road for more than 30 years, wants the speed limit axed to 80km/h.
Mrs Viggers said she had been concerned about the road's speed limit since 2014 and two serious accidents in the past 18 months near her property prompted her to take action.
She also thought the increasing popularity of the chocolaterie at Yarra Glen - one of the biggest tourist attractions in the Yarra Valley - has had "a big influence" on increased traffic on the road.
"We all live along this road and we feel 100km/h is too hard and too dangerous getting in and out of our properties," she said.
But the chocolaterie's managing director Ian Neeland said he didn't see a reason to lower the speed limit, which is already restricted to 80kp/h for a 300m section around the entrance.
Mr Neeland said he and wife Leanne were more worried about hoons speeding nearby late at night.
But Mr Neeland said the chocolaterie would support dropping the speed limit to 80km/h along the entire road if it received significant community support.
Yarra Ranges Council has backed the residents' calls after showing unanimous support for the petition at its July 25 meeting. The council will now write to VicRoads outlining concerns.
Councillor Fiona McAllister said she travelled on the road regularly and thought there was "benefit in reducing it for the entire length".
"We have increased tourist visitation in the valley and a lot more people are using the road," Cr McAllister said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr McAllister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Healesville Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Neeland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Ranges Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Valley Chocolaterie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Neeland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Viggers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana Viggers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Glen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leanne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Fiona McAllister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
