<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432715233172096</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/fit-and-healthy-boxing-coach-paul-panos-one-of-nrahs-first-patients/news-story/e01fa4ab0408e799e96c23adfb734e08</url>
  <title>First outpatient for nRAH revealed</title>
  <content>
PAUL Panos does not look like a man that needs a serious medical check up every three months.
The cyclist and State coach for Boxing SA is in very good shape for 51 year old.
But like many South Australians, the boxing talent identification coach and gym founder
needs regular hospital check ups.
"When you are fit and young, you are so oblivious to people's conditions," Mr Panos said.
"When you do go through a life changing experience it makes you realise there are people suffering in silence."
At 37 Mr Panos was diagnosed with kidney disease.
"I was a very active kid. I started boxing at age of 17," he said.
But a routine blood test showed he had a lot of protein in his urine.
"It was established I had renal reflux as an infant. One of my kidney's was destroyed. I was fighting and training with one kidney."
In 2011, at 45 years old his mother donated her kidney to him for a transplant.
"I have a 73-year-old kidney."

The new RAH is at technical completion stage - here's what it looks like inside

Go inside the new Royal Adelaide Hospital
Mr Panos has been revealed as the New Royal Adelaide Hospital's first outpatient.
His first appointment at the new hospital will be on August 14.
The new hospital's official opening is September 5.
But, starting with Mr Panos, about 150 renal outpatients and 20 radiation oncology patients will start treatment from August 14.
Each and every three months, since his transplant, Mr Panos has had to have a check up.
"They check all my blood levels and how the kidney is functioning," he said.
He said he has had "ongoing good service" at the Royal Adelaide Hospital.
But he is looking forward to checking out the new $2.3 billion hospital.
"I am excited and curious to see the new state of the art facility," he said.
"It will be pleasant change from the old dreary place on the sixth floor of the old Adelaide Hospital."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAUL Panos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boxing SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>nRAH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Panos</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
