<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651432500484805193</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/teams/collingwood/brodie-grundy-set-to-come-under-mrp-scrutiny-after-dangerous-tackle-on-ben-brown/news-story/e0e988f62953dd430ed470601d8c228f</url>
  <title>'I'm a lover and I feel terrible'</title>
  <content>
WELCOME to the new AFL era, where highly-efficient tackles with no malice get you suspended.
Patrick Dangerfield, meet Brodie Grundy.
At the same venue, on the same night of the week and executing the same act, Grundy laid a tackle that will see him rubbed out.
LIVE BLOG:
Where Dangerfield concussed Matthew Kreuzer, Grundy did likewise to North Melbourne's Ben Brown.
A stationary Brown was poised to handball 20 minutes into the second quarter of Saturday night's clash at Etihad Stadium when he was wrapped up from behind by an alert Grundy.
Grundy, like Dangerfield, is a ball-player without a dirty streak. Unfortunately for both men, this is irrelevant.
The Pies' ruckman had a vice-like grip on Brown's two forearms and turned him into the ground where his head was slammed into the turf.
Grundy's issue is that when you pin the arms of an opponent and choose to put him to the deck, you assume a duty of care. You also risk being found guilty of using "excessive force".
The three chief discussion points for the Match Review Panel to assess a dangerous tackle are understood to be a lifting motion, double movement or rotation of the body to build speed and momentum.
Dangerfield's tackle had none of those and he was gone. That's because one of the criteria for dangerous tackles under MRP guidelines is "The player being tackled is in a vulnerable position (ie arms pinned) with little opportunity to protect himself."
This is why it's impossible to conclude Grundy will get anything other than a suspension.
Some may also argue there was also an element of double movement in his tackle - grabbing Brown from behind, the pause, and then the drive into the turf.
Was there intent to hurt? Almost certainly not, but this is the climate.
Also at play is that unlike Kreuzer, Brown wasn't able to leave the field of his own volition. He was fitted with a neck brace and driven from the ground on a motorised stretcher.
Yet controlling umpire Hayden Gavine saw no issue. When play finally resumed, Grundy had a free kick for Brown's incorrect disposal.
Go figure.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne's Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grundy</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayden Gavine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
