<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433703075660177</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/3665974/youth-find-their-voice/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Youth living with cancer lead the way</title>
  <content>
FINDING A VOICE: Hannah Marshall, Caitlin Stanford, Benji Killorn, Angie Elder, Jessica Kerpsie, Jodie Smith and Natalie Meti at Stanwell Tops. Picture: Georgia Matts

Twenty-year-old Benji Killorn is using the voice he once lost following cancer surgery, to speak up for young people living with cancer.
First diagnosed at just 18 months of age with a tumour in his adrenal gland, he was cancer free for 13 years, until being diagnosed at the age of 15 with a tumour in his thyroid gland. Surgery to remove his thyroid followed, resulting in him losing his voice for five weeks.

Recovering to complete high school and go on to study nursing at university, Benji has relied on CanTeen for support during his illness and more recently has taken on leadership roles with the aim of helping other young people going through a similar experience.
"I lost my voice in every sense of the word and the people from CanTeen helped me get that zest back for life and help me get my voice back," Benji said.

"When I was unwell I took inspiration from the people who helped me and showed me how to deal with cancer, and that is what I hope to do for other young people.

"CanTeen helped me find my voice and find my identity again. They helped renew my energy to give back to young people going through something similar.
"The best people to help out young people with cancer are other young people with cancer."
Now Chair of the National Member Advisory Council, Benji is just one of 113 young people who have gathered at Stanwell Tops this week for a five day national leadership development program.

The camp is designed to develop leadership skills that will help them play key strategic and advisory roles with youth cancer charity CanTeen.
CanTeen national leadership coordinator Natalie Meti said the young people, aged between 12 and 24 will participate in a variety of workshops designed to develop their leadership skills including team discussions, practical activities, creative workshops, physical activities and sharing personal stories.

"The leadership program provides opportunities for our young leaders to develop relationships, skills, knowledge and confidence to take up leadership within and beyond CanTeen," Mrs Meti said. 

Every year, 23,000 young people have their lives changed by cancer, whether they have been diagnosed themselves or whether they're dealing with cancer in their family. 
"These young people are incredibly resilient. Just when life should be full of possibilities, cancer turns their world upside down and yet here they are saying 'yes' to leadership. That's really inspiring.

"Once they've participated in CanTeen's services, many young people want to contribute to CanTeen and support young people living with cancer around Australia."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Member Advisory Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angie Elder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Matts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanwell Tops</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caitlin Stanford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chair of the National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Meti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benji</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Kerpsie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Meti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benji Killorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
