<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433793269974248</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/03/32/eviction-fears-invade-sydney-s-tent-city</url>
  <title>Eviction fears invade Sydney's tent city</title>
  <content>
While authorities have drawn straws over who should uproot Martin Place's homeless encampment its residents have slept uneasily, fearing a pre-dawn eviction and an uncertain future.
"What the powers-that-be have done is put fear into one of the most marginalised groups in Australian society," Camp organiser Lanz Priestley told AAP late Saturday.
"There is a fear in the camp that something is going to happen, whether it's the police, state or local governments," he said.
Police Commissioner Mick Fuller and NSW Social Housing Minister Pru Goward urged Sydney City Lord Mayor Clover Moore to resolve the issue at crisis talks on Friday.
Ms Moore said the camp wouldn't be dismantled until she was assured there was a long-term housing solution for the residents.
But Mr Fuller indicated he wanted a resolution by the end of the weekend - and that placed the camp's residents on edge.
As evening fell on Saturday, Mr Priestley tweeted "All good at Martin Pl. Que sera sera". The camp looked like it would survive another night.

Related Articles

But, he said, an early morning raid before the journalists watching the makeshift community began their morning shift on Sunday would be the opportune time for authorities to forcibly uproot the settlement.
He felt it unlikely police would be the ones to adopt such a tactic given their history of treating the campers with courtesy.
"The police are cognisant enough to know people have nowhere else to go," he said.
"This (camp) reduces other areas of crime.
"They came through a full three days beforehand to tell us their operational plan the last time they moved us."
A NSW Police spokeswoman told AAP, as of Saturday night, there were still no official plans to enter the camp.
Dubbed the Mayor of Martin Place, Mr Priestley said camp organisers had an obligation to continue to provide safety, shelter, food and support to the residents, regardless of the talks going on behind closed doors.
"Touch wood someone will consult with us at some point along the line," he said.
"They haven't so far."
Mr Priestley is concerned about the few lines of dialogue which have emerged from the discussions so far.
"I laughed when they started to call it a protest - protesters go home," he said.
"But changing the narrative, getting people on board with the idea of this being a protest makes it political.
"They can be seen to smash a protest, they can't be seen smashing a community of homeless people."
There are reports temporary housing has been offered to those living in the camp but a resident told AAP many had refused because there was no guarantee of long term accommodation.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Social Housing Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz Priestley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Pl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor of Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney City Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
