<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434261421413428</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/world/official-minnesota-mosque-blast-was-caused-by-bomb-thrown-through-a-window/news-story/316f30eda59afb17cef4361b07719c5a</url>
  <title>US mosque rocked by bomb blast</title>
  <content>
SOMEONE apparently threw a bomb through the window of a suburban Minneapolis mosque overnight as people were preparing for morning prayers, damaging the imam's office but not injuring anyone, an official said.
The blast happened at around 5am (7pm AEST) at the Dar Al-Farooq Islamic Centre in Bloomington. Police Chief Jeff Potts said at a news conference that investigators were trying to determine the cause of the blast, but authorities have released few details.
Asad Zaman, director of the Muslim American Society of Minnesota, said at a news conference that a witness saw something being thrown at the imam's office window from a "van or truck" before the blast. Local news stations reported that he said it may have been a fire bomb. Mohamed Omar, the centre's executive director, said a worshipper saw a truck speeding away afterwards.
There were 15 to 20 people inside the mosque when the blast happened. Worshippers managed to extinguish the blaze before firefighters arrived, the society said in a news release.
The mosque, which primarily serves people from the area's large Somali community, occasionally receives threatening calls and emails, Omar told the Star Tribune.
"It was 5am," Omar said. "The whole neighbourhood was calm. People were supposed to be sleeping, that's how peaceful this should be. I was shocked to learn this happened."
The mosque serves as a religious centre and community organising platform for Muslim activists and leaders in the area, said the society, which is offering a USD$10,000 (A$12,000) reward for information that leads to an arrest or conviction.
Trevin Miller, who lives across the street, told the Star Tribune that the explosion woke him up, saying that he felt it on his "insides." Yasir Abdalrahman, a worshipper at the mosque, said the explosion was "unimaginable." "We came to this country for the same reason everyone else came here: freedom to worship," Abdalrahman said. "And that freedom is under threat. Every other American should be insulted by this." The FBI and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives are involved in the investigation.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BLOOMINGTON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Alcohol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevin Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yasir Abdalrahman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD$10,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Tribune</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dar Al-Farooq Islamic Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somalis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Omar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINNEAPOLIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asad Zaman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Jeff Potts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim American Society of Minnesota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdalrahman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
