<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433398132979014</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/samesex-marriage-wa-liberal-senator-dean-smith-to-defy-prime-minister-malcolm-turnbull-with-bill/news-story/6097a88ce3c477f8c95f5f278c7e2ae5</url>
  <title>Smith to defy PM with same-sex bill</title>
  <content>
DEFIANT WA Liberal Senator Dean Smith has vowed to this week introduce into the Senate his private member's Bill to legalise same-sex marriage - even without the support of his party.
Senator Smith said he would argue at tomorrow's party room meeting of Federal Liberal MPs in Canberra that there should be a free vote on same-sex marriage in Parliament, rather than a "wasteful and divisive plebiscite".
He warned that if his colleagues remained welded to the idea of a plebiscite he would go it alone and introduce the Bill into the Senate within days.
"I will respect the decision of my colleagues if they choose to continue with a plebiscite position, but I will use my privileges as a backbench senator to introduce my Bill to the Senate this week," Senator Smith said.
Civil war has broken out within the coalition since Senator Smith The Sunday Times that he was preparing the Marriage Amendment (Definition and Religious Freedom) Bill 2017, with the aim of changing the Government's policy of first holding a $170 million plebiscite on the issue.
Since then, a compromise solution has been being floated by senior Liberals, including senior minister Peter Dutton, for a postal plebiscite. But Senator Smith and a small group of rebel Liberals - Warren Entsch, Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Trent Zimmerman - are continuing to push for a parliamentary vote.
"I can confirm that a Bill to allow two people to marry, while at the same time protecting religious views about marriage in Australia, has been completed," Senator Smith said.
"Having spent almost six months drafting the Bill, I am confident it is the most considered response to the issue of same-sex-marriage so far."
Civil celebrants who refuse to marry same-sex couples will be protected from legal action under the Bill.
The proposal will radically extend religious freedoms by creating a new category of "religious marriage celebrants" who can refuse to officiate a same-sex ceremony without the fear of being taken to court for discrimination.
But bakers, musicians, florists and photographers will need to prove they are linked to a "religious body" to reject a gay couple, and small businesses won't be able to claim a conscientious objection unrelated to religion.
The debate looms as a huge test for Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull, a supporter of same-sex marriage, with some Liberals claiming his leadership would be at risk if he allowed a free vote.
Senator Smith said tomorrow's party room meeting would be to "determine a pathway forward for resolving the issue of same-sex-marriage in Australia".
"If the free vote argument wins the day, this Bill can be presented to the House of Representatives with a parliamentary free vote taking place within days," he said.
Without a free vote, Liberals in the House of Representatives would need to cross the floor to give the Bill any chance of being not only debated but passed into law.
In the Senate, it would rely on the support of like-minded moderate Liberals, as well as crossbenchers Nick Xenophon and Derryn Hinch to combine with Labor and the Greens.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Religious Freedom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Amendment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
