<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433750320300942</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/world/texts-on-a-plane-about-child-sexual-assault-lead-to-two-arrests-20170805-gxq69f.html</url>
  <title>Texts on a plane about child sexual assault lead to two arrests</title>
  <content>
Photo: AP
A woman who spotted a fellow plane passenger texting about sexually assaulting children has led police to arrest two people and rescue two potential victims, according to authorities.
Michael Kellar, 56, of Tacoma, Washington, was arrested after arriving in Mineta San Jose International Airport airport on a flight from Seattle on Monday night, police said.Photo: AP
Officers also arrested 50-year-old Gail Burworth at her home in Tacoma, Washington.
It appears that two children, aged five and seven, were at risk of being sexually assaulted, according to investigators.
The arrests follow an incident on a flight on Monday in which a woman caught a glimpse of some text messages that alarmed her.
A man seated in front of her on the Southwest Airlines flight was "texting about sexually molesting young children," the San Jose Police Department said in a news release.

The man, Kellar, was using a large smartphone with enlarged text, making it easier for her to read his messages and take photographs of them.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The woman alerted a member of the flight crew, who notified police officers working in the Mineta San Jose International Airport. Kellar was arrested after the plane landed.
The woman is a preschool teacher, said Detective Sergeant Brian Spears, commander of the San Jose Police Department's Internet Crimes Against Children Taskforce.
"She's definitely a hero in our eyes," he said.
Kellar was charged with attempted child molestation and solicitation of a sex crime, both felonies. He was arraigned on Thursday and was being held without bail at the Santa Clara County Jail.
Police named Gail Burnworth, 50, also a resident of Tacoma, as the person Kellar was suspected of texting. They have also located two children, ages 5 and 7, who may have been victims of sexual abuse.
Spears said the text messages "described specific sex acts performed on children, as well as bestiality."
"It definitely goes beyond just that flight," he added. "There is a history of conversations between them."
According to a statement from the city of Seattle on Wednesday, it seems that Burnworth "had access to the children either as a caregiver or baby sitter." She was arrested in Tacoma on Monday but was released after prosecutors did not formally charge her within 72 hours.
She was arrested again on Friday night on a federal warrant for conspiracy to produce child pornography.
Southwest Airlines did not provide access to the crew member who alerted police because of the criminal investigation. In an emailed statement, it said, "We always encourage customers to say something to our employees or law enforcement if they see something suspicious."
Authorities in California and Washington said federal charges are likely, and the FBI was involved in the continuing investigation.
Capt. Mike Edwards, commander of the Seattle Police Department's Internet Crimes Against Children Taskforce, said the two children who may have been victims remained at their home with their parents.
Police did not identify the teacher who reported the text messages. "We're very grateful that she was on that plane," Edwards said.
"I think the big message and the big takeaway on this is, for all of us, is to pay attention to what's going on around you," he said. "You never know how important it could be."
New York Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tacoma</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellar</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Kellar, 56, of Tacoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southwest Airlines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle Police Department's Internet Crimes Against Children Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Burworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Jose Police Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Sergeant Brian Spears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Burnworth, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Clara County Jail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mineta San Jose International Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Jose Police Department's Internet Crimes Against Children Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
