<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433746025333600</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/2049500/26-hunter-drivers-speeding-in-school-zones-daily/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>26 Hunter drivers speeding in school zones daily</title>
  <content>
26 Hunter drivers speeding in school zones daily

exit
HUNTER motorists are being warned to slow down in school zones after copping more than $2.1million in fines last financial year.

That's a rate of 26 tickets a day, or an increase of 25 per cent more than in 2010-11.
School zone speed limits of 40km/h come back into force today, and drivers who don't comply face fines of up to $3612.
But drivers are more likely to be caught speeding near schools out of school hours.
Of the 8000 motorists who were clocked by fixed speed cameras in Hunter school zones in 2012-13, more than 5000 did so outside school hours when regular speed limits apply. 
Another 1400 drivers were caught while ignoring the 40km/h school-zone speed limit.
Though most students return to school tomorrow, today is the first official school day of the year and school-zone speed limits apply.
"Research shows a pedestrian hit at 40km/h is twice as likely to survive as a pedestrian hit at 50km/h," a Roads and Maritime Services spokesman said.
"Not all motorists will know if the school they are driving past is having a pupil-free day or if students are at school. This is why all 40km/h school zones are consistently applied and will be in force from the first gazetted school day of term one."
There are two fixed digital speed cameras in school zones in the Hunter: one on the Pacific Highway at Gateshead, outside Gateshead Primary School and Hunter Sports High, and one on the New England Highway at Lochinvar, outside St Joseph's Campus of All Saints College and St Patrick's Primary School.
The NRMA says most motorists do not wilfully exceed speed limits in school zones. Those who do often do not realise they are in a school zone.
They may also be unaware of the time, their speed or that it is a school day.
An NRMA survey conducted in October found that 41 per cent of Hunter and Central Coast school zones have faded signs and 73 per cent have not been updated to comply with Australian standards.
It also found that 36 per cent of school zones in the survey had signs obscured by trees, making them difficult for drivers to see.
In addressing some of those issues, Roads Minister Duncan Gay has promised to have at least one set of flashing lights in every school zone by December next year.
Flashing lights, which trials have found help to slow motorists by an average 7km/h, were installed at the school zones at Lochinvar and Gateshead in 2007.
Newcastle and Lake Macquarie Parents and Citizens council president Margaret Bryden said the issue of road safety and slowing down around schools was raised with staff and parents at the start of every term.
"I know there's a little bit of confusion about the first day of school and the last day of school, but I think [that's when] motorists need to be particularly careful . . . with some students and parents negotiating these areas for the first time," Mrs Bryden said.
Senior Sergeant Justin Cornes, of the Newcastle Traffic and Highway Patrol, said the message could not be clear enough.
"Speeding is still the biggest killer on NSW roads and pedestrians are the most vulnerable when it comes to speeding drivers, particularly young people," he said.
"We want people to slow down and be aware - particularly of school children, who have a habit of running in and out of traffic."
Speeding blitz nabs 703
 By MATT CARR
A NEWCASTLE man will face court after allegedly travelling at 134km/h while intoxicated.
Police allege the man, 21, was stopped on the Pacific Highway at Johns River about 7.50am on Australia Day when he was clocked driving 134km/h in a 100km/h zone.
He failed a roadside breath test and was taken to Taree police station, where he was alleged to have returned a blood-alcohol reading of 0.103.
He was charged with mid-range drink-driving and speeding.  And his licence was suspended.
He is one of 703 drivers police caught allegedly speeding in Northern NSW during Operation Safe Return, which began on Friday.
Out of more than 21,907 breath tests,  48 people have also been charged with drink-driving.
Acting Assistant Commissioner Stuart Smith, of NSW Traffic and Highway Patrol Command, said it was vital road users took care as the long weekend drew to a close.
''There will be a strong police presence on our roads today and motorists are reminded double demerits remain in place until midnight,'' Mr Smith said yesterday.
''Do the right thing by yourself, your family, your friends and other road users - slow down and take extra care.''
FINE FACTS
Fines issued to Hunter motorists caught speeding in school zones in 2012-13
■ By fixed speed camera on school days in relevant hours: 2945 fines, costing $737, 281
■ By fixed speed camera outside school days/hours: 5094 fines, costing $948,808
■ By police during school days/hours: 1464 fines, costing $442,643
Source: Office of State Revenue website

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Traffic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New England Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lochinvar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation Safe Return</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateshead</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRMA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Joseph's Campus of All</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highway Patrol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Bryden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Commissioner Stuart Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Patrick's Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie Parents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Sports High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Highway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roads Minister Duncan Gay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Bryden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateshead Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johns River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highway Patrol Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Justin Cornes, of the Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
