<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434304371086749</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/2577706/bellambi-family-left-high-and-dry-waiting-for-pool-repairs/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Bellambi family left high and dry waiting for pool repairs</title>
  <content>
Bellambi resident Sandra Cram with her children Daniel and Zoe  in their empty concrete pool. They have waited seven months for it to be repaired. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Daniel and Zoe Cram would have been enjoying the school holidays in their heated pool if a hole in the surface had been repaired.
Their mum Sandra Cram notified the pool company in February about the hole but it wasn't until last Wednesday, seven months later, that the $37,000 pool was drained and properly inspected.
It was then that a contractor discovered that the crack in the surface was caused by issues in the concrete under the pool.
Mrs Cram said the contractor further told her that the pool's coating may crack if left without water for more than five days.
The pool at the Crams' Bellambi home is under a seven-year warranty with Autumn Solar Installations trading as Autumn Pools. The company is based at Ulladulla in the Shoalhaven, but the Crams engaged the company to build their pool in 2012 through its Unanderra office. That office has since closed.
''With no water in the pool we were afraid that further damage might be made to the pool's surface, but the company wouldn't give us an answer as to when they were coming to fix it,'' Mrs Cram said. ''My husband and I rang the Ulladulla office 10times on Friday.''
She said she had contacted the firm every week since February to try  to have the pool repaired.
''It's been very frustrating and stressful that it's taken so long for them to fix it,'' she said.  ''The lack of communication has been terrible. You can never really talk to anyone.''
On Monday afternoon, company director Stephen Merrett travelled from Ulladulla to drill a hole in the surface of the pool to repair the crack underneath. The company said the contractor would return on Wednesday to recoat the pool's interior.
Part-owner of the company Amanda Merrett said there had always been plans to fix the pool on Monday afternoon and believed there would be no further damage due to the delay.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crams' Bellambi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellambi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Autumn Pools</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Cram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Cram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ulladulla</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Cram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Autumn Solar Installations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unanderra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
