<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434304371086693</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/energy/electricity/origin-energy-in-energy-tech-innovation-hunt-20170717-gxd19x</url>
  <title>Origin Energy in energy tech innovation hunt</title>
  <content>
Origin Energy has turned to Silicon Valley to sharpen up on the cutting-edge skills and technology it needs to prosper in the rapidly changing energy sector, quietly making a series of investments in start-ups in energy innovation.
Chief executive Frank Calabria is set to reveal the moves at a clean energy conference in Sydney on Tuesday, including Origin's acquisition of a $US1.2 million ($1.5 million) stake in internet of things software company People Power. where it has invested alongside German giant in the new energy field, innogy.
The investment in Palo Alto-based People Power, which uses artificial intelligence to interpret real-time data from the home to help customers manage their daily lives, follows Origin's partnership with innogy earlier in 2017 to found Free Electrons. That initiative brings together eight utilities and 12 start-ups involved in smart grids, electric vehicles, renewable energy and home energy management.
Origin, which has set up an office in Palo Alto in a sharing arrangement with innogy, has also bolstered its board capacity in new energy,  appointing in May Silicon Valley veteran and venture capitalist Teresa Engelhard as a non-executive director.

Major utilities such as Origin and arch-rival AGL Energy have been pushing more forcefully into investments that may help them predict and meet the future energy needs of their customers and keep abreast ofsector.

, with investments in California-based solar/storage player Sunverge and in the Energy Impact Partners global coalition, which gives it access to technology from home energy monitoring provider Sense Labs and big data energy analytics firm AutoGrid Systems.
Origin is also backing home-grown innovation, becoming principal sponsor of EnergyLab, the new UTS-hosted home for clean energy innovation in Australia, based in Sydney.
Mr Calabria argues that while Origin doesn't know whether its investments will pay dividends over the long term, it has to act to be part of the transition toward a zero-emissions energy system. Its near-term priorities remain, however, to reduce debt and improve shareholder returns, requiring careful consideration of any new initiatives.
The retailer and generator is believed to be preparing to announce further moves starting as early as next week as it trials and invests in start-ups that offer insights into managing energy use for customers in the home.
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palo Alto-based People Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunverge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teresa Engelhard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sense Labs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Calabria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AutoGrid Systems</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTS-hosted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Impact Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Calabria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnergyLab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Free Electrons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palo Alto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin Energy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
