<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434437515073961</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/men-take-lead-on-rentvesting-path-to-property-ownership/news-story/7a57d52e53cec253d4529e3f6a2729bb</url>
  <title>Men take lead on rentvesting path to property ownership - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Abbotsford rentvestor Bobby Kennedy bought an apartment as an investment in Canberra.

FIRST-time buyers are increasingly taking the rentvesting path to property ownership - and young men are leading the way.
New research from Westpac, to be released tomorrow, reveals the typical rentvestor is a metro-based male aged 20 to 34.
"We know the trend of rentvesting is growing, with 41 per cent of all Australians surveyed believing it's better to buy an investment property in a more affordable area and rent a house in an area you really want to live in," said Westpac head of home ownership Lauren Fine.
But Ms Fine said many rentvestors still aspired to own their own home to live in, despite soaring property prices.
"The majority of this group (77 per cent) are looking to buy a house or apartment to live in as their next property, indicating that being an owner-occupier remains an aspiration," she said.
"Those rentvesting are most likely to have purchased their property in the last two years, which aligns with the increase we've seen in property prices across many areas of Australia,"
CoreLogic figures show Melbourne's median house price has jumped from $485,000 to $651,000 in the past five years, a rise of 34.2 per cent.
The median unit price has climbed 11.2 per cent in the same period, from $445,000 to $495,000.

Bobby Kennedy, 25, rents in Abbotsford for the lifestyle but owns an investment property in Canberra.

The Westpac survey found 65 per cent of rentvestors were men, 61 per cent were born between
1983 and 1997, and 81 per cent lived in metropolitan areas.
The majority, 61 per cent, bought a freestanding house and 25 per cent bought an apartment.
Abbotsford renter Bobby Kennedy turned to rentvesting three years ago, at age 22, when he bought an apartment in his home city of Canberra.
Mr Kennedy moved to Melbourne for work after graduating from university but his dream of homeownership in his new home town slipped further away as property prices soared.
"The entry point in Melbourne was higher than what I could afford," he said
"I wanted to be in the property game and not fall behind, but also have the lifestyle and career opportunities I do in Melbourne."
Mr Kennedy said the difference between the mortgage repayments and rental income on his Canberra investment property was about $50 a week.
"It would have been nice to have owned something in Melbourne, given the growth in the city's prices, but the reality was that I didn't have the money to purchase anywhere I would have liked to live," he said.
The Westpac report predicted rentvesting would continue to grow as affordability hampered young Australians' ability to enter the housing market.
"If you are looking into rentvesting, it's important to consider a home that will appeal to tenants such as being close to public transport," Ms Fine said.
Ms Fine said Noble Park, Doveton and Craigieburn, were popular suburbs for rentvestors to buy in, while further afield they looked to Castlemaine, Geelong, Ballart and Shepparton.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shepparton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobby Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Fine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doveton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigieburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbotsford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobby Kennedy, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
