<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434570659061182</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/erin-molans-wedding-wont-be-a-big-grand-do-20170804-gxpl5j.html</url>
  <title>Erin Molan's wedding 'won't be a big, grand do'</title>
  <content>
Some spend their lives imagining the day they'll say "I do", but not The NRL Footy Show's Erin Molan.
"I have not grown up dreaming of my wedding," she laughed to Fairfax Media this week at the  multimillion-dollar fashion precinct.Photo: Erin Molan/Instagram
"I'm so bad with all of that stuff, I just don't really care."
​Detective Senior Constable Sean Ogilvy  to Molan four months ago, but they have yet to decide on a location or a date.

"We have not planned a thing. We won't wait that long. He's 42 and I am 33 ... but we are just waiting for a day to sit down and actually try and plan," she said.
"It won't be a big, grand do. We are very normal, simple people. As long as both of our families are there, that's all we really care about.

"For now we are just enjoying being engaged. It's just nice. Being engaged is a nice feeling." 

You will now receive updates from

Daily Life Newsletter

Daily Life Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

She laughed again: "I'll probably be calling up on the wedding day asking for someone to send around flowers."Photo: Wesley Nel Photography
Ogilvy proposed with a bespoke, oval diamond and double halos, set in 18K white gold by House of K'dor with a six-figure price tag.
It had been suggested that it might have been gifted, but the popular Channel Nine presenter and Bowel Cancer Australia ambassador cleared up those rumours, explaining that Ogilvy saved for six months to buy it.
"He is very good with that stuff. I didn't know prior, but he is. I love it," she said, looking at the rock. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Molan/Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowel Cancer Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ogilvy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL Footy Show's Erin Molan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Molan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Senior Constable Sean Ogilvy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesley Nel Photography</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
