<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434574954028525</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/whale-and-vessel-collide/3209192/</url>
  <title>Whale and vessel collide, four hospitalised</title>
  <content>
FOUR people on board an A1 fishing charter vessel have been taken to Proserpine Hospital in serious but stable condition tonight.

The injuries were a result of a whale making full impact with the port side of the boat at 3.45pm this afternoon north-east of Gloucester Island.

The impact caused the vessel to spin and "decomissioned" one of the engines.

VMR Whitsundays and a rescue helicopter were tasked on standby but it was deemed "too dangerous" to get anyone off

After impact, the 8-person crew returned to the mainland via the Abell Point Marina boat ramp at 6pm, where paramedics were able to apply medical treatment.

A QAS paramedic on the scene stressed that the four people taken to hospital were in varying states but all were in stable condition.

One is suspected to have suffered spinal injuries.

It is unclear what type of whale hit the vessel and how large it was.

Residents reeling after tragic crash on Saturday motorbike ride
Rider pronounced dead on scene after tragedy strikes social ride
Police believe Sam may have hidden the bodies of three people
I HAVE worked through some very buoyant years.
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abell Point Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gloucester Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Proserpine Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VMR Whitsundays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
