<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433415312848435</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/perth-arena-naming-rights-cost-wa-79m-compensation-to-stadium-operator/news-story/d7f3cf743ca3be50e6057860d3210582</url>
  <title>High price for naming rights decision</title>
  <content>
THE decision not to sell the naming rights to Perth Arena has cost taxpayers almost $8 million.
The McGowan Government revealed AEG Ogden, which manages the Arena, had been paid $7.9 million since 2012 as compensation for not being able to sell naming rights to the venue.
Over the past five financial years, AEG Ogden received payments of $2.1 million (2012-13), $1.4 million (2013-14), $1.4 million (2014-15), $1.5 million (2015-16) and $1.5 million (2016-17).
It can be revealed that in 2012, AEG Ogden was in advanced negotiations to sell the naming rights after being given the all-clear by the former Barnett government, before being ordered to halt talks.
The revelations come on the back of a decision by Premier Mark McGowan's Cabinet this week to sell the naming rights to Perth Arena and the Perth Stadium.
The move is expected to fetch an estimated $10.5 million over four years.
"West Australians have forked out $8 million so far because of Colin Barnett's stubborn refusal to sell the naming rights of Perth Arena," Treasurer Ben Wyatt said.
"It's time to end this madness and actually act with some financial maturity so we can start to fix the mess left behind by the reckless attitude of the Liberals and Nationals."
A spokesman for Premier Mark McGowan said there was "no requirement" for the word "Perth" to be included in the renaming of the arena or stadium.
"It is, however, expected that these two premier venues remain synonymous with Perth and continue to show its capability as an exciting event destination," he said.
He said VenuesLive (Perth Stadium) and AEG Ogden (Perth Arena) would be responsible for securing naming rights partners, with guidance from VenuesWest.
Mr Wyatt and Tourism Minister Paul Papalia said WA could not afford to miss out on the revenue expected to be generated from the sale.
"We no longer have the luxury of squandering potential income for taxpayers on not selling naming rights," Mr Papalia said.
"Our hotel and hospitality sector is also in a critical situation with huge oversupply of rooms and far fewer travellers.
"The best thing for our businesses and taxpayers right now is for Tourism WA to focus on direct campaigns that fill aircraft seats, get visitors to WA and fill our hotel rooms."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan's Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Papalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VenuesWest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Minister Paul Papalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEG Ogden</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Arena</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Ben Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Barnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VenuesLive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
