<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433402427946344</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/1157321/heart-condition-claims-young-dancers-life/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Heart condition claims young dancer's life</title>
  <content>
Heart condition claims young dancer's life

ON A CLOUD: Adam Loiterton was headed for greatness.

exit

ADAM Loiterton had the world at his feet.
But just weeks after being accepted into the prestigious Queensland Ballet, the brilliantly talented 19-year-old lay on the floor of the Newcastle Dance Academy to stretch last Monday and never got back up.
Relatives and friends have been left to mourn the premature death of the New Lambton teen, who had continued to excel in the world of dance despite battling a pre-existing heart condition.
It was this condition which ultimately took his life.
"He was destined for great things and was such a beautiful boy," ballet teacher Tracy Caldwell-Ostermann said yesterday.
Adam had been full-time at the Newcastle Dance Academy since completing his Higher School Certificate at the Hunter School of Performing Arts in 2010.
He had spent four weeks studying at the Montgomery Ballet in Alabama this year after international experts noticed his talent.
But his greatest feat to date in his short career was being accepted as a pre-professional to start at the Queensland Ballet next year.
After surviving through the cut-throat audition process, Adam had received a call just a few weeks ago from Queensland Ballet's artistic director, Li Cunxin, to say he was in.
"Adam was floating on a cloud that day," Ms Caldwell-Ostermann said.
They are now left to pick up the pieces after Adam finished a routine training program on Monday afternoon before lying on the floor to finish stretching, when his heart stopped.
"Words can't explain the devastation - our hearts are broken," she said.
"Adam was a very special young man. He was gentle and caring and a great friend to all our students.
"He was passionate and a beautiful soul and we are very blessed to have had the privilege to teach such a remarkable young man."
His parents John and Judy and sisters Anna and Kelly will join other relatives and friends at a service for Adam at St John's Anglican Church at Cooks Hill on Monday at 10.30am.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Caldwell-Ostermann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ballet</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooks Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Higher School Certificate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Loiterton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montgomery Ballet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John's Anglican Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Li Cunxin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alabama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracy Caldwell-Ostermann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Dance Academy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter School of Performing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
