<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433484032326037</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/465070/crash-rips-lives-apart/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Crash rips lives apart</title>
  <content>
Crash rips lives apart

TRAGIC: The mangled wreck of the Holden sedan, which split in two after hitting a tree on the Central Coast. -  Picture by Phil Hearne

exit

A 29-year-old man is dead after a car slammed into a tree on the Central Coast early yesterday, the impact slicing the vehicle in two.
Emergency services closed the Central Coast Highway in both directions for several hours  after the  crash involving a Commodore sedan at Wyong.
Tuggerah Lakes police were called to Wilfred Barrett Drive soon after 5am when the vehicle left the road and struck  the tree about four kilometres south of the Main Road roundabout.
A Norah Head man, 29, died at the scene.
A 23-year-old Central Coast man suffered multiple fractures, and was airlifted from the scene in a serious condition.
He underwent surgery at the John Hunter Hospital and remained in a serious but stable condition last night.
Crash investigators remained on scene for several hours yesterday, closing the road in both directions between Denison Street and Bungary Road until about 12.20pm while crash investigators inspected the site.
Police said it seemed likely from the state of the vehicle that speed was a factor in the crash.
A report is to be prepared for the coroner.
The accident has prompted police to renew calls for drivers to exercise caution after it was the second fatal accident on the region's roads in the past five days. Cyclist Graham Denton died after he was struck by a car riding on the Pacific Highway on Thursday.
''I think it is a wake-up call and a reminder to drive to the conditions and stick to the speed limits,''  Tuggerah Lakes duty officer Inspector Stephen Eggleton said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Hearne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Stephen Eggleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bungary Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norah Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denison Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggerah Lakes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilfred Barrett Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
