<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433831924680249</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/world/donald-trumps-national-security-adviser-hr-mcmaster-says-north-korea-a-real-danger/news-story/a8befa6487a9c4bee92533cdaa83b576</url>
  <title>US 'will not tolerate' N Korea 'threats'</title>
  <content>
US President Donald Trump's national security adviser Lieutenant General H.R. McMaster says it is "impossible to overstate the danger" posed by North Korea.
In a television interview that aired overnight, General McMaster said Mr Trump has been "deeply briefed" on the strategy on North Korea. Tensions have mounted with Pyongyang's two recent successful tests of intercontinental ballistic missiles.
General McMaster reiterated the administration's position that all options, including a targeted military strike, are on the table. Still, he said the United States would "like to resolve it short of what would be a very costly war."
The UN Security Council was set to vote overnight on tough new sanctions drafted by Washington that would deprive North Korea of vital export income after it defied international pressure to test its second intercontinental ballistic missile.
General McMaster emphasised that Mr Trump is "not going to tolerate North Korea being able to threaten the United States."
"So of course, we have to provide all options to do that. And that includes a military option," he said.
The Security Council resolution, drafted by the US, follows a month of negotiations with Pyongyang's main trading partner and ally China over ways to compel the regime of Kim Jong-un to halt its missile and nuclear program.
It calls for a ban on all exports of coal, iron and iron ore, lead and lead ore, as well as fish and seafood by the cash-starved state - which would strip the state of roughly a third of its export earnings estimated at USD$3 billion (A$3.7 billion) per year.
The Security Council was scheduled to vote at 3pm (5am AEST) on the measures, as a diplomat who briefed reporters said he had "high confidence" that neither China nor Russia would exercise their powers of veto.
General McMaster said Mr Trump had told China's President Xi Jinping it was no longer enough for North Korea to "freeze" its programs since it had already crossed "threshold capability" and the goal was now denuclearisation.
He said: "The president's been very clear about it. He said, he's not gonna tolerate North Korea being able to threaten the United States ... It's intolerable from the president's perspective.
Asked whether Mr Trump had been "walked through" scenarios in which the US carried out a pre-emptive strike, General McMaster replied: "He's been very much involved and has been deeply briefed, you know, on all aspects of the strategy."
Backed by its European allies, Japan and South Korea, the United States has been leading the push at the United Nations for tougher sanctions in response to North Korea's launch of an intercontinental ballistic missile on July 4.
A second test on July 28 further raised alarm about Pyongyang's drive to develop a missile capable of hitting the US mainland with a nuclear warhead.'WORKING WELL TOGETHER'
Meanwhile, it comes as Mr Trump issued a defence of General McMaster against criticism he's not supportive enough of Israel and is stifling conservative viewpoints.
Mr Trump came out with a public endorsement late Friday. In a statement, Mr Trump said: "General McMaster and I are working very well together. He is a good man and very pro-Israel. I am grateful for the work he continues to do serving our country."

General McMaster, an Army lieutenant general, came under attack after the recent firing of White House intelligence adviser Ezra Cohen-Watnick, who was a protege of Mr Trump's first national security adviser, Michael Flynn. Critics have accused General McMaster of trying to remove conservative voices from Mr Trump's national security team.
McMaster was also the subject of a widely circulated Facebook post by a Jerusalem Post columnist that called him "deeply hostile to Israel."
Mr Trump's statement of support comes after a turbulent period at the White House and a major reshuffling of top staff. New White House chief of staff John Kelly, a retired four-star Marine general, is now seeking to impose order on a chaotic West Wing.
Mr Cohen-Watnick's departure came as part of a string of shake-ups at the White House and National Security Council. General McMaster had sought to remove Mr Cohen-Watnick in March when CIA leaders raised concerns about him. But Mr Cohen-Watnick appealed to Mr Trump's top advisers, Steve Bannon and Jared Kushner, who got Mr Trump to intervene to save his job.
On Friday, Mr Kushner also offered support for General McMaster. Speaking to The New York Times, Mr Kushner called General McMaster "a true public servant and a tremendous asset." Mr Trump had recently pondered a different role for General McMaster. In a recent Situation Room meeting, the president - who is frustrated by his options in Afghanistan - raised the idea of firing the top US commander in Afghanistan and replacing him with General McMaster, according to officials with knowledge of the discussion.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kushner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's President Xi Jinping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Situation Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ezra Cohen-Watnick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Cohen-Watnick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N. Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerusalem Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Security Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant General H.R. McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WORKING WELL TOGETHER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General McMaster</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CIA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
