<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434519119453265</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/05/54/survivors-of-melbourne-cbd-gun-rampage-speak-out-10-years-on</url>
  <title>Survivors of Melbourne CBD gun rampage speak out, 10 years on</title>
  <content>
It was the morning that stopped Melbourne - an armed gunman terrorising innocent bystanders in the middle of the CBD.
On June 18, 2007 Christopher Hudson opened fire on two men and a woman on the corner of William Street and Flinders Lane.
High on drugs, Hudson was out to kill his girlfriend, Kaera Douglas. He didn't care who got in the way, and as 60 Minutes' Tara Brown reports, it so easily could have been anyone on the streets.
For perfect strangers, Natalie Gullace, Paul de Waard and Brendan Keilar, this Monday morning forever changed their lives.
The three heroes stepped directly into the line of fire of the armed madman to protected Kaera.
Their heroism saved the terrified girlfriend, but it came at a cost - Brendan was shot and killed.
This Sunday, 10 years on from the violent attack, Kaera speaks out for the very first time.

Related Articles

"For a very long time Kaera was silenced by the negative reaction she'd experienced from the media at the time she was shot," Brown said.
"She felt the public blamed her for the shooting, that she was responsible for the death of Brendan and the threat to so many others and that she somehow deserved what happened to her.
"That judgement resulted in her spending many years trying to recover and shying away from any public discussion of those events.
"It's only now that she feels strong enough to talk about it publicly."
In this Sunday's report, the brave survivors are also meeting for the first time since the terrifying shooting.
"By stepping in to save a stranger, Paul and Brendan were only compelled by compassion and tragically Brendan paid the ultimate price with his life," Brown said.
"The fact that at today Paul says he would do it all again speaks to the bravery and sense of justice these men displayed in the split-second decision they made to help instead of walk away.
"Similarly, Natalie's first instinct was to help, drawn to the screaming Kaera before being stopped in her tracks by Hudson, who would have shot her too - if he hadn't run out of bullets."
For then 24-year-old Kaera, Christopher Hudson was the idyllic bad-boy, a sadistic Hell's Angels bikie who she believed to be a real romantic.
She didn't know it at the time, but Hudson had a long and violent criminal history. It didn't take long until his violent streak emerged towards Kaera.
"The relationship between Hudson and Kaera had not been going for long but was very quickly abusive," Brown said.
"The level of violence was escalating in the days leading up to the shooting.
"Hudson tormented Kaera both physically and mentally. Some of the physical abuse was terrifying.
"As well as burning and beating her, he would threaten Kaera with his gun, holding it to her head and shoving it into her mouth."
On the morning of the shooting, Hudson told Kaera, "I've decided you need to go. Today you're going to die. Today's the last day of your life".
A petrified Kaera attempted to escape Hudson, running through heavy morning traffic.
Natalie, Paul and Brendan heard Kaera's screams for help and without hesitation tried to stop the vicious assault.
"Their courage was extraordinary," Brown said.
Hudson fired three bullets - one each at Kaera, Paul and Brendan. He then returned to shoot Brendan another two times and Paul once more.
Brendan - a father of three - was executed while he lay helpless on the ground.
Hudson then turned his gun towards Natalie, who had witnessed the entire attack from the middle of the intersection.
"All I remember is locking eyes with him and just staring at the end of the gun," she told Brown.
By a sheer stroke of luck, Hudson had no more bullets and his attempt to kill her failed.
Hudson was filmed on CCTV running from the scene, quickly discarding his jacket and gun.
He went into hiding for two days before Hell's Angels members turned him in.
Hudson pleaded guilty to murder in May 2008, and was sentenced to life imprisonment in September.
His crazed attack continues to affects so many, even after all these years.
Rather than forget the trauma Melbourne endured 10 years ago, Brown believes revisiting this story is incredibly important.
"The shooting was such a savage and random attack - the very scale of it deserves coverage, as does its tragic outcome," she said.
"For the first time Kaera speaks openly and publicly about the events leading up to the shooting and what happened on the day itself.
"It's also the first time the survivors meet to discuss how they've recovered and what the impact has been on their lives all these years later.
"It's a privilege to tell their story and celebrate their bravery."
"In the Line of Fire" airs this Sunday at 8.30pm on 60 Minutes.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaera Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 18, 2007 Christopher Hudson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Keilar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hells Angels</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minutes' Tara Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williams Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaera</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lines of Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hudson</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Hudson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Gullace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
