<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434175522066773</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/3801788/happy-helping-others/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Happy helping others</title>
  <content>
HUNTER HERO

Margaret Wilson

John Hunter Hospital volunteer

Voluntary role: Margaret Wilson has gotten just as much out of volunteering for the John Hunter Hospital as she has given. Picture: Marina Neil.
MARGARET Wilson began volunteering at John Hunter Hospital at a time when it felt as though her world was falling apart.
Almost 20 years ago, Mrs Wilson lost a grandson to leukaemia, and her husband died soon after.
But more death and heartache was to come.
Mrs Wilson, of Fishing Point, sadly farewelled another grandson, and her son-in-law.
"I was very down, I wasn't coping very well," Mrs Wilson, 82, said.
"I'd always worked, all my life. My doctor suggested I do something at the hospital and I have been there ever since.
"The hospital has been wonderful to me."
Over the past 19 years, Mrs Wilson's volunteering has led to her working in the wards, washing, sewing and doing alterations, helping out at the hospital gift shop, packing lollies, sorting the mail and stamping documents.
She has also helped look after the on site accommodation at the hospital for people from out of the area.
"We do a lot of things that save the staff time," she said.
Staff at the John Hunter Hospital say that without volunteers like Mrs Wilson, their jobs would be much more difficult.

Mrs Wilson has also sat with grieving families as they said goodbye to a loved one, and hospital staff who needed a shoulder to cry on at the end of a harrowing shift.
"I enjoy what I do, it makes me feel good," she said.
"I come home some nights and cry all night, but it gets it out of my system.

"I've seen some sad things, but there is plenty of people worse off than me."
Her motto is: "You don't get over it, but you've got to get on with it."
"Everyone here has a problem or has had a problem," Mrs Wilson said.
"I'm not the only one who has lost some family, and we are all very close.
"I've sat with families at the end. I didn't think I could do it, but I've been through it, so if I can help them I will."
Mrs Wilson said without the volunteers at the hospital, a lot of things wouldn't get done.
As well as doing all of the behind-the-scenes things that help the staff and make the patients more comfortable, the volunteers also raise a lot of money to buy cutting edge equipment for the hospital.
"I just worry about when I've got to give it away, whether the young ones are going to come through and do what we do," she said.
"Most of the volunteers are retiring age and up. The hospital would be in great difficulty without volunteers.

"We shouldn't have to raise money to buy all these things, but they are needed, so we do.

"There are a lot of people out there who could volunteer and don't."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HUNTER HERO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Wilson, 82</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Wilson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter Hospital</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Wilson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Wilson, of Fishing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
