<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435378112919988</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/entertainment/2017/08/06/another-sex-scandal-fox-news-host-suspended-lewd-pictures/</url>
  <title>Host suspended as another sex scandal rocks Fox News</title>
  <content>
Fox News says it has suspended Eric Bolling, co-host of its late-afternoon news program The Specialists, while it investigates allegations he sent a lewd photo of male genitalia to colleagues.
Word of the suspension came one day after a HuffPost report relying on anonymous sources stated Bolling had sent an abscence photo to at least three female colleagues at Fox News and Fox Business.
"Eric Bolling has been suspended pending the results of an investigation, which is currently underway," Fox News said in a brief statement.
A lawyer for Bolling, Michael J Bowe, denied the allegations.
Bolling is the best-known personality on Specialists, the show replaced the network's series The Five in April. He also hosts the weekend show Cashin' In.
He joined Fox News in 2008 after working as a commodities trader, according to his bio on the network's website.
A vocal supporter of President Donald Trump, Bolling wrote a March op-ed accusing House Speaker Paul Ryan, R-Wisconsin, and establishment Republicans of betraying the president with their version of a plan to overhaul the nation's health system.
The suspension is the latest in a string of sexual harassment complaints against personalities who appear on Fox News and Fox Business Network.
In July, Fox Business host Charles Payne was suspended after the Los Angeles Times reported based on anonymous sources that he harassed a female political analyst.
Payne remains suspended while an investigation into the allegations continues.
Other allegations were levelled against Fox News' former star, Bill O'Reilly, who was fired in April after several women reported being harassed by the host.
The network's founding leader, Roger Ailes, resigned in July 2016 because of harassment allegations. He died in May after a fall at his home.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolling</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Speaker Paul Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill O'Reilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R-Wisconsin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Business Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cashin' In</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Ailes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HuffPost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Business</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael J. Bowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Bolling</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
