<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435249263899770</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-named-the-cheapest-city-in-australia-to-have-a-funeral-20170802-gxnmzn.html</url>
  <title>It's cheaper to die in Canberra than any other Australian city</title>
  <content>
The cost of living in Canberra may be going up, but when it comes to the cost of dying, the nation's capital is the cheapest of Australian cities.
Figures  show Canberra is the cheapest capital city in the country for funerals, with the average cost of a service $6131.Photo: Michelle Mossop
On average, it is more than $1600 cheaper to hold a funeral in the nation's capital than it is in Perth, which had the highest average cost at $7764.
Sydney was close behind at $7621, followed by Melbourne, Brisbane, Adelaide and Hobart. Data was not available for the cost in Darwin.Photo: Cathryn Tremain
The cost of a burial service in Canberra on average is $6399, with Sydney being the most expensive place to bury the dead at $8225.
Canberra was also the cheapest city when it came to cremation, with the average cost being $6000.

The most expensive city to be cremated in was Perth, at $7607 on average, and Melbourne and Sydney, at $7402 and $7324 respectively, rounded out the top three. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The figures were compiled by comparison website finder.com.au, analysing data from every capital city on funeralplanner.com.Photo: Virginia Star
Finder's money expert Bessie Hassan said while the average burial or cremation in Canberra was just more than $6000, services can easily be more expensive.
"Although it's bleak, it's common for a funeral service to surpass the $10,000 mark, and when you include additions like candles or celebrant fees, the cost could really impact whoever is left to foot the bill," she said.
"Although our research found that those from Canberra pay the cheapest funeral costs on average, over $6000 is still a sizeable amount to fork out without notice."

A spokeswoman for InvoCare - the company that represents funeral providers such as White Lady Funerals, Guardian Funerals and Allan Drew Funerals among others - said prices for a funeral were more dependent on individual needs, rather than which state they lived in.
"Price fluctuations aren't based on where you live, they are based on meeting the needs of the individual family," the spokeswoman said.
"Wherever there are pricing variances between the states, it is more a result of cultural and historical differences."
While the cost of funerals has increased over the past few years, the spokeswoman said there were multiple reasons for this.
"The average costs have been impacted by normal CPI increases and also the celebratory and involved nature of a funeral service. Families are looking for more elements to be included when celebrating the life of their loved one, and these decisions do impact the cost of a funeral service," she said.
 A recent consumer study of 2000 people found that 60 per cent weren't planning on paying for their own funerals before they die, leaving the cost to relatives.
According to the study, 14 per cent of those surveyed believed their life insurance would cover the cost, with 8 per cent using funeral insurance.
Just 4 per cent had already paid for their funeral using a pre-paid plan.
The InvoCare spokeswoman said the option of pre-paid funerals had become more popular over recent years, with the number of pre-paid contracts increasing by 25 per cent in 2016.
One in 10 people selected for the study said they had already entered their plans, including donating their bodies to science, or choosing not to have a funeral.
Students are the most likely to rely on their life insurance, with 21 per cent choosing to pay for their funeral this way compared to 6 per cent of retirees.
On the other hand, 10 per cent of Baby Boomers surveyed had already taken out funeral insurance, compared to 6 per cent of Generation X and 7 per cent of Generation Y.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Lady Funerals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>InvoCare</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathryn Tremain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Drew Funerals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baby Boomers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bessie Hassan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virginia Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Mossop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Generation Y</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Generation X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian Funerals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
