<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433411017881095</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/most-perth-children-not-active-enough-university-of-wa-research/news-story/ad66491a82d52d22fca67fe17b721edb</url>
  <title>Most Perth kids not active enough</title>
  <content>
FEWER than a third of Perth preschoolers are active for at least three hours a day, a new study measuring childhood body movement shows.
University of WA population health researcher Dr Hayley Christian said the "alarming" revelation should prompt the introduction of activity guidelines at childcare and early learning centres.
She has released preliminary findings on the three-year PLAYCE study, which shows only 30 per cent of the 1200 children aged two to five surveyed so far had achieved national guidelines of three hours activity a day.
The research was even more damning on youngsters' sedentary life when looking at the gender divide.
While 39 per cent of boys reached the three-hour standard, the figure was just 21 per cent for girls.
The study analysed the movement of children who attend childcare and early learning centres across Perth.
Each child wore a "superhero belt" fitted with an accelerometer to measure the amount and intensity of their body movement over seven days, both at home and away.
The study, the biggest of its kind in Australia, showed only 8 per cent of the kids moved for three hours or more during a typical day at an early learning centre.
It also showed children were completely sedentary for an average of eight hours a day, not including sleep or light play which the accelerometer can detect.
"It's concerning there is such a large proportion of young children who aren't active enough," Dr Christian said.
"We have guidelines for what kids eat at centres but there's nothing that spells out how many hours kids should be active."
She said there was a "huge gap" in the guidelines when it comes to physical activity.
"There's been such a focus on school readiness and social and emotional development which are all important but it may have been to the detriment of other aspects of a child's development," Dr Christian said.
New program to get kids active

"There are many domains to a child's development and they all work together. If we miss part of that, such as physical development, then we could be missing out some other aspects of the child's development."
The study, which is set to analyse 2500 kids by the end of this year, is the first time such a big cohort of two-to-five-year-olds has had activity levels measured objectively by a tracking device.
Dr Christian said the PLAYCE study would also analyse data from a subset of 400 children who wore a GPS tracker to show activity "hotspots" and "cold spots" in their neighbourhood.
Dr Christian said there was a positive trend at early learning centres towards creating more natural play spaces.
She said her team was working with centres to help establish activity guidelines for interactions between staff and children, and also guidelines for creating effective play areas.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PLAYCE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Hayley Christian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Christian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
