<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434957206121079</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/its-all-about-taking-responsibility/3208739/</url>
  <title>It's all about taking responsibility</title>
  <content>
THE evolution and the breakthrough of what eventually led me to applying and then writing Responsibility Theory came about after many years and a variety of life-changing events and experiences.
The first of these transformative occasions began when I left school at the age of 16 and commenced an apprenticeship, which eventually led to me to becoming a tradesman.
The next step in this life's journey began during this same time, when I totally committed myself to accepting and valuing all of the imposed rigors and arduous mental, emotional and exacting physical demands pertaining to the traditional martial art of Goju Karate.
My commitment to the unrelenting demands of Goju Karate training is what, in due course, also paved the way to me undertaking all of my academic studies and also becoming involved with La Mama Theatre.
These three experiences led to me looking at and thinking about life differently.
My academic studies began with my night school HSC (Higher Certificate Studies). During the day I worked at my trade and during the evening I attended Goju Karate training on Tuesdays and Thursdays, as well as on Saturday afternoon.
During the same week I attended night school on Monday and Wednesday evenings after work.
It took me two years to complete my HSC certificate. This success led to me, over many years, to eventually realising two Bachelor degrees - one in physical education and one in psychology - five post-graduate awards (pedagogy; sports science; exercise and the sports sciences; health counselling; communication studies); three Master of Education awards (education; guidance and counselling; leadership and management) and my recently-completed PhD in cognitive neuroscience (at CQUniversity) under the supervision of Prof Ken Purnell.
The PhD thesis surfaced and entered three new descriptors into the lexicon of human biology. The first being neurofluidity - the neurological processes that lead to the condition of brain plasticity.
The second is holos, a term which, for the first time in history (to the best of my research and understanding), provides a descriptor which unifies the brain and the body with one word.
Prior to this the brain and the body had been referred to as two separate entities (the brain - and - the body). As Guy Claxton, writing in his book: Intelligence of the Flesh, stated: "The body and brain is designed to blend all internal and external influences together in one seamless operating holistic entity".
The third descriptor is Complex Brain Based Multi-Movement Therapy (CBBMMT).
When I completed my Physical Education degree and my Post-Graduate Diploma in Education, I became a qualified teacher.
I vividly remember my first day as a teacher. At the end of his first day, my wife Janet, who was also a teacher, asked how it went.
I remembers telling Janet that I basically enjoyed it; however, I told her there were some students who simply didn't want to do anything.
Not only that, to my great surprise, some students were defiant and disrespectful.
This led to Janet responding with the insightful words: "You can lead a horse to water, but you can't make it drink".
Those words rang loud and long in my ears and his mind from that day onwards.
The defiance, the disrespect and the reluctance of some students to learn or to even engage in their education, was all foreign to me.
My family background, my apprenticeship and tradie work life, all of my traditional martial arts, sports karate training and instructing experiences; my theatre and academic understandings provided me with the insight that my achievements and successes had taken place because I listened to others (the teachers, tradesman, karate sensei, coaches).
Associated with this, I engaged in all of these activities willingly and with passion.
It was all about the power of self-motivation.
As Ambrose Palmer, the trainer of World Boxing Champion John Famechon, stated succinctly: "First listen, think, think, think. Learn, learn, learn. Work, work, work. Harder, harder, harder. Faster, faster, faster. Practise, practise, practise. Perfect, perfect, perfect (Famechon & Quill, 1997).
However, in this new role of being a school teacher, I was surprised to the extreme that some students were rude and disrespectful and simply refused to follow instructions.
During this time of teaching I continued to train and teach at my Goju Karate school and also continued with my academic studies.
One day, after many, many years of school teaching (Goju Karate instructing) and regularly thinking about and dealing with those school students who were not willing to engage in their education, I found himself in the situation where I was at a new school and was introducing myself to a new classroom of senior primary school students.
From my years of teaching experiences, this informed me that it was very likely that here, in this new class (as with all of the other schools and classrooms I had been involved with), there would be some students who would refuse to participate and engage in their schoolwork.
There would also be some students who would behave rudely and disrespectfully.
I also knew that this would inevitably lead to the all-too familiar presentation of poor behaviours and unnecessary potential conflict; which was not good for anyone.
With that thought going through my mind I had an epiphany which began with the words "You can lead a horse to water, but you can't make it drink".
What this meant to me was that each student was responsible for their thinking, their behaviour, their choices, their learning and consequences.
This became the model for a new form of teaching. With that in mind, I said that it was time to leave the "us and them" model of teaching behind and start with the all-inclusive responsible behaviour approach.
With that all important universal axiom (You can lead a horse to water, but you can't make it drink) also ringing in my ears and swirling in my mind, I said that this then was the start of the Responsibility Theory program and subsequent book.
The Responsibility Theory program points out that there is immense potential in recognising the power of one's own thinking and behaviour.
The students are informed from the outset that their thinking and behaviour changes their neurology. They are informed they have power over what they think, do, say, choose and learn.
Responsibility Theory also brings with it a specific question that is followed by 10 precepts, the purpose of which is to provide a set of intellectual skills that can be applied immediately. 
The purpose is to again, inform and reinforce to the students that they have power, and this power is real and it can be used immediately. 
This power arises from the knowledge that they are responsible for what they think, do, say, choose and learn; and this power brings with it consequences.
This is further reinforced through the words and wisdom of Elisabeth Kugler-Ross who points out: "We are solely responsible for our choices and we have to accept the consequences of every deed, word, and thought throughout our lifetime." 
The empirical evidence has shown that once RT is applied, positive behavioural changes begin to take place.
As time progresses, this evidence suggests the students are now much more willing to act positively and engage in academic learning.
That begins to have a positive flow-on effect which leads to most of the students developing greater self-confidence, self-esteem, and self-efficacy.
Responsibility Theory is available from the CQUniversity Book Store. Website: bookshop.cqu.edu.au Phone: (07) 4930 9421.
Dr Ragnar Purje PhD is an Adjunct Lecturer and Research Higher Degree Student Supervisor, CQUniversity Australia. Responsibility Theory(C) is the prescribed text book for pre-service graduate teachers at CQUniversity. Ragnar is also a teacher at Beerwah State School.
RIVERS were fundamental to the development of the region.
How the Black Widow was caught
Palmer is shifting his treasures as liquidators circle his assets
Residents reeling after tragic crash on Saturday motorbike ride
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elisabeth Kugler-Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ragnar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Famechon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity Book Store</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambrose Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Responsibility Theory</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Widow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Ken Purnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Boxing Champion John Famechon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PhD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janet</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Mama Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Research Higher Degree Student Supervisor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Claxton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intelligence of the Flesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Higher Certificate Studies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Ragnar Purje PhD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adjunct Lecturer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBBMMT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Complex Brain Based Multi-Movement Therapy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quill, 1997</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Physical Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beerwah State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goju Karate</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Post Graduate Diploma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
