<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435339458213966</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836002/man-charged-after-police-pursuit/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Man charged after police pursuit</title>
  <content>
POLICE have charged a man after he allegedly led them on a pursuit through the Central Coast.

Officers from Tuggerah Lakes Local Area Command were conducting traffic enforcement duties on the Pacific Highway, Doyalson, around 5pm on Friday when they detected a Subaru WRX speeding in the 80 kilometre an hour zone.
Police stopped the vehicle and subjected the male driver, 35, to a mobile drug test.

The test allegedly returned a positive reading.
After being told he was under arrest, the driver allegedly started his car and drove south on the highway.

Police started to pursue the vehicle.
The car left the road onto an embankment, before it allegedly hit a Holden Captiva and small passenger bus.
The driver allegedly attempted to leave but was detained by members of the public.

Police arrived and arrested the driver.
NSW Paramedics treated the man for head injuries and he was taken to John Hunter Hospital.
The driver was then taken to Waratah Police Station where he was charged with exceeding speed limit by more than 45km/h; pursuit (Skye's Law); driving recklessly/furiously or speeding in a dangerous manner; and escaping lawful custody.

He was given strict conditional bail and will appear before Newcastle Local Court on August 24.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratah Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Captiva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doyalson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggerah Lakes Local Area Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skye's Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Paramedics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru WRX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
