<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434562069126543</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/buffalo-mustering-in-the-top-end-involves-precision-flying/8770088</url>
  <title>Buffalo mustering from the sky as demand for 'buff' beef soars at home and abroad</title>
  <content>
Dan Hayes runs Mainoru Station, a 1,300-square-kilometre property skirting the bottom of Arnhem Land in the Top End.
He is also the station pilot, and is quite simply a gun in the sky.
He lurches from the sky through the scrub, halting buffalo in their tracks as he hovers only a few metres from the earth.

Just as quickly as he's down, he's back up, buzzing away toward the next mob.
In something akin to a Mad Max scene, family and friends below hoon along in bull catchers, using a hydraulic arm to catch the buffalo around the neck and guide it back to a nearby truck.

It is enough to make you cover your eyes and physically gasp, expectant of carnage.
But Mr Hayes is a pilot who knows exactly what he's doing - he's been mustering livestock right across the Top End for more than 30 years.
He much prefers cattle over buffalo, which he says are a more dangerous and difficult animal.

Unfortunately he has to deal with plenty of buffalo alongside his 5,000 head of cattle. He estimates there are about 2,000 of the unwanted animals.
Mr Hayes said for the past five years it had been cheaper just to cull the animals, but lately that had changed thanks to the high price of beef.
"Cattle prices have jumped so much that there is a profit margin in going and getting them," he said.
In 2016, 6,000 head went into live export.

The majority of the buffalo caught the last few days at Mainoru Station will go to Vietnam as an alternative source of protein, particularly for the middle class.
A handful will head to the abattoir just outside Darwin, where demand for boxed buffalo is also on the rise.
"The money isn't as good as export but it's a secondary market that we've never had before," Mr Hayes said.
The abattoir started with a trial run of buffalo and is now devoting a day every few months for commercial slaughter.

Australia Agricultural Company's Darwin manager Steve Pocock said in a media briefing the abattoir "gets calls roughly every fortnight requesting buffalo meat".
He conceded consistency was, however, an issue.
"Both supply and markets are hard," he said.
"Access to Indigenous lands for buffalo would require changes through the land council, which are still in the works."
There is estimated to be roughly 100,000 buffalo running wild in Arnhem Land, but it is one place that is not easy to get in to.

The Buffalo Industry Council pointed to some difficulties in negotiations over a section 19 permit which must go through the Northern Land Council (NLC) on behalf of traditional owners.
Mr Hayes said it appeared a complicated and costly exercise.
"Without a doubt it would lessen the buff numbers if they could get in there," he said.
"I think the NLC is very difficult to deal with, in actually giving you access to that land."
NLC chief executive Joe Morrison said four agreements covering about 20,000 square kilometres had now been negotiated.

He said consultations were also underway for another 9,000 square kilometres.
"They're going to be negotiated in the next few months I understand, pending on availability of traditional owners," Mr Morrison said.
"Of course there are some in the industry that may be frustrated by delays, but it's the land council's statutory responsibility to ensure land holders are consulted."
He said some applications had been rejected because not all traditional owners wanted buffalo harvesting on their country or would prefer to cull the animal.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buffalo Industry Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NLC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mainoru Station</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Land Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buffaloes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Agricultural Company's Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hayes</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Pocock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
