<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434441810041281</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4459438/shark-kills-sammy-the-seal-beach-closed/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Shark kills Sammy the seal, beach closed</title>
  <content>
Shark kills Sammy the seal, beach closed

Sammy the seal.

Sammy the seal.

Sammy the seal photobombs a picture of Dave Magilton.

Sammy the seal.

Sammy the seal.

Sammy the seal.

Sammy the seal.

Sammy the seal.

Sammy the seal.

Mish Stewart sent in this picture of Sammy the seal.

Cherie Marcos

Bizzy Nelson sent in this picture of Sammy.

Janine Gapes sent in this picture of Sammy.

Sallyann Hall sent in this picture of Sammy.

Jay Williams sent in this photo of Sammy.

Simone Kinross sent in this picture of Sammy.

Cherie Marcos sent in this photo of Sammy.

Kassy Ovens sent in this picture.

exit

AUTHORITIES have closed a Victorian beach after a seal was ripped apart by a shark on Thursday night.
Sammy the seal, a popular and friendly fixture at the beach, was " torn apart by a large shark outside the pavilion about 11pm last night", Warrnambool Surf Life Saving president Michael Owen said.
He is now concerned the shark might return.
"It is out of the ordinary for a shark to come in this close," he said.
"Now that it's had a feed in here it knows to come in here."
Heartbroken locals have even created a .

Sammy the Seal.
How it's panned out

10.30AM: Warrnambool beach is expected to be reopen about 5pm if there are no shark sightings.
Members of the club believe the last time the beach was closed due to a shark sighting was about 10 years ago.
10AM: The female who witnessed the shark attack described it as "vicious."

She said it was a big shark that attacked a large seal.
Warrnambool Surf Life Saving president Michael Owen said he was concerned the shark may return.
"It is out of the ordinary for a shark to come in this close," he said.
"Now that it's had a feed in here it knows to come in here."
Mr Owen said he believed there was a possibility it may even return tonight.
He said there had been a high number of shark sightings over summer than we have had in years.
Police will interview the witness.
9.47AM
A female fishing near the lower jetty on the breakwater witnessed the attack.
Warrnambool Surf Life Saving president Michael Owen said the beach was now closed.

"A shark came up and grabbed the seal and ripped it apart," Mr Owen said.
He urged residents to stay out of the water.
9.30am: A shark attacked and killed a popular seal on Thursday night.
Warrnambool Surf Life Saving club captain David Owen said the shark killed Sammy the Seal.
"Sammy the seal has been torn apart by a large shark outside the pavilion about 11pm last night," Mr Owen said.
The beach is closed.
Warrnambool Surf Life Saving Club is about to send out a boat to search 
The Emergency Vic website has a report of an unconfirmed shark sighting.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherie Marcos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool Surf Life Saving</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kassy Ovens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sallyann Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janine Gapes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool Surf Life Saving Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Owen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone Kinross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bizzy Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sammy</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Magilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Owen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Owen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
