<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435163364552833</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/territory-tales-vogue-megaqueen-on-getting-ready-for-show/8774606</url>
  <title>Territory Tales: Vogue MegaQueen reveals tricks of the trade for drag queens in the tropics</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

In a small dark room at the back of an old tropical house in Darwin, behind feather boas, sequined gowns and six-inch heels piled from floor to ceiling, Phillip Coffey is beginning a three-hour transformation.
Wearing a faded singlet and shorts, he sits on a chair with a fluffy pink cover in front of a table scattered with multicoloured makeup pallets.
Phil will soon become Vogue MegaQueen: one of Darwin's best-known drag queens.
"I started drag when I was 16," he says, dipping his brush into a jar of heavy prosthetic wax, painting it over his eyebrows, again and again, creating a smooth blank canvas to create tonight's look.
Dressing up in drag was a way to get into clubs underage, and Phil soon learned he could get away with more.
"I think there's an unwritten rule that drag queens can overstep boundaries that other people might not be able to," he says.
"It's more accepted to be a bit cheeky," he says with a grin, dabbing powder over the glue on his eyebrows.
That a town known more for its croc wranglers, beer drinkers and army soldiers has a thriving drag scene can come as a surprise to outsiders when they first arrive.
Vogue and Phil are the same person

Phil is now drawing thick lines along his cheekbones, nose and across the top of his forehead, contouring a more feminine face and building the signature exaggerated features of a drag queen.
But drag is more than just the dramatic makeup - it's an attitude.
"When I'm a boy I'm pretty shy to start with," Phillip explains.
"But when I'm in drag I'm more loud and out there.
"When I open up as myself as Phil, pretty much Vogue and Phil are the same person.
"It just takes a lot longer for Phil to open up."
Being a queen in the sweltering, sticky tropics presents some unique challenges.
In Darwin's monsoon season, temperatures and humidity soar, and so Phil says drag queens here have to take extra steps to ensure their makeup can withstand the sweat and heat.

"You have to pile it on thick and set it properly," Phil says, dabbing a line of glitter onto his eyelids.
They're part of the tricks of the trade passed on from older drag queens to the next generation. The 'baby queens' starting out usually find a mentor, their 'drag mum'.
And with less than 10 queens on the Darwin scene, Vogue is now on the lookout for the next generation.
"We try and create a safe space for everybody ... the more the merrier."
After wiggling into a gown, securing a black wig and spraying her face with hairspray to set the makeup in place, Vogue MegaQueen is ready to hit the town.
"Can you hear all those plastic bags in there?" Vogue says, pressing down on the towering wig.
Showtime

Backstage at the club, Vogue is touching up her makeup with her support dancers for tonight's performance.
After 16 years Vogue still gets nervous sometimes, especially "if I'm going to a hen's night where I don't know anyone or everyone's going to be sober".
"But if everyone's drunk they always appreciate a drag show," she says.
"There's no feeling like when you first walk on stage and get the audience reaction."
After knocking back a final shot of vodka and slipping two breasts inside her leotard, Vogue MegaQueen struts out into the spotlight.
"I always wanted to be famous. This is my way of being famous I suppose."

This story is part three in a five-part weekly series taking you into the lives of some of the Northern Territory's most colourful characters. Read  and .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vogue</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showtime</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Coffey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vogue MegaQueen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
