<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435077465206261</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/young-family-has-bought-a-36m-apartment-at-yungaba-house/news-story/36b6b0faee167eb485587010b70aff2d</url>
  <title>Young family has bought a $3.6m apartment at Yungaba House - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
A young family has secured the first post-launch sale in The Residences at Yungaba House, paying $3.6 million for a four-level apartment.

A LOCAL family has secured the first post-launch sale at located within 130-year-old Yungaba House on the riverfront at .
The young family, who wish to remain anonymous, from neighbouring Bulimba, paid $3.6 million for four-level Residence Five, one of the flagship homes of the 10 home project.
Frasers Property general manager Residential Queensland Cameron Leggatt said The Residences had attracted a significant level of inquiry since its launch.

The Residences, Yungaba House.

"There has been a tremendous amount of interest in The Residences thanks to its status as
one of Brisbane's most unique residential offerings," Mr Leggatt said.
"This is riverfront elegance at its finest with the opportunity to secure a modern and luxurious
lifestyle wrapped in a carefully restored historic shell.
"The fact that this is located on an east-facing riverfront site only 800m to the CBD just
underlines the exceptional and unrepeatable value proposition that is The Residences."
Spanning over four levels, the sold three-bedroom apartment has its own turret, stunning CBD and Story Bridge views and expansive basement level.
It is the second most expensive apartment in The Residences, only Residence Six tops it, priced at $4.25 million.

The Residences, Yungaba House.

Luxury market specialist Sherrie Storor, of McGrath New Farm, said prestige waterfront
properties in Kangaroo Point were highly sought-after and tightly held.
Ms Storor said The Residences' heritage aspects, modern interiors and amazing location
had delivered an exceptionally rare offering to the area.
"The supply of new high-end apartments and homes is extremely limited, particularly on the
riverfront, which serves to increase their value when they do enter this already tight
marketplace," she said.
"There are not that many three-bedroom residences being built, yet there's strong interest in
this style of property from empty-nesters or families who want to downsize in the suburbs
and get that much closer to the CBD."

The Residences, Yungaba House.

The Residences' three and four-bedroom homes were created during a decade-long
restoration effort that involved dedicated and detailed work from the design and construction
teams.
Each of the private homes features original woodwork throughout, including sash windows
that have been reglazed and re-engineered for their modern residents.
The homes overlook Yungaba's 3,000sq m heritage-listed gardens and lush parklands while
an adjacent Recreation Centre offers residents-only access to a private gymnasium and 25m
infinity-edge pool.
The Residences are priced from $1.795 million to $4.25 million and can be inspected by
private appointment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulimba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath New Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Residence Five</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recreation Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Storor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Leggatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherrie Storor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yungaba's 3,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frasers Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Residential Queensland Cameron Leggatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Residence Six</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yungaba House</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Story Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
