<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434355910694648</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/the-fitz-files-bill-shorten-bonza-bloke-makes-big-impression-at-arm-20170804-gxpihw.html</url>
  <title>The Fitz files: Bill Shorten, bonza bloke, makes big impression at ARM</title>
  <content>
Having gushed unseemingly a few weeks ago, how it seemed as though Malcolm Turnbull had his mojo back - after seeing him in action at Mia Freedman's book launch - I do hope you'll indulge me doing a little gushing about Bill Shorten, too. I don't know him that well, but when I asked him in February in Darwin if he would address, in late July, the gala dinner of the Australian Republic Movement - which I chair - I had no idea just what he would deliver. He arrived early, left late, and I swear, shook hands or had his photo taken with damn nigh all of the throng of 900 of our ARM members there. He laughed, he discussed, he debated passionately he posed for photos. All up, though, he looked less like a politician working a room than a proud Australian having the time of his life. And of course, in his singularly eloquent and passionate speech, he committed a future Shorten government to having a referendum on the republic in its first term. In my reply speech I noted, and I meant it, that the ARM remains entirely non-partisan - and we look to the PM to match the commitment - but I cannot overstate how impressive Shorten was overall, and just how likeable he was. As I said to him afterwards, walking him to the car, he was the second-biggest star of the night. Far and away the biggest was Chloe Shorten who, prior to Saturday night, I didn't know at all. Like Malcolm Turnbull, Bill Shorten has married way above himself, and I'll bet that is one of only two things those two can agree on, the other being the republic.
Turnbull's waking moments?

And yes, I know that, meantime, the Prime Minister makes a fair fist of resolutely defending the whole idea of a plebiscite on same-sex marriage, and steadfastly maintains that it is the right thing to do. But quietly, privately, in the silent watch of the night, when no one is around, don't you think he might do a fair portrayal of Edvard Munch's famous painting The Scream? He is Malcolm Turnbull. He's been one of the loudest voices for same-sex marriage from the beginning! He knows that the issue is over, that Australia has decided, that all the plebiscite will accomplish is wasted money and open wounds, to get to the same result the Parliament could get to this week  . . . and yet, presumably to placate the hard-core rump in his own party, and perhaps because of a deal he did to get into power in the first place, he must continue defending the indefensible, calling wise what he knows is ludicrous. I say bravo to those Libs looking to cross the floor, stop the nonsense, and get it done. Warrant Entsch, particularly, has been another strong voice for sanity, and if he and his crossbenchers can prevail with their private members bill, it will be a triumph for justice and common sense. As to Senator Abetz's idea for non-binding, non compulsory postal plebiscite that has to be the most absurd proposal yet. Please, parliamentarians - just get it done!
Talk to the trolls?

And of course both views expressed above will see me draw a little heat on social media. I never particularly mind. And whatever flak comes my way would be about a tenth of what the likes of the great lawyer and human rights campaigner Julian Burnside takes on a weekly basis. On that subject, Julian posted a fascinating tweet this week: "I invited people who disagree with me & troll me to DM their email: 3 trolls did. I emailed them to meet me & talk. They have not replied."
Extraordinary, yes? It reminded me of something that Adam Goodes once told me, that despite all the nasty cat-calls and booing and racial vilification he suffered on the football field, never ONCE on the street, face-to-face, did anyone do it. In my own case it's happened only once - a moment I cherish - when walking through Adelaide Airport, an elderly businessman shouted at me to "stop bullying Andrew Bolt!"Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
What They Said

"I remember saying to my husband, you know, 'Why, why is this lady around?' And he said, 'Well I refuse to be the only Prince of Wales who never had a mistress.' [When I confided to the Queen] I said, 'I'm coming to you. What do I do?' And she said, 'I don't know what you should do, Charles is hopeless.' And that was it. That was help."
Princess Diana, on a just revealed tape. Don't start.

"I love the President and I'm very, very loyal to the President, and I love the mission that the President has. He is the most competitive person I have ever met. I have seen this guy throw a dead spiral through a tyre. I have seen him at Madison Square Garden with a topcoat on, he's standing in the key, and he's hitting foul shots and swishing the ball on them. He sinks 30 foot putts."

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Anthony Scaramucci, the new Communications Director of the White House, just before he was sacked on his 10th day.
"Now look, I . . . It is, ahh, I've been asked a few questions about that and I've, I've dealt with the issue."
Malcolm Turnbull, firmly dealing with a question about whether he would allow a postal plebiscite for marriage equality. 
"For other women it is totally unacceptable in 2017 to say that women should have to answer that question in the workplace. It should not predetermine whether they are given a job or have job opportunities."
Jacinda Ardern, the new Labour leader in New Zealand, asked on radio if she intends to have children.
"That would tell the Australian people that the government had lost its authority."
Senator Eric Abetz warning that the sky would fall if Liberal parliamentarians crossed the floor to vote in favour of marriage equality.
"I've been in the Canberra Press Gallery for 48 1/2 years. I've been the Nine Network's political editor since December the 1st, 1984 - the day of that year's federal election. And I'm about to turn 74."
The great Laurie Oakes makes his announcement - it's time.
Twitter: @Peter_Fitz
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Well I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Burnside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edvard Munch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda Ardern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Goodes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince of Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madison Square Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mia Freedman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter_Fitz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communications Director of the White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Press Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Republic Movement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
