<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434686623179019</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/vic-weather-strong-winds-alpine-blizzards-forecast/8778700</url>
  <title>Victoria hammered by strong winds overnight as alps brace for blizzards</title>
  <content>
Blizzard conditions with heavy snowfalls are expected in Victoria's alpine areas today, as a powerful cold front makes its way across the state.
The front began battering the south-west yesterday evening and peaked in Melbourne in the early hours of this morning, with some bayside suburbs hit by gusts of up to 80 kilometres an hour.
The Grampians in the state's west recorded the strongest winds of 102 kilometres per hour.

External Link:

Kellie Helmers: Plenty of snow at Hotham today bring on more snow
Bureau of Meteorology senior forecaster Richard Carlyon said alpine areas would be hit by the strongest winds today and could receive their heaviest falls of the winter so far.
"We may see wind gusts up to about 110 kilometres per hour. Probably easing a little through the afternoon but still quite windy," he said.
"We will just see steady snow up there with expected totals of between 20 and 40 centimetres."
He said Melbourne could also expect more wind and rain during the day.
"The winds will ease off a little through the morning but they'll stay fresh to strong from the north-west through the day, and we'll see reasonably frequent showers moving through," he said.
Yesterday, holiday makers at Victoria's alps awoke to fresh snow dumps, .
The  and stick to marked ski runs.
"Ensure you play it safe up there," SES deputy chief officer David Baker said on Friday.
"It's going to be big dumps, hopefully very enjoyable, but blizzards can pose particular dangers and we don't want anybody to go missing up in the mountains."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Carlyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hotham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grampian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellie Helmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
