<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435249263899750</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/get-ready-for-the-2017-avon-descent-august-5-6/news-story/e67025a171d219230e20af0fd9643721</url>
  <title>Get ready for the 2017 Avon Descent - August 5 & 6</title>
  <content>
SEE THE RESULTS:

THE Avon Descent is one of Western Australia's oldest and greatest sporting events and attracts competitors and spectators from throughout Australia and the world.
Avon Descenters challenge the Avon and Swan rivers in a variety of paddle and power craft in an exciting two-day time trial over 124 gruelling kilometres.
The Avon Descent was first held in 1973 with just 49 competitors, no rules, no officials, no checkpoints and very few spectators. In the years since, over 35,000 people have competed in this iconic race, from novices and families, to World Champions and Olympic competitors.
Continuing the Hell or High Water' theme in 2017, the Avon Descent is offering a fantastic event for not only our loyal competitors, but especially for newcomers. On top of it all, a new category has been introduced to the race - SUP.
Don't miss out on a fun filled weekend starting August 4th to 6th- watching Paddleboats, Powerboats and SUP's compete, while enjoying the festivities of the Family Fun Days along the river.
For more information, please visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Water</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Champions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Fun Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon Descent</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon Descenters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
