<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433660125986753</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/the-best-thing-about-having-small-boobs/news-story/6bc1274006a4f8277eaf121e68cfcd05</url>
  <title>Best thing about having small boobs</title>
  <content>
LAST week my 7-year-old son had a friend over to play. After a bit of Lego and a game of hide-and-seek they decided to get out the paper and pencils.
"What are you drawing?" I asked, looking over their shoulders. "Boobs!" they cried.
The friend showed me her illustration: two U shapes with nipples pointing downwards at the bottom. My son's sketch was quite different. He'd drawn a couple of neat circles with smaller circles inside: fried eggs.
I laughed at the accuracy of the diagrams. The friend's mother has DD-cup breasts. I'm a double A.
I wasn't keen on puberty. I didn't want any of it: The hairy armpits, the periods, the pimples. It all seemed awful and unnecessary. Fortunately, I was a late bloomer. My insipid hormones and underweight body led to a fairly unremarkable pubescent transformation.
As a teenager I was quite content with my childlike figure. I didn't envy the well-developed girls at school who had to devise tricky ways to change into their PE uniforms lest anyone catch a glimpse of their new assets.
Things changed a little in my twenties. I finally felt like an adult, and I wanted to look like one too. My lower half co-operated - I had, by this time, grown some "good child-bearing hips" - but there still wasn't much going on up top.
I discovered padded, push-up bras; however, even the smallest size wasn't quite small enough: there was always a gap between my skin and the stiff cup.
When I fell pregnant at 26 I had no idea how my body would change. My stomach was suddenly a forest of black hair - thanks, hormones - but I also developed ... wait for it ... full B-cup boobs! It was amazing. I loved having cleavage, adored my new silhouette, enjoyed being able to buy "proper" bras at last.
But I couldn't breastfeed forever. When my second child weened himself at 14 months I briefly considered pursuing a career as a wet nurse. Instead, I threw away my maternity underwear and said goodbye to my inflated bosoms.
I'm now 37. When I turn side-on and look at myself in the mirror I see a plank, a pancake, an ironing board. And while I'm an outspoken body-acceptance advocate (in front of my children), practising what I preach can be difficult.
Breast augmentation has crossed my mind. It seems like a relatively simple procedure: choose a size, get knocked out, wake up with bigger boobs (and a smaller bank account). But in my heart I know that silicon isn't for me. I don't dye my hair, I haven't got any tatts, I hardly wear makeup: natural is my preference.
Putting on weight is another possibility - if only it worked. Extra fat does not enhance my womanly curves - it just deposits itself exclusively onto my stomach and thighs. I'm pretty sure I could double my body size and still fit into an AA-cup brassiere.
But you know what? There is one definite upside to being bosomly challenged: I am streamlined and aerodynamic. I am built for speed.
I took up running last year. I didn't mean to - a friend encouraged me to join her - and although I wasn't especially keen at first, it didn't take me long to develop a slight obsession. I now run 5-6 km two or three times a week (and would go more often if I had the time).
Although I often run by myself or with my friend, every Saturday morning I head along to my local park run: A free, 5km, timed event organised by volunteers. The number of attendees varies, but there are generally around 120 Lycra-clad people at the starting line.
Recently, as I waited for the countdown, I looked around at my fellow park runners and something dawned on me: maybe having a flat chest is an advantage.
Almost all of the women who participate in park run have bigger breasts than me. When they run, things bounce. When I run, things stay right where they are. There's no wobble and no extra weight to carry. I have nothing (except my own lack of fitness) to slow me down.
When I first started running I bought a generously padded sports bra. It had no function other than to hide my nipples and give people the impression I had something to support. Lately, however, I've been exercising in a non-padded crop top, which means there's only a thin layer of material between me and the world.
And, for the first time in my life, I'm okay with that.
I'm not sure what happened - maybe I'm just getting more apathetic as I age - but suddenly I don't feel so embarrassed about my Keira Knightley - esque torso - I just think of myself as a strong, fast, runner.
I will never have cleavage or fill out a swimsuit. Mammograms are going to be pretty much impossible. But when it comes to high-intensity exercise, I will appreciate my fried eggs.
And if I ever stop running I could always become a life model, because I'm pretty easy to draw - just start with two circles.
Jean Flynn is an author. Her new novel "Lovesick" won the inaugural XO Romance prize and is .

Erin Molan prefers 'incidental' exercise to keep fit

How The Footy Show's Erin Molan keeps fit and healthy
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footy Show's Erin Molan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XO Romance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Molan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DD-cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AA-cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lycra-clad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keira Knightley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
