<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651433788975006908</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/03/32/decision-pending-on-terror-plot-accused</url>
  <title>Decision pending on terror plot accused</title>
  <content>
Police must decide what to do with a fourth Sydney man accused of involvement in a terrorist plot to bomb an Etihad airliner destined for the Middle East.
Khaled Merhi has been detained since he and three others were arrested by counter-terrorist police last Saturday.
Two of them have been charged with preparing for or planning a terrorist act while a third man was questioned and released without charge.
Police allege Khaled Mahmoud Khayat, 49, attempted to have his brother take a bomb on the Abu Dhabi-bound flight on July 15.
His unamed sibling was unaware the military-grade explosive was hidden in a meat grinder and stashed in his luggage but it never made it through security, police say.
They allege a second attack was planned after the first plot failed. It involved an attempt to build an improvised chemical dispersion device to fill a plane with hydrogen sulfide, a colourless toxic gas.
Khayat, of Lakemba, and co-accused Mahmoud Khayat, 32, of Punchbowl, had their matter mentioned in Parramatta Local Court on Friday after being charged on Thursday night.

Related Articles

They have been refused bail ahead of another court mention on November 14.
Meanwhile, Merhi has been held under specific provisions of the Commonwealth Crimes Act, which according to police "recognises that terrorism investigations are inherently complex and that there can be legitimate reasons for extended periods of detention for suspects in such matters".
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Mahmoud Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Crimes Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khayat, of Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
