<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435464012266649</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-06/un-imposes-new-trade-and-investment-sanctions-on-north-korea-over-intercontinental-missile-tests/1691574</url>
  <title>UN imposes new trade and investment sanctions on North Korea over intercontinental missile tests</title>
  <content>
The United Nations Security Council has unanimously imposed new sanctions on North Korea over Pyongyang's recent intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) tests, in a move that could slash the reclusive state's $3 billion annual export revenue by a third.

Key points:

UN sanctions could cost North Korea a third of its annual export revenue
New joint ventures with North Korea are also banned
The US says it will continue to take prudent defensive measures to protect itself and allies

The US-drafted resolution bans North Korean exports of coal, iron, iron ore, lead, lead ore and seafood.
It also prohibits countries from increasing the current numbers of North Korean laborers working abroad, bans new joint ventures with North Korea and any new investment in current joint ventures.
"We should not fool ourselves into thinking we have solved the problem. Not even close," US Ambassador to the United Nations Nikki Haley told the council.
"The North Korean threat has not left us, it is rapidly growing more dangerous," she said.
"Further action is required. The United States is taking and will continue to take prudent defensive measures to protect ourselves and our allies," she added, saying that Washington would continue annual joint military exercises with South Korea.

Video:(ABC News)
In late July, North Korea , which proved its ability to strike America's mainland.
North Korea has accused the United States and South Korea of escalating tensions by conducting military drills.
North Korean ally China and Russia both slammed the US deployment of the THAAD anti-missile defence system in South Korea. China's UN Ambassador Liu Jieyi called for a halt to the deployment and for any equipment in place to be dismantled.
Mr Liu also urged North Korea to "cease taking actions that  might further escalate tensions".
US pressure on China

Video:(ABC News)
Russia's UN Ambassador Vassily Nebenzia said he hoped recent remarks by US Secretary of State Rex Tillerson "were sincere - that the US is not seeking to dismantle the existing [North Korea] situation or to forcibly unite the peninsula or to militarily intervene in the country".
While the Security Council has been divided on how to deal with other international crises like Syria, the 15-member body has remained relatively united on North Korea. Still, negotiating new measures typically takes months, not weeks.
North Korea has been under UN sanctions since 2006 over its ballistic missile and nuclear programs and the Security Council has now ratcheted up the measures in response to five  nuclear weapons tests and four long-range missile launches.

What is an ICBM and how far can one travel?

Intercontinental ballistic (ICBM) missiles can fly thousands of kilometres and carry nuclear weapons
The missiles are similar in construction to rockets which launch people into space
The US has numerous interceptors in place, but their effectiveness to bring down ICBMs is yet to be tested

The United States negotiated with China for a month on the latest resolution, before expanding negotiations to the full 15-member council.
US President Donald Trump's administration has been frustrated that China has not done more to rein in North Korea. Washington has threatened to exert trade pressure on Beijing and impose sanctions on Chinese firms doing business with Pyongyang.
"We had tough negotiations this week," Ms Haley told reporters.
"I think that the Chinese realized that the United States was going to push, but they responded and we appreciate how they cooperated with us during these negotiations."
Mr Liu, asked about the role of US pressure in negotiations, said China has been consistent on its aim of achieving denuclearisation, peace and stability on the Korean Peninsula and trying "to re-launch negotiations to achieve this end."
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intercontinental</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's UN Ambassador Vassily Nebenzia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Ambassador</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-drafted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Nikki Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THAAD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Security Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's UN Ambassador Liu Jieyi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Liu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
