<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434948616186373</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/hampton-rise-is-the-latest-infill-estate-in-bridgeman-downs/news-story/d3bf587394db828cfd9dba47f70c82bc</url>
  <title>Hampton Rise is the latest infill estate in Bridgeman Downs - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Ausbuild has just launched Hampton Rise, a new prestige infill estate in Bridgeman Downs in north Brisbane.

THE BASICS
HAMPTON RISE
Developer: Ausbuild
Price: From $395,000. House and land also available.
Location: 307 Albany Creek Road, Bridgeman Downs
Hampton Rise is a new estate in Bridgeman Downs with 22 lots just released in stage one ranging from 450sq m to 674sq m.
PRESTIGE land in a new infill estate in has just been launched with five lots already sold to pre-registered buyers.
, being developed by Ausbuild, is the company's second estate to be launched in the north Brisbane suburb, with its sister project, , selling out stage one in six months.
Ausbuild joint managing director, Matthew Bell, said despite knowing there was pent up demand for this style of development on Brisbane's northside, they had still been pleasantly surprised by the flurry of sales.

One of the new home designs on offer at Hampton Rise.

"Hampton Rise is a unique opportunity to buy prestige land in an established community that is close to premium amenities, yet also bordered by natural reserves and parklands," Mr Bell said.
"The traditional larger block sizes, proximity to the new Chermside precinct and public transport make Hampton Rise an attractive choice.
"Ausbuild has a reputation for sourcing the best land in the best locations and creating communities people are proud to call home."

Hampton Rise estate in Bridgeman Downs.

The well established suburb of Bridgeman Downs is experiencing a revival with families wanting access to parks, natural reserves and well regarded schools.
The 22 lots released in stage one are sized from 450sq m to 674sq m with a starting price of $395,000.
Mr Bell said Ausbuild aimed to create a suburban oasis at Hampton Rise, with the newly released two storey designs set to feature prominently throughout the estate.
"We think buyers in Hampton Rise will opt for homes from our new two storey range," Mr Bell said.
"These homes are architecturally inspired and are a perfect match for a development with a lot of class."

One of the new home designs on offer at Hampton Rise.

Mr Bell said Harrington, Ausbuild's sister development also in Bridgeman Downs, had commenced civil works after strong stage one sales.
"We believe Hampton Rise will follow a similar pattern of sale given how well Harrington has been received at Bridgeman Downs," he said.
"To me this shows if you build the right estate, in the right environment, it creates an appreciation of quality and a desire for people to want to be part of that community."

One of the home designs on offer at Hampton Rise.

Ausbuild has been creating homes and estates for more than 30 years across South East Queensland.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany Creek Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chermside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South East Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hampton Rise</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ausbuild</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridgeman Downs</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
