<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434901371545863</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/marriage/pr-queen-roxy-jacenko-reveals-she-suffered-depression-while-her-husband-was-behind-bars/news-story/ade078b07ff30fb5a1342f1d08ad4ee1</url>
  <title>PR queen Roxy Jacenko reveals she suffered depression while her husband was behind bars</title>
  <content>
Roxy Jacenko declares she's 'not single' on The Morning Show
0:42

Roxy Jacenko tcategorically stated she's 'not single', saying she's still committed to her jailed husband Oliver Curtis. Courtesy: The Morning Show/Channel Seven

March 13th 2017
5 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Roxy Jacenko reveals how she battled with depression. Picture: Supplied

Share

AS one of Australia's biggest names in publicity, Roxy Jacenko knows how to turn it on.
A a mother-of-two, multiple business owner and brand ambassador - the PR queen thought she could take on the world.
.
Her husband, Oliver Curtis, had been sentenced to prison for insider trading. She faced a year alone raising their two young children Pixie, 5, and Hunter, 3, at their Bondi apartment.
She had businesses to run, and within three weeks of Curtis' sentence -

Roxy Jacenko was 'crumbling' inside despite looking together. Picture: Jenny Evans.Source:News Corp Australia
Behind the shiny facade, the designer handbags and million-dollar smile; the 37-year-old was in damage control - and she was "crumbling".
"It was the worst 12 months of my life," she told news.com.au.
"I got to the eleven month point [during Curtis' jail term] and I broke.
"Five days I'd come to work with puffy eyes and miserable ... I'd then have to go to a function or an event and I'd have to turn it on. And yes I would turn it on, but I was crumbling inside.

"I couldn't cope anymore."
But instead of seeking help, Jacenko said she did what she does bet. She went on with the show.
"You put this facade on, that everything is fine and everything will be OK, but it wasn't," she explained.

Roxy Jacenko has opened up about her hidden struggle with depression while her husband was in jail. Photo Jeremy PiperSource:News Corp Australia
"There was so much sh*t. I'm critiqued for what I wear and critiqued for being a bad mother because I work.
"I was critiqued for what I wore to the trial. But if I didn't go, I'd also be critiqued.
"If I wore garments from Kmart I'd be critiqued because that's not what I'd normally wear. "There's nothing I can do right."
When Curtis was sentenced in June 2016 - Jacenko started to lose her happiness.
"I was very depressed ... I hid it [but] I was miserable," she said.

A post shared by Roxy Jacenko (@roxyjacenko) on

"I had a lot of resentment [towards Curtis]. Why did he let me have children if he could potentially go to jail? It's irresponsible, how could he have told me it would never happen?
"I was angry, and I was resentful."
This week, Jacenko revealed that she didn't think there was any hope for her five year marriage while her husband was behind bars.
Speaking to news.com.au exclusively, she admitted she'd spoken to a divorce lawyer while Curtis served his jail sentence at Cooma Correctional Centre.

'You put this facade on, that everything is fine and everything will be OK, but it wasn't'. Picture: Instagram.Source:Supplied
"We were at each other's throats, so when he went for 12 months, I set up a life for myself and the children and that was it. I thought that would be the end of it [marriage]," she said.
"He [Ollie] knew that as well. He didn't want his marriage to end, but he was aware of the circumstances and that it hadn't been easy.
"Marriages are hard at the best of times, to throw what we had into it - it's a disaster."
In April, just two months before her husband's release - Jacenko was pictured getting intimate with ex-boyfriend Nabil Gazal at a party in Sydney.
Speaking about the photos, Jacenko said there was more to the snaps than was published.
"You can read a lot in to three seconds of pictures," she said.
"We were stupid ... that's where it starts and that's where it stops. My marriage in my eyes had come to an end ... it had been a seriously tough 12 months ... [we were] drunk and stupid and mucking around."

Roxy Jacenko was papped kissing her ex-boyfriend, Nabil Gazal at a party in April. Picture: MatrixSource: Matrix Media GroupSource:Matrix Media Group
"The picture that shows two people was a picture that really in real terms should've shown 15 people at a party dancing to Ed Sheeran," she said.
"Ollie has seen them [the pictures]. He's not stupid.
"I have been candid all the way along as he has been with me.
"He didn't know if his marriage would survive. That's not just from the jail perspective, that's from the whole five years of the case and knowing that was at the back of his mind and what could happen."
Jacenko, who alongside her own business commitments is the digital fashion ambassador for Birkenhead Point's new high-end outlet precinct in Sydney, says her life has gone back to have normality - especially for her children.

Alongside running three business, and a mother-of-two, Roxy Jacenko is the digital fashion ambassador for Birkenhead Point's new high-end outlet precinct that opened earlier this week in Sydney.Source:Supplied
"My life [now] is completely different," she said.
"I went from being very depressed ... now, I am very focused on my work, my children are happy and I'm happy.
"I am calm, I'm collected, I'm not all over the place running everywhere to try and make myself happy.
"The chapter is closed. I'm now very focused on my work ... and I've got normality in my life."
If you or someone you know needs help, please contact Lifeline on 13 11 14.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Curtis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter, 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooma Correctional Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Sheeran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ollie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morning Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matrix Media Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MatrixSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kmart I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacenko</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birkenhead Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo Jeremy PiperSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matrix Media GroupSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morning Show/Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy Jacenko</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtis</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nabil Gazal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Evans.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
