<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435464012266713</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/gynaecologist-answers-all-the-sex-questions-youve-been-too-scared-to-ask/news-story/7b17cfa9806e2645bc30f589841474e2</url>
  <title>All the sex questions you can't ask</title>
  <content>
A GYNAECOLOGIST has revealed the answers to the most common questions about sex - specifically, seven questions women often ask about the potentially-unpleasant side effects.
Dr Alyssa Dweck, author of The Complete A to Z for your V, revealed everything you need to know about how to have better sex.
How do you avoid urinary tract infections?
Dr Dweck told Mail Online that this is one of the most common concerns among the women she sees, with over half of women likely to suffer a UTI at some point in their lifetime.
Caused by a bacterial infection in the urethra, UTIs are a relatively common side effect of having sex.
The uncomfortable symptoms of a UTI include intense pain in the lower back, pelvis or vagina, a constant urge to urinate, pain or difficulty urinating, and bloody or cloudy urine.
Among the other symptoms are fever, chills, shakiness and faintness.
But Dr Dweck has a couple of hacks to reduce your chances of contracting a UTI.
She said: "The myth really is true: urinate before and after sex. It's very, very helpful. Doing that naturally flushes the bacteria from the urethra."
Another tip is to stock up on cranberry juice or take supplements every day, since the fruit is a great natural defence against UTIs.
Dr Dweck explained: "It makes the bladder more slippery to bacteria, especially E.coli."
Can a penis be too big?
Dr Dweck says: "I love this question. If you think about how accommodating the vagina is, considering we have babies, it would be highly unlikely that a penis can be too big for a vagina.
"Even though penises come in all sizes, most erect penises are about the same size".
Why am I suddenly more dry than before?
Dr Dweck reckons that dryness, particularly in women going through the menopause, is one of her most common complaints.
Triggered as a result of hormonal changes, dryness can be overcome by using a vaginal cream - or, as obvious as it sounds, by using lubrication whenever you have sex.
Is period sex unhygienic?
According to the doctor, there's nothing wrong with period sex, provided you're both comfortable with it.
She said: "The infection risk would be if there's an inherent infection like HIV or hepatitis. If not, you're fine.
"The nice thing about period sex is that some women find that their libidos soar in that time. And orgasms may help with cramps.
"Alternatively, this could be a perfect opportunity for shower sex."
How can you beat bad smells in your private parts?
Since the vagina is designed to self-clean, you should be sparing with any products you use to keep it fresh.
Instead of intense scrubbing or using anything too fragrant, Dr Dweck encourages women to start taking vitamin D supplements, eating more probiotics and keeping hydrated.
It's also important to make sure you aren't smothering your privates, since they need some fresh air to work properly.
Is pool sex safe?
As fun as it may be, having sex in pools can cause problems if you don't react well to the chlorine.
Dr Dweck said: "In general, some women who have sex in very heavy chlorine pools do become quite irritated.
"There is a very real risk of infection to watch out for".
What is bacterial vaginosis and how do I treat it?
Caused by an imbalance in the vagina's natural bacteria, BV can bring about unpleasant symptoms including a bad smell, pain or discomfort.
A more serious impact of the condition is that it increases the risk of contracting STIs, diseases or other infections, which can be passed on the babies of pregnant BV sufferers.
To avoid it, Dr Dweck advises women to always use condoms and avoid sitting around in wet clothes after the gym or a shower, since this can affect their bacterial balance.
If you have BV, you can beat it by eating more probiotics, like yoghurts, and steering clear of carbohydrates and sugar.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mail Online</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BV</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Complete A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Dweck</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTIs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Z</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Alyssa Dweck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
