<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435678760633159</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836088/illawarra-wants-experts-property-council/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Illawarra wants experts to make decisions on development, not local politicians: Property Council</title>
  <content>
Property Council Illawarra regional director Kim Rawson.

The Property Council has released research indicating that the Illawarra community wants experts to make decisions on development, not local politicians.
- Kim Rawson
The Newgate Australia research claims that Illawarra councils rated poorly when it comes to assessing planning applications and being open and transparent, with their best performance found to be when providing services for the community.
The research surveyed 1300 homeowners across metropolitan Sydney, the Hunter and Illawarra regions.
"The research shows that the community supports experts making decisions on development decisions and would prefer councils stick to maintaining local roads, sporting facilities and providing community services," Property Council Illawarra regional director Kim Rawson said. 
"We need a system across the board where local councils set the strategic direction for their area and make the planning rules, and experts make the decision as to whether particular developments meet these rules.
"We already have some local council areas using planning panels to great effect in the Illawarra, but this system can be expanded to depoliticise the planning process and ensure we have experts making the decisions about our community's development."
According to the Property Council, 84 per cent of respondents from the Illawarra said they would prefer a panel of experts to make the decisions on local development projects worth $10-$20 million, rather than local politicians.
Also, 97 per cent of respondents think the planning panels should be formed from qualified experts; and 30 per cent rated their council performance as excellent/good.

"The Property Council has long supported the use of independent planning panels to stop the politics of planning and reduce the planning burden for councils," Ms Rawson said. "This can only be achieved if panels are mandatory and comprised of experts appointed on merit."

READ MORE: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newgate Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Rawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Council</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Council Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Rawson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
