<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435549911613503</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/opinion/opinion-time-to-get-rid-of-annastacia-palaszczuk-bill-shorten/news-story/36b4a3238991990bfd2319d49eb10338</url>
  <title>Dump Annastacia, then kill Bill</title>
  <content>
A FISH rots from the head down. So do governments.
The tumbling popularity of Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk is a signal Labor's hold on power in Queensland is coming to an end. I sincerely hope so.Blog with Des Houghton in the comments section below
A Galaxy poll conducted exclusively for The Sunday Mail confirms Palaszczuk has lost her way, with her , down eight points since the last poll.
The same opinion poll also showed support for Opposition Leader Tim Nicholls was slowly rising. Labor now clings to the narrowest margin on a two-party-preferred count.
One Nation, too, seems to be in decline, with Pauline Hanson's support leaking to the LNP.
Is it any surprise that the ALP is on the nose in Queensland?
Cabinet ministers have been sacked or stood aside. Labor has failed abysmally to curb soaring power prices in a state with some of the greatest coal reserves on earth. At the same time it brought in a costly and unachievable renewable energy target. You pay and pay while Labor panders to the Greens and strangles business.
Labor has snubbed its working class roots by surrendering power to union fat cats and effectively blocking state police investigations into union corruption.
There is another good reason why Labor will be defeated at the next state election. Voters will go to the polls before the federal election so they will be able to cast a vote of no confidence in federal Opposition Leader Bill Shorten's billion-dollar tax grab - and a host of populist social programs pandering to Aborigines, homosexuals and republicans.
Small businesses will be worse hit under Shorten's proposed tax grab. Small business is the backbone of the Queensland economy, and the state will suffer most if he becomes prime minister.
Shorten does not hide the fact that he plans to steal from the best performers to reward the underperformers. It is the same plan we have seen in Queensland with disastrous effects. Debt is soaring and jobs are harder to find. That's what happens when your policy is to strangle business.Don't tinker with the Constitution
FRANKLY I can't see the point of tinkering with the Australian Constitution to give special recognition to a select group, in this case aborigines.
Aborigines have the same legal protections as everyone else.
Why should they be singled out? In a multicultural society like ours, one should not be singled out on the basis of race, surely.
Aborigines make up a vital part of our national identity, but constitutional recognition would be only a token gesture doing zilch to assist the disadvantage suffered by some of our indigenous brothers and sisters.
And many Aborigines themselves oppose constitutional recognition. This is because they believe it will imply that they consent to being governed by what they regard as an illegitimate government.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Des Houghton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aborigines</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Tim Nicholls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annastacia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
