<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435506961940087</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/celebrities-fork-out-thousands-of-dollars-to-detox-and-starve-themselves-at-spas/news-story/831330be867b62f8fbd46197008ac125</url>
  <title>Celebrities fork out thousands of dollars to detox and starve themselves at spas</title>
  <content>
Gwyneth Paltrow Says She Doesn't Diet After Posting Restrictive Detox Plan
1:23

Gwyneth Paltrow has been caught with her foot in her mouth - over what she does and doesn't put in her mouth. The health enthusiast says she never restricts her diet, just days after releasing a strict detox plan.

January 13th 2016
2 years ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Alicia Silverstone is one of the many celebs who pays for detox. Picture: Frederick Brown

NY Post

Share

IF YOU can't detox like a celebrity, maybe it's best not to detox at all.
At a facility like We Care Spa in Desert Hot Springs, California, stars like Days of Our Lives actress Lisa Rinna, Clueless actress Alicia Silverstone, wrestler Brie Bella and How I Met Your Mother actor Josh Radnor pay top dollar to detoxify their bodies under the care of professionals.
"Weight loss, mental clarity, physical energy, improved focus, and attitude, renewed sense of motivation and purpose. I've never left We Care without feeling these things," Radnor claims on
"It reliably delivers what it promises. I also feel more centred in my heart, more spiritually aligned, and less prone to neurotic or anxiety-provoking thoughts. I've seen profound transformations in people who say yes to it, myself included."

How I Met Your Mother star Josh Radnor heads to the California spa. Picture: Neilson BarnardSource:Getty Images
Clients take yoga, relax and unplug while being restricted to an all-liquid diet consisting of vegetable juices, soups and "carefully designed therapeutic teas" for the duration of their stay, which can range anywhere three days to two weeks.
"We're providing them with nutrients they need to get through the day but it's all liquid," resort manager Dominic Chevalier told . "It doesn't require a lot of energy to process liquid which allows your body to focus on ridding yourself of toxins."
Premium accommodations, like a club room, can run up to $A8,702 for eight nights (which Chevalier says is the typical length of stay).

A post shared by Kaitlynn Carter (@kaitlynn) on

Most celebs gravitate toward larger rooms, he adds, where they can have their detox materials sent for their convenience.
"You're not going to find the Ritz Carlton," he said of the facility's bohemian desert vibe.

In addition to the detox program, which also features colonics and "digestive release" massages, the spa also offers traditional treatments like facials and body wraps.
"They're here for a combination of detox and weight loss," Chevalier said of their celebrity clientele, explaining that while weight loss isn't guaranteed, it's possible to lose 1.5kg in a week's stay.
"They're working very hard and it's kind of a way to get away from the hustle and bustle of L.A. or New York," he said.
Kristin Cavallari, who rose to fame on MTV's Laguna Beach and The Hills, is the latest celeb to sing the spa's praises on Instagram, claiming she's "feeling like a new woman" after her stay.

A post shared by Kristin Cavallari (@kristincavallari) on

A post shared by Kristin Cavallari (@kristincavallari) on

But despite her glowing review, some health professionals feel differently about the concept of detoxing.
"If the average person has a lot of money and wants to try this for three days, go for it," says nutritionist Brigitte Zeitlin, MPH, RD, CDN, but "in general, your body does not need to detox."
New York City based Zeitlin specialised in gastrointestinal disorders, diabetes, heart disease, sports nutrition, weight management and women's nutrition while working as a clinical dietitian at Mount Sinai Medical Center.
She describes detoxing as "completely unsustainable" for long-term weight loss and explained that juicing vegetables removes necessary fibre.
"Fibre is what keeps you full so you're not hungry for your next meal and it's what's keeping your gut healthy and what's moving things through," she said.
Hence We Care's inclusion of colonics, but for someone not under pricey professional care, restricting themselves to a liquid diet can result in bloat, constipation, and hunger, according to Zeitlin.
She says detoxing can work for "something specific, like three days before your friend's wedding, or three days before your someone's date to an award show something like that. That's where it has a place."
Which is why, according to Chevalier, We Care sees an uptick in celebrity clientele when award season rolls around.
"I have noticed personally that before awards programs some of the celebrities will come out here for a quick detox, maybe do some massages or something like that and then they'll finish with a day polish or a facial [so] they're ready to kind of go and hit the runway," Chevalier said.

Celebs like Alicia Silverstone typically head to the spa before red carpets. Picture: Jaime McCarthySource:AFP
Guests - who Chevalier says are mostly return customers - are following an individualised program, including a pre- and post-detox plan.
Before beginning the detox program, participants are advised to avoid grains, pasta, bread, meat, cheese, fish, dairy, processed food, caffeine, and alcohol.
After they've completed the program, guests are provided with supplements and information for an easy transition back into digesting solid food.
"[For] the average person, really what you're doing is throwing money away," Zeitlen said, explaining that "that as soon as you can eat real food, you're going to overeat, you're going to want everything," she said.
While celebrities may rely on detoxes to shed a few extra pounds, it costs a pretty penny to do it right.
originally appeared on The New York Post and has been republished here with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chevalier</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L.A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NY Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brigitte Zeitlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristin Cavallari</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gwyneth Paltrow Says She Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zeitlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zeitlen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desert Hot Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Days of Our</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care Spa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neilson BarnardSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominic Chevalier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ritz Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brie Bella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gwyneth Paltrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frederick Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Met Your Mother</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTV's Laguna Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Rinna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alicia Silverstone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaitlynn Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radnor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Radnor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime McCarthySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diet After Posting Restrictive Detox Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Sinai Medical Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cdn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
