<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435386702854600</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/private-sydney/george-and-amal-clooney-discover-the-cost-of-fame-after-the-birth-of-the-twins-20170802-gxnrdo.html</url>
  <title>George and Amal Clooney discover the cost of fame after the birth of the twins</title>
  <content>
When George Clooney came to Sydney in 2011, he was here for barely 24 hours, but it was certainly a lucrative trip - collecting a whopping $600,000 fee in return for giving an inspirational speech and posing for selfies with a few cashed-up fans.
Yep, fame has certainly paid off for Clooney, a man who generates millions of dollars in fees for spruiking coffee capsules and can command a $20 million salary to headline a major motion picture.Photo: Francois Mori
We have had ringside seats to his various relationships, played out in the public gaze as he was named the world's sexiest man alive, year after year.
Then we felt like guests at THAT wedding, which was pretty much a full-scale public event on the canals of Venice, complete with a flotilla of paparazzi in hot pursuit as the beaming couple waving regally to their adoring fans and smiled widely for the hundreds of cameras. Hello! and Woman's Day magazines paid about $1 million for the rights to cover the wedding.
And then, two months ago this picture-perfect, world-famous couple welcomed their first offspring to the world: twins.
Clooney issued a statement on June 6 announcing the news to the world's media but, uncharacteristically, Clooney has now gone all shy on the matter, keeping details of the new bubs secret, and intentionally keeping them far away from cameras.

There have been no glossy magazine spreads, a la Angelina Jolie and her brood, nor has an official portrait been released, as they do over at Buckingham Palace.
And yet the lack of information and imagery has only fuelled demand for both.

You will now receive updates from

Daily Life Newsletter

Daily Life Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

So it was French magazine Voici which became the first media outlet in the world to show images of little Ella and Alexander.
In the photos we see the Clooneys, and at some distance, enjoying the delights of the actor's Lake Como estate in Italy's Lombardy region. It appears they have no idea they are being photographed, safely ensconced in their walled compound, enjoying their most special of times.
Well, that was until Clooney saw those images on the front of Voici.
"Over the last week photographers from Voici magazine scaled our fence, climbed our tree and illegally took pictures of our infants inside our home," he said.
"Make no mistake the photographers, the agency and the magazine will be prosecuted to the full extent of the law.
"The safety of our children demands it."
Clooney was playing the role of protective father with aplomb, while the photos have not materialised in Australia and local editors are staying well clear of them in the post-Rebel Wilson legal victory era.
Voici has released its own statement attempting to defend its actions.
"George and Amal Clooney have been very public personalities for the last few years.
"Their wedding in Venice ... the pictures of them smiling to the public were seen all around the world.
"The birth of their twins, Ella and Alexander, had also been commented on a lot, by themselves and their families.
"The images published in Voici this Friday are a response to a public demand.
"Those pictures do not put in danger Mr Clooney, his wife or their kids."
While the Clooneys have long enjoyed the fruits of their fame, it is only now they have truly discovered exactly what price they come at.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venice</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebel Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Como</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woman's Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelina Jolie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ella</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voici</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clooney</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GEORGE CLOONEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francois Mori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Clooney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy's Lombardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amal Clooney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
