<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435034515533017</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/usain-bolt-runs-his-final-ever-100m-final/news-story/1f42959a1a60e1fabb9ca5a08157069f</url>
  <title>Usain Bolt's final race disaster</title>
  <content>
AMERICAN veteran Justin Gatlin was booed after he stunned Usain Bolt to win the 100m world title in London.
Gatlin, who served a doping ban between 2006-10 and won silvers behind Bolt at the last two world championships, clocked 9.92 seconds, with countryman Christian Coleman winning silver in 9.94 sec.
Bolt suffered a dreadful start and could only claim bronze in 9.95 seconds.
"I'm sorry I couldn't end it on a winning note, but I want to thank you for your support," said Bolt, who embraced Gatlin after they streaked through the line with no clear victor immediately apparent. It's been a wonderful experience as always."
Gatlin was afforded the same rough reception as he had in the heats and semi-finals, loud boos and jeering ringing around the same stadium where in 2012 his rivalry with Bolt was presented as "good against evil", given the American's doping-tainted past.
But Gatlin has form as the last man to beat Bolt over 100m - by a hundredth of a second in Rome in 2013 - and at the age of 35, can still produce the goods, something he has in the past ironically credited with his four years of forced exile from the track.
USAIN BOLTS INTO HISTORY
USAIN Bolt may have finished third in his final competitive 100m race, but he also carved out another slice of history.
His bronze medal, ironically his first ever at a major event, was his 14th medal at a World Championships. This tied him for most ever by a Jamaican athlete, joining Merlene Ottey.
Bolt still has the opportunity to claim the record on his own, when he compete in the 4 x 100m relay next week.

Usain Bolt did win his 14th World Championships medal (and 1st bronze), tying fellow Jamaican Merlene Ottey for the most by any athlete. 🇯🇲
'THE CHEAT' CONDEMNDED
Justin Gatlin's shock win in the Men's 100m final silenced the London Stadium, but not social media. Several fans came out to attack the American's triumph.

Re-100m, Bolt was beaten, problem I have is by someone banned for drugs. I think if you're a drugs cheat you shouldnt be back in the sport

Credit to Gatlin, running in a straight  line with that many drugs inside your body. Bolt GOAT.  ⚡️

Until cheats are ineligible for major championships forever as part of their ban, results like Gatlin's win will keep happening.

I would have accepted any winner but Justin Gatlin. But Bolt retires as a hero. Absolute hero.

Glad to hear the crowd BOOING Gatlin. Well deserved, you should never have been allowed to be compete in the first place.
The London crowd savaged the man who has served two bans for doping violations after his victory. The American was booed during his introduction, and when he was announced as the winner. The crowd even began a chant of 'Bolt' post-race. But Gatlin said he paid little attention to their taunts.
"The people who love me are here cheering for me, they're at home cheering," Gatlin said post-race. "My countrymen are cheering for me and that's what I've been focusing on."
BOLT'S ULTIMATE ACT OF CLASS
Usain Bolt showed his class in defeat, congratulating Gatlin and reassuring the American amid the crowds jeers.
"The first thing he said to me was congratulations," Gatlin told reporters. "He said, 'You don't deserve all these boos'. I thank him for inspiring me throughout my career and he's an amazing man.
Gatlin also showed respect to the man who will hang up the spikes following the championship's in London, bowing to Bolt on track post-race.
The American did not complete a victory lap following his unpopular victory - leaving the stage for the Jamaican hero to take his final bow, following his final competitive Men's 100m.

Gatlin leaves the track without a victory lap. As he should. No one wants to see a two time cheat take victory.
- with AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Gatlin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHEAT' CONDEMNDED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championships</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOOING Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merlene Ottey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Men's 100</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican Merlene Ottey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt GOAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOLT'S ULTIMATE ACT OF CLASS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USAIN BOLTS INTO HISTORY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
