<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435597156254081</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/university-through-to-ntru-grand-final-with-win-over-south-darwin/news-story/cacec4998765709b5a77fbc4ecb5f0f7</url>
  <title>Pirates crush Souths to claim grand final spot</title>
  <content>
University will play Casuarina in next week's NTRU grand final after the Pirates beat minor premiers South Darwin 32-12 at Rugby Park last night, sending them out in straight sets.
The match was either side's to win until the 70th minute when Isaac Taulelei crossed twice within four minutes.
Souths had an opportunity to level the scores at 15-15 with 16 minutes remaining, but winger Jake Rainger missed a penalty goal attempt and from there it was all Pirates.
Uni coach Hone Edwards said patience was the key to his side's victory.
"Souths are a good team and right through that first half we had to put a lot of pressure on them to get in front and it was 8-5 at half time," he said.
"At half time all we said was we had to keep doing what we did in the first half. We continued to put pressure on and we broke them."
Souths scored first when Rainger crossed in the right corner after a slick backline move.
The Pirates took the lead through a try to fullback Liam Walker and another at the start of the second half to fly-half Robbie Butcher.
Souths cut the margin to three when Setefano Cakau darted to the blindside and put Rainger over for his second.
However, from there Taulelei came to the fore.
The outside centre crossed underneath the posts to take the score out to 22-12, before sealing the match soon after.
Cutting back on the inside, Taulelei barnstormed his way through three Souths would-be tacklers to score. And then Joseph Tuhakaraina put the icing on the cake with a try on the bell.
Edwards said Taulelei's match-sealers came on the back of a strong platform laid by his teammates.
"When he comes through, he's coming with pace and the boys (allowed) him to do that. He really is the one that reaps the benefits from the team," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NTRU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac Taulelei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hone Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taulelei</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Butcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pirates</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Rainger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Setefano Cakau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rainger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Tuhakaraina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casuarina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
