<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435506961940035</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832971/spate-of-child-approaches-across-the-illawarra/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Spate of child approaches across the Illawarra</title>
  <content>
Police are investigating a spate of cases of men acting suspiciously around children and teenagers.

Police suspect one of them may be a repeat offender.
On Friday at 8.30am police said a six-year-old boy was approached in Oakland Avenue, Windang, by a man in his 40s.

He is described as 175cm and of medium build.
The incident was reported to police on Saturday.
A police spokesman said there were concerns the man may have been responsible for other reports of children being approached.
The spokesman said the man could be homeless or have a mental illness "but it still gives you cause for concerns when he's approaching children".
Also on Friday, four children aged between 12 and 16 reported a man in a car acting suspiciously near them.
The boys were fishing at the boat ramp near Charles Avenue when they spotted a white Barina hatchback sporting a white number plate with black lettering being driven by a man described as being of large build.
"No words were said but he went back and forwards past them slowly multiple times, which triggered a bit of suspicion from the young blokes," the police spokesman said.
"They left shortly after that and he drove past them again."
These latest cases follow on from an incident on Friday morning at Barrack Heights when a 17-year-old girl was approached by a man while on her way to school.

The girl was walking to school around 8.30am when the car pulled up alongside her in Keross Avenue. 
Police were told a man inside the red sedan, which had a black stripe down the driver's side and dark tinted windows, instructed her to get in. 
She declined and continued to school where she alerted staff and police were contacted.
The male is described as being aged in his 30s, with an olive complexion and wearing a grey jumper and sunglasses.
Anyone with information is urged to contact Lake Illawarra police on 42325599 or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
Meanwhile, police are searching for a man after a reported attempted abduction of a nine-year-old girl at netball courts in Wandella Road, Miranda.

A police spokesman said the girl was with her family when the man approached her at around 9am on Saturday.
"The man picked her up and began to carry her away, but the girl yelled out and broke free," the spokesman said.
"The girl told her father about the incident and police were alerted."

The girl was injured in the abduction attempt.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wandella Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakland Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miranda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keross Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrack Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barinas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
