<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435464012266657</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/acland-mine-new-hope-exploration-plans-jobs-uncertainty/8773584</url>
  <title>Acland coal mine expansion uncertainty leaves jobs in limbo</title>
  <content>
The company at the centre of one of Queensland's longest running mine disputes says time is running out for the people who rely on it for jobs, as activist groups question New Hope's exploration plans.
New Hope Group lost a court battle to expand its New Acland mine and the company warns job losses are inevitable when it runs out of coal next year.
"Currently we have approval within our budget process to mine through to mid-next year, unfortunately our reserves aren't very great post that point," the mine's maintenance manager Trent Knack said.
The Land Court ruled New Hope's $900 million stage three expansion should not go ahead due to the risk it posed to groundwater.

The decision on whether it goes ahead lies with the Queensland Government which has sought an extension until January, by which time an election could be held.
Mr Knack said it had been a decade-long battle to get the expansion approved.
"It is disappointing that we haven't been able to get a favourable outcome to this point in time but we are hopeful we can still get a favourable outcome and secure a future mining lease," he said.
The mine said it currently employs 300 locals, 160 contractors and contributes to 2,300 indirect jobs.
Local farmer Lyle Douglas has also worked at the New Acland mine for 14 years and is fed up with the uncertainly surrounding his future.
"It's not good, it plays havoc with a lot of people [but] I'm probably one of the lucky ones," he said.
"There are lots of fellows here who have mortgages, families they're trying to support."

Mr Douglas said he was one of 55 farmers who need to work at the mine as farming does not provide enough of an income.
He said he was sceptical of the mine, but the company's progressive rehabilitation changed his mind.
New Acland's environmental officer Tom Sheppard said once mined, the land is shaped back, top soiled, seeded, and fenced off.
It is then handed over to Acland Pastoral Company.
A trial with the University of Southern Queensland is underway to put cattle on recently rehabilitated mining land to monitor them and the land's health for future productivity.

When asked about the groundwater concerns raised in the court battle, Mr Sheppard said work was being done to fix that.
"We did have some shortfalls in the groundwater assessment under the ruling, however as part of our associated water licence requirements we're addressing those shortfalls," he said.
"There's been a lot more drilling done, there's been a lot more data capture and that's been put into updated modelling."
But Lock the Gate's Rick Humphries is not convinced and said looks can be deceiving when it comes to the rehabilitated land.
"It's going to take several decades to work out whether that grazing trial that they're conducting out there is actually going to deliver long-term sustainability," Mr Humphries said.

"New Hope admits in their EIS and their rehabilitation plan for stage three that they will not be able to return that cropping land to its pre-mining condition.
"The Land Court found the project shouldn't go ahead and the Government should accept that."
Claim Acland eyeing stage four expansion

An objector in the case, Darling Downs dairy farmer David Vonhoff, said the court win came as a huge relief.
"When you only have a small amount of top fertile country we should save that, we should look after it because the planet is expanding with people and they really need to be fed in the future," Mr Vonhoff said.
His property lies within sight of the mine and for the past decade he has fought the expansion, fearing for the security of his bore water.

"If it's far more than a metre draw down. We won't have any water for irrigating, to grow feed in the drought times for our cows," he said.
Mr Vonhoff fears the fight is not over yet, and believes the company has far greater plans.
"I've had information that there will be a stage four if stage three does go ahead," he said.
Lock the Gate echoes those fears.
"They've just granted 160,000 hectares of exploration licences to New Hope and New Hope isn't going to explore unless it intends to mine, should it find anything," Mr Humphries said.
Financial flow-on to nearby towns

The New Acland stage three expansion has been a divisive issue for the Darling Down's community and some residents in the nearby town of Oakey fear the impact if jobs start to go.
Butcher Tony James supports the mine because it supports his business.
"There's more people for it than there are against it," Mr James said.
He said many people would be severely impacted.
"I'd say there'll be a few more shut shops in town if that did actually happen."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Southern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sheppard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Land Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Hope</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Acland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyle Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Hope Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butcher Tony James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acland Pastoral Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Sheppard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gate's Rick Humphries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Downs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Hope's $900</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Knack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Knack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Vonhoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Humphries</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Vonhoff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
