<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435210609193617</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/more-sports/world-athletics-championships-twice-banned-justin-gatlin-makes-sure-usain-bolt-has-no-fairytale-ending/news-story/e90514a60f1f5de0c429fd51ce4d7db3</url>
  <title>Drug cheat proves the ultimate party pooper</title>
  <content>
IT doesn't get much worse than this.
BOLT UPSTAGED:
The greatest athlete the world has ever seen not only fails to win his final race but is beaten by a two-time drug cheat who epitomises everything that is bad with the sport.
While a bronze medal in his last 100m race won't in anyway impact on the legend of Usain Bolt, it's a dirty asterisk that unfortunately will haunt, not just him, but everyone who loves track and field.
In 10 years people will be saying, remember how good Usain Bolt was?
Unfortunately the answer will be now: "Yeah, but how about how he got beaten by that drug cheat in his last race."
Gatlin was busted for drugs in 2001 and served a one-year ban. Then in 2006 he tested positive again and was originally kicked out of the sport for eight years but had his sentence halved after an appeal.
There are many who believe drug cheats don't deserve second chances. That opinion is certainly going to get a lot more supporters after what happened at these championships.
Gatlin won the Olympic 100m gold medal at the Athens Games in 2004 and then took the sprint double at the 2005 world championships in Helsinki.
Twelve years later at the age of 35 he returned to claim the title of the fastest man on the planet.

Athletics: Justin Gatlin has defeated Usain Bolt in his last ever race.

'It's a moment for Usain'
It even hurts typing that sentence.
Bolt doesn't deserve to have his farewell party spoiled but sport doesn't always believe in fairytales.
Don't forget Muhammad Ali, who Bolt has often been compared to in terms of his reach across the globe, lost his last fight against Trevor Berbick.
Despite this unfortunate result, there will never be another athlete like Bolt.
No-one has come close to the world records he set when he was at his best throughout 2008 and 2009.
After announcing himself at the 2008 Beijing Olympics by winning three gold medals, the only time he's stumbled until Sunday morning (EST) was when he beat himself in the 2011 world championships final in Daegu.
Bolt false-started that night and was disqualified. He returned a couple of days later and won the 200m title.
A couple of times he has overcome ordinary preparations, finding ways to win when it mattered the most.
At the 2015 world championships in Beijing, he'd had a horrible preparation while Gatlin was on a 28-race unbeaten run yet Bolt got him in the final by .01sec.
It was a similar tale at last year's Rio Olympics with the world record holder battling injury and form issues. His response? Another three Olympic gold medals.

Athletics: Usain Bolt 'disappointed' with race.

Usain Bolt 'disappointed' with race
Gatlin's victory in Bolt's final race is a PR disaster on a number of fronts.
Bolt has saved the sport by being this shining light that people have loved while around him scandals have reduced athletics to its knees.
Despite everything that is bad such as the expulsion of Russia from competing at last year's Olympic Games and at these world championships because of doping, it was put aside because Bolt would win and entertain everyone.
This time he didn't win and it sucks.
Welcome to the new scary Bolt-less world of track and field.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOLT UPSTAGED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athens Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beijing Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt-less</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muhammad Ali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daegu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Berbick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helsinki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
