<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435592861286736</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/fremantle-dockers/fremantle-dockers-let-mccarthy-off-the-afl-leash-and-he-boots-four-20170806-gxq7e8.html</url>
  <title>Dockers let McCarthy off the AFL leash</title>
  <content>
Fremantle coach Ross Lyon hopes the extra freedom granted to forward Cameron McCarthy will pay off big time for the AFL club.
McCarthy booted 4.2 from 18 disposals in Saturday night's 12.18 (90)-10.7 (67) win over Gold Coast in Perth.Photo: AAP
It was McCarthy's biggest goal haul since crossing to Fremantle at the end of last season, and a positive step forward in what has been an otherwise tough season for him.
McCarthy had kicked just 19 goals in 16 matches before the win against Gold Coast.Photo: Tony McDonough
The former GWS forward has been allowed to roam further up the field over the past fortnight, and Lyon believes it is a tactic that will get the best out of him.
"We just freed him up a little bit," Lyon said of McCarthy, who missed all of last season with GWS while he dealt with personal issues.

"With Brennan Cox in the team and (David) Mundy and (Nat) Fyfe playing forward, it allows that to happen. It makes it more flexible.
"He's an incredibly good athlete - speed, endurance, and very mobile. Playing deeper probably doesn't suit him."
Another big positive to come out of the game for Fremantle was the form of defender Luke Ryan.
The 21-year-old tallied 28 disposals and took 16 marks playing as a loose man in defence.
Nine of his marks were intercept grabs - falling just one short of the all-time AFL record.
Ryan and Cox were dropped for a game last month after breaking the team's alcohol policy and Lyon has been pleased with how the pair have responded.
"It's important that once you challenge, you respond," Lyon said.
"If you don't respond, you're not worth being here. It's pretty simple for me.
"Those that don't respond, we basically move on. It was important both boys responded."
Lyon said his fledgling team's progress will be put to the test in Saturday's clash with Sydney at the SCG.
Brady Grey is set to miss the rest of the season with a hamstring injury.
Gold Coast have now lost five straight games, and were dealt another injury blow when midfielder Aaron Hall damaged his hamstring against the Dockers.
The Suns won the contested possessions 146-109, but their horrible disposal efficiency cost them dearly.
Gold Coast coach Rodney Eade, who faces an uphill battle to win a contract extension, conceded his team's turnovers cost them victory.
"There were a lot of times the players were out and we either visually didn't see them, or missed them by foot," Eade said.
"It's frustrating, but it's frustrating for the players who have worked hard to see the ball get rebounded the other way."
AAP 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony McDonough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fyfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brady Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brennan Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCarthy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
