<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435468307234069</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/a-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-tour-de-france-what-they-dont-prepare-you-for/news-story/9270adee4062074bc6ff246e0d01cdc7</url>
  <title>Never attack when it's time for 'Pause Pipi'</title>
  <content>
NEVER attack when a rival is having a bathroom break. Think viruses spreading quicker than a bushfire, inhaling cow poo and grown men fighting over cake. What you don't know about Le Tour.
SAM EDMUND on the eight things they don't tell you about the Tour de France.
1 GERMAPHOBIA
GO anywhere near a team bus or a rider for an interview and you'll get to know hand sanitiser very well.
By the third week of the Tour de France, the 22 teams are so paranoid about their guys getting sick they'll go to extreme lengths to avoid it. It's at this point that finishing becomes almost as important as winning.
Immune systems have been savaged and viruses spread quicker than a bushfire. These are athletes who spend five hours on a saddle every day on crowded French streets while inhaling everything from dust to cow poo particles, before shaking hands with backslappers at the finish line.

Team Sky is known to have nine washing machines - one for each rider - and an advanced party of clean freaks who go to hotels before the team checks in to wipe down everything from the light switches to the TV remote control.
Michael Matthews' Team Sunweb is one of several to bring their own mattresses and hypo-allergenic sheets in a bid to avoid sickness.
2 PUBLICITY CARAVAN
WHEN do you see grown men in a fist fight over a cake? When the Tour de France publicity caravan rolls through ahead of the race.
Started in 1930, this seemingly endless parade of freebie-flinging, tricked-up sponsor vehicles, more than 170 in all, has become an essential part of Le Tour.
This loud, multicoloured and multi-shaped procession lasts about 45 minutes from first vehicle to last and hands out more than 14 million items over three weeks. It is enormous and so ingrained in French culture that, regardless of age, roadside fans show off their plastic acquisitions like trophies.
A survey found 47 per cent of spectators come first and foremost for the caravan. No wonder they're frothing by the time the peloton comes past.
3 FINISH LINE SCRUM
THE running of the bulls isn't limited to Pamplona. A form of it takes place at the end of every stage of the Tour de France.
It's the media and fan scrum to speak to a rider or grab a selfie and 198 weary cyclists run straight into it after every finish.
This is a major sporting event with no turnstiles and no boundary line and from a journalist's perspective, you're often only limited by how you fast you can run after a bike.
Where football code interviews take place well after the final siren in sterile press conference settings, here the emotional is raw and real.
Security do an admirable job of restricting the hordes, but try holding back more than 1000 reporters desperate to know if Peter Sagan elbowed Mark Cavendish into the barriers at more than 50km/h.
4 THE SIZE
THE technical compound, or "Zone Technique", that lives behind the stage finish area is like a small town.
With more than 120 TV stations covering the event, about half of them live, you can get lost in this wire-laden labyrinth of broadcast trucks, generators and catering vehicles.
There's 70-odd radio stations, more than 550 accredited media organisations and 13,000 police mobilised for the duration of the race.
The estimated number of fans who line the roadside for three weeks is 10-12 million, making it the largest sporting event in the world.
Oh, and then they pick it all up and move it to another town. Over and over again for 21 days.
5 YOU GET GOOD AT EYE-SPY
NO matter how you choose to watch the Tour de France in-person, be prepared to spend a lot of time in the car.
Whether you drive the route and catch some of the action, or get straight to the finish line to soak up the atmosphere, more than 6500km - virtually the equivalent of Melbourne to Perth and back again - is likely to be showing on the odometer by the time you get to Paris.
There's traffic, road blocks, out-of-the-way detours, one-way streets and if you think it's hard to park at Chadstone, try getting one in a French village that's just had its population quadrupled.
6 BRAVERY
GET in the car, get the speedo up to 78km/h and jump out the window.
That's what Richie Porte did and he couldn't walk for a month after coming off his BMC on the Mont du Chat.
Of 198 riders, 31 failed to finish because of crash injuries or sickness. If Dan Martin is anything to go by, there would be many more soldiering on in discomfort. Martin suffered two fractured vertebrae in the crash with Porte.
They fly down alpine peaks at speeds nearing triple figures on an inch of rubber, tearing around bends with no guard rail where you can pay for a mistake with your life.
TV shows the select few fighting for a stage win or overall victory, but on the ground you get a ringside seat to suffering.
The vast majority of the bunch is just happy to live to fight another day, while others are battling to make the time cut. They are the men who have worked for their team leaders more earlier in the day or those who have crashed and are bleeding and grimacing their way to the line.
7 PEAK HOURS
THINK huge game at the MCG, but just one Punt Road lane is open and it's the only road home.
The mountain stages of the Tour de France are epic for everyone - the riders, the organisers, the fans and the world's media.

As the Tour de France nears the finish line in Paris, fatigue and general confusion have firmly set in. WSJ's Joshua Robinson quizzed riders, coaches and reporters for a little reality check.

Tour de France: Do You Know What Day It Is?
But unlike cycling, driving down France's most fearsome peaks is more problematic than getting up them. The roads are initially blocked so riders and teams can get back off the mountain first and start their recovery. Then the tedious battle begins to get a frightening amount of infrastructure down the hill.
Be prepared for a long wait, unless you can get on the back of a Gendarmerie convoy screaming down the mountain on the wrong side of the road.
8 WHEN NATURE CALLS
IF YOU suffer from stage fright you would never make it as a Tour de France rider.
One of cycling's unwritten rules is that you never attack when it's time for "Pause Pipi" - the scheduled loo break on the side of the road.
While there are times when riders have to relieve themselves on the run, there's always a mass stop at some point in a stage.
One minute the peloton is flying through the French countryside and the next, it's exit stage left and right for to answer nature's call.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GET GOOD AT EYE-SPY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATURE CALLS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gendarmerie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Tour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pamplona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FINISH LINE SCRUM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Know What Day It Is</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Cavendish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Sagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAM EDMUND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSJ's Joshua Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PUBLICITY CARAVAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GERMAPHOBIA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punt Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pipi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PEAK HOURS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Matthews' Team Sunweb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pause Pipi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zone Technique</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richie Porte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
