<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435425357560572</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/sa-wild-weather-to-continue/8778862</url>
  <title>Sandbags on offer as South Australia's wild winter weekend continues</title>
  <content>
External Link:

WOW!! Amazing scenes at Port Lincoln in South Australia tonight as the powerful front hit! Just a little bit of water! Via Port Lincoln Hockey Association.

Related Story:

Adelaide has dodged the brunt of wild weather overnight but a severe weather warning remains in place for parts of South Australia, with wind gusts of up to 120 kilometres per hour possible.
Heavy weather hit the state's west on Saturday but the capital city did not get battered
Between midnight and 8:30am the SES responded to just nine calls, although it had responded to more than 60 in the 24 hours to 8:30am.
Bureau of Meteorology senior forecaster Tom Boeck said wind gusts of up to 90 kilometres per hour were possible in the morning as an intense low-pressure system moved across the state.
"It covers much of the agricultural area of South Australia for the potential for some damaging winds and again, they look like being peaking towards the later part of the morning and into the afternoon as the low-pressure system moves closer to South Australia," he said.
The bureau said wind gusts will increase to 120kph and extend northwards during the late morning or afternoon, while damaging winds averaging between 55 to 65kph will develop near coasts and over elevated ground.

SES offering sandbags at:

Hoods Rd Northfield
Cnr Lindsay and Brian rds Lonsdale
Beagle St Lynton
Montecute Rd Campbelltown
Simper Cres Mt Barker
Willochra St Largs North(10am-2pm on Sunday)

All ferry services between Kangaroo Island and Cape Jervis have been cancelled.
Mr Boeck said flash flooding could occur in the Mount Lofty Ranges.
"Rainfall totals through that area could peak in the sort of 30 to 60 millimetre mark by the time we get to the end of the day," he said.
Sandbags are on offer at six SES units in Adelaide and Mount Barker.
The blustery and wet conditions are expected to have a strong impact on the Showdown between local AFL rivals the
Tens of thousands of people are expected to arrive anyway and the bureau warned spectators to expect cool conditions and bring wet weather gear.
The wild weather is expected to clear by Monday.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cnr Lindsay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoods Rd Northfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Lincoln Hockey Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Lincoln</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Lofty Ranges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willochra St Largs North(10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonsdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Boeck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beagle St Lynton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Boeck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montecute Rd Campbelltown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cres Mt Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Jervis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
