<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435635810959941</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/this-week-in-finance/8775908</url>
  <title>This week in finance: CBA record profit to be overshadowed by money laundering scandal</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

In normal circumstances another record full-year profit from the Commonwealth Bank, getting on towards $10 billion would grab the headlines. Not this year.

Markets on Friday's close:

ASX SPI 200 futures +0.4pc at 5,684, ASX 200 [Friday's close] -0.3pc at 5,720
AUD: 79.22 US cents, 67.27 euro cents, 60.76 British pence, 87.75 Japanese yen, $NZ1.07
US: Dow Jones +0.3pc at 22,093, S&P500 +0.2 at 2,477 NASDAQ +0.2 at 6,352
Europe: FTSE +0.5pc at 7,511 DAX +1.2pc at 12,297 Eurostoxx50 +1.2pc at 3,507
Commodities: Brent oil +0.8pc at $US52.42/barrel, Gold -0.8pc at $US1,259/ounce, Iron ore [Nymex] +1.1pc at $US74.21/tonne

What will be by far the largest profit of the August results season has all of a sudden become tainted by yet another CBA scandal, this time involving Austrac, the federal agency policing breaches of money laundering and terrorist funding laws.
As regulatory and policing issues go, it doesn't get much more serious than that for banks.
The results announcement on Wednesday will be a testy affair.
The influential analyst brigade from the big broking houses, feeling duded and blind-sided, will no doubt demand answers .
Most already had the CBA at the bottom of their list of investment preferences of the Big Four banks, given it has the most work to do to meet APRA's demands on building an "unquestionably strong" capital buffer.
The consensus view is to be underweight on CBA, a view that no doubt will further sour when the next spate of broker reserach drops.
CBA boss Ian Narev may well trot out the old "We take out obligations very seriously...we are fully cooperating ... beyond that we can't comment as the matter is subject of on-going investigations" routine, but it is hard to see how that will cut it.
A potential near-trillion-dollar liability in the form of a cumulative penalty for 53,700 at $18 million a pop for breaches of anti-money laundering and terrorism financing laws looks fairly "material", even to the most casual observer.
OK maybe not $1 trillion, what is the precedent?

No one seriously believes the CBA would - or could - be forced to pay that, although one could imagine Treasurer Scott Morrison for a fleeting moment thinking a fine like that flowing into consolidated revenue would fix his deficit problems, plus a bit more.
So how much trouble is the CBA in? and is perhaps the best precedent nervous directors, directors' insurers and shareholders can draw upon.
Tabcorp fessed up to 109 breaches, or about 0.2 per cent of CBA's staggering rap sheet.
One of the most scurrilous breaches Austrac pointed to in its statement of claim against Tabcorp was failure to notify a dubious $100,000 payout.
The more "colourful" client base of CBA's Intelligent Deposit Machines seemed to dealing in vast multiples of that and  probably could provide several series - not just episodes - of a true life crime TV pot-boiler.
"My Beautiful CBA Laundrette", perhaps.
Tabcorp bargained its fine down to $45 million - a 98 per cent discount - although .
Lawyers, it seems, do not to hand out the same bulk discounts on offer from Austrac and the Federal Court.
Not that these things are necessarily linear, applying the Tabcorp discount to the CBA's alleged crimes - and assuming Austrac nails the case - the figure comes in at $22 billion, give or take a billion.
CBA's market capitalisation at last count? $140 billion. And the analysts think the bank has a problem with its current capital base.
Another record CBA profit forecast

For the record, the consensus tip is the CBA will post a $9.8-billion profit, with a small increase in dividend for fraught shareholders.
While the bank's margins may benefit from the  on investor loans, increased competition may offset that to a degree.
One area where analysts agree CBA still enjoys a significant advantage is over its peers is its ability to attract deposits.
But then again, the CBA has Intelligent Deposit Machines, or Instruments of Depositor Misconduct as they may become to be known.
The other results of interest this week include AGL [Thursday] which should see its handy $700-million profit from last year boosted again by higher energy prices, while AMP [Thursday] drops interim numbers with its struggling life insurance business once again the focus.
Despite some optimism, the big results of the first week were a bit disappointing.
forecast. , Tabcorp and Crown Resorts hardly shot the lights out either.
The market will be hoping for something better this week.
Wall Street gains on positive jobs news

The market should enjoy a positive start to the week - futures point to a 0.4 per cent lift - given a solid lead by Wall Street.
The blue chip Dow Jones index chalked up its eighth straight record close on Friday, led by the banks.
New jobs - up another 209,000 - were better than expected and there were upward revisions to previous months as well, but the highlight was solid rise in wages.
July saw the biggest jump in wages for five months, lifting annualised wage growth to 2.5 per cent, while unemployment fell to 4.3 per cent.
That boosted the chances of another rate hike from the Federal Reserve this year to a 50-50 bet, and shortened the odds the Fed will start shrinking its bloated $US4.2 trillion bond portfolio as early as next month.
The main interest for Fed watchers this week will be US inflation on Friday.
Energy should drop out of the equation as a significant factor, while rents and phone charges have been falling. Nonetheless the forecast is for another step up inflation to 1.8 per cent for both headline and core readings, well on the way towards the Fed's target of 2 per cent growth in the next month or so.
RBA governor fronts parliamentary committee

Locally, RBA watchers have booked their seats for governor Philip Lowe's biannual testimony to the House Economics Committee in Melbourne on Friday.
Dr Lowe will undoubtedly maintain his upbeat view of economic growth. His discomfort with slow wage growth and a high Australian dollar are well known and will probably get another airing.
Despite all that, the RBA is stuck in neutral and not going anywhere rate-wise for some time.
Given one of the RBA's important responsibilities is Australia's financial stability and Dr Lowe chairs the Council of Financial Regulators, a question or two about the CBA wouldn't be out of order and could make for quite interesting listening.
Australia

DateEventForecast

Monday
7/8/17Job adsJul: ANZ series, has been solid
Construction indexJul: AiG index showing expanding activity

Tuesday
8/8/17Business surveyJul: NAB series on confidence and conditions, both solid

Wednesday
9/8/17Consumer confidenceAug: Westpac series, pessimism trumps optimism
RBA speechAsst governor for financial markets Christopher Kent speaks
Home loansJun: APRA & RBA will be hoping for a slowdown in investment lending

Thursday
10/8/17

Friday
11/8/17RBA testimonyGovernor Lowe biannual meeting with house economics committee in Melbourne
Corporate

DateEventForecast

Monday
7/8/17

Tuesday
8/8/17Transurban FY resultsProfit should creep up to $290m, no change to guidance
Scentre FY resultsGuidance for the former Westfield business is a +8pc profit rise, but has a history of beating its own forecasts
IOOF  FY resultsProfit forecast to slip from $174m last year to $160m. Margins and guidance important

Wednesday
9/8/17CBA FY resultsNormally a record profit approaching $10bn would be the headline, but the AUSTRAC scandal will be the focus
Carsales FY resultsProfit should be up around $120m, but car sales have been weaker

Thursday
10/8/17AGL FY resultsProfit could be up more than 10pc to $790 boosted by higher energy prices
AMP  interim resultHalf-year profit may slip. Focus will be on troubled life insurance business
Orora FY resultSolid result with profit up 7pc to $180m forecast
Magellan Financial FY resultFlat profit around $195m expected along with updates on new investment funds

Friday
11/8/17News Corp FY resultQ3 surprised, so a profit increase around 40pc to $US250 on the cards
REA FY resultA solid result with $240m profit & higher dividend expected. Update on US investment.
NAB Q3 updateIt will post a handy number and be asked a lot of questions about money laundering. Thanks CBA.
Overseas

DateEventForecast

Monday
7/8/17CH: Foreign reservesJul: Holding back above $US3tn
US: Consumer creditJun: May pull back
OPEC: Meeting2-day meeting in Abu Dhabi discussion production cut compliance

Tuesday
8/8/17CH: Trade balanceJul: Both exports and imports have been strong, Surplus around $US45bn
US: Small business optimismJul: Positive

Wednesday
9/8/17CH: InflationJul: readings of consumer and producer inflation

Thursday
10/8/17NZ: RBNZ rate decisionHold at 1.75pc
CH: New loansJul: Another tightening of credit expected
US: Monthly budget statementJul: Currently running a big deficit around $US90bn

Friday
11/8/17US: InflationJul: Still stuck below 2pc

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scentre FY resultsGuidance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA testimonyGovernor Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ch</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA speechAsst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trade balanceJul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold -0.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign reservesJul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX SPI 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lowe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Four</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US4.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Economics Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US52.42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beautiful CBA Laundrette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban FY resultsProfit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>resultHalf-year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer confidenceAug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX +1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA FY resultsNormally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB Q3 updateIt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New loansJul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business surveyJul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD: 79.22 US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APRA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Job adsJul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nymex] +1.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magellan Financial FY resultFlat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBNZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer creditJun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>loansJun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp FY resultQ3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council of Financial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>statementJul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 (  ): +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orora FY resultSolid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA's Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ1.07</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carsales FY resultsProfit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>InflationJul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REA FY resultA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eurostoxx50 +1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>indexJul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones +0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>optimismJul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74.21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>decisionHold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY resultsProfit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instruments of Depositor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DateEventForecast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE +0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL FY resultsProfit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OPEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1,259</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IOOF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
