<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434952911153739</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/our-waterways-have-always-been-a-drawcard/3208728/</url>
  <title>Our waterways have always been a drawcard</title>
  <content>
FROM the impressive hinterland waterfalls to the string of sparkling beaches, there is no doubt water is one of the key attractions of the Sunshine Coast.
Local residents and visitors alike can enjoy the rolling surf or smooth water, bathing in the region's many pools and streams.
Fishing from the ocean beaches or in one of our many creeks and lakes provides an opportunity to relax and unwind.
There are also many opportunities to enjoy a wide variety of water sports or simply enjoy one of the many picturesque views of water as a feature in the landscape.
A look back in time reveals the important role the coast and rivers have played in the early growth and development of the Sunshine Coast region and how widely they continue to be used for recreation, transport and economic purposes.
Several of the region's larger towns are located at rivermouths.
Maroochydore is located on the beautiful Maroochy River, Mooloolaba on the Mooloolah River and Caloundra is located at the junction of the Pumicestone Passage and the open ocean of the Coral Sea.
Early records show that from the beginning of European settlement, rivers were fundamental to the development of the region.
They served as "transport highways" and were the site of many valuable stands of timber, including the prized red cedar.
By the mid-1860s, timber-getting was big business. It started in coastal areas near rivers and moved inland as reserves of timber became depleted.
The rivers provided both a means of access to timber resources and the most efficient means of transporting timber - rafting it downstream from the logging areas.
Brisbane sawmiller William Pettigrew established a timber depot near the mouth of the Mooloolah River in 1865 and a depot and sawmill on the Maroochy River at Maroochydore.
The mill began operation in 1891 but the depot at the Mooloolah River eventually failed because of a lack of timber supplies and the Maroochydore mill closed in 1903.
While the importance of the timber industry declined, the ports and small settlements that had developed at the rivermouths made it possible for holidaymakers to visit and by the late 1880s their potential as resorts was recognised.
Caloundra had not been a transport base for servicing the timber industry but the sheltered waterway of the Pumicestone Passage developed as a thoroughfare for boats shipping provisions from Brisbane to Caloundra, as well as passenger steamers serving resorts at Redcliffe and Bribie Island.
Many people preferred to travel north from Brisbane using the coastal steamers as road access into the Coast region remained very difficult until well into the inter-war period.
The opening of the North Coast Railway in 1891 attracted more visitors to the area but because road access to the coastal beaches remained poor, the rivers continued to play an important role in providing a link between the inland towns with railway stations and the coastal resorts.
Many daytrippers and holidaymakers travelled by boat down the Maroochy River to Cotton Tree. Some came via Yandina and some by tram from Nambour to Deepwater in Petrie Creek, where they then boarded boats.
For settlers living along the riverbank the waterway continued to provide a vital link, bringing supplies and transporting agricultural produce destined for Brisbane.
This was a time when few people could swim, so the emphasis was on safe bathing locations. The sheltered waters of the Maroochy River and the Pumicestone Passage were ideal spots and the wide expanse of calm water at Cotton Tree, inside the bar in the Maroochy River, was very popular - as it is today.
Like Maroochydore, the development of Mooloolaba as a resort at the mouth of the Mooloolah River reflected a preference for swimming in the sheltered river.
The surf beach beckoned the more adventurous.
Early tourist brochures provide interesting descriptions of the rivers as "a fisherman's paradise" with their hire boats and the many good fishing spots abounding in cod, bream, flathead, whiting and tailor.
They also highlight the attractive walks along the river, the calm creeks and lakes for swimming, the safe rockpools abounding with marine life and the wooded foreshores that made an ideal picnic ground.
In the hinterland, the deep gorges on the steep slopes of the Blackall Range meant the presence of numerous waterfalls and picturesque streams and it was those water features, along with the panoramic views of the coastline, that early guest houses promoted.
In more recent times several key dams built during the period from the late 1950s to 1989 have not only provided valuable supplies of water but also became tourist destinations, offering recreation and camping areas, walking tracks and spectacular water views.
By taking a glance back it becomes evident that the Sunshine Coast's waterways and coastal areas have always been a magnet drawing people to the area for various reasons.
Thanks to Sunshine Coast Council's Heritage Library Officers for the words and Picture Sunshine Coast for the images.
RESPONSIBILITY Theory is helping young students shine.
How the Black Widow was caught
Palmer is shifting his treasures as liquidators circle his assets
Residents reeling after tragic crash on Saturday motorbike ride
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Picture Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bribie Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Pettigrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Widow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coral Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redcliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackall Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolah River</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Coast Railway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pumicestone Passage</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council's Heritage Library Officers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
