<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435399587756572</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:54</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/trump-praises-sessions-for-cracking-down-on-leaks-following-weeks-of-public-criticism-2017-8</url>
  <title>Trump praises Sessions for cracking down on leaks, following weeks of public criticism</title>
  <content>
President Donald Trump on Saturday offered up praise of Attorney General Jeff Sessions, whom he has publicly criticised for weeks.

"After many years of LEAKS going on in Washington, it is great to see the A.G. taking action! For National Security, the tougher the better!" .

the previous day announcing new steps to investigate and prosecute those who leak classified information. His remarks garnered backlash from press freedom groups after he said the Department of Justice will review its policies regarding media subpoenas.

"We respect the important role that the press plays and will give them respect, but it is not unlimited," Sessions said. "They cannot place lives at risk with impunity. We must balance their role with protecting our national security and the lives of those who serve in our intelligence community, the armed forces, and all law-abiding Americans."

Trump's praise on Saturday came after he fiercely criticised Sessions' decision to recuse himself from the Russia investigation, even publicly saying he would never have appointed Sessions as Attorney General had he known Sessions would recuse himself.

Trump had not announced plans to fire Sessions, however, and Sessions himself said he planned to remain in the job "as long as that is appropriate."

In a series of tweets sent late Saturday afternoon, Trump also insisted he's not on vacation, even as  on Instagram.

"Working in Bedminster, N.J., as long planned construction is being done at the White House. This is not a vacation - meetings and calls!" he .

Trump also praised the United Nations Security Council, which voted earlier that day to  that could cut by one-third the country's annual $US3 billion export revenue. North Korea had tested two intercontinental ballistic missile tests in July.

The United Nations Security Council just voted 15-0 to sanction North Korea. China and Russia voted with us. Very big financial impact!
- Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump)

United Nations Resolution is the single largest economic sanctions package ever on North Korea. Over one billion dollars in cost to N.K.
- Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Resolution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N.K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N.J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General Jeff Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald J. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Security Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>realDonaldTrump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
