<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435421062593218</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/storm-chaser-kylie-gee-began-indigo-storm-photograph-as-a-hobby/news-story/bf6ac14a3fda29a792ce7f487ab559ff</url>
  <title>Chasing the perfect storm</title>
  <content>
SPARE a thought for Kylie Gee next time you're scared, peering out the narrow crack in the curtains at the barrage of hail and lightning crashing down from the sky.
And next time you run, shoes slipping, brolly twisting, arms pumping to escape the wild wet and wind of a summer storm.
Because in those moments, perched perilously, or perfectly, in exactly the right spot, Gee is about to capture some of nature's greatest performances.
She is a weather photographer, or "storm chaser".
A storm chaser is someone she describes as "passionate about weather and will drive thousands of kilometres to see it."
"I'm the mad woman who stands out in the middle of the paddock in a storm with a camera," she said tongue-in-cheek.
When pressed on why she does it, Gee claimed each photograph was her chance to capture the beauty of the moment.
"And I'm always looking for the perfect shot," she said. Something she admitted she hadn't found yet.
Many storm chasers do it for the adrenaline, the danger.
Not Gee.
"I am very much safety first. It's all about calculated risks, relying predominantly on radar information," she said. "A good chase is a safe chase."
"There have been a couple of occasions where lightning has struck a bit too close for comfort and it definitely put the wind up me a little bit."
But at the end of the day, Gee said no photo was worth her life.
Her business - Indigo Storm Photography - started as a hobby, but has since morphed into a passionate business venture that earned her a spot as one of only 12 Australian photographers featured in the 2017 Bureau of Meteorology calendar.
Based in the Wheatbelt, Gee loves the colours, landscapes, and breathtaking scenery that the Pilbara, Karijini and the Gascoyne regions offer in what she calls "a magical part of the world".
Right now, she is gearing up for a storm season- generally October to April - which she hopes will be much better than 2016.
"Last season was a real dud. We live close to the train station and it got to the point where I'd hear the trains rattle through and run out in the hope it was thunder," she laughed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Gee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gascoyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wheatbelt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karijini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigo Storm Photography</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gee</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
