<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435429652527955</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/18-year-old-woman-hospitalised-after-car-surfing-m/3209230/</url>
  <title>18-year-old woman hospitalised after car surfing mishap</title>
  <content>
AN EIGHTEEN-year-old woman has been taken to hospital after a 'car surfing' mishap.
Police and ambulance officers were called to Fred Chaplin Cct at Bells Creek at about 10.45pm last night after the teenager fell from a moving vehicle.
Reports to police were that the woman had fallen from a ute and suffered a number of injuries.
A Queensland Ambulance Service spokesman said the young woman had been on a bike which was tied down to the tray of a ute.
The spokesman said the ute had been travelling at about 60km/h when she fell off, suffering head and shoulder injuries.
She was taken to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital in a stable condition.
DAILY'S historical books are stirring up memories.
RESPONSIBILITY Theory is helping young students shine.
RIVERS were fundamental to the development of the region.
Residents reeling after tragic crash on Saturday motorbike ride
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred Chaplin Cct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bells Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
