<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435549911613498</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/entertainment/books/tex-review-tex-perkins-lays-out-the-riffs-of-a-longtime-rocknroller-20170731-gxm6kj.html</url>
  <title>Tex review: Tex Perkins lays out the riffs of a longtime rock'n'roller</title>
  <content>
TexPhoto: Supplied
MEMOIR
Tex
Tex Perkins with Stuart Coupe
Macmillan, $34.99
It's a long way to the top, we're often told. The beautiful part of the rock and roll game, though, is how short that first step from nowhere to spotlight. Substitute the AC/DC-sized ambition with a solid work ethic and a healthy sense of humour and life is a lark.
That's the artless moral of Gregory "Tex" Perkins' easily digestible memoir of a life in countless bands spanning nearly 40 years, from a Queensland Uni one-night stand with a "completely ridiculous shamble" called Corpse of Christ to the venerable ilk of the Cruel Sea and the Beasts of Bourbon.

"There's a difference between scratching your arse and ripping it to shreds," the rock philosopher notes after 60-odd bite-sized, episodic memories big on belly laughs and very light on anguish.
It's telling that the most gleeful hail from the pre-fame pits of Sydney's mid '80s squat scene. "If there were three people in a room together you'd make a band," he recalls. "I was in The Bush Oysters, Thug, The Poofters, Toilet Duck, The Bumhead Orchestra ..." and so on.
Conversely, the closest he gets to existential crisis is backstage in New York in '93, a prince of the Australian underground schmoozing in the elite grunge circle of Nirvana, Sonic Youth and the Red Hot Chilli Peppers. "I'd never felt more like a jerk-off B-grader in my life," he writes, cold sweat still prickling.
With similar apparent perversity, he glorifies the filth and fury of the sordid Beasts gig that landed him in hospital in 1997, while recalling the heebie-jeebies of his ARIA-winning peak with the Cruel Sea, and the suffocating victory of his perennial Johnny Cash show, The Man In Black.
Not that he's complaining. With the love of an "astonishing" woman and a growing sprawl of kids and animals running amok on his Byron Shire property, he exudes the gratitude of an underachieving Catholic boys' school dropout blessed with spectacular good fortune.
Even the most tragic of missteps are spun for comedy, from his spiteful, career-jeopardising contractual obligation album with the Ladyboyz to the permanent injury sustained falling down the stairs of a first-class cabin on an alcohol-hazed flight to Europe.
More dirt? Well, there's too much respect for family for anything really lurid ("Mum, you've already read too much," reads the opening inscription), and substance abuse hangs permanently, unapologetically in the air rather than big-noting itself Motley Crue-style.
There are somewhat revealing chapters on best buddy Tim Rogers and that legendary, blood-soaked night at the ARIAs, and frank opinions about select individuals, from occasional touring companions the Rolling Stones and P.J. Proby to that "dweeb from Universal" who ... well, he'll know who he is.
Equally entertaining are his potted asides about rap, football, Iggy Pop, interviews and his not entirely predictable tastes in music (loves Coldplay, hates Meat Loaf). Despite the ghostly presence of veteran rock journo Stuart Coupe, it all comes through in the eloquently sweary, faultlessly self-effacing voice that every fan will recognise as unrepentantly Tex.
"If, as they say, a change is as good a holiday, then I'm on permanent vacation," Australia's jack of all bands concludes contentedly. It might be a fair way from the top, but it sounds like a blessed place to be.
Tex Perkins is a guest at this weekend's Byron Bay Writers Festival and Melbourne Writers Festival.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meat Loaf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladyboyz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Coupe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P.J. Proby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bush Oysters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hot Chilli Peppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tex</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonic Youth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-graders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nirvana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bumhead Orchestra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Uni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay Writers Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corpse of Christ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macmillan, $34.99</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beasts of Bourbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Cash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toilet Duck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Shire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tex Perkins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Rogers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man In Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coldplay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cruel Sea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iggy Pop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TexPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Writers' Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rolling Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIA-winning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Motley Crue-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AC/DC-sized</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
