<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435549911613492</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/entertainment/2017/08/06/10/14/adele-surprises-young-grenfell-tower-survivors-with-movie-screening</url>
  <title>Adele surprises young Grenfell Tower survivors with movie screening</title>
  <content>
Pop star Adele has treated the young survivors of the Grenfell Tower fire to a special movie night in London.
Photos of the 29-year-old singer emerged online on Saturday, showing her and the grinning children she invited to the event.
The Hello singer hosted the screening of Despicable Me 3 at the Whiteley's cinema in Queensway, London, and organised for life-sized Minions to attend as a surprise for the children.
It is not the first time Adele has shown her support for those affected by the fire.
She was spotted volunteering her time at the site of the disaster in the immediate aftermath of the fire and has donated her time several times since.
Last week, she was spotted helping disadvantaged children at a local learning centre close to the Grenfell Tower.

Related Articles

She has raised hundreds of thousands of dollars for the victims, and earlier dropped by a local fire station to show her support for first responders.
Adele cancelled the final two dates of her 123-show world tour last month, but not before asking people to donate to the victims of the fire.
"I've been down to Grenfell Tower. They are being neglected now," she told fans at her first show in Wembley.
"I promise any money that we raise will get to them. I am not leaving them.
"I'm involved now. I'll be banging on for this for days, weeks, months and years. I want everyone to donate.
"I didn't have a social conscience that long ago. You can grow one. I grew one. It comes with age."
The next day she told her second Wembley crowd that her fans had helped her raise more than A$165,000.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wembley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Despicable Me 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grenfell Tower</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whiteley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
