<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435468307234084</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/obituaries/robert-hardy-portrayed-churchill-and-vet-in-all-creatures-great-and-small-20170804-gxpias.html</url>
  <title>Robert Hardy portrayed Churchill and vet in All Creatures Great and Small </title>
  <content>
Robert Hardy, the actor, who has died aged 91, could claim a fine record of television performances spanning more than 40 years, ranging from several portrayals of Winston Churchill to that of the peppery vet Siegfried Farnon in the popular 1980s series All Creatures Great and Small.
Hardy's acting was many-faceted, energetic, and - like the English climate - subject to sunshine, small storms and changeable moods. It was said that, in his wide range of character roles, he was to British television between 1960 and 1980 what Alec Guinness was to British cinema in the 1940s.Photo: AP
He could be darkly overcast and this attribute, together with a certain physical likeness, suited him for the Churchill role which, in various television, stage and film productions, he filled no fewer than seven times. Of these, perhaps the most memorable was his portrayal of the great man in Winston Churchill: The Wilderness Years (1981).
Though he showed early talent at the Old Vic in the 1950s, playing roles ranging from Laertes in Hamlet to Ariel in The Tempest, he failed to progress to the National Theatre owing, he said, to a disagreement with Peter Hall. Photo: Australian Broadcasting Corporation
While maintaining a firm foothold in the theatre, Hardy also turned to television, starring as Henry V in the Shakespearean series An Age of Kings (1960), Leicester in Elizabeth R (1970), and Prince Albert in Edward VII (1975).
But it was as the country vet Siegfried Farnon in All Creatures Great and Small (1978-1990) that Hardy secured his lasting place in England's affections. At Skeldale House in the fictional North Riding town of Darrowby (Askrigg in reality), the flamboyant Farnon and his easygoing brother Tristan (Peter Davison) built up a large rural practice, tending to the needs of farm animals and pets amid the Yorkshire dales in the late 1930s.

Hardy typified a versatile, sensitive, sometimes tumultuous man of action among the rough-hewn farmers and their assorted animals. Based on the popular books by James Herriot, and rich in its nostalgic evocation of a vanished age amid some of England's most beautiful countryside, the series became one of the BBC's biggest successes.
He also acted in films and was the author of numerous television documentaries, in some of which he appeared himself. One of his hobbies was archery and in 1976 he published Longbow, a history of one of England's oldest weapons of war. He claimed to be a quarter Welsh.Photo: Supplied
Timothy Sydney Robert Hardy was born in Cheltenham on October 29, 1925, the son of Major Henry Harrison Hardy CBE, headmaster of Cheltenham College and later of Shrewsbury School. Robert followed his father to Rugby, and then to Oxford, where he read English Literature at Magdalen College, gaining enough acting experience to join the Shakespeare Memorial Theatre, then touring in Australia, at the age of 24.
During the 1960s his stage appearances dwindled as television increasingly claimed him and in 1966 he appeared as Alec Stewart in The Troubleshooters, a series set in the oil industry. It became one of the decade's most popular television dramas.
His work in feature films included in 1984 The Shooting Party, a tale of class conflict and intrigues, and in 1985 Jenny's War.
Hardy's more recent big screen roles included that of Cornelius Fudge, the Minister of Magic, in four Harry Potter films between 2002 and 2007.
He was appointed CBE in 1981, was a Fellow of the Society of Antiquaries and held three honorary doctorates. Hardy lived in a Tudor farmhouse in Oxfordshire and, as well as archery, numbered horsemanship and bowyery among his recreations.
He was a member of the Battlefields Trust, and its patron since 2010, and served on the Battlefields Panel of English Heritage. As well as Longbow (1976) he published a second book on his favourite weapon, The Great War-Bow (2004), was a trustee of the Royal Armouries from 1984 until 1995 and, in 1988-90, master of the court of the Worshipful Company of Bowyers.
His first marriage, in 1952, to Elizabeth Fox was dissolved and he married, in 1961, Sally Pearson, the daughter of the actress Dame Gladys Cooper. This marriage ended in 1986. He is survived by a son of the first marriage and two daughters of the second.
Telegraph, London
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winston Churchill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alec Guinness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Worshipful Company of Bowyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister of Magic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilderness Years (1981</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame Gladys Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shrewsbury School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tudor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Sydney Robert Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shooting Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Broadcasting Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battlefields Panel of English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Longbow (1976</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leicester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Churchill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battlefields Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Herriot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cornelius Fudge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siegfried Farnon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Armouries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxfordshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laertes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Creatures Great</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tristan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry V</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farnon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skeldale House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorkshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fellow of the Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Welsh.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Hardy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardy</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Askrigg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare Memorial Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ariel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Literature</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Riding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespearean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheltenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magdalen College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Davison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheltenham College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth R (1970</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny's War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Albert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Age of Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darrowby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alec Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Henry Harrison Hardy CBE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward VII (1975</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great War-Bow (2004</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
