<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435721710306460</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836107/liberals-pin-gay-marriage-hopes-on-religious-protections/?cs=7</url>
  <title>Liberals pin gay marriage hopes on religious protections</title>
  <content>
Rebel Coalition MPs pushing for a free vote on same-sex marriage hope that a comprehensive set of religious freedom protections will help persuade wavering colleagues to support their private members' bill rather than the conservative plan for a postal plebiscite.

Five Liberal backbenchers - Dean Smith, Trent Zimmerman, Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Warren Entsch - support the bill which is being circulated to government MPs ahead of an emergency same-sex marriage party room meeting to be held on Monday afternoon.
They will urge their colleagues to ditch the plebiscite policy they took to the election - which was blocked in the Senate - in favour of a free vote on their bill. The party room debate is being seen as a key test for Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull's leadership.
Senator Smith says the Marriage Amendment Definition and Religious Freedoms Bill would enshrine protections and exemptions for religious communities.
"None of the other bills that have ever come before the Parliament - we've had in excess of 15 of them - none of the other bills have more comprehensively dealt with the issue of religious freedoms or religious protections," Senator Smith told ABC's Insiders on Sunday.
"Now, this is important because there might be some people in my own party that would like to legislate for same-sex marriage but want to be satisfied that those religious freedoms will be in place. This bill does that.
"People cannot be guaranteed that if a future Labor government is elected, these religious freedoms will be there."
Under the bill, both religious ministers and civil celebrants who refuse to marry same-sex couples will be protected from legal action. The bill will create a new category of "religious marriage celebrants" who can legally refuse to officiate a same-sex ceremony.
But business owners and service providers such as bakers, florists and photographers will need to prove they are linked to a "religious body" to reject a same-sex wedding.
While Senator Smith was the key architect of the bill, he says it is important for its "moral authority" that it is introduced in the lower house.
But it appears increasingly likely the party room will back the idea for, as advocated by conservative Immigration Minister Peter Dutton.
But Senator Smith says that would be even worse than the original plebiscite proposal, costing up to $100 million but lacking in any force or authority. It would disenfranchise younger voters and Australians overseas, and , he said.
A postal vote would likely be struck down by the High Court unless it was underpinned by specific legislation - which would almost certainly be rejected by the current Senate - according to legal advice obtained by marriage equality advocates.
The Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays group say it will not hesitate to take the government to court based on the advice prepared by Ron Merkel QC and Christopher Tran.
Spokeswoman Shelley Argent said: "Some in the government are so intent on continuing the discrimination of LGBTI people they are now stooping to un-constitutional practice".
If the Liberal party room does not back their bill the five rebel MPs are considering a high-stakes strategy of crossing the floor to support a motion to bring on debate.
Mr Zimmerman said that would be "a very serious decision" but did not rule it out on Sunday. He too hopes the religious exemptions in the private members' bill will persuade others to support a free vote.
"We need to a find a way to get some finality on this issue," he told Sky News.
Opposition frontbencher Tony Burke says even if the government splits Labor "will not use this issue as an issue of confidence in the government - in no way, shape or form".
Long-time marriage equality advocate and spokesperson for just.equal, Rodney Croome, said: "A postal vote will not be representative of the whole community, will not be binding on politicians and is just another desperate delaying tactic. It will also be a platform for fear-mongering and hate against LGBTI Australians."

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friends of Lesbians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Amendment Definition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Insiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Croome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelley Argent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Tran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Religious Freedoms Bill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron Merkel QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
