<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435721710306457</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/how-bushranger-martin-cash-killed-a-man-but-died-of-old-age/8774304</url>
  <title>How did Martin Cash, a gentleman bushranger, evade the hangman despite killing a man?</title>
  <content>
Martin Cash occupies a unique position in the Australian hall of infamy.
Unlike most of his outlaw contemporaries, Cash managed to evade the hangman's noose, dying of natural causes in his bed in 1877.
This is despite him being sentenced to hang for murder in 1843.
The story of how this gentleman bushranger was captured is one of legend in the history of Hobart.
"It's a remarkable story," historian Reg Watson said.
The story centred around Bessie Clifford, Cash's girlfriend, who had left the bushranger to live with another man, Joe Pratt, in Hobart Town following a short stint in prison.

Jealousy a bushranger's downfall

Overcome with jealousy, Cash decided to leave his hideout in Dromedary, north of Hobart, to confront and kill Pratt.
Accompanied by fellow bushranger Lawrence Kavanagh, with whom he had escaped prison at Port Arthur months earlier, Cash is said to have arrived in Hobart Town around 8:40pm on August 29, 1843.
"In Hobart at that time people were still out in the street, the shops were still open, and of course the taverns were still very active," Mr Watson said.
"There was a lot of activity."

Cash and Kavanagh donned hats as disguises and headed for where Cash thought Pratt lived.
As he did not know the address, Cash asked two strangers for help to find him.
As chance would have it, the strangers were constables watching Pratt's house in case Cash showed up.
Upon being recognised Cash and Kavanagh fled and were pursued by the police.
Kavanagh was injured and caught early, but Cash evaded police and was soon being chased through the town by as many as 100 locals keen to get their hands on the reward.
"Cash was armed and had three pistols under his coat but he was a great runner," Mr Watson said.
Trying to reach the area of what is today the Queen's Domain, a refuge of bushland often used by bushrangers to escape capture, Cash ran down Melville Street towards Campbell Street not knowing it was a dead end.
"Cash was very unlucky," Mr Watson said.
"All the other main streets of Hobart led to the Domain.
"That area of Hobart became known as Martin's Mistake."
Death of a policeman and sentence to Norfolk Island

Cash had to double back, giving his pursuers a chance to catch up to him, and when he ran onto Brisbane Street he was confronted by Peter Winstanley, an off-duty policeman.
Cash shot Winstanley, which caused both men to fall over and allowed the crowd to capture the bushranger, which they did rather violently, knocking him out before he was taken into custody.
Winstanley died a couple of days later and Cash was charged with murder and sentenced to hang.
But the bushranger's luck had not totally run out when his sentence was challenged and postponed, resulting in the governor writing to the authorities in London to seek guidance.
In the end Cash and Kavanagh were sentenced to Norfolk Island, where Cash eventually was granted a ticket of leave allowing him to return to Tasmania.
Cash was far from done with drama and adventure in his life, going on to run brothels in New Zealand before returning to Tasmania for the last time where he lived out his days in a cottage in Glenorchy.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reg Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melville Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart Town</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Watson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kavanagh</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawrence Kavanagh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queens Domain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Pratt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Cash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Winstanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winstanley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norfolk Island</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenorchy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin's Mistake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bessie Clifford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
