<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435721710306498</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/national/public-service/mary-scott-one-of-the-most-effective-least-conventional-public-servants-of-her-time-20170725-gxi7fb.html</url>
  <title>Most effective, least conventional: Public servant remembered</title>
  <content>
Photo: Supplied
September 28, 1944 - July 8, 2017
Mary Scott was a one-of-a-kind public servant who died on July 8 after a long battle with an obscure form of lymphoma. While her latter years were spent with her partner Alan Bansemer and her beloved horses at Serpentine in the WA countryside, she is probably best remembered for her time on the national stage as a social policy leader, public service trail blazer and change advocate.
Over her thirty years as a public servant, Scott was at the centre of the development and implementation of a range of key social policies and programs that broke new ground. She left a profound legacy not just in policy terms but also in the APS leaders that she mentored and developed throughout her career.

But these dry statements don't begin to capture the complex, passionate, tenacious, eccentric, warm-hearted, unpretentious, generous person that she was. Scott lived life on her own terms. She was equally at home in a Senate estimates hearing as she was out in the paddock delivering a foal. Her lack of formality was legendary, epitomised for many colleagues by her practice of attending ministerial meetings with her current orphan baby kangaroo stuffed into a pillowcase in her capacious handbag and fed from a small bottle every couple of hours.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The personal qualities that so endeared Scott to her friends were also those that made her one of the most effective - if least conventional - public servants of her generation. With passion she espoused difficult, sometimes deeply controversial social policy issues ranging from Indigenous land tenure, childcare, through home and community care for the aged and disabled, to HIV/AIDS and Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander health. Her contribution was testament to her crisp and incisive intelligence combined with a warmth, a generosity of spirit and an openness to thinking right outside the box. She could strongly hold a view and also consider all points of view.
Scott began her public service career in the now long gone Department of External Territories. In 1966 as a new graduate she was appointed to a taskforce to report on a suitable system of land tenure for Papua New Guinea. During this time she was sent to Africa to look at the then highly regarded land tenure model in Kenya and she often said that this experience influenced her profoundly. At the completion of this task she was appointed as the executive officer to "The Committee of Enquiry into the Social and Economic Conditions of Aboriginals on Pastoral Properties in the Northern Territory". During this enquiry she learned much from another legendary public servant, Dr H C (Nugget) Coombs, who went on to become a lifelong friend.
Perhaps it was these early experiences that influenced her future career choices. Whatever the reasons, throughout her life Scott was fiercely committed to equity and social justice and predictably and consistently spoke out for people who were marginalised and vulnerable.
In 1973, following the election of the Whitlam government, Scott joined the newly-established Social Welfare Commission, under the leadership of the formidable Marie Coleman. These were heady days for anyone interested in a comprehensive national approach to social policy. Scott was in her element. Childcare, a social security safety net including a single parents' benefit, comprehensive aged care, inter-country adoption and the Australian Assistance Plan for regional Australia were just some of the issues taken up by the commission. With the change of national government in 1975, the Social Welfare Commission was abolished.
Scott was appointed to the senior executive service in 1975. She was one of less than a dozen women. She was also the first SES woman to have a baby and take maternity leave. From an early age, her beloved daughter Maya was silent witness to many policy and political debates, often over long dinners, asleep on her handbag under the dinner table.
She stood out for her ability to predict the tension points for stakeholders and in her use of humour to keep everyone talking.

Three major national programs that Scott successfully developed from the ground up stand out: building the Home and Community Care (HACC) program in the mid-1980s, implementing the first cabinet-endorsed National HIV/AIDS Strategy and successfully managing the politically fraught transfer of responsibility for Indigenous health from the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Commission (ATSIC) to the Department of Health.
Not everybody appreciated Scott's approach to these issues, or indeed the programs themselves. The conservative independent Tasmanian senator, Brian Harradine, saw her approach to the HIV/AIDS strategy as clear evidence that the "gay lobby" had captured the program and that family values were under attack. Nonetheless, the programs that Scott established thrived.  Australia's response to HIV/AIDS was widely recognised as the gold standard in HIV/AIDS programs across the world.
Scott's approach to program development was essential to the impact and endurance of these signature achievements. She insisted on building them inclusively, with affected communities, service users, front-line professionals, and politicians from all parties. She stood out for her ability to predict the tension points for stakeholders and in her use of humour to keep everyone talking. She listened where many did not and was always open to constructive advice and ideas. She was not as tolerant to what she saw as counterproductive ideological conservatism or professional gatekeeping.
It should also be said that Scott was no saint. She certainly never aspired to be one. Her serious fear of flying, which she was frequently required to do, was often solved with medicinal alcohol. She appalled the corporate services personally responsible for building maintenance by illegally unscrewing windows in her office so she could smoke out of them. She was known for being chronically late, and would not infrequently rush into meetings, after morning chores on the farm, with her dress on backwards or mismatched shoes. Scott swore like a trooper and she loved to shock, particularly those she considered to be narrow-minded stuffed shirts.
Throughout her public service career Scott was surrounded by and part of an extraordinary generation of social policy practitioners, many of whom went on to be lifelong friends. She loved nothing better than to solve the world's problems over good food and a glass or two of red and the dinner parties at her home at Namerik became legendary. Her friends, peers and the people whose careers she influenced were people steeped in the best traditions of the public service, hard-working, committed to evidence, to rational policy and to giving frank and fearless advice.
She made it clear to those who worked with her that governments and ministers change and it was therefore their responsibility as public servants to ensure that the public policy advice they gave and the programs they developed focused also on the medium- and long-term.
More than holding her own in the company of these peers, Scott stood out. She could be both pragmatic and strategic and she served ministers from both sides of politics with distinction. She worked closely and well with ministers as diverse as Neil Blewett, Margaret Guilfoyle, Brian Howe and Graham Richardson.
A recent conversation with Dame Margaret Guilfoyle, Minister for Social Security from 1975-1980, following Scott's death, sums her up: "Mary was a wonderful public servant. She was never content with just good enough and was always looking and researching for ways to do it better. The programs she ran are a testament to her commitment and to her talent."
In 1995 Scott made a major change. She resigned from the Commonwealth Public Service. With her daughter Maya, numerous horses and dogs, including her dingoes, she left Namerik, the beautiful mud brick home she and friends had built just out of Canberra, and moved to WA with Alan Bansemer, when he was appointed Commissioner of Health for WA. Together they settled at Serpentine just out of Perth and Mary focused her enormous energy and talents on one of her other passions - breeding thoroughbred horses. She became well-known and sought out for her deep knowledge of horses and her exceptional handling skills. She acted with integrity in all aspects of the thoroughbred industry with all its tribulations.
She continued to take an intense and active interest in all matters related to social justice and equity. She was the fiercest advocate for outsider voices in the health and welfare system because her heart as well as her intellect made space for their viewpoint.
Scott had an extraordinary capacity for friendship that was perceptive and honest. Throughout the Serpentine years, Mary and Alan spent hours, days, weekends caring for friends in need, available and generous. Relationships built over the public service years not only endured but deepened.
Her circle included people from every issue, program or cause she espoused. One never knew who you would find around Mary and Alan's dining room table, arguing vehemently, laughing, sorting out the world over long afternoons and late evenings. She will be deeply missed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Committee of Enquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Public Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Guilfoyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maya</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Bansemer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HACC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame Margaret Guilfoyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of External</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV/Aids</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Welfare Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATSIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coombs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Howe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitlam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Assistance Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 28, 1944</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Blewett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National HIV/AIDS Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Harradine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pastoral Properties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Security</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Economic Conditions of Aboriginals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 8, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr H C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Namerik</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
