<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435077465206268</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/technology/techknow/surveillance-footage-captures-creep-lurking-in-neighbours-attic/news-story/1ff94810ea377298bd5a178e782a1cce</url>
  <title>Creepy footage catches man lurking in attic</title>
  <content>
THE eerie noises coming from the attic at this Pennsylvania home were reason for alarm after all.
Surveillance footage from Jerome Kennedy's Pittsburgh home revealed that someone had been crawling through his attic at night.
According to Kennedy, that person is his next-door neighbour Robert Havrilla, 69, who he claims was peering into his bedroom through a vent, the  reports.
Kennedy said he installed the camera in his home when he started hearing noises after his 10-month-old baby girl was born. He said he would also notice flashlights and mysterious drill holes.
"It shows him removing a false wall that he engineered, climbing onto my ceiling, above my baby's crib, and he lies on some planks that he put there, in my ceiling," Kennedy .
He contacted police on July 17 to report footage of Havrilla allegedly crawling into Kennedy's attic from his own.
The video showed the alleged stalker, who was carrying a drill and a light, peering from the attic for about 30 minutes.
"It's very disheartening to feel violated in this way that somebody can come in and disrupt the sanctity of my home," Kennedy told KDKA.
Authorities questioned Havrilla, but he denied trespassing, claiming that he could only get to his neighbour's attic with a ladder.
Havrilla was charged on Thursday with burglary, criminal trespassing and stalking. He is scheduled to next appear in court on October 3.
This article originally appeared on the  and was reproduced with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havrilla</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Havrilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KDKA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pennsylvania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerome Kennedy's Pittsburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
