<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435292213573168</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/doing-it-rough-highflying-hawk-jarryd-roughead-marks-his-250game-milestone-20170805-gxq0c2.html</url>
  <title>Doing it Rough: High-flying Hawk Jarryd Roughead marks his 250-game milestone</title>
  <content>
Sam Mitchell says most footballers that go deep into a career care about game numbers 200, and 300, and not necessarily about the ones in between. His close friend Jarryd Roughead on Sunday is passing 250 AFL games, like a train passing a mile marker on its way to a grand view.
For a four-time premiership player, this is just a number among others. Perhaps, more than anything, Roughead's 250th is representative of his progress from serious illness towards normality, which for him means Hawthorn winning games of football.Photo: Paul Jeffers
"From the start of his career, Rough never worried about stats like other players," said Mitchell. "He was the guy at Hawthorn who drove that style we had of tapping the ball to a teammate's advantage. We never really trained it, but he led the way."
Roughead began at Hawthorn in the same season as his only coach, Alastair Clarkson, who, alongside Roughead, recruited Jordan Lewis and Lance Franklin in the same year. The three were pushed onto the senior field early and together developed their signature talents relatively unimpeded.

With a name too obvious for mockery, Roughead was a popular and reliable player from the start. In some ways he was a more subtle and complete forward than Franklin, if not as dominant. What he gave away to Franklin in athletic ability he made up for with craft, and what to this day is an underrated ability to win ground balls, which he hand passes, or taps, to a teammate's advantage.
Roughead looks reluctant in long runs, his big body not suited to steady states. But he has a turn of speed, natural power and, moreover, incredibly durability.

"By the GPS numbers, he was one of the worst on the ground," Mitchell said. "But the key was just getting him near the ball. The challenge was always where to utilise him on the ground to get his best energy."

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

For years Hawthorn have relied on Roughead to win or neutralise contests inside 50, then move up the ground and compete to keep in the ball inside the forward half. Always he found a way to drag himself into important areas of the ground. He rarely goes missing in key stages of games, another quality common to great players. He never looks anguished when he's exhausted, and instead wears a look of mild boredom.
Mitchell tells of Roughead's "exasperated face", the one he wears more often now as he ages, and the players around him get younger.
"He can do so many things easily, that he gets annoyed by other people's mistakes," Mitchell said. "How can you not hit that 20-metre pass? And he likes to watch the ball carrier for about three seconds after they kick it over his head when he's leading."
Roughead is a very complete player, a phrase commonly misattributed to modern footballers. Aside from his ability at ground level, he's also possessed of that traditional key forward quality that allows him to run at full speed into a flat pass and take the ball without slowing down. And he tackles.
One of the popular lies about tackling is that it requires no talent. Intent to try to tackle is attitudinal, sure, but applying a tackle that's worth a damn requires timing. It's a rare quality among big players and Roughhead has it.
In 2007, two years after he made his debut, he was already a forceful player who by the end of 2008 had his first premiership. Even at that time, when anything seemed possible at Hawthorn, no one could have imagined for Roughead another three premierships and a cancer diagnosis before his 30th birthday.
As a footballer he has had tremendous good fortune and, as a young man, the shocking bad luck of melanoma. The quiet, straight talking with which Roughead referred to his situation, and the way he has since returned to football duties, is a fair representation of his style. I asked him to say something this week, and he said only that he didn't feel like talking about himself.
"Rough's more introverted than Hodgey or me," said Mitchell. "He's the guy, if you were a bit worried about something, you'd call for advice."
Earlier this year, when Hawthorn were coming out of an ugly month and Roughead was adjusting to uncharted territory as a losing captain, he told me he was still at ease with football.
"It's hard to get too worried about it now," he said, referring both to his experience with cancer and, I think, his long exposure to the sport.
He has won a Coleman Medal, too, and could have won more without Franklin in his way, and without playing ruck, or loose in defence, or on the ball, or wherever his team needed him most.
His four premierships are the great fact of his football life, and a fair reflection of it too.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodgey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughhead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High-flying Hawk Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead's 250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alastair Clarkson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
