<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435335163246604</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/rugby-union/crusaders-beat-lions-in-super-rugby-final-to-claim-eighth-title-20170805-gxq69x.html</url>
  <title>Crusaders beat Lions in Super Rugby final to claim eighth title</title>
  <content>
The jubilant Crusaders are once again the kings of Super Rugby.
A 25-17 victory over the Lions, who were reduced to 14 men when flanker Kwagga Smith was red-carded late in the first half, on Sunday morning has elevated the New Zealand club once again to the penthouse of the competition and marked a fairytale finish to the season for first-year coach Scott Robertson and captain Sam Whitelock.Photo: AP
A strong start, they led 25-3 by the 53rd minute, enabled the New Zealanders to build an all-important buffer before the Lions made their inevitable comeback at 1700m above sea level.
The victory means the Crusaders have now won eight titles. This was their first since 2008.

The turning point came in the 39th minute when Lions flanker Smith inexplicably took Crusaders fullback David Havili out in the air.
Havili, who had his eyes transfixed on the ball, had his undercarriage whipped out from under him and landed in an undignified heap. Although early fears he had been injured were quickly allayed, there was no doubt Smith was about to be issued a one-way ticket to the showers.

Referee Jaco Peyper had no option but to tell the No.7 to go and take the walk of shame, explaining to Smith it was his responsibility to look after the man in the orbit. Not even the massive crowd, a spectacular blanket of red inside the famous ground that was hosting its first final in the Super competition, could muster the energy to disagree. They knew Smith had to go.

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Now we have really got a fight on our hands," Lions coach Johan Ackermann, who was in his final game in charge of the team prior to moving to England, said during his half-time speech. He wasn't joking.Photo: AP
The Crusaders trotted in for their half-time pow-wow ahead 15-3, and then roared out after the break to compound the Lions' misery by immediately adding another try to No.8 Kieran Read under the bar. With Richie Mo'unga adding the conversion that put the Crusaders ahead 22-3.
Even with coach Robertson going to his bench early - he had replaced his props by the 47th minute and emptied the entire bench before the three-quarter mark, the Crusaders began to tire as the Lions generated more heat in their attack.Photo: Phil Magakoe
A try to Malcolm Marx, the bulky hooker charged over near a ruck in the 63rd minute, finally gave the Jo'burg crowd something to shout about and when replacement prop Corne Fourie scored with seven minutes left, then began to cheer themselves hoarse.
But the Crusaders held firm and immediately after the match Whitelock made it clear how much this win meant to him and the club: "It's great, no one had us picked from the word 'go'. It was awesome, we just believed in ourselves and started our season really well," he said.Photo: AP
"It has just been an amazing year. We knew we had to play, the Lions are such a great side - they have shown it all year and scored a massive amount of points in the last 20 minutes. We knew we had to keep playing, keep attacking."
There was only one team in the contest in the first half, with the New Zealanders having the Lions' measure in all facets.
The Crusaders' rushing defensive line repeatedly prevented the Lions from generating any profit from their attack; it was often bolstered by the bodies of their big forwards, a by-product of their decision to limit the number of men committed into the breakdowns, where openside flanker Matt Todd was such a menace.
Then there was the scrum - Crusaders loosehead Joe Moody had a field day against Ruan Dreyer, who conceded multiple penalties
If Todd was liked a mad dog with a bone in the rucks, then the backs were like whippets chasing cats when they managed to get their hands on turnover ball.
A fine tackle by Read on Lions first five-eighth Elton Jantjies in the eighth minute resulted in the pill bobbling forward, and when it was shifted to Seta Tamanivalu the left wing must have felt like the luckiest man in Africa. With only fresh air standing between Tamanivalu and five points, he gassed almost 80m to score the first try.
Five minutes later centre Jack Goodhue joined Tamanivalu on the score sheet. Ryan Crotty gave the visitors precious go-forward, and when the ball was swung wide, Read, who could have scored himself, unselfishly slipped the final transfer to Goodhue.
Now the Crusaders will fly back home ready to party. Job done.
Crusaders 25 (Seta Tamanivalu, Jack Goodhue, Kieran Read tries; Richie Mo'unga 2 con, 2 pen) Lions 17(Malcolm Marx, Corne Fourie tries; Elton Jantjies 2 con, pen). HT: 15-3.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Todd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seta Tamanivalu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Magakoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Havili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Marx</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Goodhue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lions 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Crotty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richie Mo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johan Ackermann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elton Jantjies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitelock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwagga Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corne Fourie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamanivalu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruan Dreyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaco Peyper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crusaders 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Whitelock.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodhue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Moody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elton Jantjies 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Read</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
