<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435854854293511</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/40-million-fund-my-community-program-launched-by-sa-premier-jay-weatherill/news-story/94144d5a12a3303405e83c5c9f03ea37</url>
  <title>Vote for your favourite community projects</title>
  <content>
PROJECTS as diverse as hall upgrades, community gardens, playground revamps and strengthening community cohesion are eligible for funding through a new State Government scheme.
The $40 million Fund My Neighbourhood program was launched by Premier Jay Weatherill this morning.
South Australians can nominate projects valued between $10,000 and $150,000 to improve their neighbourhood or bring their communities together, and then vote for their favourites.
Mr Weatherill said Fund My Neighbourhood was "one of the world's biggest participatory budgeting exercises".
A total of $20 million has been allocated across the state for round one of the program.
A further $20 million will be available in round two next year.
"Nobody knows your neighbourhood better than you," Mr Weatherill said.
"You and your neighbours will get to decide which projects are funded in your community - you are the experts."
Ideas must be sponsored by an organisation with an ABN - such as a sporting club, charity, school, community group or non-government organisation - to receive the funding.
Individuals, businesses and organisations with a gaming-machine licence are not eligible.
The program is based on the government's online Fund My Community program, which allows community groups to nominate ideas such as providing programs or services for isolated, vulnerable or disadvantaged South Australians.
Between April and May this year, nearly 2500 people took part in deciding which 62 ideas nominated as part of that scheme would share an allocated $1 million.
Fund My Neighbourhood nominations are now open and close on September 8.
Eligible projects will then be put to the online vote with successful projects announced later this year.
For full eligibility criteria and to submit an idea, visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Weatherill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fund My Neighbourhood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fund My Community</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
