<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435764659979775</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4824329/the-voice-of-football-will-be-long-remembered/?cs=298</url>
  <title>Les Murray state funeral to be held this week</title>
  <content>
Picking up the phone a very familiar voice came through the handset. "Hello it's Les Murray speaking," the familiar voice said on the other end of the line.

Given it was early evening and the phone call had come out of the blue it took every ounce of my being not to respond "yeah, and I'm Mark Bosnich". Yet, despite the initial disbelief, the tone of the voice coming down the line was unmistakable.
It was indeed the voice of SBS football .... well, really the voice for football for the entire nation. The great man, Les Murray. "Would Mitch Cohen be there please,"  the voice said politely. "Sure just one moment,'' was the response.

My disbelief was only bettered by the look of disbelief when I turned around and uttered the words to the young football scribe sitting nearby: "Um Mitch, I've got, um, Les Murray on the line for you". He could tell I wasn't joking. 
Read more:

It was the first time Les would call in and personally express his passion around a southern expansion team in the A League, something he was truly committed to for the region he grew up in.
As someone who grew up in a cricket and Aussie Rules state, the voice of Les Murray was the voice football. In many ways he taught this editor most of the very little he professes to know about the world game.
Like many of my generation of Australians, Les Murray played a huge role in inspiring our love for the game, especially when watching our country on the world stage.
When John Aloisi scored that goal to qualify to Socceroos for 2006, I blame the passion Les instilled in me for my knee slide across the lounge room carpet for which the wounds took months to heal. I still have the scars.
The great man will be farewelled in a State funeral this week. RIP Les and thank you for a life well lived.

Read more: Les Murray dead at age 71
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Bosnich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Um Mitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIP Les</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Aloisi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Rules</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
