<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435768954947120</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/police-issue-fresh-warning-after-close-call-truckie-fined/news-story/56961fdb34d7f8af94f60b4995fb39cd</url>
  <title>Truckie fined after SE freeway 'close call'</title>
  <content>
A TRUCK driver has been fined for driving offences after a close call on the main highway through the Adelaide Hills.
Traffic police spotted the B-double truck travelling down the South Eastern Freeway with smoke coming from the brakes just before 7pm on Saturday night.
Officers stopped the truck on Portrush Road where inspections found the brake temperatures ranged from 210-270 degrees celsius.
The truck and both trailers were defected and the company's owner is now under investigation "regarding the maintenance of the vehicle".
The Queensland driver, 21, was fined for disobeying the use of low gear sign and breach of load restraint.
On Sunday police issued a fresh warning about the "close call", in which truck drivers
"must control their speed using gears only on the freeway".
"The presence of major or minor defects in any vehicle increases the risk of causing a crash," a spokesman said.
"Vehicles that have not been properly maintained are known to have been responsible for a number serious crashes.
"This serves as a timely reminder to not only truck drivers but all vehicle users to ensure that their vehicle is roadworthy and their tyres and brakes are in good condition."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-Double</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Eastern Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portrush Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
