<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435816199587686</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/get-me-out-of-the-cleaning-kfc-workers-heartfelt-p/3209251/</url>
  <title>'Get me out of the cleaning': KFC worker's heartfelt plea</title>
  <content>
ONE of the Coast's favourite ladies has made a heartfelt plea to her loyal legion of KFC-loving fans.
Legendary KFC Maroochydore drive-thru operator Barb Ehrlich has taken to social media to get out of the cleaning, reminding people the popular fast-food restaurant is open for business.
She posted on a local community Facebook page in a bid to clear up any confusion, with a series of roadworks around the restaurant leaving some thinking the outlet was closed.
"This is to let you (know) that our store is open and ready to take your orders," Barb's post reads.
"A lot of people think we are closed because there are roadworks going on around our store.
"When we are not busy I have to clean (and you know how much I enjoy doing that...not, hahaha). Please come in and see us."
The popular customer service expert holds a special place in many local hearts.
She took out an online poll a few years back asking people to nominate the best customer service provider on the Coast and there was even a crowd-funding campaign to send her on an overseas holiday.
After more than 30 years at the Maroochydore store, it's clear she still has a passion for hooking people up with a serve of Colonel Sanders' best.
Weather Bureau backtracks on severe storm prediction
DAILY'S historical books are stirring up memories.
RESPONSIBILITY Theory is helping young students shine.
Road cut off after rollover latest in string of Coast crashes
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonel Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barb Ehrlich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC-loving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
