<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435210609193633</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/more-sports/nude-man-storms-track-before-usain-bolt-farewell/news-story/fea6d585ba8a06bdefbc2fa575707fdf</url>
  <title>Streaker smashed before Usain's final bolt</title>
  <content>
A NAKED streaker attempted to spoil Usain Bolt's farewell at the World Championships after running onto the track before the 100 metres final.
Bolt's last 100m race was not only sabotaged by a streaker but also by Justin Gatlin as the Jamaican finished third.
The streaker had "PEACE + LOVE" written on his chest as he sprinted before the 100m final.
The fully nude man exposed himself to the thousands of spectators at the Olympic Stadium who were eagerly anticipating Bolt's 100m goodbye.
But before they caught a glimpse of the 30-year-old, they instead watched stewards desperately try and tackle a streaker.
A steward hauled the man to the ground by tackling him over boards alongside the track.
A group of officials then escorted him off of the track as one man held a blue Hi-Vis jacket to cover up his genitalia.
The streaker held up two fingers as a peace sign while he was taken away.
Stewards quickly dealt with the matter, clearing the path for the 100m final to take place.
The final then turned out to be anti-climactic as  and Christian Coleman in second.
Bolt paid the price for making a shocking start and no matter how hard he tried to get back on level terms he came up just short and had to settle for a time of 9.95 secs.
Despite failing to win the race, Bolt was still given a memorable farewell from the crowd following his final 100m race.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Streaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HI VIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt's 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
