<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435116119912253</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/budget-cuts-replace-ribbon-cutting-for-wa-government/8775878</url>
  <title>'No new taxes' pledge on shaky ground as WA braces for tough budget</title>
  <content>
Mark McGowan spent the latter part of his week cutting ribbons on projects including a freeway extension in Perth's north and mining equipment constructed in the city's south.
But it is cuts of a totally different kind which will be causing the WA Premier plenty of stress.
Mr McGowan, Treasurer Ben Wyatt and their most trusted lieutenants are putting the finishing touches on their first budget, the release of which is a defining moment in the early days of any new government.
Earlier this week, Mr McGowan claimed the budget to be unveiled by his treasurer on September 7 would be the "best in living memory", but for households it's not expected to be without pain.
Ever since taking office nearly five months ago, the Government has been setting the stage  but the rhetoric on that front has been ramping up in recent weeks.
Mr McGowan frequently blamed his predecessor for the state's ongoing deficits and large debt, although it is generally accepted in political circles that a government's ability to point the finger at the previous regime wears off once its first budget is handed down.
New GST blow 'heartbreaking'

The Premier was keen to emphasise this week how much circumstances have changed since the election, saying write-downs to GST and federal funding as well as mining revenue provided a $5.4 billion budget blow.
caused by revised population, a situation Mr McGowan described as "heartbreaking" as it only emerged in the latter stages of budget preparations.
While those revenue hits have been substantial, the Government's language around it has struck most political watchers as an effort to "soften up" voters for hip-pocket pain in the budget.
After already substantially raising power prices and other household charges earlier this year, a range of new revenue-raising options have emerged as possibilities.
A South Australian-style tax on bank deposits and bonds was confirmed by Mr McGowan as being under consideration, while proposed measures such as an increase in mining royalty rates and a levy on water rates on investment properties have not been ruled out.
In fact, virtually the only revenue-raising measure the Government guaranteed will not happen is the mining tax on BHP and Rio Tinto
If the Government chooses to proceed with any of the other ideas, it will be a difficult sell for a party which repeatedly promised during the campaign there would be
The Premier was asked more than once this week whether the latest GST hit had given him an excuse to break the "no new taxes" pledge, a suggestion he batted away each time.
But both Mr McGowan and Mr Wyatt have been getting asked for months about that promise and neither have been willing to repeat it.
'Budget will be robust'

Mr McGowan was not keen to go into detail about just how much pain would be handed to households, but admitted the task of selling the budget to voters would be a difficult one.
"We will have to explain and we will explain very thoroughly," Mr McGowan said.
"The budget will be robust, it will be tough but I'm not going to speculate exactly what's in it."
The budget is also set to include a raft of spending cuts after government agencies were ordered to go through their allocations and find significant savings.
It is understood some areas of government came back with what they believed were extensive savings, only to be told to find more.
Big spending cuts are expected in the public service with the amalgamation of scores of government departments, after Labor promised during the election campaign to find $750 million of savings over four years.
In the lead-up the state poll, Labor also said the budget would be back in surplus by 2019-2020, and that it would pay off the state's large debt bill "over time, like paying down a mortgage".
But it now looks very likely that Mr Wyatt's first budget will contain deficits for years to come, with no debt reduction on the horizon.
While it's too early to determine the veracity of Mr McGowan's claims the budget will be "best in living memory", there's not doubt the Government will have its work cut out convincing voters the "tough" measures they've been warned about were absolutely necessary.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wyatt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Ben Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
