<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435730300241186</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/the-house-annabel-crabb-reveals-the-secrets-of-parliament-house-20170803-gxockc.html</url>
  <title>Annabel Crabb reveals the secrets of Parliament House</title>
  <content>
When Annabel Crabb was a primary school student her uncle worked at the Adelaide Zoo and during the school holidays he used to take her behind the scenes.
Crabb recalls her delight and wonder at being able to see all sorts of things the ordinary visitor would not be able to see and says she got a similar thrill making her new documentary series, The House, which takes people around, inside and even beneath Parliament House.Photo: supplied
"It was like a real treat getting to wander around and having someone to answer all my questions," she says.
"Everything about the building is thought out. One of the things that stuns me is the extent to which the original design team still has a say in what goes on. You can't just knock out a wall and add on a pergola. Every change has to be talked through with the members of the design team who are the moral rights holders. There's no other building like it in Australia.".Photo: AUSPIC
The series begins this week but has been years in the planning.
Negotiations first began when Bronwyn Bishop was Speaker of the House of Representatives. Filming eventually began last year and took place over 10 months.

Crabb and her crew were given unprecedented access to the building and the presiding officers - the Speaker and the President of the Senate - relaxed the usually very strict rules about filming to allow cameras into areas they would not normally be allowed.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Entry to the cabinet room, for example, is normally restricted to members of cabinet, select staff and cleaners.Photo: supplied
It holds one of the building's many examples of local craftsmanship, something Crabb was keen to show a wider audience.
"So many amazing extraordinary local artisans were used to create the features seldom noticed by the building's regular inhabitants, such as the marquetry above the cabinet table which features flowers and leaves and other foliage but there's a couple of bugs peeping through," Crabb says.Photo: Supplied
She likes to think the bugs were the craftsman's nod to the leaks of information that periodically come from the room.
Viewers will also see the labyrinth of underground corridors and the 1100 subterranean rooms where everyone from stone masons to engineers to pastry chefs work.
Beneath the building is also where Parliament House's multimillion-dollar art collection is housed in a special climate-controlled room.
Five thousand people work in Parliament House, which has a gym, squash courts, tennis courts, sports fields, extensive gardens, hairdresser, bank, several dining areas and library.
While the politicians come and go many of the building's staff have worked there since it opened in 1988.
Head cleaner Maria Ljubic came to Australia from Croatia as a young woman and was once mistaken for the Queen while she was doing some last-minute cleaning.
Chamber attendant Luch Jonceski​ worked as a builder's labourer during the construction of the building. 
Crabb lists seeing what is known as 'the cathedral' - an enormous three-storey cavern beneath the building - and the changing of the flag as highlights.
"Those giant flags are only used for a few weeks at a time. Getting up there is so difficult. It's a tiny elevator about the size of two coffins and two guys take the old, tattered flag off to be repaired and patched," Crabb says.
The documentary also shows viewers one of the building's most poignant design features: when all the doors from the cabinet room through to the Great Hall and out to the main entrance are opened, the Australian War Memorial can been seen, a reminder to MPs of the consequences of their decisions.
"I begged and sobbed and made cow eyes and just beseeched and they agreed to it," Crabb says.
"That was an amazing thing to see. It was very moving and the Prime Minister launched into a speech about how when you're in cabinet you should always remember the lives of people who have served their country. "
The House with Annabel Crabb begins on ABC on August 8.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria Ljubic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Speaker of the House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Zoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crabb</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSPIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luch Jonceski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian War Memorial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annabel Crabb</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Croatia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
