<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435768954947124</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/juan-mata-donates-earnings-to-charity-and-wants-others-to-follow/news-story/335c4ed07497834b6af5b9e117d76f24</url>
  <title>Mata wants to change football with brilliant gesture</title>
  <content>
MANCHESTER United's Spanish international Juan Mata has promised to give one per cent of his earnings to charity and wants all fellow professional footballers to do the same.
"I am launching something that I hope will change the world, even if only in some small way," he announced on The Players Tribune website.
Mata said he would donate the money to Common Goal, a fund run by the charity streetfootballworld that supports football charities around the world.
"I'm asking my fellow professionals to join me in forming a Common Goal Starting XI. Together we can create a movement based on shared values that can become integral to the whole football industry - forever.
"I'm leading this effort, but I don't want to be alone."
Mata, who said he was shocked by the poverty he saw on a visit to Mumbai, said the long-term aim was for the entire football industry to contribute 1 per cent of revenue to grassroots football charities.
The United midfielder is estimated to earn PS7 million ($11.5m) a year. Neymar, the Brazilian who moved from Barcelona to Paris St Germain this week, has been reported as earning more than PS40m annually.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Common Goal Starting XI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mata</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris St-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United's Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PS40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PS7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Players' Tribune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juan Mata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Common Goal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumbai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
