<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435249263899755</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4832630/driverless-vehicles-on-trial-in-nsw/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Driverless vehicles on trial in NSW</title>
  <content>
Kiama MP Gareth Ward is looking forward to the day he can hitch a ride in a driverless vehicle.

That day has come a little closer with the NSW government announcing a trial of the technology at Olympic Park.

Next year this automated shuttle bus will be driving people around the streets of Olympic Park. Picture: AAP
Last week the government unveiled plans to get an automated shuttle driving along the roads of Olympic Park.
The news was welcomed by Mr Ward, who has long been a proponent of the new technology - partially because of the freeing effect it could have on his life.
"As someone whose visually impaired and can't drive, I raised this in the parliament several years ago and have continued to push for the government to follow other countries, including the United States, to introduce driverless vehicles," Mr Ward said.

"I want to see people, particularly those who are elderly or have disabilities, have access to this technology.

"This is the way of the future and I look forward to seeing the roll-out of driverless vehicles across the state, once safety can be assured."
The first stage of the government's trial will see the small shuttle put through a series of tests and safety checks off-road where the shuttle will run autonomously on a pre-programmed route.
"We will then extend the trial to public use with the shuttle making the rounds on the roads at Sydney Olympic Park," said Roads Minister Melinda Pavey.
She expected office workers at Sydney Olympic Park to be using the automated shuttle next year.
"There is still some way to go before automated shuttles become common place on Australian roads, but as a government we are ready to take the next step and from here all sorts of possibilities open up for transport in NSW," she said.

- Gareth Ward on driverless vehicles
Mr Ward was aware of the concerns some might have about getting into a vehicle without a human in the driver's seat.
"They can spot a plastic bag blowing in the wind two football fields away," he said. "They are really innovative vehicles.

"Once upon a time people would have watched The Jetsons and thought, never in my lifetime. Well, that's not the case any more."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roads Minister Melinda Pavey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ward</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gareth Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama MP Gareth Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
