<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435464012266697</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/rubbish-dumped-ipswich-gold-coast-waste-levy-scrapped/8763520</url>
  <title>Ipswich the 'dump capital' after waste levy scrapping</title>
  <content>
Ipswich has become the "dumping capital" after a waste levy was scrapped to make it cheaper for interstate businesses to get rid of their rubbish in Queensland, the Acting Mayor says.
Paul Tully said locals are sick of the stream of trucks coming into the city, west of Brisbane, hauling rubbish from New South Wales.
"We're being flooded with hundreds of trucks a week ... and the people of Ipswich have had a gutful of it," he said.
"It's coming up the M1 and the Logan Motorway and the Ipswich Motorway right into Ipswich.
"We're basically becoming the dumping capital of south-east Queensland."

In 2012 the former Newman government abolished the waste levy, with the amount of rubbish coming into Queensland increasing since.
In 2014-15 Queensland landfill operators received 353,000 tonnes from interstate, rising to 566,000 the year after.
The waste heading to Ipswich goes to a number of privately run landfill sites, including Remondis at Swanbank and Cleanaway at New Chum.
The exact figure going to the city has not been released due to commercial in confidence.
Councillor Tully said council is unable to introduce a fee to reduce the landfill because of the privatisation.
Cr Tully wants the Palaszczuk Government to reintroduce the levy, but the Queensland Government is making no promises.
Environment Minister Steven Miles said the Government promised not to introduce any new fees or charges in this current term, but is looking at other options to reduce the amount of landfill coming to Queensland.
The Gold Coast City Council took matters into its own hands after also seeing a spike in dumping.

Private landfill operator supports changes

Cleanaway would support a reinstated levy, saying it would balance the cost of waste disposal in Queensland and NSW.
"Cleanaway does not transport waste from NSW to Queensland because we believe it goes against the spirit of the legislation in NSW," the company spokesperson said.
"[And] because of the potential risk that comes with the movement of large volumes of waste over long distances."
Peak industry body, Waste Recycling Industry Queensland, said the Ipswich facilities are coping well with the load.
"To put some perspective on it waste has always come into Queensland from northern New South Wales," chief executive Rick Ralph said.
"About 80 per cent of the waste coming in to Queensland would be coming by rail and then being transported on the Ipswich Motorway to private facilities.
"It's a commercial decision by those businesses whether they choose to take the material or otherwise.
"These facilities are coping very well, they're world-class, they're licensed, the environmental regulator regulates them, our industry reports the waste tonnes that are being imported from interstate and it's a very transparent process."
Council-led levy working on Gold Coast

At the start of this financial year, it introduced a $200 per tonne fee for out-of-city businesses to dump at its landfill.
Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate said he had already noticed a difference.
"We have put up a wall - an economic wall - so that New South Wales waste stays in New South Wales," he said.
"It now makes no economic sense for New South Wales transfer waste trucks to come over the border.
"Long term we won't have to look around for another dump site."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleanaway</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Tully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Motorway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Chum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waste Recycling Industry Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remondis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Ralph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Tully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acting Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Tully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
