<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435077465206309</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/06/08/22/staking-out-the-wild-cats-roaming-los-angeles</url>
  <title>Staking out the wild cats roaming the hills of Los Angeles</title>
  <content>
There are stories we produce in our careers that you know are special and potentially going to influence our viewers in a very positive way - and this indisputably was one of them.
A little earlier this year while working in the 9NEWS Los Angeles bureau, I was lucky to strike gold and become involved in a story that not only prompted a lot of viewer response, but won our team a prestigious LA Press Club Award.
We began this story like a covert mission, meeting our contact on an isolated stretch of road at the base of a dry hillside - a location disclosed only a few hours earlier.

The hills, which are home of some of the last surviving California mountain lions, are a protected secret.
From the moment we shook hands with our guide Robert Martinez, you could tell he was a passionate enthusiast and a proud protector of the wild cat colonies.
For a while he's been placing remote cameras in the gullies, ravines and hilltops across the back of Los Angeles.
A citizen scientist refining his craft by self-taught lessons, his cameras - activated by motion sensors - capture high definition stills and video.

Related Articles

Flashes activate but the animals in the frame don't seem to mind, going on about their normal activities, unaware they're being recorded.
By watching their habits, Robert determines where the cats meet, drink and carry their kills to devour.
With Robert as our guide, we set off on a hike to download the cameras, replenish batteries, SD cards and realign sensors.
There's a reason the cats have remain largely out of the public view - they live in areas where there's no trails, and which are largely overgrown or incredibly steep.
As mountain lions are apex predators in the dark, our plan was to complete our work and be back out of the area by nightfall.
Carrying the gear, combined with an awareness of our surroundings and the ticking clock however proved a challenge.
Robert's expertise ultimately paid dividends: each camera had recent captured activity, not only by the big cats and their cubs, but also wild bears.
It's hard to believe this vision has been filmed not that far from one of the world's most heavily populated cities. Even more surprising still, it's also helping change scientific theory.
Robert's video shows the animals engaging in behaviours completely at odds with what biologists traditionally thought about the way the cats and bears communicate, hunt and co-exist.
He is hopeful that his data will prove a vital piece in protecting an endangered animal - something traditional research doesn't have the time or resources to produce.
Yet with the cameras being low-cost and easy to operate, Robert believes aspiring citizen scientists in Australia can replicate his work by conducting their own study of native animals or environmentally sensitive areas.
Behind-the-scenes video provided courtesy of 9NEWS cameraman Tim Myers and producer Rachael Dyer.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Martinez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA Press Club Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWS Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachael Dyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
