<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434815472199249</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/06/07/14/former-murder-accused-amanda-knox-defends-woman-in-us-texting-suicide-case</url>
  <title>Former murder accused Amanda Knox defends woman in US texting suicide case</title>
  <content>
Amanda Knox, the American exchange student convicted and later cleared of a murder in Italy, is offering her support to a Massachusetts woman convicted of manslaughter for encouraging her suicidal boyfriend to kill himself.
In an  published Thursday in the Los Angeles Times, Knox wrote that Michelle Carter deserves sympathy and help, not a jail sentence.
Carter on Thursday was sentenced to 15 months in jail for the 2014 death of 18-year-old Conrad Roy III. Carter, now 20, was 17 years old at the time. A judge agreed to her request to remain free on bail while her state appeal is pending.
The 30-year-old Knox is no stranger to sensational trials drawing global media coverage.
The student from Seattle was convicted along with her Italian boyfriend in the 2007 killing of Knox's roommate, British student Meredith Kercher, in Perugia, Italy. Knox spent four years in jail but was exonerated by the Italian Supreme Court in 2015.

Knox said she felt a "sickening sense of deja vu" as she watched prosecutors try to depict Carter as a "femme fatale", the way she said the media tried to portray her during her trial.
Knox noted that it's difficult to feel sympathy for Carter, who sent Mr Roy dozens of text messages urging him to follow through on his plan to take his own life.

Related Articles

But Knox pointed out that for months leading up to Mr Roy's suicide, Carter had tried to talk Mr Roy out of it and urged him to seek mental health counseling. She also wrote that Carter - who struggled with depression, bulimia and anorexia - was "ill-equipped" to help Mr Roy, who also suffered from depression.
"By holding her accountable for Mr Roy's death, we increase the tally of victims in this case, we ignore the mental health factors that lead to suicide, and we learn nothing about how to prevent it," Knox wrote.
"Conrad Roy III needed our sympathy and our help and didn't get it in time," she wrote.
"Michelle Carter deserves the same sympathy and help now."
Mr Roy's mother, Lynn Roy, has filed a wrongful death lawsuit against Carter.
The lawsuit was filed last month on behalf of her son's estate. It seeks US$4.2 (A$5.3) million in lost future wages.
Readers who are seeking assistance can call Lifeline on 131114 or beyondblue on 1300 224 636.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$4.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meredith Kercher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Roy</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carters</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conrad Roy III</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perugia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynn Roy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Carter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massachusetts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knox</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Knox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
