<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435300803507919</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/06/liberals-plot-path-forward-same-sex-marriage</url>
  <title>Liberals plot path forward on same-sex marriage</title>
  <content>
A group of Liberal MPs have circulated a private members' bill on same-sex marriage ahead of a special party meeting on Monday.

41 MINS AGO  UPDATED 4 MINS AGO

Religious ministers and civil celebrants will be protected from legal action if they refuse to marry same-sex couples under a proposal by a group of Liberal MPs.

Senator Dean Smith, MPs Warren Entsch, Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Trent Zimmerman, have circulated a private members' bill to colleagues ahead of a special partyroom meeting in Canberra to discuss the issue on Monday.

The draft legislation will remove existing restrictions to allow "two people" to marry, regardless of their sex or gender, according to News Corp Australia.

It reports the bill will extend religious freedoms to all religious ministers, while service providers - such as bakers, florists and photographers - will need to prove a link to a religious body to object.

Meanwhile, there are also reports a postal vote on  - an alternative being considered by the Turnbull government - could be invalid without legislation.

Lawyers, in advice provided to marriage equality advocates, suggest the government could not circumvent parliament to enact a plebiscite by post.

Labor frontbencher Linda Burney says Monday's partyroom discussion will be "fascinating".

She said the Australian people, like the opposition, want federal parliament to just get on it with it.

"The division in the coalition party over this issue is going to not serve them well," she told ABC TV on Sunday.

She suggested a deal on marriage equality for the LGBTIQ community could also be a fix for Malcolm Turnbull and the Liberal party.

It comes as new polling shows a majority of voters in six seats held by Liberal MPs - whose positions on marriage equality are undeclared - support  and a free vote in parliament.

However, Liberal voters in each electorate were significantly less inclined to believe same-sex couples should be able to wed or that the government should resolve the issue through a free parliamentary vote.

The ReachTel poll commissioned by activist group GetUp examined the views of voters in six seats across Queensland and Western Australia.

More than 50 per cent of respondents in five of the six electorates supported .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 4 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Burney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ReachTEL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GetUp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
