<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435640105927283</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/former-wa-country-nurse-and-wa-australian-of-the-year-anne-carey-calls-for-change-after-outback-suicides-and-violence/news-story/ae6beacbdcd08661e8727d384dfc1066</url>
  <title>Conditions leading WA nurses to suicide</title>
  <content>
REMOTE and regional nurses in WA have blown the whistle on what they say are atrocious work conditions, including systemic workplace bullying and patient violence.

Four nurses spoke to PerthNow about work conditions in remote nurse posts and regional hospitals which they claim led to the suicide of three colleagues in the past eight months.

The nurses, whose identities have been protected for fear of reprisals, said it was "only a matter of time" until a nurse was seriously attacked or killed in a regional area such as the Kimberley, Pilbara and Great Southern.

They revealed their conditions were so dangerous, some had to work in clinics fully enclosed by wire fencing known as "cages". Figures obtained by PerthNow reveal more than 30 incidents of violence or aggression in remote posts last financial year.

Former WA country nurse and WA Australian of the Year Anne Carey, honoured for her work as a nurse treating Ebola patients in Sierra Leone, said the figure for violence represented just a fraction of the real problem because staff feared reporting incidents.

"Every nurse deserves to be in a safe environment," she said.

The nurses said homes were barricaded with security screens which were sometimes in disrepair or could not withstand an aggressive attack.

One nurse said verbal and physical violence, including attempted sexual assault, was common for remote nurses.

Another nurse told how a male patient threatened to sexually assault her last year at a clinic run by a Kimberley Aboriginal health service.

A nurse at a remote Kimberley post said that in late 2015 a male patient physically threatened her in the clinic. On another occasion, a male patient attempted to break into her home.

She said while there were no single-nurse posts in the Kimberley "on paper", staff were still exposed to dangerous situations at work and at home.

A northern regional hospital nurse said she had suicidal thoughts because of bullying by management and threatening behaviour by a co-worker.

There are 15 single-nurse posts run by WA Country Health Service, including eight in remote areas throughout the State, but not in the Kimberley.

There were also several isolated posts with more than one nurse, and remote posts run by Aboriginal health services.

WACHS chief executive Jeff Moffet said efforts were being made to improve safety.

It comes in the wake of the rape and murder of South Australian nurse Gayle Woodford last year in a remote area. Her killer Dudley David Davey, 35, was jailed in June for life.

There is now a national push to introduce the so-called Gayle's Law which would ban remote nurses from attending call-outs alone.

Nurses said the new WA policy was "just ticking boxes" and had done little to improve their situation.

Mr Moffet said in 2016-17 there were 33 incidents of physical and/or verbal aggression or violence across WACHS' 15 single-nurse posts in the State's regions outside the Kimberley, which is understood to be too "high risk" for single nurse posts. He said security guards were used for nurse safety at three Kimberley posts.

"Various other security measures are in place (at single nurse posts) including lockdown procedures, CCTV, and personal duress alarms and phones," he said.

Asked if he was aware of suicides and suicide attempts by nurses, Mr Moffet said: "If WACHS is made aware of any staff member with concerns ... steps would be taken to provide that support."

Questioning WACHS' grievance process, Ms Carey said: "It's hard to have faith in the integrity of the system when you see independent external grievances overridden by senior management."

Mr Moffet said he was not aware of complaints being made against senior staff.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dudley David Davey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WACHS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Australian of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PerthNow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ebola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Country Health Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WACHS' 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sierra Leone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gayle Woodford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Moffet</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Southern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gayle's Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Moffet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
