<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434961501088395</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/take-me-back-to-the-good-old-days/3208743/</url>
  <title>Take me back to the good old days</title>
  <content>
LAST week I let Ed Sheeran take me "way back when", listening to his hit song Castle on the Hill inspired me to detour into my childhood memories.
This week the Daily has done the same thing with their fantastic series of lift-outs celebrating 50 years of the Sunshine Coast.
Every day something twigs my memory, such as Thursday with the smiling figure of Cliff Butt on the cover.
Not only was Cliff the legend of the Maroochydore business centre with his supermarket, I actually worked for him carrying groceries when I was a little fat kid hungry for pocket money.
That photo brought back memories of Mr Butt as well as the other job I had to keep me well fed with Coke and barbecue chips - being a paper boy for Reid's Newsagency at Cotton Tree.
Mr Reid was really good to me while I was a little scared of Mrs Reid when we used to debate how many papers I had sold because what I thought she owed me and what she thought she was willing to pay was always slightly askew.
But, like the Butts, the Reids were legends around the area in that era - wonderful business people with great customer service.
So what was I doing apart from carrying groceries and short-changing customers in front of the Maroochy Hotel selling them late edition Telegraphs - I was in Grade 4 at Eudlo School.
That was my first year in the "big room" for grades 4-7 after coming out of Mrs Topp's "little room" for grades 1-3.
The only teachers were the principal, Jim Johnson, who taught in the "big room", and Mrs Topp but it was a wonderful way to grow up, drinking sun-warmed school milk, singing God Save the Queen as the flag went up the pole and every Friday singing Life is Great in the Sunshine State, as well as getting put on "pine cone duty" more often than most.
Frank Nicklin was the Premier of Queensland. He was a pineapple farmer from Palmwoods and good friends with my mum so we used to get a visit from him for a cuppa from time to time, which was very exciting as his big black state car rolled into the farm.
He was a great man, good to my family and many others and never forgot where he came from
Now while we are all bright and shiny with a flash name these days I would trade a lot of it for the morals of Frank, who as Premier would at times debate in Parliament with the Opposition and realise they were right and simply say "Well let's do that then".
When is the last time you saw that happen these days?
I bet Frank, or Sir Francis as he was knighted on retirement, never left anyone wondering where he stood on matters.
Yes, take me "way back when" to that.
RIVERS were fundamental to the development of the region.
How the Black Widow was caught
Palmer is shifting his treasures as liquidators circle his assets
Residents reeling after tragic crash on Saturday motorbike ride
Terry and Melek Fahey solved a family problem with a business
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
THE films in Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club.
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid's Newsagency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God Save</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Sheeran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Widow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cliff Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melek Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Nicklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Topp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Francis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotten Tomatoes' Zero Per Cent Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
