<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435704530437121</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:05</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>http://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/build-a-raspberry-pi-happiness-tracker-to-log-morale/</url>
  <title>Build A Raspberry Pi Happiness Tracker To Log Morale</title>
  <content>
If you're still using the office's water cooler to judge your office's morale, you might need an upgrade. Sometimes keeping track of how you feel can be as simple as pressing a button. That's what SEO specialist and programmer Katja Budnikov accomplished after constructing an office happiness tracker during her company's hackathon.

Image credit:

With a Raspberry Pi, LEDs and four buttons, the happiness tracker records four emotional states ranging from "super good" to "bad". The button push is recorded and appears in Grafana, a database visualisation tool. There's a five-second delay after every button push to mitigate falsified results.

Katja placed the happiness tracker near her office entrance to track the moods of employees coming into work or leaving at the day's end.

Brushing your teeth only takes a couple minutes, and so does increasing your happiness. Here's a super easy way to train yourself to look on the bright side.

, or emotions in general, can help you identify patterns in your behaviour that affect your emotional state. If you're always , having a record of your grumpy state recorded for a period of time can help you figure out the culprit, make changes that will boost your mood or help you appreciate the mornings.

And if you're managing a team of people, tracking morale can give you valuable information about your team's state of mind and positive changes that you may want to implement.

[Hackaday]

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raspberry Pi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEDs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackaday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katja Budnikov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raspberry Pi Happiness Tracker To Log Morale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
