<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435292213573192</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-life/amanda-taylor-had-her-first-baby-at-19-and-twins-aged-40-20170803-gxokq6.html</url>
  <title>Mums with a 20 year break between kids</title>
  <content>
It's hard to fathom the energy required to be a mother of eight.
But that's Queanbeyan mum Amanda Taylor's story, and she wouldn't have it any other way.Photo: Dion Georgopoulos
The 40 year old has stretched her child bearing years across two decades.
Her eldest, 20-year-old Caitlin, flies in and out between shifts at work and Amanda nurses her four-month-old twins Lili and Lucy.
"I was 18, almost 19, when I had Caitlin in 1996, Sarah in 1998, William in 2001, Samuel in 2003, then Thomas in 2008," she said.
"I was 36 when I had Adam and didn't expect to be pregnant again but had the twins in 2016."

Ms Taylor said her pregnancies weren't all the same. She had heartbreaking miscarriages and struggled to conceive before Adam and then had to take hormonal supplements to carry him safely to term.
Her twins were the "hardest pregnancy of all". They arrived premature and their positioning meant a caesarean birth was the only option.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I didn't expect to have as many kids but I wouldn't want it any other way," she said. "I love my twins but with so many children it is a hectic household."

Amy Kruck with her three youngest children Selia, Dane, and Lachlan. Photo: Supplied

53-year-old Canberra mum Amy Kruck has a remarkably similar story.
She was 23 when she first gave birth to her daughter Brittany. Fourteen years on she had her second child Lachlan aged 37, her third Selia at 38 and fourth child Dane aged 44.
"They were all naturally conceived and I was able to have naturally delivery with all of them," she said.
"I was lucky there were no complications. One was born on the floor at home but we got by."
She laughed as she reflected on how overwhelming it was first becoming a mother.
During her "second round" in a new relationship she quickly recognised how the years had shaped her.
She was financially better set up and felt ready to take on the challenge of expanding her family.
"I was a lot more prepared mentally and emotionally with the second one because I had so much more experience between the two births," she said. "I trusted my body a lot more by the time I got to the second child."
Ms Kruck said for women in their 30s and 40s there seemed to be a lot of stress, fear and doubt about pregnancy, something she feels detracts from the joy parents should be feeling.
"I read online people saying they are 34 and questioning should they have a baby, and I think go for it," she said.
There were risks to consider being an older mum but Ms Kruck said after seeking medical advice and having available screenings she felt the odds were good for her and her babies' health.
"We are so made to do this if we just trust in it," she said. "I don't get out there and tell women they should do this or do that but I strongly believe this is what our bodies were created to do."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brittany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kruck</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dion Georgopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caitlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Kruck</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
