<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435077465206257</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4835948/an-angel-to-orphans/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>An angel to orphans</title>
  <content>
NO PLACE LIKE HOME: Siblings Anita and Manoj Tamang completing their homework at Noble House after the death of their father and with their mother living in a remote part of Nepal, unable to care for them.

When Trish Ryan's daughter died, she refused to sit and grieve at home.
Instead the nurse and mother of four gathered up all the love in her heart and took it across the world to an orphanage in Nepal.
Meg was just 23 when complications from spina bifida claimed her life in 2003.

She had been studying a Bachelor of Education at Charles Sturt University and was a popular teacher's aid at schools in the district.
It was the brave young woman's dream to help disadvantaged children once she finished her training.

As the first anniversary of Meg's death loomed, the grieving mother booked a flight to Nepal - she'd longed to volunteer there since her early nursing days.

When Mrs Ryan arrived at the small orphanage in Bagmati, on the outskirts of Kathmandu, she discovered a deplorable place overflowing with malnourished children dressed in rags.
Managed by a corrupt administration, staff were often forced to beg for food on the streets and there was an open sewage drain running through the house.

On her return to Australia, Mrs Ryan rallied residents in her local farming community of Bowna who began fundraising in earnest.
Meg's Children was founded in 2005 and has been tranforming the lives of disadvantaged children in Nepal ever since.
Initially the charitable trust supported the children from Bagmati orphanage and their house mothers Nanda and Bibechana to be relocated to a new home in Bhaktapur with Mrs Ryan travelling back regularly to oversee its operation.

From that first move to create a stable and loving home for vulnerable children, the focus of the charity has expanded with education its underlying ethos.

Six of that original band of children are now at university`and today the Meg's Children Trust operates in partnership with Siddhi Memorial Hospital and a dedicated group of Albury volunteers.

GIFT OF LIFE: Nurse and mother of four Trish Ryan has spent more than a decade helping destitute children in Nepal after the death of her daughter Meg, who was 23.
It has truly been a labour of love for Mrs Ryan who funds all her own travel costs.
Fundraising is the lifeline to a brighter future.

Melbourne businessman Mike Coen was so moved by her efforts he has pledged to raise $100,000 in an epic walk from August 21.
Mrs Ryan said it was this type of support that would continue to education children in the hope they would be leaders of the future and help Nepal out of its poverty.

Looking back on her journey during the past decade, Mrs Ryan said in many ways it was meant to be.
She knows Meg would approve of the legacy in her name.

"I think she would be 100 per cent impressed and she would also say don't ever give up - keep on going," Mrs Ryan said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg's Children Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siblings Anita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bibechana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Sturt University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg's Children</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Ryan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bhaktapur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Coen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Place Like Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manoj Tamang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bagmati</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathmandu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nepal</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siddhi Memorial Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trish Ryan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
