<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435206314226220</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-06/syria-executes-renowned-prodemocracy-activist-bassel-khatabil-safadi/1691550</url>
  <title>Syria executes renowned pro-democracy activist Bassel Khatabil Safadi</title>
  <content>
Bassel Khatabil Safadi represented everything Bashar Al Assad's regime feared; a passionate, committed non-violent democracy campaigner, the up-and-coming entrepreneur believed in using technology as a medium to empower people, share information and bring communities closer together.
This week, his family learned he had been executed in 2015.
"I think if Bassel did not decide to leave everything and commit to the Syrian revolution he would be now a very successful businessman anywhere in the world," says Safadi's close friend and fellow internet activist Mohamad Najem.
Safadi was born in Damascus in 1981 to a Palestinian father and a Syrian mother. By his late twenties, he was following his passion for the online world.

Audio:(Correspondents Report)
He had set up his own tech company, was a regular contributor to Wikipedia and worked as Syria's lead for Creative Commons, an NGO that works to make creative content more freely available for others to build on and share.
"Probably a year before the uprising Bassel started something in Damascus called the Hackers' Space. Internet was still limited, it was slow in Syria, but he had this space where people could come and get connected," recalls Mohammad Najem, who runs the Beirut based organization SMEX, which focuses on digital freedom.
"So when the uprising happened, Bassel was in the middle of all this.
"He was already well connected to many networks."

Photo:
Safadi's contacts and online expertise proved invaluable, when in March 2011, the uprising against Syrian President Bashar al-Assad began.
Calls for demonstrations were often issued through Facebook pages, and activists' broadcast news and videos through social media.
Safadi helped lead a network of pro-democracy campaigners operating in secret, to bring news from Syria to an outside world.
"That's when he started to go to Beirut back and forth, bringing smart phones, cameras, video cameras, computers, teaching people how to connect on the internet, teaching people how to use bridge networks to bring the internet from point A to point C to point B," Mr Najem says.
"He was always trying to help people to get the stories out in terms of what's happening in terms of protests against the regime."
It was incredibly dangerous work.
Disappearing without a trace

Syrian civilians and peaceful activists were being shot in the streets by their own government. Thousands were arrested and tortured simply for daring to call for freedom, democracy and the downfall of Bashar Al Assad.
Bissan Fakih, a campaigner with The Syrian Campaign in Beirut, says activists like Safadi exhibited amazing bravery.
"This was at a time when anyone who would take this risk of speaking to a Western journalist could have been rounded up, detained by the Syrian government and never heard from again, and that happened to many people," Ms Fakih says.
"The Syrian regime identified the people who inspired everyone, especially the non-violent people. And they took them and they locked up."

Photo:(Facebook: Noura Ghazi)
Mr Najem remembers this time well.
"All the networks that Bassel helped, they were arrested, imprisoned, tortured, killed or fled the country," he explains.
"Bassel was wanted for many, many months and unfortunately he had no place to hide at the end."
On March 15, 2012, Syrian forces stopped Safadi on a Damascus street.
Overnight, he disappeared.
For eight months, Safadi's family, friends and fiancee - human rights lawyer Noura Ghazi - had no idea where he was. Eventually, he surfaced in the regime's notorious Adra prison.
"When Noura went to see him she said he was unrecognisable," Ms Fakih recalls sadly.
"She said that he was very skinny. That he had been tortured. That he was held in solitary confinement."
Mr Najem used to exchange letters with Safadi while he was in jail.
"He told me the stories from when he was arrested," he says.
"I mean there was a lot of torture ...  he was tortured a lot unfortunately."
Keeping the spark alive

Safadi's friends and contacts in the online world campaigned for his immediate release. Foreign Policy Magazine named him as one of its top global thinkers of 2012 and the Index on Censorship awarded him their prestigious prize for digital freedom.

Photo:(Facebook: Noura Ghazi)
But the Syrian regime refused to release Safadi.
The young activist never allowed his detention to limit his intellectual pursuits.
"He used to translate books and he was trying to keep his brain always intact," says Mr Najem.
"He kept his entrepreneurial mind alive all the time."
Laila Kiki was one of Safadi's friends who used to go and visit him inside jail.
"He was always providing help to other prisoners. He was even helping with some of the IT equipment at the prison itself," she remembers, giggling.
"He always asked friends to bring books even though it was difficult to smuggle the books inside the prison."
Safadi and his fiancee exchanged vows while he was in prison and Ms Kiki says it was his absolute love for Ms Ghazi that kept him going.
"He loved Noura more than anything," Ms Kiki says softly.
"He used to get very excited in the morning whenever it is the day for her visit.
"He used to borrow t-shirts from his fellow prisoners so she could see him in a nice outfit."
On October 10, 2015 Ms Ghazi and Safadi's families discovered that his name had suddenly been taken off the prison register.
"Bassel disappeared very suddenly from Adra prison," explains Ms Fakih.
"It was at a time that his friends thought he was soon to be released.
"And then he disappeared one day without a trace."
Ms Ghazi and Safadi's friends mounted a relentless campaign to discover what had happened to Safadi.
"There was always hope that we might hear some good news soon about Bassel," Mr Najem says.
Worst fears confirmed

This week, more than two years after he disappeared from prison, Ms Ghazi confirmed everyone's worst fears.
"Words are difficult to come. I am about to announce, on behalf of Bassel's family and mine, the confirmation of the death sentence and execution of my husband," Ms Ghazi wrote in a Facebook post on Wednesday.
"He was executed just days after he was taken from Adra prison in October 2015. This is the end that suits a hero like him. This is a loss for Syria. This is loss for Palestine. This is my loss."
Safadi was 34 at the time of his death.
"When we were going through his Twitter feed, we saw this amazing poignant tweet that said 'they can't stop us' and we thought, it was so defiant, it was so strong," Bissan Fikah says tearfully.

External Link:

Bassel tweet
"This is the kind of person that Bassel was. A person who loved. And who didn't deserve to be detained and killed."
Safadi's friend, Anwar Al Bounni, a famous Syrian human rights lawyer who himself served five years in jail for signing a declaration calling for a democratic Syria, says the regime murdered Safadi because he represented the future of the country.
"He was really, really a great man. A great mind. A genius really. He was so important," describes Al Bounni mournfully.
The lawyer says Safadi risked all, and ultimately gave his life, in order to expose injustices to a world that did not care about his or his people's fate.
"Bassel did what he could to send this picture in Syria to the world. And what happened?" the lawyer demands angrily.
"The picture arrived to the world and all the world saw what happened in Syria and how huge the crimes were, but still they stayed silent!"
'Bassel will be remembered as a Syrian hero'

The Syrian Network for Human Rights reports that more than 100,000 Syrians have been detained by the Assad regime since the uprising began, with the fate of so many still unknown.
Amnesty International says they have evidence that .
Mr Najem says he believes the regime saw Safadi as such a threat because he spoke a language they did not understand.
"They don't understand how to face this kind of enemy because they are asking for their rights, they are asking for democracy, they are asking for freedom of expression," Mr Najem says bitterly.
"The regime only understands the language of brutality, sectarianism, violence. They cannot face people, with critical thinking, with access to information, with freedom of expression.
"So all these norms and notions and beliefs that Bassel brought into the space, they were really challenging for the regime."
Mr Najem contrasts Safadi's execution to the fate of Islamist prisoners that the regime released from custody.
"What the regime did is it basically released the extremist, Islamist prisoners from jail and put people like Bassel and others in jail because those are the people who can make the regime lose this fight," he says.
Safadi's friends say that now, as armed factions have taken over Syria's revolution that began as this peaceful pro-democratic movement, his story and legacy have never been more important.
"One day I will tell my children about Bassel," Ms Kiki says sadly.
"I want them to see him as a role model, as a Syrian role model at a time when it is very difficult to find the right role models.
"I guess this is one of the main reasons why he is not here with us anymore... because he would make such a [powerful] community leader."
Mr Najem says Safadi sacrificed his life for Syria.
"I think Bassel will be remembered as a Syrian hero, as a fighter for a better life for his own people."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 15, 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Bounni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Creative Commons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bassel</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Najem</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Policy Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amnesty International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Correspondents Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noura</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wikipedia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fakih</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noura Ghazi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bashar Al-Assad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohammad Najem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anwar Al Bounni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMEX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ghazi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damascus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian Campaign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bissan Fikah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bassel Khatabil Safadi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIRUT</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safadi</name>
    <count>23</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestinians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian President Bashar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laila Kiki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADRA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 10, 2015 Ms Ghazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Internet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamad Najem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kiki</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bissan Fakih</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackers' Space</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
