<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435549911613477</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/tennis/nothing-is-going-right-in-maria-sharapovas-comeback/news-story/b09645570af2a449676c93121948c68c</url>
  <title>Nothing is going right in Maria Sharapova's comeback</title>
  <content>
Kyrgios retires again
0:49

Tennis: Nick Kyrgios has been booed off the court in Washington after retiring from another match.

August 4th 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Tennis news and galleries/

Times are tough.

Share

APRIL was supposed to witness the rebirth of Maria Sharapova. Instead, it signalled the beginning of another descent into hell.
The tennis star has endured a horror run since returning to the court this year from a 15-month suspension for taking a banned substance. It doesn't make for pretty reading.
Maria Sharapova's comeback...
Sharapova's latest setback - pulling out of a tournament in Stanford with an arm injury after her first round win - is especially devastating considering the elation she showed following her 6-1 4-6 6-0 triumph over Jennifer Brady.
"I feel like I just want to hug everyone and say thank you," Sharapova said. "It's my first match in the States in a really long time, and it's the closest thing to home for me."
A day after telling the world how happy she was to be back playing in front of a "special" crowd, she was once again hit by bad news.
The tennis gods clearly don't want Sharapova to be happy. Perhaps they don't believe she has suffered enough for testing positive to meldonium, a drug which improves oxygen flow around the body. It's one explanation for her horrific luck over the past three months:
- MADRID: Defeated in the second round by Eugenie Bouchard, a loss that hurt more than most given the Canadian publicly blasted Sharapova as a "cheater" who should never be allowed to play professional tennis again.
- ROME: Retired hurt in the third set of her match against Mirjana Lucic-Baroni at the Italian Open with a thigh injury.
- FRENCH OPEN: Organisers at Roland Garros denied Sharapova a wildcard into the year's second major.

- BIRMINGHAM, WIMBLEDON: The injury sustained in Rome was worse than first thought, a tear preventing her from appearing at the Aegon Classic in Birmingham and keeping her out of Wimbledon qualifiers.
- STANFORD, TORONTO: The arm injury that ended Sharapova's tournament in Stanford will also keep her out of Toronto's Rogers Cup.

Eugenie Bouchard dissed Sharapova then defeated her in Madrid.Source:Getty Images
To make matters worse, the Russian won't have enough ranking points to walk straight into the first round of the US Open later this month because she missed the entire grasscourt season.
Put yourself in Sharapova's shoes. You've just come back from 15 months out of the sport you love thinking the worst period of your life is behind you, only to cop these fresh blows to your body and your ego.
Few in the tennis world will hold much sympathy for Sharapova. When she admitted to using meldonium - which she stressed she didn't know was in violation of any anti-doping rules - virtually none of her rivals came to her defence.
The 30-year-old was initially slapped with a two-year ban but the Court of Arbitration for Sport reduced it to 15 months on appeal. That will only have strengthened angry players' resentment.
Bouchard attacked her and . That was a common theme - Sharapova was reportedly so icy in the locker room she was never going to be able to rely on fellow players' support.
Their attitude didn't change after she'd served her time. Former world No. 1 Caroline Wozniacki said it would have been "disrespectful" had she won a wildcard into the French Open. Heather Watson questioned the morality of welcoming her back with open arms. German Angelique Kerber said it was "strange" Sharapova's first tournament back at the Stuttgart Grand Prix came at the expense of one of her countrywomen receiving a wildcard.
So if you think you're going to find players sending Sharapova get well soon cards, think again.

Good news has been hard to find.Source:Getty Images
The five-time grand slam champion has taken her rotten luck hard, saying she found it impossible to see any silver lining after injuring herself in Rome. "If the birds were still chirping, I couldn't hear them," she wrote in a piece for .
"I was pretty down after all that. It seemed so cruel, after those 15 long months away from the game, to have finally started to feel like I was taking a step forward - only to be forced to take two steps back. To now have to skip the French and Wimbledon, both, for the second year in a row ... to now have to come off tour again ... it seemed like someone was playing a mean trick on me. I'm sure there are critics of mine, reading this now, and thinking, you know, karma."
Sharapova mentions those critics again in the same piece, saying she'll  in the face of any negativity and refuse to bite back. She's certainly upheld that promise over the past two years, but whether it earns her any respect in the locker room she's done such a good job of dividing remains to be seen.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Open</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roland Garros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Wozniacki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bouchard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madrid.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eugenie Bouchard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuttgart Grand Prix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Brady</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria Sharapova</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wimbledon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>German Angelique Kerber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aegon Classic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heather Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharapova</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-36</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrgios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Kyrgios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Court of Arbitration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirjana Lucic-Baroni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto's Rogers Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birmingham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
