<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435081760173643</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/victoria-politicians-told-to-behave-as-parliament-gets-rowdy/8775930</url>
  <title>Calls for Victorian politicians to behave as State Parliament becomes unruly</title>
  <content>
With parliament resuming this week after a winter break in which many MPs sought refuge in warmer climes, there are calls for Victorian politicians to lift their standard of behaviour.
And with a sensitive debate on voluntary euthanasia laws to come this year, the timing to improve is critical.
In the past two-and-a-half years, MPs have been ejected 354 times from Victoria's lower house.
By comparison, during the four years of the heated 57th parliament - which saw Labor exploit fragile government numbers to openly defy speaker Ken Smith and cause chaos - 359 MPs were turfed.
Former speaker-turned Liberal backbencher Christine Fyffe has called for MPs to improve their behaviour.
Ms Fyffe, who replaced Mr Smith, told the ABC that debate had become too personalised and angry.
"I find it very sad. I am disappointed. It is far more aggressive than it used to be," Ms Fyffe said.
The trend of poor behaviour started in the previous parliament when Labor pushed the limits, she said.
"I think they overstepped the boundaries on a number of occasions and it's carried into this parliament," she said.
"It is the lack of respect for other individuals, the trying to howl down someone when they are on their feet.
"It is a robust place and passionate, and it is not for the faint hearted, but it is a place where every member should be treated with respect."
MPs are frequently kicked out of Question Time for yelling across the chamber.
Some MPs have even been caught on the official records swearing at their opponents.
Nationals Leader Peter Walsh was recorded calling Labor MP Tim Richardson "a dickhead".
People should look at their behaviour, Speaker says

Fuelling much anger from the non-government benches is the fact , although Mr Nardella was booted from the party.
The pair were caught claiming a residential allowance for living away from Melbourne despite their electorates being in the metropolitan area.

Speaker Colin Brooks agreed with his predecessor that MPs should behave better.
"Parliament is always going to be a place for robust and passionate debate, it is a place where ideas are tested and there is always going to be that level of energy in the chamber," Mr Brooks said.
"But there is no doubt in recent years where we have moved too far from what I would call the right balance.
"We have probably got a situation where people probably should look at their behaviour."
MPs 'could be more courteous': Premier

Mr Brooks said MPs needed to keep in mind what the community thought of their behaviour.
"I think they do want to see a better standard of behaviour and debate," Mr Brooks said.
But he held high hopes for the upcoming conscience vote debate on euthanasia, saying he expected it bring out the best in parliament.
Mr Brooks and others have highlight how the abortion debate in 2008 saw MPs at their best.
Premier Daniel Andrews said all MPs could be more courteous in parliament.
"I think the average person watching on whether it be school children in the gallery, or any Victorian really, would hope that we could always improve standards of behaviour," Mr Andrews said.
"I don't think you want a situation where it is timid environment or a forum that doesn't have that passion, but all of us could stand to be a bit more courteous on the floor of parliament."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nardella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Question Time</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Tim Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brooks</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Speaker Colin Brooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Fyffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals Leader Peter Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fyffe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
