<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436108257366184</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/movies/toni-collette-reveals-hilarious-worst-moment-making-muriels-wedding/news-story/6d4543a605b5dc68eedde7c1721bfc2f</url>
  <title>Toni's hilarious worst Muriel's Wedding memory</title>
  <content>
ACTOR Toni Collette has revealed her worst moment filming the 1994 Australian classic Muriel's Wedding - and it came during arguably the film's most iconic scene.
Collette played awkward 'ugly duckling' Muriel Heslop in the film, gaining 18kg for the role. Asked about the highs and lows of making her breakthrough film , Collette admitted that "I had to eat so much - I had to put on so much weight to play that beautiful girl."
But her worst day on set came when it was time for she and co-star Rachel Griffiths to film their iconic Waterloo dance routine, decked out in tight white satin ABBA jumpsuits in front of a live audience.
"I remember they changed the shooting day ... My period was due. I had to wear that white, very tight suit to do the Waterloo dance. But my period jumped and just went with it! That was confronting, that was confronting," she laughed.
Waterloo

Despite the wardrobe near-disaster, Collette said filming Muriel's Wedding was a "delicious experience" for a then-unknown 22-year-old actor.
"It absolutely changed my life, but when we were making it I had no idea if there was even going to be an audience. It was only my second movie and I was having fun, I was having the time of my life," she said.
Another of the film's stars, Gennie Nevinson, who played the homewrecking scarlet woman of Porpoise Spit, Deidre Chambers,  last year. Nevinson described Collette as "not very friendly" and said legendary actor Bill Hunter "couldn't remember the lines" - and she thought the comedy film was too sad to ever be a hit.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deidre Chambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gennie Nevinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porpoise Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collette</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muriel Heslop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muriel's Wedding</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nevinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni Collette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterloo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
