<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435979408346044</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/travel/news/bali-hotels-price-war-top-hotels-cutting-prices-by-50-a-night/news-story/5fc0722e07af0b3b16f6e57ab42d899f</url>
  <title>Why Bali is suddenly even cheaper</title>
  <content>
Fierce competition among Bali hotels is seeing accommodation prices plummet, with holiday-makers saving more than $50 a night this month compared to last month.
The sudden spike in Bali bargains has prompted travel giant  to issue a "price drop alert".

In July, the average nightly rate for hotels in Denpasar was $274, while this month, travellers can expect to pay just $215 on average, according to TripAdvisor's figures.
Just a fraction of that can score a stay at one of the island's top properties, with a $90 budget enough to secure one of the highest rated hotels according to TripAdvisor reviewers, .
With the midyear school holiday peak over, four and five-star hotels are waging in a price war to lure budget-conscious travellers - making now a perfect time for visitors to nab a bargain, according to TripAdvisor.
"August is one of the best months to visit Bali because weather is dry and cool," a TripAdvisor spokeswoman says.

Although this month is a standout for savings, it's part of an overall downward trend for Bali hotel prices as the island's resorts battle for tourist dollars.
It's not that tourists are abandoning Bali - far from it. According to booking site , demand for Bali has risen more than 550 per cent since 2011 and almost 20 per cent since 2015 - but it seems even a phenomenal rise in tourists flocking to the island cannot keep pace with the hotel development.
"Over the past six years, average flight prices to Bali dropped nearly 30 per cent to $549 and average accommodation has decreased almost 15 per cent to $145 per night, which is great news for travellers," says  managing director Michael Pearson.
Figures suggest Bali has so many hotel rooms it would need 92.5 million tourists a year to achieve 100 per cent occupancy, but the island recorded 11.15 million tourists in 2015.
Six new hotels opened in Bali in the first quarter of 2017 alone, with a further 34 hotels in the pipeline for completion by 2019,  show.
For now, tourists can expect the hotel price war to continue.
"If the anticipated supply in 2017 arrives ... the hotel market in Bali will continue to experience a tough time," .
The flip side is big savings for travellers, according to Expedia - with many hotels teaming up to offer attractive package deals in conjunction with flights to entice visitors to book with them.
"We are seeing savvy Aussies save even more by booking their hotel and flight together. Since 2012, demand for Bali packages has risen by nearly 185 per cent and this is our top tip for travellers - book your flight and hotel together to save even more," Pearson says.
"Take the October long weekend this year, we have return flights from Sydney, plus three nights at the four-star , which is amazing."
Despite budget airline Tigerair's withdrawal from Bali in early 2017, flights to the island remain affordable too.
"When Tigerair announced it would stop flying to Bali earlier this year, we saw a tiny increase in airfares from other carriers, given the drop in the overall number of seats available," Pearson says.
Meanwhile, other international destinations are rising in popularity among Aussies - with Jetstar even predicting "Vietnam has the potential to become as popular as Bali" when it this year.
But competition from other destinations is unlikely to detract from Bali, according to Pearson.
"With Jetstar now flying directly from Australia to Ho Chi Minh City, and cheap-as-chips flights to the likes of Hawaii opening up more affordable travel options from Australia, we expect to see Aussies expanding their wings and exploring new destinations. However, we don't think this will have a huge impact on Bali and it will continue to be a favourite for Aussie holiday-makers," Pearson says.
TRIPADVISOR'S TOP PICKS FOR AUGUST BARGAINS:
1.
Average nightly hotel price for August: $123. Opened last year, this hotel earns reviewers' praise for its "trendy and super knowledgeable staff with a great atmosphere".
2.
Average nightly hotel price for August: $108. Opened last year, this hotel is punching well above its official three-star rating. "The hotel felt very luxurious, and the beds were the best I've ever slept in," posted one TripAdvisor reviewer recently.
3.

Average nightly hotel price for August: $124. Reviewers say it's "very clean and comfortable, centrally positioned and good value."
4.
Average nightly hotel price for August: $90. Opened in 2016, the hotel has earned some rave reviews, such as: "staff are unbelievably friendly, the place is decorated to perfection and the restaurant food is absolutely incredible".
5.
Average nightly hotel price for August: $119. Reviewers rate its location highly. "Coming off the busy road through Sanur this hotel is a haven of tranquillity," says one.

For more travel news and inspiration sign up to .

Unable to retrieve weather information.

SYD
0h 0mSYD

Estimated flight time.  to get a more accurate estimation.

Most viewed

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denpasar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>mSYD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigerair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TripAdvisor</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expedia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRIPADVISOR'S TOP PICKS FOR AUGUST BARGAINS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ho Chi Minh City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
