<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435034515533021</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/06/07/51/chris-hadfield-astronaut</url>
  <title>Ground Control to Major Chris: Musical astronaut coming back to Australia</title>
  <content>
Canadian astronaut Chris Hadfield doesn't have a bucket list.
He thinks they can be a millstone around your neck, but I guess if you've been spent nearly 4000 hours in space and orbited the earth 26 hundred times, a bucket list is almost redundant.
Now, he enjoys looking at the stars from the ground up alongside his young granddaughter.
These days, the astronaut is more involved in talking about space than actually living in it, having retired from the space program in 2013 after more than two decades of service.
He is currently involved with a number of documentary series' as well making the rounds on the international speaking circuit which will bring him to Australia in two weeks.
But despite his aeronautical achievements, Hadfield is probably still best known for his galaxy rendition of David Bowie's Space Oddity performed while he captained the International Space Station a few years back.
The performance was actually his son's idea and garnered over seven million views online within days of being back on earth. When Bowie caught wind of it, he said "it was the most poignant version of the song ever created".
Music is still a big part of his life.

Speaking to 9news.com.au on the eve of his visit, Hadfield said he's just recorded some of his own songs on board a Russian icebreaker in the Arctic which he'll perform with the Vancouver Symphony - a far cry from the International Space Station.
He does keep his hand in the space program as well, as a consultant in the Canadian astronaut selection process.
But would he like to be back among the stars? Well, the spaceman said... "if you are offering to send me I'd be happy to oblige", but realistically he has stepped aside for the younger ones with the right stuff.
Hadfield said he truly wasn't envious as he was luckier than most having been one of the longest serving astronauts ever with his 21 years in the space program. Even Neil Armstrong was only an astronaut for eight.
But what about space travel for tourists and the dream of getting to Mars?
Hadfield said in 1917, people talked about commercial air travel the way we now talk about commercial space travel.
It was decades, even after the Wright Brothers famous flight, before air travel became an everyday reality. But here we are now, for a relatively low cost flying around the world in the same way we climb aboard a bus.
He said getting civilians into space is within our reach with people like Virgin's Richard Branson, Amazon's Jeff Bezos and Tesla's Elon Musk pushing the boundaries.
But the real challenge is not just getting them above the atmosphere which is legally defined as 100 kilometres up, but having them orbit the earth.
Hadfield says that takes 70 times the amount of energy and the risk is far greater.
It's the same as attempting to get people to Mars.
Hadfield says it's a lot farther than most people think, often on the other side of the sun and right now the technology to get people there just doesn't exist.

He said it was like canoeing on the Bay of Biscay, off the coast of France, and saying "let's go to Australia".
We have the boats, we have the paddles and we have the water but it's just not that simple.
"It's not that it won't happen, but we have lots to invent before we go and there's no rush or timeline other than human curiosity," Hadfield said.
And what about this talk that he's actually afraid of heights?
Hadfield said it's actually not heights he's afraid of but rather hitting the ground.
We should all be afraid of heights, he added, because a momentary lapse of attention to heights can kill you.
But he says there is a fundamental difference between fear and danger so he just makes sure he can't fall.
"It's impossible to fall from a space station even when you're outside because of the weightlessness so it's actually liberating...like you have super powers."

But back to that bucket list that he wants no part of.
Isn't there something he wants to do?
The astronaut said he truly just wants to learn and understand as many things as he can so he can help other people see the world...from his young granddaughter to those who will be in the audience here in Australia.
"I never wish I was somewhere else, it's such a waste of time. I enjoy the reality of where I am and where I'm lucky enough to have been."
You can see Chris at the following locations:
BRISBANE
Date: Tuesday 22 August at 7.30pm
Venue: Great Hall, BCEC
Bookings: 132 849 or ticketek.com.au
SYDNEY
Date: Thursday 24 August at 7.30pm
Venue: State Theatre
Bookings: 1300 139 588 or ticketmaster.com.au
MELBOURNE
Date: Friday 25 August at 7.30pm
Venue: Palais Theatre
Bookings: ticketmaster.com.au or 136 100
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Armstrong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Space Station</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday 25 August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mars</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hadfield</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vancouver Symphony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palais Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arctic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay of Biscay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday 22 August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday 24 August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin's Richard Branson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hadfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright Brothers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon's Jeff Bezos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla's Elon Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Chris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bowie's Space Oddity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
