<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435515551874800</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/world/north-korea-crisis-un-imposes-punishing-new-sanctions-following-missile-tests-20170805-gxq6vx.html</url>
  <title>North Korea crisis: UN imposes punishing new sanctions following missile tests</title>
  <content>
Washington: The United Nations Security Council has voted unanimously to impose the new sanctions on North Korea, banning exports that supply up to a third of the country's annual $US3 billion ($3.7 billion) earnings.
The US-sponsored resolution is the most punitive against the rogue state in 11 years and comes in response to North Korea's launch of two intercontinental ballistic missiles last month, activities prohibited under existing UN resolutions.Photo: AP
The sanctions ban North Korea's largest export, coal, along with exports of iron and iron ore, lead and lead ore, and seafood. Together, those exports amount to more than $US1 billion a year in income for Pyongyang.
The measure's unanimous approval was a diplomatic victory for the Trump administration and partly reflected growing impatience with North Korea by China. US President Donald Trump has repeatedly called on China to exert more pressure on its neighbour over its nuclear belligerence.

Whether Trump's badgering played any role in China's support for the resolution is unclear. But its willingness to enforce the resolution's provisions will be critical to its effectiveness.
China's ambassador to the United Nations, Liu Jieyi, hinted at his country's vexation with North Korea in his Security Council remarks after the vote. He urged North Korean authorities to "cease taking actions that might further escalate tensions".

But Mr Liu also criticised the US, calling for dismantlement of the THAAD missile defence system it has begun installing in South Korea.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

US Ambassador Nikki Haley told the council the vote showed Pyongyang that the world was united in seeking to end its nuclear and ballistic missile programs. But "we should not fool ourselves into thinking we have solved the problem," Mrs Haley said. "Not even close. The North Korean threat has not left us."Photo: AP
She said the US had no plans to decrease its military exercises with South Korea, despite calls from China and Russia to do so, in exchange for gradual deescalation of its prohibited weapons activities.
Both Beijing and Moscow, in casting their votes for the new sanctions, said they appreciated statements by US Secretary of State Rex Tillerson last week that the US does not seek North Korea's collapse, replacement of its government or "accelerated reunification" of the Korean peninsula, and has no intention of send troops there.Photo: AP
"Our hope is that the United States will translate these 'four no's' into a firm policy," Mr Liu told the council.
And he repeated THAAD would "not bring a solution" to the crisis."What it will do is to seriously undermine the strategic balance of the region."
China also called for the resumption of talks between North Korea, regional powers and the United States. Last Week, Mr Tillerson said Washington was interested in a "productive dialogue," but only on the basis of Pyongyang's acceptance of nuclear disarmament.
"We don't think having a dialogue where the North Koreans come to the table assuming they're going to maintain their nuclear weapons is productive," he said.
China  accounts for 90 per cent of North Korea's economic activity. Passage of the new resolution follows nearly a month of US-Chinese negotiations over the text, bolstered with Trump administration warnings that it was preparing to lodge unrelated complaints against Beijing at the World Trade Organisation.
It condemns the long-range missile tests, and reminds North Korea that tests of both the missiles and nuclear weapons are prohibited by previous resolutions.
In addition to banning exports, the resolution also prohibits all countries from increasing the number of North Korean labourers they employ, prohibits any new joint ventures and commercial agreements with North Korea, and increased investment in existing ventures.
The goal is to prevent North Korea's access to hard currency, which Mrs Haley and other delegates said are not used for the welfare of the North Korean people. The US had initially hoped to ban oil exports and additional banking and commercial penalties, which were opposed by China and Russia.
Although UN sanctions were first imposed in 2006 against North Korea, they have not prevented tests of five nuclear warheads and four long-range missile launches since then, including the two launches in July.
Washington Post, New York Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liu Jieyi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Haley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-sponsored</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Ambassador Nikki Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THAAD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Liu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Trade Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
