<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436103962398850</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:38</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/more-news/showdown-43-pride-prejudice-destiny-winner-takes-all/news-story/a2af56a7501b997178d15e8cd94cbb1a</url>
  <title>Showdown 43: Pride, prejudice, destiny</title>
  <content>
NOT since the "Ultimate Showdown" - their semi-final encounter almost 12 years ago - has an Adelaide Crows v Port Adelaide clash carried so much significance.
Adelaide, sitting top of the ladder, is aiming for a fifth consecutive Showdown victory, which would give it the lead on the head-to-head ledger, currently tied at 21-21.
More importantly, a win will take the Crows a step closer to a coveted top-two finish and a home qualifying final for the first time in five seasons. Port Adelaide, meanwhile, will be looking to thrive on its underdog status as it chases a top-four spot and the double chance.
The two sides have not played finals in the same season since 2007, when the Power went all the way to the Grand Final, only to lose to Geelong by 119 points.
More than 50,000 fans are expected to brave the wet and windy conditions for today's crunch match, which starts at 4.10pm.
The Bureau of Meteorology is forecasting the possibility of a thunderstorm and hail in the afternoon, possible heavy rainfall, and a maximum temperature of just 13C. Fans are urged to allow an extra 20 minutes to enter Adelaide Oval, where enhanced security inspections will be implemented in the wake of a flare being set off at the venue last month.
The Crows and Power will be hoping to avoid the off-field unpleasantness that has plagued the past two matches and earlier this season led to both clubs taking a united stance against racism.
Supporters from both sides will continue to speculate over the fitness of star small forward and Showdown specialist Eddie Betts, who had his appendix removed just 14 days ago, until Adelaide announces its final 22 an hour-and-a-half before the bounce.
There also will be anticipation over which Port player will tag Rory Sloane - the Showdown medallist the last time these two teams met in round three when the Crows won by 17 points. The battle lines are drawn, the time for talking is over. Who will be triumphant? It should be an epic game.
ARE YOU A SHOWDOWN SPECIALIST? Take our quiz then check the answers at the bottom of the page
1. Which team won the first Showdown and what was the margin?
2. Who are the current Adelaide and Port Adelaide captains?
3. When was the infamous fight at the Ramsgate Hotel?
4. Which players have won the most Showdown medals and how many did they each win?
5. Who described the 2005 Ultimate Showdown as a "dream final"?
6. Which three players have kicked a record seven goals in a Showdown?
7. Who was awarded the Phillip Walsh Medal in 2015?
8. How many Showdowns have ended in a draw?
9. What is the Showdown equivalent in Western Australia?

10. Who were the inaugural Showdown coaches?
11. What is the Showdown win-loss record since moving to Adelaide Oval?
12. Who was the leading goalkicker in the 2005 Ultimate Showdown?
13. Who are the only two players to have shared the Showdown Medal and in which year?
14. What is the longest winning streak in a Showdown?
15. Which five players have played for both Adelaide and Port Adelaide in the AFL?
16. When was the last Showdown played at Football Park?
17. Who kicked six goals in Adelaide's 58-point win in round 15 2012?
18. Andrew McLeod and Kane Cornes played in how many Showdowns each?
19. What was the margin in Showdown 42 earlier this season?
20. Who had a perfect 10-0 playing record in Showdowns?
SHOWDOWN BY THE NUMBERS
3931 - total score kicked by Adelaide in Showdowns
3692 - totals score kicked by Port Adelaide in Showdowns
570 - goals kicked by Adelaide in Showdowns
537 - goals kicked by Port Adelaide in Showdowns
511 - behinds scored by Adelaide in Showdowns
470 - behinds scored by Port Adelaide in Showdowns
21 - wins each for Adelaide and Port Adelaide in 42 Showdowns
53,698 - Showdown attendance record in round three, 2017
1,872,576 - total attendance in 42 Showdowns
100 - per cent coaching record for Don Pyke in three Showdowns
83 - the biggest Showdown margin (Adel 123 Port 40)
3 - the smallest Showdown margin (Adel 116 Port 113)
1139 - the total margin in 42 Showdowns
153 - the highest Showdown score (Port 23.15)
40 - the lowest Showdown score (Port 5.10)
33 - Showdown goals kicked by Taylor Walker (ranked no. 1)
31 - Showdown behinds scored by Warren Tredrea (ranked no. 1)
18 - Showdown goal assists by Scott Thompson (ranked no. 1)
380 - Showdown kicks by Andrew McLeod (ranked no. 1)
293 - Showdown handballs by Scott Thompson (ranked no. 1)
614 - Showdown disposals by Scott Thompson (ranked no. 1)
267 - Showdown contested possessions by Scott Thompson (ranked no. 1)
422 - Showdown uncontested possessions by Kane Cornes (ranked no. 1)
434 - Showdown hit-outs by Sam Jacobs (ranked no. 1)
124 - Showdown clearances by Scott Thompson (ranked no. 1)
162 - Showdown marks by Chad Cornes (ranked no. 1)
109 - Showdown inside 50s by Andrew McLeod (ranked no. 1)
45 - Showdown marks inside 50 by Warren Tredrea (ranked no. 1)
141 - Showdown tackles by Scott Thompson (ranked no. 1)
42 - Showdown contested marks by Chad Cornes (ranked no. 1)
69 - Showdown rebound 50s by Graham Johncock, Nathan Bassett and Troy Chaplin (ranked equal no. 1)
39 - Showdown free kicks awarded to Dean Brogan (ranked no. 1)
48 - Showdown free kicks awarded against Scott Thompson (ranked no. 1)
79 - Showdown 1 per cent efforts by Nathan Bassett and Ben Rutten (ranked equal no. 1)
14 - Showdown Brownlow votes by Josh Francou (ranked no. 1)
23 - Showdowns coached by Mark Williams (ranked no. 1)
QUIZ ANSWERS
1.Port Adelaide by 11 points 2. Taylor Walker and Travis Boak 3. 2002 4. Mark Ricciuto and Josh Francou have won three each 5. Chad Cornes 6. Peter Vardy, Tony Modra and Warren Tredrea 7. Scott Thompson 8. None 9. Western Derby 10. Malcolm Blight and John Cahill 11. Adelaide 5 Port Adelaide 2 12. Scott Welsh 13. Simon Goodwin and Shaun Burgoyne in 2005 14. Port Adelaide won seven in a row 15. David Brown, Ian Downsborough, Brett Chalmers, Matthew Bode and Brad Symes 16. 2013 17. Ricky Henderson 18. 27 19. Adelaide by 17 points 20. Josh Carr
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Vardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Modra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Derby 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rutten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Sloane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultimate Showdown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Symes 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Johncock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Bassett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Ricciuto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C. Fans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Burgoyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Thompson 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Blight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Tredrea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adel 116 Port 113</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Downsborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Tredrea 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Cornes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHOWDOWN SPECIALIST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Francou</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Brogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Thompson</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide 5 Port Adelaide 2 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Cornes 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Henderson 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Cahill 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adel 123 Port 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Goodwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port 23.15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Pyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Boak 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Cornes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McLeod</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Walsh Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Chalmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Chaplin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Welsh 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port 5.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Bode</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramsgate Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
