<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651434948616186370</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/sport/athletics/usain-bolt-takes-third-in-100m-final-behind-justin-gatlin-at-world-championships-20170805-gxq6h4.html</url>
  <title>American denies Bolt golden end to solo career</title>
  <content>
London: It seemed hardly fitting, but Usain Bolt did not go out as a champion  in what he insisted was his final individual race. Instead, he was beaten in the 100 metres at the world track and field championships.
Justin Gatlin of the United States took the gold medal instead, in a time of 9.92 seconds. Bolt finished third in 9.95, one-hundredth of a second behind the runner-up, Christian Coleman, another American.Photo: Matt Dunham
Gatlin has twice been banned in the past for testing positive to banned substances.
By the force of his talent and personality, Bolt has been the seminal figure in his troubled sport for nearly a decade, dominating the sprints at the world championships and the Olympics since 2008.
He still plans to compete on  Saturday in the 4x100-metre relay for Jamaica, but the heaviest lifting is now done unless Bolt, who will turn 31 later this month, changes his mind about retirement.
"My dad said he's going to give me a year off and then I'm going to come back, but I don't think so," Bolt said.

Though his rare defeat here in London Stadium was deflating, his career has been an against-the-odds joy ride at a time when track and field has been buffeted by doping and credibility crises. Though many of his rivals and some of his Jamaican compatriots have been suspended for violations, Bolt has never been sanctioned and has never tested positive for a banned substance.
He is one of three men  - the others are the Americans Carl Lewis and Maurice Greene  - who have won three world 100m titles. Shelly-Ann Fraser-Pryce, another Jamaican, has won three world titles in the women's 100m.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But no great runner has ever possessed Bolt's mix of race-day playfulness and ruthlessness. He has been as good at communicating with the big crowds who have paid to see him (and often only him) as he has been adept at shutting down all opposition on the grandest occasions.
He swept the 100 and the 200 at each of the past three Olympics, an unprecedented feat. He also has won four world titles in the 200, though he chose not to compete in that event, long his favourite, in London this year.
Since 2008, when he became a global star at the Beijing Olympics, he has lost only two individual races at a major championships. The first came in 2011, when he beat himself with a false start in the final of the 100 meters at the world championships in Daegu, South Korea.
The second came Saturday in London, in the same stadium where he won three gold medals at the 2012 Olympics.
Bolt has won as an overwhelming favourite, as he did at the world championships in 2009 in Berlin, where he set world records that still stand: 9.58 seconds in the 100 and 19.19 seconds in the 200.
He also has won  -  repeatedly  -  despite less-than-ideal preparation and legitimate concerns about his form.
He had run three 100m races this year before London, breaking 10 seconds in only one of them, when he won in 9.95 seconds in Monaco last month.
He was vulnerable, no doubt, but in the past, when it mattered most, he still found the speed and the will to remain the fastest man in the world. This time he faltered, but although he was left behind for a change, he is the one who leaves a void.
For Bolt's sport, filling his golden spikes will be a monumental challenge.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Dunham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maurice Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Gatlin of the United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelly-Ann Fraser-Pryce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beijing Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daegu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americans Carl Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
