<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435206314226268</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/moreland-toy-library-is-expanding-north-of-bell-st-and-looking-for-volunteers/news-story/fb5f0cf384eaf7d17c61434f2d3cb3b5</url>
  <title>Taking the toys to Pascoe Vale</title>
  <content>
THE Moreland Toy Library's popularity and expansion into a new branch in Pascoe Vale comes as no surprise to volunteers and members Tereza Candioto and Monique Zytnik.
For Ms Candioto, who moved to Australia from Brazil five years ago, the original library at the Scout Hall, 14a Jolley St, West Brunswick has opened up social opportunities for her and daughter Serena, 4, and saved her home from the clutter of unused and out of favour toys.
Being able to share toys, rather than spend money and resources on individual items for her child also ties in with her "environmental effort".
"When she grows out of (toys) I don't have to throw them out.
"It also teaches her sharing and to take care of her things," Ms Candioto said.
Monique Zytnik said joining the toy library after a six-year stint in Berlin had been a great way to reconnect with the community.
And having the large hall space next to the toy library where children could play provided some welcome relief from the four walls at home on wet days.
"You see people at the toy library you might see down the shops, with over 250 families as members it's quite a large community," she said.
The library has proved to be such a hit there's now an expansion underway over the Bell St border to Pascoe Vale next to the swimming pool and community hub, currently under construction.
president Lauren Holland said securing the new site was just the beginning.
"We've already started stockpiling toys for the new branch but I am sure you can imagine the sheer number of toys needed to run a toy library and this means not only fundraising but also purchasing, cataloguing, data entry and bagging of the toys, and we're mainly volunteer run so any help that our community can give can make a big difference," Ms Holland said.
The first Moreland Toy Library Pascoe Vale branch sub-committee meeting will take place on August 23 in Pascoe Vale.
To get involved contact committee co-ordinator Emma on 0406 114 617 or email  or go to
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pascoe Vale</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tereza Candioto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland Toy Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serena, 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Candioto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolley St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scout Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Brunswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monique Zytnik</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland Toy Library Pascoe Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
