<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436189861745365</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/towing-fees-to-be-capped-in-queensland/8778912</url>
  <title>Towing fees to be capped in Queensland after complaints about dodgy operators</title>
  <content>
Queensland's tow truck industry will be regulated and fees will be capped under a plan to crack down on dodgy operators.
The 22 recommendations come from former judge Michael Forde's independent investigation.
It was sparked by complaints that people who parked on private property were being charged exorbitant fees to get their cars back.
Mr Forde said fees, which often exceeded $500 should be capped at $250.
People would only be charged $150 if the car was returned to the person onsite, after being loaded onto a truck.

"The business plan is different now ... it won't be as profitable but they can still make a living if they're honest," Mr Forde said.
The investigation concluded that tow truck drivers who tow cars from private properties should be accredited and licensed.
People with criminal records could be banned from getting a license, and fines for flouting regulations would be increased.
"What we've tried to do is bring under the umbrella of the legislation the tow truck operators who presently feel they can do whatever they want to do," he said.
Under his proposal guidelines would be put in place to ensure signage at carparks is clear.

External Link:

The suburbs with the most complaints about questionable towing practices.
Acting Main Roads Minister Steven Miles said he would push for Cabinet to accept all the recommendations when it considered the report on Monday.
"What this does is make sure motorists won't be tricked, won't be ripped off, when their vehicle gets towed," Mr Miles said.
received hundreds of complaints, with more than half of those coming from inner north Brisbane suburbs such as of Fortitude Valley, Albion and Ascot.
The majority of complainants, 74.4 per cent, reported towing fees in excess of $500.
In the barrage of gripes that flowed in, there were numerous cases of cars being hoicked up on a tow truck just minutes after parking.
Others said warning signs were worn or not adequate, making them hard to see, especially at night.
One complainant's car was being towed about five minutes after being parked, and the owner jumped in to save it only to be wrestled out by four men.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ascot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortitude Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads Minister Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Forde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Forde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
