<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435635810959965</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/10/31/two-injured-as-crane-crashes-into-sydney-apartment-block</url>
  <title>Two injured as crane crashes into Sydney apartment block</title>
  <content>
Two people have been injured after a crane crashed into an apartment block in southern Sydney today.
Footage shows the crane leaning against the damaged building on Brodie Spark Drive at Wolli Creek, after it fell about 9.30am today. 
Paramedics treated two patients at the scene, one for a leg injury, who were then taken to St George Hospital.
Resident Simon Murphy told 9news.com.au he awoke to the noise of the crane smashing into the building, a day after he and his wife expressed concern about the machine's safety.
"There's some fairly significant damage to the side of the building, a lot of shattered glass on the floor," he said. 
Mr Murphy said he and his wife had been worried about the crane's stability.
"By mid-afternoon [yesterday], I said I can't believe that they've built that crane on that platform, and my wife and I discussed what would happen if it were to fall," he said.

Related Articles

The condition of the victims is not known, a NSW Ambulance spokesman said.
Police evacuated two buildings at the scene and have also established an exclusion zone, with road closures in place, a spokeswoman said. 
No one was in the crane at the time of the collapse, the spokeswoman confirmed. 
 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Spark Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
