<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435120414879581</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/indigenous-university-students-funding-program/8776026</url>
  <title>From prison to university: Live-in program for Indigenous students changing lives</title>
  <content>
Growing up, Marlon Johns rarely questioned his life of crime.
Enveloped in drugs, alcohol and violence before he had even hit his teens, it was the easiest course to follow.
But after 15 years behind bars, it was a conversation with an older Noongar man that made him question his behaviour.
"He was walking around the basketball court crying," Mr Johns said.
"He said he has got kids and grandkids and how he has been coming in and out of prison his whole life."
That man was Marlon Johns' future.
"It's either you are going to do something now with your life or you are going to be that old boy around the courts," he said.
The 26-year-old had heard about a live-in program being run at St Catherine's college in Crawley, helping Indigenous students achieve a tertiary education.

"I made contact with the college and they told me the doors are open ... if I want to apply myself," Mr Johns said.
It was the inspiration he needed to complete a number of courses and a diploma while still in prison.
He is now studying a Bachelor or Youth Work.
"Since the age of 12, in and out of prison, that would probably have been the easy option," he said.
"Without this place here for me I would probably strongly believe that I would be back in adult prison."
Statistics show Indigenous students struggle at university, with more than 50 per cent dropping out.
St Catherine's Dandjoo Darbalung program has lifted retention rates to more than 90 per cent, by using a model that has students living together with cultural support.
Indigenous students dropping out of university

It was started in 2012 by Lynn Webber, who ran a similar program at one of Perth's private schools.
While the Indigenous students were excelling at school, once they hit university they were dropping out.
"Where does a group of Indigenous kids belong at university?" Mrs Webber said.
"The Indigenous centres are great ... but that knocks off at five o'clock and what do they do after that?"
The 50 Indigenous residents at St Catherine's have their own cultural space and are supported by mentors and elders.
Cultural leadership training is also a focus. Students do not only support each other but also visit secondary schools with high Indigenous populations.
Mrs Webber and Mr Johns have just returned from Alice Springs where they visited six schools.
"I told a couple of kids it is really a no-brainer ... either you could drink and stuff like that or you could come to university and make a life for yourself," he said.
"I think the program has painted a bigger picture, that it is not just about us kids coming through the program, it is about years to come."
St Catherine's funded to double accommodation

Last month St Catherine's received $12.8 million from the state and federal governments to double its accommodation space.
"We would love every residential college in Australia to pick up this program," Mrs Webber said.
"So we can change overnight the whole graduation and retention rates of [Indigenous students] in Australia."
Mr Johns hopes to start a Masters degree at UWA next year.
" I was in a cell and thinking that I was going to be stuck in the system for the rest of my life," he said.
"With a phone call to this college my life just changed and has done a complete 360 - with a bit of hard work."
"I will never go back."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Work</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Webber</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynn Webber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Catherine's Dandjoo Darbalung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noongar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlon Johns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr John</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Catherine</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Live-in</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crawley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
