<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435120414879553</docid>
  <date>05/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/solis-on-kings-beach-is-almost-50-sold-in-just-over-two-months/news-story/e236ac97262fb9be919890e0ac799eb3</url>
  <title>Solis on Kings Beach is almost 50% sold in just over two months - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Luxury apartments on the Sunshine Coast are being snapped up with Solis on Kings Beach almost 50 per cent sold just two months after its sales launch.

THIS sites previous owner loved the location so much that he has bought back in, securing an apartment at on
Graham and Barbara Carter have spent 50 years lapping up the Sunshine Coast lifestyle and have just purchased a unit on a site previously owned by Mr Carter.

Mosaic's regional sales manager for the Sunshine Coast, Marcus Muir and previous site owner and new unit buyer Graham Carter meet on site at Solis.

"The location and architecture set this development apart from others but it's the people behind the development that really bring it all together," Mr Carter said.
"Mosaic do a great job from start to finish. They're the first decent company I have come across that really follow up and do what they say."
The couple said they were excited to have secured their own piece of paradise at Solis.
"Solis features a liveable design concept, and showcases the very best of the Sunshine Coast," Mr Carter said.
"The boutique concept also makes the project that much more appealing to owner-occupiers like us."

Solis by Mosaic

Being developed by Mosaic Property Group, the 33 two and three-bedroom luxury apartments, over eight levels, are crowned by three sub-penthouses and two exclusive penthouse apartments.
In just over two months since its launch the $23 million development is almost 50 per cent sold, drawing buyers from the Sunshine Coast, interstate and overseas with owner-occupiers leading the way.
Solis is the first multi-unit residential development on the Sunshine Coast to secure a six-leaf EnviroDevelopment certification, bolstering the 'green' appeal to buyers.
The project has ticked the EnviroDevelopment boxes for ecosystems, waste, energy, materials, water and community.
Locals are buying in with two of the penthouses being purchased by local buyers at $1.395 million each.

Solis by Mosaic

There are also various owner-occupiers who are relocating from Brisbane, Toowoomba and London, while international buyers looking to migrate back to the coast, have come from the United Kingdom, Macau and Singapore.
Mosaic Property Group's managing director Brook Monahan said the development was capitalising on the pent-up demand for luxury beachside apartments in Caloundra, particularly from owner-occupiers.
"Several of the purchasers at Solis were buyers who missed out on Cyan, our nearby boutique apartment project launched in December last year," Mr Monahan said.
"We've noticed increased owner-occupier activity in Solis with people keen to secure luxury, low-maintenance apartment living on the Sunshine Coast," he said.
"It is an active market with a shortage of boutique luxury apartments that appeal to both owner-occupiers and investors."

Solis by Mosaic

Apartment prices are one-bedroom from $405,000, two-bedroom from $520,000 and three-bedroom from $790,000.
The two penthouses and one sub-penthouse have sold, leaving two sub-penthouses with more than 200sq m of living space starting at $950,000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Monahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mosaic Property Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brook Monahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbara Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Muir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solis</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Carter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnviroDevelopment</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
