<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435850559326204</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/bushranger-brings-you-the-latest-territory-gossip/news-story/0ecc6dffe1aae9df65e97e80ec35400d</url>
  <title>Bushranger brings you the latest Territory gossip</title>
  <content>
Princess Scrumpy's return
AFTER an unsuccessful tilt at last year's Territory election, Princess Scrumpy has licked her wounds and entered the race for Darwin Council. Of all the places in Australia, Darwin would probably be the most likely to give a pooch wearing a onesie a shot at public office.
Corflute mystery
THE corner of Dick Ward Drive and Totem Rd is one of the most popular spots in Darwin for council hopefuls to place their corflutes. Almost every candidate's face was there bar one notable exception - Mick Palmer. But come Tuesday morning one of Bushie's spies noticed all of the other corflutes had disappeared and in their place was Mick's smiling face. It's believed one alderman called Mick to see if he knew anything about the disappearing corflutes - he didn't.
Fat cats dine out
REMEMBER the NT Government's promise to cut back on fat cat salaries? Well it's created a whole-of-government technology leadership position to spearhead its digital agenda. The Department of Corporate and Information Services (DCIS) will get an executive director to lead the Territory's new Office of Digital Government. The successful applicant gets a fixed four-year contract with an annual salary of $246,537.
New administrator
TALK on who will replace His Honour the Honourable John Hardy AO as the next Northern Territory administrator is hotting up. Latest names being put about include Sommerville chief executive officer Vicki O'Halloran and Darwin International Airport chief executive Ian Kew.
Departing tourists
WHAT'S happening in the Government's tourism department? The Government has been advertising for a general manager of marketing, replacing Jo Smallacombe, and Bushie hears another key long-term member of management will soon be gone.
Build a bridge
STILL on tourism, its board is still scratching its head over why chairman Michael Bridge, who has so much experience in the aviation industry, was not included in recent airline discussions in China. Bushie understands he was available.
ABC fun
TAXPAYERS have forked out big time for a bunch of ABC heavyweights to make their way to Darwin for business ... Bushie wonders if they will get to the lavish Darwin Cup Ball or the Darwin Cup races on Monday? Oh, that's right, they've come up for Garma.
Delia's finger on the pulse
FORMER ALP Opposition leader Delia Lawrie is keeping close tabs on the Gunner Government. Bushie knows of at least two newly elected backbenchers in regular contact with the disendorsed member for Karama. Attorney-General Natasha Fyles switched camps to lead Labor's Left after Lawrie was dumped.
Lucky sevens
DARWIN Corporate Park Cup Day had a lucky feel to it on Wednesday. Amazingly, the four quaddie legs were all won by horses carrying the No.7 saddlecloth. The quaddie paid $2514 on UBET but $2182 jackpotted, meaning hardly anyone was lucky enough to scoop the pool. For those who believe in omens, No.7 in tomorrow's Darwin Cup is Harrebs Time. Good luck!
Men's club
THE annual Carbine Club Darwin Cup luncheon attracted around 530 people again this year. Popular former Darwin ABC radio presenter and now South Australian political minder Kevin Naughton was back in town as MC. It was his 25th year in the role. The standouts in the crowd were the two women who showed courage in being at the very blokey event.
Little legend
ALSO at the Carbine lunch was four-time Cox Plate-winning jockey Brent Thomson, who won the $14,000 main raffle prize of an all-expenses-paid trip to the AFL grand final. He gave the prize back to be auctioned off to help the Carbine Club raise more funds for the NT sporting community.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Scrumpy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General Natasha Fyles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALP Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's Left</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bushie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick Ward Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sommerville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox Plate-winning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Cup Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Corporate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gunner Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DCIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Smallacombe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Digital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delia Lawrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Information Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN Corporate Park Cup Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki O'Halloran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Totem Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Kew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bridges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Naughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carbine Club Darwin Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carbine Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honourable John Hardy AO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrebs Time</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
