<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435472602201420</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/whats-small-screen-week/3209229/</url>
  <title>What's on the small screen this week</title>
  <content>
RICHARD Roxburgh returns to our screens tonight, reprising his role as Roger Rogerson more than 20 years after he originally portrayed the killer cop.

Toni Colette stars opposite Roxburgh as Rogerson's wife in the mini-series, which continues on Monday.

In the realm of reality TV, the drama continues on Australian Survivor and The Bachelor, plus Marco Pierre White puts a crop of Aussie celebrities through their paces in the new series Hell's Kitchen Australia.

Hamish and Andy also hear another ripper yarn on True Story.

Here are this week's highlights of the small screen and why you should see them:

Sunday August 6: Blue Murder - Killer Cop, Seven, 8.30pm

Roger Rogerson struggles to make a living in a world that's rapidly changing, caught between the pressures of criminals, police and a love that might save him.

Why you should watch: Richard Roxburgh reprises his heralded portrayal of Australia's most notorious former detective Roger Rogerson in this two-part mini-series and he's joined by all-star cast including Toni Collette, Matt Nable, Dan Wyllie, Emma Booth and Aaron Pedersen.

Monday August 7: Australian Survivor, Ten, 7.30pm

Tensions run high on day 12, as the castaways endure further wind and rain, struggling to maintain morale without fire and adequate shelter. As fires are extinguished, so are crucial alliances, with one tribe scrambling to organise a spectacular blindside and the other growing increasingly wary of a potential immunity idol hidden within the group.

Why you should watch: There's plenty of drama as the competition ramps up in Samoa. A lengthy immunity challenge will test the tribemates' endurance, and two castaways will cement their ability to outplay and outlast the others.

Tuesday August 8: True Story with Hamish and Andy, Nine, 8.40pm

This true story follows Phil, who thought he'd taken a cushy job on a luxury resort in the Kimberleys. Instead, he finds himself on a run-down cattle station in the middle of nowhere, hosting two French millionaires on a holiday from hell.

Why you should watch: Set in the Outback, this episode boasts some of the best production values to date and Damien Garvey is hilarious as Phil.

Wednesday August 9: The Bachelor, Ten, 7.30pm

Two bachelorettes find themselves on a dreaded double date. Later, at the cocktail party, competition for Matty tips one girl over the edge, resulting in a shocking meltdown and a dramatic rose ceremony.

Why you should watch: This year's bachelorettes are more intense than ever before so this double date is likely to be even more awkward. And if that wasn't enough drama, who has a freak out at the rose ceremony?

Thursday August 10: Why Are We Getting So Fat?, SBS, 8.35pm

Cambridge geneticist Dr Giles Yeo believes that for many obese people, simply eating less is a lot harder than you might think - and he is taking a road trip around the UK and America to uncover why. He meets the real people behind some of the more shocking newspaper headlines, and through their stories, reveals surprising truths which dispel commonly held myths about obesity.

Why you should watch: Forget The Biggest Loser - we need science to help tackle the issue of obesity.

Friday August 11: Naked, Netflix

Rob Anderson (Marlon Wayans) is all set to marry the girl of his dreams, but can't quite get to the altar. Every time he comes close, he finds himself waking up naked in his hotel elevator, forced to relive the beginning of his wedding day over and over again.

Why you should watch: This original Netflix film is a bit of modern take on Groundhog Day and is a remake of the 2000 Swedish film Naken.

Saturday August 12: Compass - The Staffroom, ABC, 6pm

In this three-part documentary series, three high schools give Compass unfettered access into their classrooms and staffrooms to find out what makes teachers tick. Presented by Jane Caro, well known for her interest in education, The Staffroom reveals what really goes on in the teachers' hidden sanctuary.

Why you should watch: Focusing on the experience of six teachers, Jane explores what drives them, what defeats them and what inspires them, busting some myths along the way.

Weather Bureau backtracks on severe storm prediction
DAILY'S historical books are stirring up memories.
RESPONSIBILITY Theory is helping young students shine.
Road cut off after rollover latest in string of Coast crashes
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
It sold 35,000 copies in its first month
Pauline Hanson declares latest reports another 'witch hunt'
Celebrity chef accuses doctors of being in love with bread
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getting So Fat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni Colette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Wyllie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Pedersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Groundhog Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Giles Yeo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine, 8.40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Compass</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Booth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Nable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlon Wayans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hell's Kitchen Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Garvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>True Story</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggest Loser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Caro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Killer Cop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS, 8.35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni Collette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten, 7.30</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
