<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436280056059302</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/nsw/buildings-evacuated-after-crane-collapses-20170806-gxq7al.html</url>
  <title>Home units evacuated in Wolli Creek after crane collapses onto penthouse</title>
  <content>
A Wolli Creek resident has described the dramatic scenes as a crane operator attempted to rescue the driver of the crane that crashed into a block of apartments on Sunday morning.
"The man from the white crane, he jumped over to the rooftop of the penthouse. So they (the second crane) went to the rooftop and picked him up," Felicia Nguyen said.
The rescue attempt came after a crane that is believed to have been in the process of being set up fell backwards onto a building behind it. The crane was anchored to an apartment block that is currently under construction.
The crane slammed into the penthouse apartment, causing structural damage to the upper levels and roof of the building.Photo: Felicia Nguyen
"It was the penthouse and it just crushed the black balcony. All the glass fell out onto the road and that's why they blocked the road from the station to that building."
Emergency Services are currently assessing the scene and are taking caution so as not to cause further damage to the impact building or surrounding buildings.

"We currently have search and rescue teams from Fire and Rescue in attendance and in consultation between them and an engineer, they'll have a look at the extent of the damage before we can actually start looking at a plan to remove the crane." Superintendent Josh Turner from Fire and Rescue NSW said.
"We have a secondary mobile crane on site which will obviously be required to take the weight of the crane and be an integral part of the removal process. But we won't do that until we ensure that all areas are safe around it and no further damage is done by removing the crane."Photo: Felicia Nguyen
While there is structural damage to the building, Mr Turner assured residents that there is no threat of the building collapsing.
"No, the building itself is quite stable, the damage is just up to the roof area."Photo: Sally Du
There are concerns that the crane may shift position and fall onto the street or surrounding buildings. Four buildings have been evacuated.
Mr Turner was not sure what caused the crane to collapse.
Paramedics treated three people at the scene for minor injuries. They are all in stable conditions.
Emergency services have closed the roads surrounding the area.
Train services have also been affected by the incident. 
No trains are running between Central and Turrella on the T2 Airport Line, the Transport Management Centre said. Buses are being organised to operate between Sydenham and Central.
Passengers are advised to listen to announcements, check indicator boards and allow plenty of additional travel time or consider an alternate mode of transport.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>T2 Airport Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felicia Nguyen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Du</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Management Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turrella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rescue NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Josh Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
