<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436413200046600</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/energy/origin-energy-putting-customers-in-the-picture-on-use-20170805-gxq6ib.html</url>
  <title>'Find a way' - Origin boss in plea to Canberra on energy</title>
  <content>
Energy giant Origin will roll out new technology allowing customers to track which appliances in their homes are using power as part of a deepening trend that sees retailers working more closely with consumers.
In partnership with American firm Bidgely, Origin will shortly begin trialling the new solution with 5000 customers in Victoria so they can see where they are using power and adjust their consumption.

Up Next

Maximising your solar panels

02:12

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Another headache for Turnbull

Questions have been raised about Malcolm Turnbull's leadership amid backbench angst over the Finkel report into energy security and prices.

In a highly competitive market the move is one that allows Origin to differentiate its offering from other retailers and also encourages consumers to moderate their usage at peak times.
"We see a future for energy that is both smarter and cleaner," Origin chief executive Frank Calabria told Fairfax Media, in an interview where he renewed calls for action on a clean energy target from Canberra..Photo: Supplied
"We really do see that the consumer experience is going to change.If we are truly customer-focused and in the business for the long term it is going to be for us to find solutions for them and create a relationship and trust over the long term."
The system works by examining the unique signatures of appliances in the houses and then matching that with environmental factors such as temperature to give a picture of major uses within a house without the need for fitting hardware .

Customers can also monitor usage through a smartphone app and will receive updates on usage.
"It has got great promise to give greater insight to our customers. We want people to help understand where their energy is going ... we are really trying to help people get that greater insight," Mr Calabria said.Photo: Mathew Dunckley
Abhay Gupta, chief executive of Bidgely said, strong competition had driven retailers to look for ways to get an edge.
"The pressure to keep customers happy and retain their loyalty is paramount."
The closer relationship between customers and retailers also helps pave the way towards a more "behind the meter" approach to managing power demand as flagged by new head of the Australian Energy Market Operator Audrey Zibelman.
"That may well be one of the more efficient ways to manage our demand peaks," Mr Calabria said.
We think it is a package of 50
Origin boss Frank Calabria

More broadly, Mr Calabria urged the government to get on with implementing the Finkel energy review's recommendations in full to provide policy certainty as the industry sought to meet expectations on reliability, affordability and sustainability.
So far the government has backed 49 of the recommendations but become bogged on the last, and most controversial, measure of a  clean energy target
"We think it is a package of 50," Mr Calabria said.
"We are strongly encouraging that government make decisions to move forward on that basis. It allows us to set the road map. We have got to get on with bringing it to reality. It has become a difficult decision for government, we just continue to encourage them that they find a way."
Origin is due to report its full-year results later in August and investors will be looking for a promised update on the spin-off of the new Lattice business.
Mr Calabria said the transaction was still "on track" for completion this year either via a float or a trade sale.
"It is progressing well," he said, adding that he felt there should be strong demand for a business with access to the east coast gas market with contracted supply deals and development opportunities."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Calabria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Calabria</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathew Dunckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abhay Gupta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bidgely</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Energy Market Operator Audrey Zibelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
