<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435987998280734</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/eviction-fears-at-martin-places-tent-city-as-politicians-battle-over-responsibility-20170806-gxq7y4.html</url>
  <title>Eviction fears at Martin Place's 'tent city' as politicians battle over responsibility </title>
  <content>
While authorities have drawn straws over who should uproot Martin Place's homeless encampment its residents have slept uneasily, fearing an eviction and an uncertain future.
"What the powers-that-be have done is put fear into one of the most marginalised groups in Australian society," Camp organiser Lanz Priestley said late on Saturday.

Up Next

Crane crashes onto Wolli Creek penthouse

00:32

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Tent city inappropriate: Berejiklian

NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian calls on Sydney mayor Clover Moore to use her powers to move on the large group of tents in Martin Place.

"There is a fear in the camp that something is going to happen, whether it's the police, state or local governments," he said.
Police Commissioner Mick Fuller and NSW Social Housing Minister Pru Goward urged Sydney City Lord Mayor Clover Moore to resolve the issue at crisis talks on Friday.

Ms Moore said the camp wouldn't be dismantled until she was assured there was a long-term housing solution for the residents.
But Mr Fuller indicated he wanted a resolution by the end of the weekend - and that placed the camp's residents on edge.

As evening fell on Saturday, Mr Priestley tweeted "All good at Martin Pl. Que sera sera". The camp looked like it would survive another night - and on Sunday morning, the camp remained.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

He felt it unlikely police would be the ones to forcibly uproot the settlement, given their history of treating the campers with courtesy.Photo: Michele Mossop
"The police are cognisant enough to know people have nowhere else to go," he said.
"This (camp) reduces other areas of crime.Photo: John Veage
"They came through a full three days beforehand to tell us their operational plan the last time they moved us."
On Sunday morning, Premier Gladys Berejiklian and Ms Goward released a statement calling on Ms Moore to act on the issue at the City of Sydney council meeting on Monday night.
If they don't act, the NSW Government will take appropriate action to resolve this issue for the homeless people and the people of Sydney.
Premier Gladys Berejiklian

"It has become increasingly clear that Clover Moore has no interest in resolving this issue and serving her ratepayers, but would rather play political games," Ms Berejiklian said.
"We call on councillors of the City of Sydney to do their jobs and move against this blatant act of politicking at their council meeting on Monday night.Photo: Michele Mossop
"If they don't act, the NSW Government will take appropriate action to resolve this issue for the homeless people and the people of Sydney.
"The NSW Government should not be required to do the job of council, but in extreme circumstances where the Lord Mayor will not do what is required and uses public property and people's lives to make a statement, we may be forced to do so.
"It is disappointing that vulnerable people are being exploited by a few people who are engaged in a political protest. The NSW Government is exploring all options available to it to resolve this issue."
Dubbed the Mayor of Martin Place, Mr Priestley said camp organisers had an obligation to continue to provide safety, shelter, food and support to the residents, regardless of the talks going on behind closed doors.
"Touch wood someone will consult with us at some point along the line," he said.
"They haven't so far."
Mr Priestley is concerned about the few lines of dialogue which have emerged from the discussions so far.
"I laughed when they started to call it a protest - protesters go home," he said.
"But changing the narrative, getting people on board with the idea of this being a protest makes it political.
"They can be seen to smash a protest, they can't be seen smashing a community of homeless people."
There are reports temporary housing has been offered to those living in the camp but a resident said many had refused because there was no guarantee of long term accommodation.
Fairfax Media, AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Social Housing Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz Priestley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Pl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor of Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney City Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Veage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHELE MOSSOP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
