<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436065307692860</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836163/time-out-in-the-illawarra-social-photos/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Time out in the Illawarra: social photos</title>
  <content>
Time out in the Illawarra: social photos

Ash Hillier, Sophie McNamara, Maddie Phair, Paige Reid, Chelsea Green, Sorrell Handforth and Ash Green at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Jarrod Sainsbury, Zane Richardson, Brady Anderson and James Moore at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Ben Nasralla, Danny Nasralla, Ken White, George James, Damien Challenor, Marco Bersell and Laurie Denyer at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Sue Phair, Karen Staunton, Valerie Pemperton, Katrina Robson and Jo Hansforth at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Jarrod Corbeski, Rellim Simpson, Riley Shaw, Scott Robinson and Jake Crea at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Alex Gardener, Anthony Richter, Cameron Dunstan, David Brown and Paul Knight at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Nathan Perks and Kosta Skrapis at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Zoe Pantalon and Mishelle Toms at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Kieren Fernie and Sam Solberg at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Mark Tindall, Terence Cuthbert and Steven Warner at Kembla Grange Racecourse.

Greg Peddie and Logan Peddie at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Joe Wilson at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Sebastian Barran and Brock Goroch at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Frank Kennedy and Helen Kennedy at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Kristy Mitrevski, Nelia Mitrevski and Kayla Mitrevski at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Andrew Roseworne and Craig Roseworne at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Katia Dwarte and Glenn Dwarte with Dee Milenkovic at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Dakota D'Amico, Alberta D'Amico, Dylan D'Amico and Rob D'Amico at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Geoff Jakeman and Annie Sothaya at St George Illawarra Dragons home game against Manly at WIN Stadium.

Scott Mawney, Wolfey Thiele, Joanne Thiele, Melissa Irish, Kandice Byrnes, David Maddalena and Scott Robertson at M2M Challenge 2017.

Renee Minotto-Specia, Cathy Tagliaferro and Angelo Tagliaferro at M2M Challenge 2017.

Rob Verheyen, Adel Jones and Raquel Moreno at M2M Challenge 2017.

Garry Forrest, Leola Walter and Col Walter at M2M Challenge 2017.

Joel Beck, Rebecca Beck, Kelly Pucillo, Melissa Todev and Ashlee Luis at M2M Challenge 2017.

Susan Wardle, Jennifer Menchin and Jo Munn at M2M Challenge 2017.

Erin Vasiliou, Bernadette Branodski, Patti Demagante and Kim Byrne at M2M Challenge 2017.

Karyn Hamilton, Peter Parker and Laura Mathiessen at M2M Challenge 2017.

Lee Copley, Peter Buckley and Kate Hajduk at M2M Challenge 2017.

Jade Smith and Crystal Smith at M2M Challenge 2017.

Lisa Devine, Lynne Carey and Julie Espinosa at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Dean Sheeran and Anita Banber at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Hayley Mahomey and Katey Mahomey at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Kirra Moule, Dolly Moule, Tim Moule, Joan McLachlan and Sandy Glover at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Emma Cappetta, Marianne Spinelli and Jacqueline Boyton at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Stephen King, Alexandra King and Liz De Graff at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Colleen Eringa, Caroline Morrow, Michelle Mania and Dolly Moule at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Steven Clark and Doris Clark at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Courtney Clark, Dean Scanlen and Rebecca Scanlen at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Kylie Disher, Jenny Whittington and Lew Whittington at the M2M Challenge 2017.

Shahid Akhund and Pippa Burns at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Greg Farmer and Chris Puplick at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Peter McLennan and Sally McLennan at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Ian Gillespie, Louella McCarthy and Stephen Hampton at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Auntie Barb Nicholson, Fabienne Else and Margie Jantti at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Natalia Hanley and Hannah Morris at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Phillippa Webb, David Nolan and Lynda Nolan at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Susan Jones and Hamish Graham at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Dr Theresa Larkin, Professor Alison Jones and John Larkin at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Dr Kath Weston and Stuart Loveday at the Caring for the Incarcerated exhibition opening at the University of Wollongong.

Sirintip Deakhamsarn, Grace Ribergaard and Tim Ribergaard at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

Debra Ebbs, Phyllis Beasley and Graham Ebbs at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

Jenny Angwin and Wayne Partridge at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

Jill Adamson, Barbara Gibb, Mannie Santos and Evelyn Dach at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

Rose Lewis, Lynn Brown, Lesley Pearson and Peter Pearson at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

Sarah Davis, Amy Davis and Kylie Vanzyl at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

Zali Sorensen, Jed Sorensen and Jacinta Sorensen at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

John Polley, Carol Polley and Margaret Dean at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

John Robinson, Judith Robinson and Mark Robinson at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

Dennis Spenceley, Wendy James and Paul James at the surprise 90th birthday party for Grace Ribergaard at the Warilla Bowling Club.

Anne Gleeson and Karen Whiting at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Dianne Keech and Sharon Sackett at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Remond Borg and Tracey Knight at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Ric Stewart, Helen Stewart, Raelene Bahr, Susan Houghton and Cheryl Perry at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Michael Brewster-Robinson, Brenda Devine, Shani Horrell, Elizabeth Jackson, Linda Twyford and Joanne Hunt at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

John McEntee, Natalie Pulley, Raymond Perry, Yasmin Perry and Tonia Martire at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Lynda Walsh, Agata Phillips, Shelian Stewart, Lisa Kurt and Jacki Hornung at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Justine Parrish, Donna Jones and Nicole Condran at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Tanya Sperring and Radmila Avramovic at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Kath Grant and Linda Curtis at the surprise retirement party for Raelene Bahr at the Albion Park Bowling Club.

Tim Dennis, Felicity Ninness and Caroline Pontello at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Ryan North, Craig North and Charmain North at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Belinda Biondich, Kathleen Keys and Donald Keys at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

David Brown and Dave Cavanagh at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Natasha Baraber, Rachel Parker and Tora Parker at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Pam Berrell and Karen Mors at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Erica Oakley and Sandra Petersen at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Braden Perry and Jerome Des Preaux at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Jeanette Prout and Rochelle Evans at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Peter Nelson and Rei Trealer at the opening of the Affordable Art & Artisan Market at Wollongong Art Gallery.

Mary Kirkwood and Inta Scully at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Tennille Dewhurst and Karen Davies at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Adam Ernst and Mija Crasnich at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Roisin Ward, Gemma Davies, Maddison Theophanou, Abby Dewhurst, Lily Theophanou and Poppy Black at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Gavin Black and Kate Edney at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Jordan Cruz, Cheryl Robinson and Taylor Cruz at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Magen Gonzalez, Mackenzie Cruz, Jorja Gosek and Amber Powell at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Geoff Poll, John Fletcher, Joanne De Jongh and Greg Hancox at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Jonah Lopes, James Lopes, Jessica Lopes and Jacqui Lopes at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

Hayden Bowmaker and Karen Bowmaker at the Mt Kembla Heritage Festival.

exit
Have you been snapped out and about in the Illawarra? Spot anyone you know?
For photo sales call 4221 2273
If you have a social event you'd like the Mercury to cover email events@illawarramercury.com.au with details of the event and a contact number.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pam Berrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Cappetta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Larkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Dunstan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Beck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justine Parrish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poppy Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Sheeran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeanette Prout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannie Santos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayden Bowmaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Keys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felicity Ninness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Bowmaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Bersell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonia Martire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pippa Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karyn Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shani Horrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Hansforth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dakota D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Vanzyl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louella McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynda Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Curtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Challenor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Brewster-Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Barran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rei Trealer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Poll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Peddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Crea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieren Fernie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patti Demagante</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paige Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheryl Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Hampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warilla Bowling Club</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M2M Challenge 2017</name>
    <count>20</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynn Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Angwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Edney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rellim Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braden Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Munn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacki Hornung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Dean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natasha Baraber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Vasiliou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colleen Eringa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Moule</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya Sperring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Dwarte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Mania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raquel Moreno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park Bowling Club</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol Polley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Maddalena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalia Hanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqueline Boyton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Verheyen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernadette Branodski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shahid Akhund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judith Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evelyn Dach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy Tagliaferro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fabienne Else</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Cruz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Devine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Hajduk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Farmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Disher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Whittington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Col Walter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandy Glover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Jakeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN Stadium</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Artisan Market</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Cavanagh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Minotto-Specia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Whiting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Morrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Ernst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terence Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raelene Bahr</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Beck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sorrell Handforth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesley Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Wardle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally McLennan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtney Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auntie Barb Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brady Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Cruz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Ebbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinta Sorensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raymond Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui Lopes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adel Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rochelle Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Pontello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackenzie Cruz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Pulley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynda Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Thiele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anita Banber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Kirkwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristy Mitrevski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Biondich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla Grange Racecourse</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Mors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Phair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dolly Moule</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Condran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radmila Avramovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Lopes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Puplick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annie Sothaya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magen Gonzalez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jade Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gemma Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonah Lopes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Mawney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Kurt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirra Moule</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Mahomey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Adamson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathleen Keys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberta D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inta Scully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roisin Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie McNamara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolfey Thiele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Goroch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tora Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARK ROBINSON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phyllis Beasley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Mathiessen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirintip Deakhamsarn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Scanlen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Kath Weston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amber Powell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Pucillo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddie Phair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ric Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doris Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mija Crasnich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Lopes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zali Sorensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Tindall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Dennis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Sainsbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Perks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agata Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charmain North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Richter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Theresa Larkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jed Sorensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McEntee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dee Milenkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lily Theophanou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Roseworne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brenda Devine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kandice Byrnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Espinosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerome Des Preaux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amico</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbara Gibb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley Shaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margie Jantti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lew Whittington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zane Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Staunton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Denyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Twyford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katrina Robson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Peddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Ribergaard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remond Borg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Partridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Copley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Alison Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jorja Gosek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Menchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marianne Spinelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Scanlen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Gleeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddison Theophanou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillippa Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Hancox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz De Graff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katey Mahomey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erica Oakley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashlee Luis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yasmin Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennille Dewhurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leola Walter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debra Ebbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Corbeski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Art Gallery</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Nasralla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra Dragons</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valerie Pemperton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Spenceley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Houghton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kosta Skrapis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mishelle Toms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Petersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter McLennan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abby Dewhurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheryl Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Gardener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne De Jongh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Nasralla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Loveday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Affordable Art</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Pantalon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Solberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelian Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelo Tagliaferro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katia Dwarte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayla Mitrevski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelia Mitrevski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Kembla Heritage Festival</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grace Ribergaard</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Sackett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Todev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Polley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Hillier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Roseworne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynne Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dianne Keech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
