<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436580703772431</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/personal-finance/superannuation-and-smsfs/coalitions-housing-budget-measures-come-under-attack-20170804-gxppww</url>
  <title>Coalition's housing budget measures come under attack</title>
  <content>
Industry superannuation funds have blasted two of the government's key budget measures designed to ease housing market pressure on the grounds they either have "serious" administrative issues, will fail to meet their objective or are poorly targeted.
The Australian Institute of Superannuation Trustees said Treasurer Scott Morrison's proposed was inconsistent with the purpose of super, could result in lower retirement incomes for retirees and would likely suffer from a low-take up.
Announced in the May budget, the proposed home saver scheme will allow first-home buyers to use up to $30,000 of voluntary super contributions to place a deposit on a house or apartment. Members will be able to withdraw a maximum of $30,000 of contributions, plus the earnings generated from those savings, from July 1, 2018, under the plan.
"AIST has a number of significant reservations about this measure," the association says in a submission to Treasury.

"While we recognise the need for governments to do more to help young people enter the housing market, we don't think tinkering with super is the answer and, in any case, the measure is likely to have minimal impact. The measure is at odds with the sole purpose test, it's confusing for consumers and there are significant implementation hurdles that could lead to all sorts of unintended consequences," AIST chief Eva Scheerlinck said.

Poor policy

Union-backed super funds argued that another budget measure which will  after they reach the age of 65 was poor policy. The amount  that can be injected into super is three times the annual limit for after-tax contributions, but the home must have been owned for at least 10 years. The sale proceeds will be included in the means testing for the aged pension.
"While the downsizing proposal does provide an additional superannuation benefit to some people, it is not well targeted and as such is not good policy," the AIST writes in its submission, obtained exclusively by The Australian Financial Review.
"This measure benefits homeowning Australians aged 65 and over who probably won't be eligible to receive the age pension, because they have too many assets, and who are able to put $300,000 of the proceeds into super," the AIST says. 

It said the measure was at odds with a regime designed to limit the amount of money that can be held in tax-friendly super accounts and was unfair because retirees using this measure would not be forced to meet the so-called work test, while retirees who otherwise make contributions will still be required to satisfy the test. The work test stipulates that individuals between the age of 65 and 74 must work for at least 40 hours over 30 consecutive days in the financial year in which they wish to make a super contribution.
Ms Scheerlinck recommended the proceeds from sale of the family home be exempt from the assets test for the age pension.
The AIST said the first home savers scheme was complex for consumers to understand and would be difficult for some employers to help administer. Only voluntary contributions are allowed to be used under the proposed model, yet some employers, when sending their employees' contributions to a super fund, do not distinguish between compulsory and voluntary, or salary sacrifice, contributions.

 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eva Scheerlinck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Superannuation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIST</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Scheerlinck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1, 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Union-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
