<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436451854752544</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/football/cheapskate-manchester-city-star-pays-hooker-for-sex-and-disputes-5000anight-fee/news-story/22c2f1e17b9df73f2a5641d1306145df</url>
  <title>'Cheapskate' soccer star's hooker romp</title>
  <content>
A CHEAPSKATE Manchester City soccer star had sex with a $5000-a-night hooker while on a pre-season US tour - and then refused to pay her full fee.
Raheem Sterling, 22, bedded the Kim Kardashian-lookalike in Los Angeles last month but disputed the prostitute's fee after the pair had sex, before later paying her cash in an envelope.
Sterling, who earns nearly $300,000 a week, sent a string of angry WhatsApp messages haggling about the cost before finally getting a Man City fixer to hand over about $2500 for the prostitute,  reports.
"Raheem may be a millionaire but he is a rude cheapskate. He seemed to assume that he would be able to just sleep with me and not pay," the sex worker told Britain's The Sun.
"Considering how much he earns that's pretty cheap."
Sterling later contacted the woman saying he was too drunk to remember their night together.
His behaviour is likely to infuriate his long-term partner Paige, mum of his six-month old son, and anger strict Manchester City boss Pep Guardiola.
The romp took place at the Ritz Carlton hotel in LA, which the club was using as the base for the tour.
England star Sterling bedded the girl after a boozy night out at a strip club, 24 hours after City were beaten by Manchester United in Houston on July 20.
Sterling and his teammates were given time off in LA before their International Champions Cup game against Real Madrid the following Wednesday.'HE HAD LITTLE PERSONALITY': TEXTS LEAKED
He wasted no time in getting in contact with the 30-year-old American "model and socialite" after a pal in the UK gave him her number.
WhatsApp messages between the pair show that he contacted her on July 21 and they agreed to meet, says.
Later that night he was out with friends, believed to be City teammates, when he messaged her.
He asked to meet her and said he was at nightclub Avenue LA, a favourite haunt of film and music stars. He added: "Going strip club now."
Sterling met up with the hooker after returning from the club at 4.30am.
She said: "Raheem seemed very arrogant and he had little personality.
"He is obviously used to treating women this way. He needs to change his attitude."
Under Californian state law it is an offence to engage in a "lewd act performed in exchange for money or another form of compensation".
Those caught can face fines, suspended sentences or jail. The messages between the pair suggest Sterling agreed to pay the woman after he slept with her.
She said: "Raheem had texted me a hotel room number that did not exist, so I was there waiting for him to show up. I was very close to leaving. Finally he arrived and we went to his room.
"It was not particularly big and his suitcases were strewn all over the floor. You could tell he wasn't staying for long.
"Raheem seemed drunk and his breath smelled of alcohol. He was upset with me for not meeting him earlier and was not very talkative.
"So I made the first move and we started messing around."
Afterwards the woman, who has dated a string of US sports stars, clashed with Sterling over cash.
She demanded about $5000 but he insisted he was only going to pay about $2500.
She said they argued before falling asleep in his suite.
The next morning Sterling headed off to an LA pool party without paying her. She said: "Raheem complained he needed to go to a cash machine".
"But he said he also needed to buy some clothes for the pool party and he'd be going straight there. He said he would leave the money in an envelope behind reception at the hotel."
But he failed to do so and the pair rowed again by text.
An apologetic Sterling messaged her later and said: "I was so drunk yesterday. That's why I forgot."
In one message sent after their romp, she said: "I need you to put the money in the front today."
She added: "And please put the total ... we spoke about."
Sterling refused to cave in but did promise that the $2500 would be left behind reception.
This article was republished from  with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avenue LA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHEAPSKATE Manchester City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Champions Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raheem</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sterling</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pep Guardiola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paige</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Kardashian-lookalike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WhatsApp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ritz Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raheem Sterling, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LITTLE PERSONALITY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
