<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436365955406125</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/markets/equity-markets/fresh-records-on-wall-st-buoy-ahead-of-cba-profits-20170804-gxpxrc</url>
  <title>Fresh records on Wall St buoy ahead of CBA profits</title>
  <content>
by
Timothy Moore and Patrick Commins

More records on Wall St set an upbeat background for investors this week, but the accelerating flow of news from reporting season will ultimately set the tone on the ASX.
The Dow powered  as positive economic news strengthened  and the Trump administration revived chatter about tax reform.
The benchmark 30-member index rose 0.3 per cent, extending its record-setting streak and an advance above the 22,000-point mark. Goldman Sachs and JPMorgan were among the top three performers.
The S&P 500 and the Nasdaq each added 0.2 per cent. For the week, the Dow gained 1.2 per cent, helped by Apple's post-results surge; the S&P 500 rose 0.2 per cent and the Nasdaq slid 0.4 per cent.

On Friday, a better-than-expected July US jobs report temporarily edged corporate results aside.

Total non-farm payroll employment increased by 209,000 in July, and the unemployment rate was little changed at 4.3 per cent, the US Bureau of Labor Statistics reported. Employment growth has averaged 184,000 per month thus far this year, in line with the average monthly gain of 187,000 in 2016.
"US growth is just fast enough to support profits and keep workers fully employed (and spending), but not fast enough to jolt wages, inflation or interest rates," said Bank of Montreal senior economist Sal Guatieri.
"A patient Fed ," said Mr Guatieri. "The Dow may take longer to reach its next milestone, but the macro climate remains supportive of further moves in that direction."
Aussie earnings in focus

At home, the August profit reporting season ramps up in the week ahead with around 20 major companies reporting, providing plenty of news for shareholders to chew over. Highlights include hearing implants maker Cochlear on Tuesday, Commonwealth Bank, James Hardie and Carsales on Wednesday, and then on Thursday there are reports from AMP, packaging company Orora and AGL Energy.
"As always, in a low interest rate world dividends will be a key focus," AMP Capital head of investment strategy Shane Oliver said. "But the key to watch will be outlook statements, as the current financial year won't have a repeat of the huge boost in commodity prices to resources profits".
Profits over the 2017 financial year are expected to have jumped by around 18 per cent, driven by a more than doubling in earnings for the listed resources sector as commodity prices rebounded from their 2016 lows. Elsewhere, profit growth remains subdued at around 5.5 per cent, on AMP Capital estimates.
"The challenge is that the good news with regard to strong mining sector profits - owing to last year's iron-ore price surge - appears largely priced in, while non-mining results are likely to be patchy, reflecting subdued growth, a high Australian dollar and intense competition," BetaShares chief economist David Bassanese said.

The Fed

Globally, a continuing source of worry for investors is the US Federal Reserve's signal that it plans to start a very gradual paring down its massive balance sheet. That decision is expected at the Fed's September policy meeting.
And Friday's US jobs data firmed ever so slightly bets that US interest rates could rise for a third time before the year is out, even though inflation remains reluctant to rise.
The latest wage growth data showed a modest improvement. In July, average hourly earnings for all employees on private non-farm payrolls rose by 9 cents to $US26.36. Over the year, average hourly earnings have risen by 65 cents, or 2.5 per cent; unchanged from June's pace.

"Tightening labour markets had been putting upward pressure on wage inflation through 2015 and 2016," said RBC Capital Markets assistant chief economist Paul Ferley. "However, data so far this year, including (the) data for July, show wage gains flattening out at around 2.5 per cent which matches the 2016 increase and compares to increases of 2.3 per cent and 2.1 per cent in 2015 and 2014, respectively.
"Though tightening labour markets will eventually return wage inflation to an upward trend, in the interim, the absence of wage pressure will keep the pace of tightening gradual," Mr Ferley said. "Our forecast assumes one further 25 basis point hike in fed funds this year with similar hikes in each of the four quarters of 2018."
Solid fundamentals

For the Dow, as well as the Standard & Poor's 500 and the Nasdaq, steady upward economic momentum and solid corporate results are the key.

Analysts, on average, expect S&P 500 earnings to have grown 12 per cent in the second quarter and they project earnings up 9.3 per cent for the September quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S.
Among the companies poised to report this week: CBS, Marriott, CVS Health, Walt Disney, Ralph Lauren, Twenty-First Century Fox, Office Depot, Agrium, Nvidia and Snap as well as retailers Macy's, Nordstrom, Kohl's and JC Penney.
Also drifting through markets over the weekend were tax reform comments by Gary Cohn, the White House's economic adviser. Cohn, the former Goldman Sachs president, said the Trump administration was continuing to press for a lower US corporate rate; he pointed to about 23 per cent - the OECD average - from 35 per cent now.
The potential for lower taxes is encouraging, but so far President Donald Trump's pro-growth agenda has failed to move beyond promise.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kohl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nordstrom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walt Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BetaShares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bassanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of Montreal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed's September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July's US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CVS Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ferley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday's US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nvidia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office Depot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Guatieri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hardie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US26.36</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Commins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JC Penney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP Capital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Ferley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Cohn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ralph Lauren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CarSales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poor's 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBC Capital Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sal Guatieri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Bureau of Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agrium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty First Century Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
