<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436408905079248</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/stage/sydney-stage/this-staging-of-ruby-rae-spiegels-breakthrough-play-pulls-no-punches-20170804-gxp8ka.html</url>
  <title>When the crunch comes in Ruby Rae Spiegel's drama, it comes hard.</title>
  <content>
Photo: Marnya Rothe
Dry Land
Kings Cross Theatre, August 4.
Until August 19
★★★★
With the cool observational precision of a journalist, American playwright Ruby Rae Spiegel walks her audience into the war zone. It is impossible not to be affected by what she shows you.
The setting is the change room where Florida high school students Amy (Patricia Pemberton) and Ester (Sarah Rae Anne Meacham)  hang out after swim training. The war being fought is over women's bodies and their freedom to make choices.
At first, it appears Amy and Ester are playing some kind of violent game. "Punch me again," Amy says. These are the first words we hear. Ester half-heartedly obliges.
"Do it harder and you can go get a Gatorade," says a slightly winded Amy. Ester squares up and puts a little more into the next one. On and on it goes, each punch a little harder than the last.
Is this one of those "who's the hardest" contests played among sporty types? It seems so, and there is a hierarchical element in the mix. But this is also a game being played - at least in Amy's mind - in earnest.

Amy is three months pregnant to an ex-boyfriend. This pummelling from Ester, she hopes, will bring on a miscarriage. If it doesn't there are other ways, and as Spiegel's unblinking study unfolds, we hear about or see them all: various kinds of induced trauma, attempted alcohol poisoning, and, eventually, the so-called abortion pill.
Though Amy's predicament is ever present, much of the play is devoted to a close examination of how young relationships are conducted: the ruthless policing of "in" and "out" crowds, the cruelties inflicted through embarrassment and shaming.
Spiegel was 21 when this play had its New York debut in 2014 and her portrayal of the switchback of teenage friendship feels completely on point. Her characters - which include the acerbic stoner Reba (Michelle Ny) and college boy Victor (Charles Upton) - might be unformed in terms of maturity but are complete and convincing nevertheless.
Spiegel's dry wit, put-downs and fumbled conversations make for a very funny play at times, though tragedy looms perceptibly. Watching Amy I couldn't help but be reminded of the fate of 14-year-old Wendla in Frank Wedekind's Spring Awakening written more than a century before.
When the crunch comes, it comes very hard. The climax of the play seems to suck all the oxygen out of the room.
In part, it's due to the visceral nature of director Claudia Barrie's staging, which, unlike Ester, pulls no punches. The performances she draws from her cast are precisely graded.
The spare, close-up traverse staging (a wipe-clean space designed by Isabel Hudson) amplifies Amy's agonies substantially. Liam O'Keefe's queasy lighting and Ben Pierpoint's sound design of hydrophone gurgles and ticking stopwatches ratchets up tension throughout.
We are being manipulated by Spiegel's writing, too, which plants images (a lemon being a notable one), sounds and even smells in our minds long before the play's climax. By the time Amy aborts on the tiles of the changing room floor, we are sitting ducks.
This production (from Sydney's Outhouse Theatre Co and Mad March Hare Theatre Co) has already earned itself an unfair reputation as one that puts people .
And true, if you think you might be triggered by the sight of blood, there's a good chance you will be. But this is no 21st century Grand Guignol, where blood is used as a cheap device. There are many other triggers embedded in this piercing play besides.
This is a very fine production, featuring one of the best performances you'll see on an independent stage this year (from Meacham as the not-too-smart, not very popular and besotted Ester). But it's also a harrowing one, too. Caveat emptor.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Pierpoint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meacham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam O'Keefe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claudia Barrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruby Rae Spiegel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Outhouse Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad March Hare Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabel Hudson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Upton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Ny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Pemberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Cross Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spiegel</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Wedekind's Spring Awakening</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Rae Anne Meacham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatorade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Guignol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marnya Rothe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
