<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436103962398846</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:38</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/11/35/blizzards-to-hit-vic-flood-warnings-in-sa</url>
  <title>Blizzards, storms and hail expected to batter Victoria</title>
  <content>
Blizzard-like conditions are expected to hit Victoria's eastern alpine areas today, while thunderstorms are set to batter Melbourne.
Up to half a metre of snow is expected to fall at Mt Hotham, Mt Bulla and Falls Creek today and tomorrow, Weatherzone meteorologist Tom Hough told 9news.com.au.
All major resorts in the alpine area are set to receive 40 to 70cm of snow, he said.
"It will be very windy as well," Mr Hough said.
"There will be strong gusty winds throughout the weekend and tomorrow with blizzard-like at times."
Mr Hough said conditions on the mountains should clear up by Tuesday.
"It will better weather to enjoy that fresh snow," he said. 
By Monday evening, the resorts should have natural snow depths of 120 to 160cm, he said.

Related Articles

The same weather system is set to batter Melbourne with rain and possibly some hail.
"There is a chance of storms (in Melbourne) as the front moves across the state," Mr Hough said.
He said that Melbourne could see wind speeds up to 80 to 90km/h tomorrow and up to 5mm of rain.
"Easing through the night but there is a chance of showers and storms again tomorrow morning," he added.
"But there will be mostly clear conditions Tuesday."
SES crews have already been called out to 47 jobs overnight. Most of the calls were for help with road hazards such as fallen trees between 11pm and 2am. 
The volunteers are expecting more calls for assistance as the weather conditions worsen. 
A severe weather warning issued by the Bureau of Meteorology has been cancelled.
"The immediate threat of severe weather has passed, but the situation will continue to be monitored and further warnings will be issued if necessary," BoM said in a statement.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weatherzone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blizzard-like</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Hotham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falls Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Bulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hough</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
