<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436323005732661</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/trout-season-opens-with-thousands-hitting-tasmanian-waters/8778990</url>
  <title>Anglers take to the waters for Tasmania's brown trout season opening weekend</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Jaiden Harris takes his trout fishing seriously. Very seriously.
"Yeah. I live for it," he said.
For the past five years the 19-year-old from New Norfolk, in Tasmania's south, has packed up his camping gear and headed for the lakes to wait for the start of the trout season opening.
"I waded up Tyenna River and sat beside the fire until opening season started at 12:00am," he said.
"I count the days from two weeks until opening season, I purchase a new rod, reel, line, plastics and hard bodies (lures) every season."
Not surprisingly the island state - woven with more than 3,000 picturesque rivers, lakes, streams and lagoons - is jumping with keen anglers.
Tasmania's  is considered one of the best is the world, attracting international enthusiasts.
Mr Harris' favourite spot to drop a line or two is the Tyenna River.
It winds its way around the edge of the Mount Field National Park and is one of Tasmania's premium trout fishing locations, with anglers estimating it has the highest fish population in Tasmania at about 150 fish per 100-metre stretch of wild river.
"The water levels are perfect and not flowing as fast as they do normally every opening season, the water is near crystal smooth flow," Mr Harris said.

Like many anglers advocating "catch and release", he is keen to ensure the sustainability of the recreational fishing sector.
"The trout are in beautiful condition and hopefully the trout anglers keep them in that condition by safe releasing the trout and only taking what you need," he said.
"We go camping every year up the lakes as a family tradition, my oldest son comes with us and I'm hoping to bring both on the next trip up there.
"It's amazing to get away from civilization for three to four days."
(IFS) director John Diggle said thousands of people were expected to take to Tasmanian waters this season.
Every year the IFS collects spawn from trout and farms the fish to be released into the waterways.
"The fishery is in good shape and we're expecting the season to be a good one pretty much across the board," he said.

New infrastructure along the South Esk River has been completed in time for the start of the season.
The $132,000 project included new parking areas, gates, steps, fence stiles and paths.
Eighteen private landholders have also agreed to allow river access from their properties, opening up and additional 40 kilometres of riverfront.
"Last season the South Esk was the third most popular river fishery in the state," Mr Diggle said.
"Rather than trying to find the local farmer, where he lives and catch up with him and ask permission, we've got that all sorted for them.
"All they have to do is turn up and go fishing."
Primary Industries Minister Jeremy Rockliff said better fishing infrastructure was important.
"We have almost 6,000 tourists coming from interstate and indeed overseas to enjoy our fisheries every single year and that's only going to increase," he said.
Brown trout can be caught with a licence from now until the end of April.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyenna River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaiden Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Harris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Esk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Esk River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Norfolk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Diggle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Industries Minister Jeremy Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Diggle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Field National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
