<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436323005732792</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/cbd/equestrian-fan-and-qantas-chairman-leigh-clifford-sacrifices-his-horse-for-his-flying-roo-20170802-gxnmra.html</url>
  <title>Equestrian fan and Qantas chairman Leigh Clifford sacrifices his horse for his flying roo</title>
  <content>
One of the supreme acts of corporate sacrifice went unnoticed last month, when Qantas chairman, Leigh Clifford, handed in his resignation as a board member of Equestrian Australia. 
Barely a year after joining the board, Clifford found that "his existing commitments, in particular as chair of Qantas," had prevented him from devoting the time required to his new gig. Photo: Quinn Rooney
But let's face it. It had been a big year with the Rio Olympics, and then the world class post-Olympics slanging match with John Coates, head of the Qantas-sponsored AOC. 
Given Qantas is Clifford's only ASX-listed board role, CBD thought it sent out a wonderful message to other corporate titans who collect board seats like a kid collecting show bags at the Easter Show. Photo: Pat Scala
And the good news is that our equestrians, who get their moment in the sun at each Olympics tournament, have continued to find new sponsors since Clifford's departure. 
Just five days after the announcement of Clifford's departure, our equestrian friends found themselves an official airline partner - rev head John Borghetti's Virgin Australia. 

EA said it is "delighted to announce it will now fly with Virgin Australia, becoming EA's preferred airline for all travel requirements of its athletes, officials and administration staff."

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Virgin Australia is one of the world's most highly regarded airlines and was recently awarded Best Airline and Best Airline Staff in Australia/Pacific at the 2017 Skytrax World Airline Awards," said EA's rather excited commercial manager, Tristan Prosser-Shaw. Photo: Joel Ryan
CBD is sure that the whole board couldn't agree more.  
Summer whine  

It is wine harvest season in the US, and it is safe to assume that Rupert Murdoch missed another chance to hand pick those precious grapes on his Moraga Estate - the only winery in Bel Air.
But Rupert is doing the next best thing, a marketing push to ensure the estate's $US175 ($220)  reds, and $US110 ($139) whites, find the audience they deserve. 
"As a businessman, it obviously can't make sense to grow wine in Bel Air, can it?" asked a hard-nosed Bloomberg reporter last month.
"I think we can get there. The land is what kills you. The taxes," replied Rupert.
Ah, taxes, that terrible tithe forced on people who do not have the power to make or break governments. Wouldn't happen here in Australia, of course, we just handed his pay TV operation, Foxtel, $30 million without any documentation.
But back to wine. Talk soon drifted to the first wines to make an impression on our media mogul.
"I'm an Australian. I drank Penfolds. Hill of Grace. I don't drink much other than Moraga these days," said an on-message Rupert.
Such is his fervour for the winery that Rupert even resorted to an The Guardian, to help spruik the business.
And how could the media group not be tempted to relay the views of Rupert's chief winemaker on climate change.
"I'm not a climate denier. Climate is always changing. We just had years of drought in California. Now we're having a lot of rain," was the reply from our media mogul. 
Code Rouge 

CBD has yet to hear back from the Commonwealth Bank on just what sort of fees it charges for those Intelligent Deposit Machines (IDM) that have caused all this ruckus about the 50,000-plus alleged money laundering breaches. 
We know that the bank charges $22 for each money transfer, which will be chicken feed compared to the potential fines that could flow from Austrac winning its law suit. 
But there is so much else the bank needs to focus on this week as the CBA board, and its new chairman, Catherine Livingstone, prepares to meet and approve the full-year financial results which will be announced on Wednesday. 
Will someone, maybe CEO Ian Narev, take the rap for the latest fiasco to hit the bank? This assumes that the bank will not be able to shaft the blame home to the rogue code in the IDMs which it says was the cause of the alleged breaches.  
There are other potential headaches for Livingstone. What would the public make of any bonuses that might be revealed on Wednesday? 
Luckily for CBA's senior execs, they get a bit more breathing room on Monday. It is a bank holiday.
Follow CBD on . Got a tip? 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moraga Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Airline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Coates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IDM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US110 ($139</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rouge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill of Grace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Clifford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moraga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Borghetti's Virgin Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas-sponsored AOC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupert Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia-Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US175 ($220</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinn Rooney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel $30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUPERT</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skytrax World Airline Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Scala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easter Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bel Air</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tristan Prosser-Shaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Airline Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equestrian Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifford</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
