<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436542049066525</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836054/teenager-takes-formal-fashion-into-his-own-hands-photos/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Tasmanian teenager Jye Marshall creates his own custom made suit</title>
  <content>
Teenager takes formal fashion into his own hands | Photos

exit

The Launceston Church Grammar Ball at the Hotel Grand Chancellor marked the culmination of nearly a month's work for Jye Marshall.
The Low Head teenager not only designed his own suit for the occasion, but also the dress of his date, Izzy Lockett. It is not the first time he has flaunted his own fashion, having created a different suit for a similar function last year.

He admitted it was a close call this time around.

LOOKING SHARP: Izzy Lockett and Jye Marshall ahead of the Launceston Grammar Ball on Saturday night.
"I only finished it the morning of the ball," he said.
"The hardest part was sewing on the pockets, and also doing the tie. 
"I stuck with the same design as the one I did last year.
"I'm trying to find more time to design clothes."
He had a slightly easier time doing the dress, which took him about two weeks.
There were no complaints from the wearer, with Ms Lockett more than happy with her attire.
"I absolutely love it," she said.

Design is just one of Jye's talents, with the 16-year-old also interested in acting and photography.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Low Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston Grammar Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Izzy Lockett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jye Marshall</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston Church Grammar Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hotel Grand Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
