<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436494804425807</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/sydney-melbourne-auction-clearance-rates-climb-back-over-70pc-20170805-gxq6qb</url>
  <title>Sydney, Melbourne auction clearance rates climb back over 70pc</title>
  <content>
Clearance rates for house and apartment auctions in Sydney and Melbourne climbed back into the 70 per cent range over the weekend with a growing portion of the sale success attributed to first home buyers.
In Melbourne's north the clearance rate surged to 91.7 per cent across a decent sample of 50 homes on the market on Saturday.
A 490 square metre block of land with a run-down, three-bedroom house on Railway Crescent, Broadmeadows, had four first home buyers bidding. They pushed the sale price $21,000 over the reserve to $371,000.
The selling agent, YPA's Michael Sassine, said two investors had dropped out of the running before the auction had even started.

"There are a lot more first home buyers since July 1. Unfortunately, I don't have enough listed for them to buy."

North catches up

New investment mortgages fell 2.3 per cent in April to, but home prices have continued to rise - driven by a 3.1 per cent increase in Melbourne over the month of July.
In Melbourne, the weekend clearance rate jumped to 73.7 per cent, up from 67.2 per cent last weekend according to Domain results. The results are still softer than this time last year when a clearance rate of 77.9 per cent was achieved.
Domain senior economist Dr Andrew Wilson said Melbourne's north was a standout on the weekend.

"I think you can mount a very strong case for the first home buyer being the reason behind an improvement in auctions," Mr Wilson said.
"Places like this were slow in the early part of the cycle and now they are playing catch up."
In Sydney auction clearance rates pushed up to 70.2 per cent from 69.7 per cent last weekend. This time last year, clearance rates reached 79.4 per cent.
Spring in Sydney

A five-bedroom brick bungalow at 34 Tillock Street, Haberfield, in Sydney's inner west sold for $350,000 above reserve at $3.85 million on Saturday.
"Spring's come early in the Sydney market," said Michael Tringali, an agent with McGrath Estate Agents Inner West.
"The demand for homes in the area is such that people are not waiting ... as long as it's a great home and well renovated, it doesn't need to be the usual stereotype Federation [style home]. It was not your fancy federation."
The inter-war brick bungalow went for a higher price than Federation-style homes in the area have fetched, Mr Tringali said.

A young family that had been looking in the area for more than two years won the auction that started at $3.1 million and was battled out in $50,000 increments, Mr Tringali said.
"It's the prelude to spring," he said.
Ray White's senior auctioneer Jerome Smith, who is on track to call 500 auctions this year, said there were strong results all round in Sydney.
Ten bidders

A three-bedroom villa at 6/3 Amiens Close, Bossley Park had a price guide of $500,000 to $600,000.
"We had ten registered bidders with an opening bid at $540,000 but after 22 bids it sold for $670,000," Mr Smith said.
"All the infrastructure coming here - I think people are searching for the extra value and they are willing to move further west for it," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Railway Crescent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerome Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Tringali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath Estate Agents Inner West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bossley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tillock Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amiens Close</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YPA's Michael Sassine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haberfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tringali</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Andrew Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
