<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436533459131857</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/sydney-dance-company-visits-regional-south-australia/8769444</url>
  <title>South Australian regional dance students get a taste of the international stage</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Regional dance students in South Australia have been given a taste of what it is like to perform on an international stage.
Becoming a professional dancer is a dream many young performers aspire to, and the fantasy has been brought one step closer with a visit from Sydney Dance Company to regional South Australia.
The contemporary dance company is touring Australia with its double bill Frame of Mind, featuring Gabrielle Nankivell's Wildebeest.
As part of the national tour the company is holding workshops, with many regional locations highly prioritised on their list.
The tour is dream come true for young regional dance student Owen Stokes.
"I want to be a dancer and a singer because I really like acting, dancing and singing," Mr Stokes said.

"I'm a very good singer. I go to choir and I really enjoy it but sometimes in my free time at home I go and do some dancing, it's really fun.
"I chose contemporary because it's really emotional and that's why I like dancing."
Workshops held around the state are teaching hopeful dancers sections from the professionally performed chorography Wildebeest, with classes in Mount Gambier, Port Pire and Renmark over the past two weeks.
Sydney Dance Company teaching artist Patricia Wood said the workshops had been very well received by students.
"We warm them up and then we also do a creative task and some repertoire, so some of the choreography from the show," she said.
"These workshops are designed to give kids an experience of what it's like to be in Sydney Dance Company."

Rare opportunity for many rural dancers

Sienna Eleftheriadis, 10, who has been dancing for half her life, also has aspirations to be a dancer in the future.
"I like doing hip hop and ballet and all the expressions that you do ... it's really good," she said.
The workshops will travel to Whyalla and Port Augusta next week.
Principal and owner of Renmark-based Rachel McLeod Dance studios, Rachel McLeod, said students had loved the experience.
"To have Sydney Dance Company visit the regions is such a blessing," she said.
"It can be quite rare. I think in recent years it has become more prolific and we're seeing companies entering the studios a lot more, which is fantastic and very inspirational for the kids."

Ms McLeod said the experience was very special for the students, as they learnt choreography from the piece that will be professionally performed in Renmark in a couple of weeks.
"It is important for them to see that there are jobs there, that they may be able to enter into one day if they show the same sort of dedication," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frame of Mind</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Gambier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Pire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renmark-based Rachel McLeod Dance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sienna Eleftheriadis, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McLeod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owen Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabrielle Nankivell's Wildebeest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renmark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Augusta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Dance Company</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel McLeod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whyalla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
