<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436323005732700</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/amazon-is-dandenongbound-but-tax-and-labour-fears-remain-20170804-gxp9at.html</url>
  <title>Amazon is Dandenong-bound but tax and labour fears remain</title>
  <content>
Photo: Rob Homer
The world's biggest online retailer has chosen Dandenong South for its first Australian distribution centre, pleasing governments with promises of hundreds of jobs.
But unions remain concerned about the $US474 billion ($595 billion) retailer's labour record, and rival retailer Gerry Harvey has questioned whether the US giant will pay its fair share of tax.
Multinationals have come under fire for shifting revenue overseas to avoid Australia's 30 per cent corporate tax rate. Amazon has also attracted the ire of rival retailers for focusing on market-share gains rather than profits. 
​Mr Harvey, the chairman of whitegoods and furniture retailer Harvey Norman, told 774 ABC Melbourne: "Their policy is [to] send everyone broke, we'll take over the business, we'll never pay any tax and then we'll put up the price and we'll own everything."
Amazon's public relations firm Weber Shandwick did not respond to whether Amazon committed to complying with its tax obligations.
But it confirmed that the Victorian government did not provide any money for Amazon to set up in the south-eastern suburb of Melbourne.

State governments can lure companies in a variety of ways, including paying grants, offering payroll tax relief and speeding up planning processes. Victoria has much faster and less restrictive planning processes than NSW, in part to encourage investment.
It is unclear whether the Victorian government provided incentives for another huge international retailer, Germany's Kaufland, to choose Melbourne as its Australian base.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Amazon is expected to open other distribution centres in Australia, probably in Sydney and perhaps also in the western suburbs of Melbourne.
Its decision to pick up a 24,000-square-metre former Bunnings site in Dandenong South, rather than build from scratch, has also quickened some expectations for the company's Australian expansion.
Investment bank UBS has tipped shipping will start next year, if not by the end of this year.
​Mr Harvey had previously warned that it would  to make a serious dent on Australia's $300 billion retail sector.
On labour concerns, Weber Shandwick said Amazon would "most likely" use a mixture of permanent stuff and labour hire staff "to enable us to move quickly, access talent and manage variations in customer demand."
The comments come after National Union of Workers national secretary Tim Kennedy said, "Our issue is that Amazon comes with a reputation for not respecting workers' rights. Our concern is they may heighten the pace of insecure work and inequality."
Mr Kennedy said Australian distribution centre workers were paid much higher rates than those in the US, and about $8 to $10 more per hour than the minimum wage of $18.29 an hour.
Investigative reporting in the US and Europe in recent years , including extensive theft screening and workers being penalised for taking time off sick or disciplined for spending too long in the toilet.
Workers are also kept under close surveillance to check for efficiency and under pressure to hit targets. They can walk more than 20 kilometres in a shift.
Greater Dandenong Mayor Jim Memeti said the council was "more than happy" to talk to Amazon about employment programs, particularly for the long term unemployed.
Wade Noonan, Minister for Industry and Employment, said: "Amazon's decision to locate its new centre in Dandenong South will create hundreds of local jobs and open up retail opportunities for thousands of local businesses."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US474</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Harvey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerry Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Mayor Jim Memeti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany's Kaufland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weber Shandwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong South</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wade Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Workers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's $300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Homer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
