<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436666603118869</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836374/richard-recognised-for-six-decades-of-ambulance-service/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Retiring Richard Poon thanked for 60 years' service with St John Ambulance</title>
  <content>
CELEBRATED: Retiring St John Ambulance volunteer Richard Poon was farewelled with a dinner at Dapto Leagues Club. Picture: Adam McLean

Richard Poon was thanked for his 60 years' service with St John Ambulance at a black tie dinner on Saturday night. 

The Fairy Meadow resident was honoured with a retirement dinner at Dapto Leagues Club. 

Mr Poon witnessed a terrible car accident on the streets of Hong Kong as a teen.
However, the helplessness he felt in not being able to help would change the course of his life.
"A long time ago I saw an accident on the road - someone hit by a car - and at the time I didn't know what to do," Mr Poon told the Mercury in 2014. 
"So after that I made up my mind that I had to learn something to help people when they're in trouble and I joined St John (Ambulance)."
Mr Poon, now 81, worked as a volunteer first aid officer for more than a decade, before emigrating to Australia in the late 1960s and continuing his volunteer work.

The highlight of his service was being a volunteer at the Sydney Olympic Games and meeting volunteers from around the world.
Despite slowing down in recent years, he said he took comfort knowing his skills could help people.

Son Stephen said ambulance officials and family members were among the gathering at the dinner. 
Stephen said his father was retiring in order to care for wife Lin. 
Leon Sawyer, superintendent for St John Ambulance's Wollongong Division has known Mr Poon since 1977.

He described him as "a quiet man" and hard worker who had been the organisation's longest-serving active member in the Illawarra prior to his retirement. 

READ MORE: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto Leagues Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Poon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Poon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Ambulance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Sawyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retiring St John Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairy Meadow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Ambulance's Wollongong Division</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
