<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437014495473149</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/aston-martin-db11-review-2017-7</url>
  <title>The Aston Martin DB11 is $315,000 worth of power, beauty, and soul</title>
  <content>
Power. Beauty. Soul. For many years, Aston Martin proudly displayed these three words on the instrument panels of its cars right before they roared to life. For me, these are the three words that sum up everything Aston Martin stands for. Together, they form the ethos of a brand so effortlessly cool one wonders if it's even possible for Aston to build an ugly car.

At the  its adoring fans the next object of their affection with the unveiling of the DB11.

For Aston Martin, the DB11 is one of the most important cars in company history and certainly the most important since its separation from Ford a decade ago. As storied as Aston Martin the brand may be, Aston Martin the business has had more than its fair share of run-ins with financial ruin in its history. The DB11 has to keep the company in the black for the foreseeable future.

However, the sleek luxury grand tourer will have the unenviable task of replacing the .

Like the super spy with whom Aston is so inexorably linked, finding the perfect successor is paramount. Get it wrong and hundreds of millions of dollars go down the drain. But, get it right and a bountiful decade awaits.

Recently, Aston Martin let Business Insider borrow a DB11 coupe in Magnetic Silver. The 2017 Aston Martin DB11 starts at $A290,649 while our test car came to $A320, 603 after a few options.

Photos by Hollis Johnson unless otherwise credited.

Hollis Johnson

Read the review .

Hollis Johnson

Aston Martin

Aston Martin

Aston Martin

Wikimedia Commons

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

With that said, knocking a small boutique car maker like Aston for its infotainment system is like complaining that a Michael Bay movie lacks subtlety. You know what you're getting into when you buy the ticket.

Hollis Johnson

Aston Martin

Hollis Johnson

Hollis Johnson

In town, the Aston is a perfectly behaved boulevard cruiser. It's more than happy to offer up its services as the automotive equivalent of arm candy.

As you leave town for the wilds of rural New Jersey, (yes, that exists.), the athlete within the DB11 emerges. The 600-horse V12 comes alive, delivering power on demand accompanied by an ear-pleasing exhaust note. As much as the twin-turbos try, they can't keep the sweet music of 12-cylinder fury at bay.

The DB11 is neither sports car nor supercar. It's a grand tourer designed to eat up large amounts of real estate at very high speeds while cocooning its occupants in absolute luxury. In that regard, the DB11 is a purebred GT car and doesn't attempt to do anything more than its job description indicates.

As the road turns twisty, the Aston hunkers down, moving swiftly and efficiently through the corners without compromising comfort.

Depending on the road, the Aston varies from relaxing to invigorating. And in a few instances, life affirming.

To drive the DB11 is akin to a 6-course meal at a Michelin Star restaurant. Each course engenders different feelings, taking you on an emotional rollercoaster until the experience is over and you're left in awe of the price tag while wanting to do it all over again the following week.

Hollis Johnson

With the DB11, you get Aston Martin at its most refined. It's easy to live with, a joy to drive, and its technology works without a hitch.

But, what makes the car a triumph of engineering also threatens its place in the hearts of those who adored its predecessors for their rough edges and imperfections. People loved the DB9's designer watch-inspired instrument cluster even though it caused so much glare you struggled to see the gauges on a sunny day. Then there are its difficult-to-use, but-oh-so-stylish touch sensitive center dash and the big 6.0 litre, V12 that was immensely powerful, but objectively antiquated.

In the twisted minds of automotive enthusiasts like myself, perfection is boring, flaws add character while noise feeds the soul. This is why cars like the Toyota Camry are often derided for their no-fuss, A-to-B demeanors.

Fortunately for the DB11, automotive excellence doesn't stifle Aston's trained-killer-in-a-Savile-Row-suit personality. Neither Mercedes' electronics nor the twin-turbos could sanitize the entertaining driving experience. There's plenty fine leather, rich wood, and throaty V12 rumble left to ensure the brand's personality abounds.

Because the new DB11 is able to deliver modern refinement without corrupting the essence of the parental heritage, it is, without a doubt, the best car to ever carry the Aston Martin badge.

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savile-Row-suit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelin-star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V12</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aston Martin</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Camry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DB9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnetic Silver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aston</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollis Johnson</name>
    <count>31</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aston Martin DB11</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wikimedia Commons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DB11</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
