<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436842696779937</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836422/woolworths-defends-controversial-kookas-decision/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Woolworths defends homegrown reputation after decision to pull Kooka's Country Cookies from shelves</title>
  <content>
Supermarket giant Woolworths has voiced its support for Australian-made goods, despite a decision to pull products from a regional Victorian manufacturer off some if its shelves.

The chain came under fire yesterday after  outside of Victoria and Tasmania.  

Social media followers of the food manufacturer said the decision showed a lack of support for Australian-made goods from the supermarket giant.

Asked why Kooka's products would no longer appear on shelves Australia-wide, a Woolworths spokesperson said: "We work hard to ensure we are responding to our customers' buying habits and that the products on our shelves reflect what our customers want to see."
The spokesman also refuted accusations the company did not support local suppliers. 
"We have a strong history in supporting local Australian suppliers whenever we can," he said. 

"Our commitment includes using local sourcing managers in each state to regularly identify niche and small opportunity Australian suppliers for supply direct into store.
"We're proud to support the growth of great local Australian suppliers and this commitment is important to us and our customers."

A post on the Kooka's Facebook page said the company was disappointed in the Woolworth's decision. 
"As you know, Kooka's is a small Australian-owned and operated business employing up to 28 staff in the rural township of Donald," the post read. 

"The Kooka's team is proud of their products and it is with disappointment that we find we cannot supply to Woolworths customers throughout Australia."

Coles, Officeworks and independent supermarkets countrywide continue to stock the biscuit brand, which began with a team of just five staff in 1994. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officeworks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kooka's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-made</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kooka's Country Cookies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia-wide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kooka</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-owned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
