<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436967250832409</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/cutting-urban-sprawl-carsharing-faces-uphill-battle-in-the-suburbs-20170706-gx6hby</url>
  <title>Cutting urban sprawl: Car-sharing faces uphill battle in the suburbs </title>
  <content>
Car sharing could curb urban sprawl and allow much-needed density in Australia's suburbs by cutting individual car ownership - and the space they use for parking.
Will Davies, the chief executive of car-share service Car Next Door, says peer-to-peer sharing services - Airbnb-like platforms by which owners rent out their cars to others - will reduce the demand for privately owned cars and free up the real estate used to house largely unused vehicles.
"It's stupid that everyone owns their own car but they only use it a few hours a week," Davies says. "It's a massive expense that costs a heap of money to build and is just sitting around doing nothing for nearly all their time. We aim to have everyone in Australian cities able to access a car within a five-minute walk without everyone needing to own one."
Technology will turn transport into a service that customers will eventually purchase like mobile phone plans, The Australian Financial Review this week and the implications for housing and urban planning are large.

By one estimate, a reduction in the number of private cars could free up many of  for conversion into extra dwelling space.

But the suburbs where car-sharing can make the biggest impact are the very areas where it is least likely to be adopted. High density urban areas attract car sharing providers, as lots of residents with little or very expensive parking space make car-sharing more viable. In the burbs, however, where parking is plentiful and public transport alternatives sparse, the hurdles facing car-sharing are much higher.
Transport for NSW figures for Sydney in 2013 - the latest available - show that the number of three-car households overtook the number of households without a car in 2008 and the gap has been widening ever since.
Car sharing is one piece of a transport puzzle that requires other services such as good  to convince people to give up private ownership, says University of Sydney research fellow Jennifer Kent. But cultural hurdles also prevent adoption of car-sharing, she says.
"It does have a lot of potential to decrease car ownership but ... why aren't we seeing more uptake of it?" Kent says. "It's very deeply embedded in notions of what it means to be a good parent, reliable at work, to be professional."

Russell Miles, who lives in Melbourne's northern suburb of Preston, lends his five-door Holden Astra out via the network. It took time for people to get used to the idea, but they did, he says.
"When I first made it available, people were getting used to that it's there," he says. "It wasn't something they were sure of, but after a few months it started getting used quite regularly."
A capital-light model such as Car Next Door stands a better chance of success than a GoGet or commercial rivals such as Hertz on Demand that own their own fleets and need a higher return to be viable, Davies says.
"The problem is that commercial car share operators of the likes of GoGet and Hertz on Demand is they need to make $10,000 to $12,000 per car a year to break even," he says. "The average owner making $3500 off car next door (after fuel, wear/tear) and we've got a quite a number of owners making in the $5000 to $10,000 range."

Car Next Door, launched at the end of 2012, has more than 1000 owners and 38,000 borrowers spread across Sydney (which accounts for half the total), Melbourne (45 per cent) and Brisbane (5 per cent). Davies' 2020 target is 10,000 vehicles and to be in seven cities across Australia.
Even he sees hurdles, however.
"We've got a chicken-and-egg problem," he says. "People are only going to want a borrow a car that's nearby them. We've got to find areas where enough people are looking to borrow and enough willing to put on cars. As you go further into the suburbs, there are plenty willing to put on a car - because they've all got three - but finding people who don't own three cars and want to borrow one, is the bigger challenge."
"What we're doing is starting in denser urban areas and slowly moving out into the suburban areas. It's habit changing over time."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Next Door</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davies' 2020</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane (5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Car Next Door</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnb-like</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne (45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Astra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoGet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Car-sharing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davies</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hertz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
