<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437010200505748</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-match-report/st-kilda-pull-of-stunning-victory-against-west-coast-keep-finals-hopes-alive-20170806-gxq8la.html</url>
  <title>St Kilda pull of stunning victory against West Coast, keep finals hopes alive</title>
  <content>
St Kilda's hopes of playing in their first finals series since 2011 are still alive after pulling off a stirring eight point victory over the West Coast Eagles at Etihad Stadium on Sunday.
The Saints trailed the Eagles by 14 points early in the final term but rallied to take the lead through a Jack Steele snap from a boundary throw in, and then hold onto the advantage for the rest of the quarter.Photo: AAP
But it wasn't without a scare, as Josh Kennedy cut the margin to one point late in the game to make the Saints nervous, but the result was assured with 30 seconds remaining when Jack Billings converted a set shot.
St Kilda, who last week succumbed to a stunning last gasp defeat to Port Adelaide at the Adelaide Oval, had been tipped by many in the pre-season to break into the eight, but in recent weeks and at times through the year indicated through their performances that they might not be ready for September action.
This win, however, added weight to their finals credentials, because they were forced to wrestle themselves back into the contest on numerous occasions, against a team of hardened finals performers.
Jack Newnes, Shane Savage and Blake Acres were assured all day for the Saints, while Billings, admittedly sloppy at times, had enough quality influence on the game to make his side good enough when operating in the forward half.

The win will also possibly extend the twilight of Nick Riewoldt's career, however the champion ended the game on the bench. Retiring at season's end he didn't have a huge impact on the contest and looked injured twice in the game, the second more serious. 
The first knock came in the second quarter when he took a hit to his leg, and then the second in inspiring fashion in the final term. Attacking a loose ball, Riewoldt clashed heads with West Coast's Dom Sheed, which forced him from the field. The champion looked groggy as soon as he got up and didn't not return. 
While the manner of their loss wasn't as meek as other away defeats this season to Hawthorn, Essendon, Gold Coast and Collingwood, the Eagles will be disappointed they couldn't win a game they looked to be in control of when they had kicked three goals to one early in the final quarter.
Their strength in the game, keeping the Saints locked in their forward half, was maintained for long enough and it ultimately cost them the chance to get back into a finals spot. 
The Saints are now equal on points with West Coast, Melbourne, Essendon, who sit in eighth position, and play the Demons (MCG), North Melbourne (Etihad Stadium) and Richmond (MCG) to end the season. 
The first quarter was tight on the scoreboard and but not tight in the contest as both sides seemed more content to look for ascendancy on the outside rather than piling on tackles and pressure.  
The Saints took three marks inside 50 for the term but wasted plenty of entries with impotent, high kicking to their forwards, a sin against the West Coast backline.  
At the other end the Eagles forwards were able to isolate their opponents one-on-one while their midfielders were frugal with their attacking kicking.
But Jack Darling, Josh Kennedy and Jack Redden missed simple set shots meaning they didn't get just reward for their cleaner disposal. 
West Coast's defensive aggression soared in the second term which, ironically, amounted to them being a more dangerous attacking unit for the Saints to negotiate.
The Eagles kicked four goals in a row in the middle of the quarter by locking the Saints into their defensive 50 but St Kilda responded with their own volley of majors, kicking three in a row to end the half and stay in touch with their opponents. 
The Intensity rose again in the third term, with the pressure taking its toll on players across the term. Not even the most experienced could avoid the heat in the game, with Nick Riewoldt inexplicably missing a shot running into an open goal.
That allowed West Coast to rebound. They went coast-to-coast from the retiring Saint champion's mistake, Kennedy getting the finish on the run from 50 meters. 
Ultimately, the Saints broke free from West Coast's press in the final quarter, to register the important win. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Newnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Redden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Acres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast's Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Billings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
