<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436323005732735</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/aborignal-leaders-tell-garma-audiences-not-to-lose-hope/8779110</url>
  <title>Indigenous leaders tell Garma audiences not to lose hope in wake of PM's address</title>
  <content>
Indigenous leaders have urged Aboriginal people not to be discouraged by the Federal Government's lack of action in the wake of the Uluru statement of the heart, delivered in May this year.
Many expected Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull to respond more strongly than he did to the Referendum Council's report released on June 30.
In his speeches at Garma, in North-East Arnhem Land,  of a treaty, a constitutionally enshrined voice in the constitution for First Australians, or a truth-telling commission.
Referendum Council member and academic Professor Megan Davis said the  would be the last attempt for meaningful change for Indigenous Australians.
Ms Davis said the Referendum Council refused to give a hard copy of the statement to politicians because they feared it would sit in Parliament house as a framed piece of paper that achieved no change.
"The only way we can get this done is to get all Australians to walk with us," she said.
"People feel like it's the last throw of the dice - so it has to be."
At a Garma panel discussion looking at state and territory-based treaty processes, Uluru delegate Thomas Mayor told the audience there needed to be brave decisions and action on the council's recommendations.

"If this opportunity isn't taken up, then we're left at the bottom ... we have momentum and we're ready to get there," Mr Mayor said.
"We heard out politicians talking over the last couple of days, talking it up.
"There was some solid commitments from one side, less from the other - but we need to nail this home, and we need your support.
"We need everybody who has experienced this spiritual and enriching Garma 2017 to not just walk away and say 'that was great'.
"We need people to keep having the conversations at home."
Mr Mayor said he believed constitutional change and treaties would lead to other systemic change.
"Like the CDP program [remote work for the dole scheme, the Community Development Program] which is an ignorant and racist piece of legislation providing slave labour," he said.
At Garma, Mr Turnbull said he knew the Referendum Council and many Aboriginal people wanted to see their recommendations implemented immediately, but said the process required time.
"There are still many questions. What would the practical expression of the voice look like?" he said.
"Is our highest aspiration to have a voice outside the Parliament providing advice to the Parliament, or is it to have as many Indigenous voices elected within our parliament?
"Australians are constitutionally conservative - it's a high bar, but it is surmountable. That's why the constitution has often been referred to as a frozen document."
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten said Labor supported a voice for Aboriginal Australians in the constitution.
"The question is not if we should do these things, but when and how," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Mayor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Megan Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Development Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
