<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436752502465687</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/what-we-know-about-the-us-marine-corps-osprey-crash/8779200</url>
  <title>What do we know about the US Marine Corps Osprey crash?</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Three US marines are presumed dead after a military Osprey aircraft crashed off the coast of Queensland on Saturday.
Here's what we know about the crash:
When did it happen?

The MV-22 Osprey crashed at 4:00pm (AEST) on Saturday.
It had launched from the USS Bonhomme Richard and was conducting "regularly scheduled operations" when it "entered the water".
An initial statement from the III Marine Expeditionary Force described the crash as "a mishap".
A search and rescue effort was launched immediately.
Where did it happen?

The crash occurred 30 kilometres off the coast of Shoalwater Bay, near Rockhampton in central Queensland.

External Link:

Map of Shoalwater Bay
Last month US and Australian forces conducted joint military training exercises off Shoalwater Bay as part of Exercise Talisman Sabre, but those exercises .
So why were the US Marine Corps still there?

The US Marine Corps (USMC) said the USS Bonhomme Richard was in the area as part of "a regularly-scheduled deployment in the Indo-Asia-Pacific region".
A post on the USS Bonhomme Richard's Facebook page on Saturday said the landing helicopter dock had begun "amphibious integration training ... exercises out here on the Coral Sea".
Who was involved?

Twenty-three other personnel aboard the Osprey had to be rescued, including one marine who was taken to Rockhampton Hospital.
"All other personnel are accounted for and safe," the III Marine Expeditionary Force said on Twitter.

Defence Minister Marise Payne confirmed no Australian Defence Force (ADF) personnel were on board, but the ADF will now assist with the recovery effort.
Do we know what caused the crash?

Not at this stage, but the USMC has launched an investigation.
The Bureau of Meteorology has said it's unlikely weather played a role, as the wind, swell and atmospheric conditions at the time of the incident were "benign".
"There was a light north-easterly wind with high cloud ... but that would have had no impact whatsoever on conditions at the surface," meteorologist Michael Paech said.
How long will the recovery take?

The USMC say it could take several months, and the next-of-kin for the three missing marines have been notified.

External Link:

II MEF Marines: Please keep these families in your thoughts and prayers during this difficult time. All other personnel are accounted for and safe.
"As the sea state permits, recovery efforts will be conducted to further search, assess and survey the area, in coordination and with assistance from the ADF," a statement said.
"Recovery and salvage operations can take several months to complete, but can be extended based on several environmental factors."

What has Donald Trump said?

There's been no word from the US President yet, but the White House said he'd been briefed on the incident.
It happened on Mr Trump's first full day of vacation at the Trump National Golf Club in Bedminster, New Jersey.
What has Malcolm Turnbull said?

There's also been no official word from the Prime Minister himself, but he did retweet a statement from Defence Minister Marise Payne on Twitter.

External Link:

Tweet by Marise Payne: I have offered our support to the US following the MV-22 incident today & confirm no ADF personnel were on board.
"I have briefed Prime Minister [Malcolm] Turnbull and spoken with Secretary [James] Mattis this evening to offer Australia's support in anyway that can be of assistance," Ms Payne said in a statement on Saturday night.
"Our thoughts are with the crew and families affected."
Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk also released a statement, saying the state's prayers were "with those US military personnel involved in the incident".
Have there been problems with Ospreys in the past?

Yes, Ospreys have been involved in a number of incidents in recent years.
The development of the Osprey - built by Boeing Co and Textron Inc's Bell Helicopter unit - was nearly cancelled after the deaths of 23 marines during flight testing in 2000, but its speed and range have made it very popular in recent years.
In December, the US military grounded its Osprey fleet in Japan after one of the aircraft ditched into the sea, injuring its crew of five when a hose connected to the aircraft broke during a refuelling exercise.
In January, three US soldiers were injured in the "hard landing" of an Osprey in Yemen.

External Link:

MV-22 Ospreys arrive in Australia in April after a trans-Pacific flight
ABC/Reuters

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yemen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marise Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exercise Talisman Sabre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Bonhomme Richard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalwater Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV-22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coral Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-three</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marine Corps Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump National Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USMC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Minister Marise Payne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>II MEF Marines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC/Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indo-Asia-Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Bonhomme Richard's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Paech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Textron Inc's Bell Helicopter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV-22 Osprey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>III Marine Expeditionary Force</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mattis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marine Corps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADF</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
