<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436795452139192</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/canberra-raiders/canberra-raiders-must-back-up-cronulla-sharks-win-against-new-zealand-warriors-20170806-gxq8cw.html</url>
  <title>At first, Canberra Raider Elliott Whitehead thought he was in trouble</title>
  <content>
At first, Elliott Whitehead thought he was in trouble when Canberra Raiders coach Ricky Stuart called him in to his office.
Instead, he was getting offered a starring middle role in a massive win to keep the Green Machine's finals hopes alive.

Up Next

Bolt defeated by Gatlin in final 100m race

00:23

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Judiciary charges loom as Cronulla slip to Canberra

In a night of ugly tackles from Graham, Fifita and Gallen, the Ricky Stuart masterclass inspired the Raiders to a 30-12 victory over the Sharks to keep their NRL finals hopes alive.

But Whitehead declared their comprehensive 30-12 victory over Cronulla would be for nothing unless they backed it up with the two points across the Ditch.
The Raiders face the New Zealand Warriors in Auckland next Sunday knowing they probably need to win all four of their remaining games to have a chance of making the NRL finals.

They face a struggling Kiwi team, who have lost their last five games to sit 12th on the ladder and have no chance of making the top eight.
But Whitehead said while the belief was there they could extend their two-game winning streak, he warned they needed to back up their effort against the Sharks or it would be meaningless.

The Raiders produced their best game of the season to knock off the reigning premiers off the back of a 91 per cent completion rate.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"We need to win every game and we've got the belief in camp that we're capable of doing that," Whitehead said.Photo: David Moir
"We proved what the team can do when we complete and get to the end of our sets.
"We'll take a lot out of that, but we need to focus on the Warriors now and we need to get that win otherwise this win doesn't mean anything.
"It'll be a tough game. I think they lost to Newcastle so they're going to want to turn that around with their home fans."
The England international was brilliant in his first ever hit-out at lock, having played on an edge all his career.
He looked right at home in the middle of the park, setting up a try for countryman Josh Hodgson and running for 169 metres in an outstanding 80-minute performance.
The 27-year-old said he was nervous going into his debut at lock and was "blowing" after the first 15 minutes.
It further franked Whitehead's versatility, with the usual second-rower adding another string to his bow that already included centre and five-eighth since joining the Raiders.
"I was a bit nervous to be honest, I've never played there ... but all the boys, Junior [Paulo] and [Shannon Boyd], got around me and kept me calm coming up to the game and just said just do what I do," he said.
"I found out on Monday. [Stuart] got me in his office and I thought I was in trouble, but he just sat me down and said he wanted to leave [Joe Tapine] there because he played well against Souths so I was happy to do that as long as I was playing."
​Whitehead wasn't sure what Stuart had in mind for him against the Warriors - whether he'd return to the right edge or if Tapine would be preferred there again.
Hodgson joked Whitehead would now be "stuck" in the middle with him.
.
"I said to him he can't put a performance like that in the middle and expect to go back to the back row, he might be stuck there," Hodgson joked.
"I thought he was outstanding, his work was phenomenal. He did a lot of minutes for us and did a real job when he was needed.
"He's a great player and one of those people that does a lot of the small things that the fans don't see and we all know what he does for our side and how important he is for us. He really put his hand up."
NRL ROUND 23
Sunday: Canberra Raiders v New Zealand Warriors at Auckland, 2pm. Live on Fox League.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tapine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehead</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Moir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodgson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Raider Elliott Whitehead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott Whitehead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL ROUND 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Raiders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tapine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREEN MACHINE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hodgson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
