<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436881351485870</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/law-order/police-hunting-gang-of-men-behind-three-service-station-raids-in-melbourne-suburbs/news-story/c0f24c73a1dc5fe5cb5807b213e3a7ee</url>
  <title>Gang hits three servos in 24 hours</title>
  <content>
POLICE are hunting a gang of armed robbers who raided three service stations this weekend.
Brimbank Embona detectives are investigating the series of robberies in Melbourne's northwest suburbs.
Three service stations were targeted by a group of up to seven men in Hillside, Laverton North and Rockbank.
In the first incident seven men smashed their way into a service station on the Melton Highway, Hillside just after 3am on Saturday.
They tried to smash their way into the cigarette cabinets but failed and instead made off with the attendant's car.
Thirty minutes later the same men targeted another service station in Laverton North.
They entered the Little Boundary Rd petrol station armed with a knife, baseball bat and hammers just before 3.30am, stealing cigarettes and a cash register.
In the last incident, six men armed with hammers attended a Melton Highway service station just before 3.30am on Sunday.
They stole the cash register and cigarettes before fleeing in a black SUV and silver sedan.
No one was injured during the robberies and detectives are treating all three incidents as being linked.
Police have released CCTV and images of a number of men they believe can assist with their inquiries.
Anyone with any information should contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or submit a confidential crime report at crimestoppersvic.com.au.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Boundary Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brimbank Embona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverton North</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melton Highway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
