<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436881351485867</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/gold/diggers-and-dealers-2017-exploration-success-gives-wa-gold-miners-a-fresh-glow-20170804-gxp9c6</url>
  <title>Diggers and Dealers 2017: Exploration success gives WA gold miners a fresh glow</title>
  <content>
New life is being injected into aging gold projects across Western Australia as the mining sector's exploration efforts strike success.
In what is shaping as a mini-renaissance for Australia's gold miners, new discoveries at pre-loved assets .
The exploration momentum is reigniting investor interest in the sector and boosting sentiment ahead of the annual Diggers and Dealers mining conference, which kicks off on Monday in Kalgoorlie, the state's gold heartland.
Northern Star Resources and Saracen Mineral Holdings both announced significant increases in their gold inventories last week after bumper exploration programs around their operations.

Carla Gottgens

Dacian Gold is just eight months away from restarting production at the historic Mt Morgans gold project and Metals X spin-off West Gold Resources kicked the Fortnum gold mine back into production in June, after buying and refurbishing the long-idled project.

And there are plenty of others - Silver Lake Resources' is working to add life to its Mount Monger gold camp and Gascoyne Resources is developing Dalgaranga, first discovered in the early 1990s.
'The answers are in the rocks'

At Mt Morgans this week, standing atop a hill that will eventually become a large open pit, Dacian executive chairman Rohan Williams said restoring shine to the old mining ground was simply a matter of trusting targeted exploration would reveal enough gold to justify a new start.
Mr Williams, a geologist and the former chief of Avoca Resources, poetically explained, "the answers are always in the rocks".

Carla Gottgens

"It is remarkable to me that we are in one of the best gold regions in Western Australia and you can still walk up on a hill that is mineralised," Mr Williams said.
Gold mining at Mt Morgans, from 1896 and through the early 1900s, sustained a boom town big enough for three breweries.
But falling grades and trouble defining more reserves, coupled with a mining downturn, saw the mine and town neglected for decades until, from the late 1980s, a string of companies, including Canadian major Barrick Gold, took a punt on reviving the project.
When Dacian acquired Mt Morgans from the administrators of Range River Gold in 2012 it became the 10th company to hold it since the 1980s. It is the first to have had any real exploration success.

Stefan Gosatti

to restart and expand both. It has boosted ore reserves to 1.2 million ounces from 136,000 ounces in 2012, made a new discovery, Cameron Well, which could shape up as Mt Morgans' third mine and is building a processing plant, from which it hopes to produce about 200,000 ounces a year for an initial eight years.
Intangible upside

"The people that can identify the intangible upside that others don't see are the ones that have success," Argonaut analyst James Wilson said, pointing to Northern Star's Jundee mine as another good example.
US gold major Newmont sold Jundee to Northern Star for $82 million in 2014. Northern Star revealed on Thursday it had doubled reserves at Jundee in just 12 months and its exploration efforts over the past three years had given it enough confidence to map out a 10-year production plan. It also revealed a new discovery, Zodiac. Some analysts now value Jundee at more than $1 billion.

Northern Star chairman Bill Beament said he was confident the efforts had returned Jundee, and the company's other operation, Kalgoorlie, "back to tier one assets".
"I have said for the last year or so that if the Australian gold sector starts to put money back in the ground they are going to find things, they are going to extend reserves, they are going to extend resources and hence mine life and you are seeing that now," Mr Beament said.
"We are sitting on world class endowments throughout Australia. We just have to spend a little bit of money ... that money wasn't spent five or six years ago and people are playing catch-up now but the results are speaking for themselves."
Liam Twigger, managing director of Perth capital advisory firm PCF Capital, says while it was still challenging to secure capital for greenfields exploration, in uncharted territory, there is plenty of money available for brownfields work around existing assets.

"The deals that have been done over the past few years with projects coming out of majors and into the Australian mid-tier have proved to be very timely," he said.
"If you have a brownfields project there are a raft of funds and financiers that will help bootstrap you into production as long as you can show the pathway there."
Risks abound

But it doesn't always work out.
"Not every operation has that kind of win," Argonaut's Mr Wilson said, pointing to the challenges Blackham Resources and Eastern Goldfields are having. 
And there is the risk of the robust Australian dollar gold price, which has made much of the new, deeper production economic, falling.
"When these assets were running the first time the gold price was probably below $US1000 an ounce and the Aussie dollar was high," Mr Wilson said.
"Now we are looking at a market where the Aussie dollar gold price is closer to $1600 an ounce and the operations that weren't economic then are much more economic now."

Geologist Allan Kelly said it was crucial the industry continued to explore for big, new deposits.
Mr Kelly, the founder and former chief of Doray Minerals and now managing director of explorer Riversgold, argued brownfields exploration would not be enough to sustain the pipeline of reserves the industry needs.
"For the last three or so years it has been obvious we have nothing really coming after the few developers we have at the moment," Mr Kelly said. "Gruyere was probably the last real greenfields discovery."
The Gruyere gold project was discovered by Gold Road Resources in 2013 is now being developed in partnership with South Africa's Gold Fields.
"A lot of the miners are really focused on their own backyards but there is no one really out there with a decent budget doing greenfields exploration," Mr Kelly said.
Diggers sentiment up

It is a gap in the market Mr Kelly hopes to jump into. Riversgold lodged a prospectus with the ASX on Friday for a $5 million to $8 million IPO and hopes to list before the end of December. Australia's second-largest gold producer, Evolution Mining, has committed $2.5 million to the IPO, for as much as a 16.2 per cent stake.
Mr Kelly famously got Doray's float off the ground after securing support at the 2009 Diggers and Dealers. He will be back at the conference this week spruiking Riversgold.

With about 2100 people expected to descend on Kalgoorlie, including more than 100 delegates travelling from about 18 countries, it will be the biggest crowd the conference has attracted since a big boom-time turnout in 2012.
With hotels, motels and university-style accommodation at capacity, more than 140 Kalgoorlie homes will be used to accommodate delegates and the town's watering holes are expected to be buzzing with corporate functions each night.
Sentiment has been buoyed by improved commodity prices and a flurry of deals leading into the conference and the potential for more on the horizon - Evolution Mining is understood to have fielded interest in its Edna May gold mine, and the historic Norseman mine is understood to be back on the market, re-branded as a potentially large open pit operation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newmont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCF Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dacian Gold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gascoyne Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dacian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saracen Mineral Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dealers 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doray Minerals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silver Lake Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Well</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Star's Jundee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Range River Gold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edna May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Star Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jundee</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackham Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortnum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gruyere</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Star</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalgaranga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riversgold</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Twigger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norseman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avoca Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Williams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Monger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metals X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Beament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evolution Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argonaut's Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Morgan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Gold Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carla Gottgens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argonauts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Goldfields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Road Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefan Gosatti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa's Gold Fields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrick Gold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
