<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436993020636349</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:05</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/thanks-to-japan-we-finally-have-a-spectacular-spider-man-homecoming-poster/</url>
  <title>Thanks To Japan We Finally Have A Spectacular Spider-Man: Homecoming Poster</title>
  <content>
We have a  with the posters for Spider-Man: Homecoming. Some of them have been pretty cool, while others have been a little bit of a disaster. Finally, though, we have one that we can all agree on, unambiguously, 100% without a doubt: this is awesome.

Courtesy of Marvel Japan, art by Yusuke Murata

The poster comes courtesy of the official Japanese Twitter account for the film. Homecoming is due out in the country on August 11th, and this commissioned poster by Yusuke Murata celebrates the premiere in style. It's not shocking that such a great Spider-Man take would come out of Japan, either. The country has a long love affair with the hero, culminating perhaps in the delightfully goofy tokusatsu TV show in the '70s.

Marata, probably best known for illustrating One-Punch Man, does a brilliant job here. The framing is dynamic, with Spidey and the Vulture barrelling into the centre of frame. The character design is fabulous, too, faithful to the film with just enough tweaks to set it apart. The whole thing pops. (And I love l'il Iron Man trailing behind in the distance. So cute.)

Tragically, there doesn't seem to be any way that we can find to buy this poster, at least for now. Which is a shame. I mean, just look at it. But there's always One-Punch Man, if you're interested in Murata's take on a more Eastern brand of superhero.

[]

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Punch Man</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spider-Man</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spidey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vulture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homecoming Poster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan We Finally Have A Spectacular Spider-Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yusuke Murata</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
