<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436112552333527</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/health/health-problems/exmodels-massive-ice-addiction-caused-house-siege-when-she-barricaded-herself-in-to-stop-police-killing-me/news-story/0c307d36e7681765b193071e4bfdcffe</url>
  <title>Ex-model's massive ice addiction caused house siege when she barricaded herself in 'to stop police killing me'</title>
  <content>
From ice addict back to wellness, Kate Amoroso is fit and hopes to help other ice users off the drug.

Candace Sutton

Share

EX-model Kate Amoroso's ice addiction reached its height behind a barricaded door in a South Australian town almost three years ago.
The one-time sporty model and elite racing car driver with a $2000-a-week habit was armed with knives and holed up with other ice addicts in the grip of a drug psychosis.
Police had blocked off her street in Mt Gambier, 500km southeast of Adelaide, and told neighbours to lock their doors because they feared Ms Amoroso might do harm.
Inside the house she had been on an eight-day drug bender, swallowing and shooting up massive amounts of the methamphetamines mixed in a lethal cocktail with prescription drugs.
Ms Amoroso believed she could hear helicopters overhead and a police shootout outside her door.
It was an hallucination, but in an effort to keep her awake the other addicts kept feeding her ice.
Plunged further into a psychotic state, Ms Amoroso became so severely deluded that she was convinced police and paramedics were plotting to kill her.
"At one point I got knives from the kitchen and tried to put them through my back because I couldn't see any way out and wanted it to end it all," she said.
"When the police finally convinced me to open the door and put my hands behind my back, I handed them a small square battery and told them to destroy it because it was a bug.

"I thought my house had been tapped," she said of the time she now calls her "Quentin Tarantino moment".

Fighting fit: Kate Amoroso has recovered from her massive drug addiction and now campaigns for more treatment centres.Source:Instagram

In hospital, nurses had to 'net' her to subdue her in the psych ward where she became paranoid and terrifiedSource:Supplied

Kate Amoroso, above in the throes of addiction, descended into a psychosis after an eight-day bender.Source:Supplied

The lists became more detailed as time went on.Source:Supplied

She had to reteach herself basic living.Source:Supplied

She also modelled but fell into drugs after a back injury.Source:Supplied

Kate was a racing car driver.Source:Supplied
Shaking and largely incoherent, Ms Amoroso was taken off under a virtual "code red" at Royal Adelaide Hospital's emergency psych unit.
She would be detained under South Australia's Mental Health Act.
It is an action the now recovered 44-year-old believes saved her life, and if she wins the chance to run for state parliament it will be one of two ice-related platforms she will campaign on.
But it was not the end of the horror for her, and in some ways worse was to come.
Unbeknown to the doctors who received her into care, Ms Amoroso had been playing a devil's game with drugs.
For two years prior to the siege, she had been injecting ice, taking Valium to ease the comedown, antidepressants for the paranoia, codeine for pain and antipsychotics to stop the hallucinations.
At Royal Adelaide, Ms Amoroso's near catatonic state changed to violence.
Terrified by the unfamiliar surroundings, the trained boxer tried to smash her way out.
Alarmed nurses did the only thing they could, and "netted" her.

Kate Amoroso before she fell into a massive drug addiction, which left her in a vegetative state.Source:Supplied

On the way to wellness, Kate Amoroso hit the gym and began training to be a boxer.Source:Supplied

Bursting with energy, Kate in recovery.Source:Supplied

Under the influence of a cocktail of drugs.Source:Supplied
They slammed me to the ground and then put me on a bed and secured me with a net so I couldn't move," she said. "They had to ... only I managed to free myself like Houdini and knocked one of the nurses over.
"The second time I was flat on my back and netted up to my neck so it was pretty much cutting off my airways.
"They were going to discharge me back to Mt Gambier. All I could think of was death, death, death.
"If they had released me I probably would have killed so many people, and myself."
It is a fact Ms Amoroso reminds herself of as disturbing statistics emerge that ice-related suicides have increased.
It doesn't surprise Kate Amoroso.
"My suicidal ideation ended up in I don't know how many attempts, because you feel so hopeless, worthless and useless.

Inspired by the security guard who told her she was 'a fighter', she began writing herself notes. Picture: Kate Amoroso.Source:Supplied

Ms Amoroso has stopped smoking and drinking coffee and is campaigning for office to help ice addicts.Source:Instagram
"That's why we need more rehabilitation centres, and mandatory rehab and detainment under the Mental Health Act.
"I've been sitting all day with a woman, a nurse, who is desperate for help.
"There's only a small window when an ice addict will want help and if they didn't get it because there's no rehab centres that window closes."
In Ms Amoroso's own case, after the netting there was more to come.
Lying on her back in the psych unit, she struggled to speak, eat or move.
In a vegetative state and diagnosed with permanent brain damage, she was not considered likely to recover full functionality.
But an unlikely member of the clinic's staff would say something that would help pull her through.
As a teenager, Ms Amoroso had played many kinds of sport including A-grade netball, and wanted to be a boxer.
Tattooed on her arm was a pair of boxing gloves, which caught the eye of the clinic's hulking security guard.
The tattoo was a relic of Ms Amoroso's ambitions before she had gone down a path of self destruction.
"You're a fighter," the guard told her. "Come on, you can fight."
It was November 2014.

Kate Amoroso, above with her son, is fit and she hopes not too damaged by her massive ice habitSource:Supplied

Ms Amoroso, right, began volunteering in her home town of Mt Gambier and now hopes to run for the SA state parliament.Source:Instagram
Kate Amoroso was about to be formally diagnosed with clinical depression, post traumatic stress disorder from childhood rape and a major anxiety disorder.
In a zombie-like state, she faced a lifetime in care.
"Dad still remembers me lying in hospital lifeless, my eyes not even flickering," she said. "My family expected that they would be going to my funeral.
"I had to be taught how to do everything again," she said.
Adelaide Hospital sent Ms Amoroso back to Mt Gambier, where her sister, her father and a mental health service nurse would help her restore her ability to take care of herself.
She had to face the fact that her drug taking, which began at the age of 15, was masking emotional issues from her childhood, including the rape when she was a 13-year-old.
Ms Amoroso had given birth to the first of her three children at the age of 17, and then started modelling and racing car driving and taking speed and cocaine on the party scene.
Ms Amoroso became engaged to a multi-millionaire and moved to the Gold Coast, where she stopped using any form of drugs for more than a decade.
But then she fell into a vicious pattern of relationships marred by domestic violence.
In 2007, she badly injured her back and was put on major doses of morphine.

Ms Amoroso lived on the Gold Coast and had three children, but then fell into meth addiction after injuring her back.Source:Supplied

Kate Amoroso with her son Jai presenting a petition for more drug rehab centres to Nick Xenophon, second left, and James Stacey.Source:Instagram

Ms Amoroso volunteered as a campaign scrutineer of SA politician Nick Xenophon's team.Source:Instagram
Ms Amoroso was then offered crystal methamphetamine. She took to her new ice addiction with gusto, and disastrous results.
She began injecting ice, while still taking Nurofen Plus, for the painful slipped discs in her back, developing a huge codeine dependency. She also took Valium and antipsychotics.
"I tried suicide several times," she said. "I was in an awful, awful dark place."
Recovering in Mr Gambier, Ms Amoroso had to learn to walk, talk and function.
Her sister began using post-it notes, with lists for just basic living: "shower, brush teeth, get dressed, repeat".
When Ms Amoroso was released into her father's care, he was strict with her.
"He wouldn't let me lie on the couch. He forced me to get up and move, make decisions and find my way back into the land of the living.
"I cried and cried and said, 'Dad, if you loved me you'd give me some Valium' and he'd say, 'I love you Kate, this is what we are doing'.
"He wouldn't let me have access to a computer. I asked for pen and paper. I started writing lists and making goals."
Ms Amoroso joined a gym and then a boxing class and began to shed the excess weight she had gained while immobile in hospital.
She found physical exercise was the most powerful tool for staying clean from drugs.
She quit cigarettes, and even coffee and began rebuilding shattered relationships with family members.
She decided to train in Mixed Martial Arts (MMA), the sport which combines boxing with kickboxing and cage fighting.

Kate Amoroso, above at the SA Parliament, would campaign on more drug rehab facilities for ice users if she stands for office.Source:Instagram
But along the way she started working for others, trying to help ice addicts flee their addictions and volunteering for Meals on Wheels and fund raising for the Leukemia Foundation.
Ms Amoroso began to advocate for more rehabilitation centres for ice addicts - in South Australia there is just one - and to lobby politicians.
The was documented in a National Drug and Alcohol Research Centre study released last week.
It showed that deaths, including suicides, had doubled in six years and the mortality rate was six times greater than in the normal population.
It's something Ms Amoroso knows first-hand, from the desperate families of ice addicts who have contacted her.
"I think people need to know the truth," she said. "And it's an ugly truth.
"Ice is no discriminator. It used to be young people and a low socio-economic demographic, but not any more.
"There are ice addicts in the workforce. There is so much demand and such a lack of facilities.
"Here in South Australia there is one place for a rapid seven to ten day detox.
"Where do you go after that?"

Kate Amoroso (right) fought her way back to health after being 'vegetative' from drugs.Source:Instagram
Kate Amoroso has been campaigning for South Australian independent Nick Xenophon's SA Best party and has been nominated as a potential candidate for next year's state election.
"I don't know what the poison I put in my body when I was taking ice has done to my vital organs," she said.
"I've seen my own hospital records, so there's no telling what the damage is and what time I have to live.
"That's why I want to leave my legacy: Mandatory rehabilitation and detainment under the Mental Health Act."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon's SA Best</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mental Health Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leukaemia Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia's Mental Health Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Amoroso</name>
    <count>23</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>terrifiedSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-model</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Amoroso.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>habitSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mixed Martial Arts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Stacey.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houdini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Gambier</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Candace Sutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen Plus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quentin Tarantino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Amoroso</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EX-model Kate Amoroso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gambier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alcohol Research Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Drug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
