<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437018790440493</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/swoop/ashleigh-gentle-beats-flora-duffy-for-montreal-world-series-triathlon-win/news-story/3d8260451fffd8b2290be20f36c8bbdb</url>
  <title>Gentle cries, faints after triathlon win</title>
  <content>
RIO Olympian Ashleigh Gentle cried, then fainted, after she became only the fourth Australian woman to win a World Series triathlon in an encouraging sign for a home town victory at the Commonwealth Games next year.
Gentle fainted 20 minutes after the race and was under medical care on a IV drip for two hour after her win in the Montreal triathlon she almost didn't race due to an upper respiratory tract infection.

A decade after she won the world junior triathlon crown, in triathlons elite series - only the fourth Australian woman to achieve the feat.
Long overshadowed by the likes of Olympic champion Emma Snowsill, multiple world champion Emma Moffatt and Olympic medallist Erin Densham during the early stages of her career, Gentle has now announced herself as Australian triathlons leading lady with her win in Montreal.

The victory, after five second places in previous races, also enhanced Gentle's prospects of delivering the sport a home town victory at next years Commonwealth Games with the Australian the 20th female athlete to win a WTS race and only the fourth Aussie after Snowsill, Moffatt and Densham.
"I arrived into Montreal feeling sick and didn't know whether I would be able to race - I only made my decision this morning, hours before the start," said Gentle, who was the first triathlete to qualify for next year's Commonwealth Games.
"I'm in shock really ... I can't believe it. I had my first WTS start in the London Test event in 2011 so it's been six long years of ups and downs, five silver medals and finally I've had a win ... that was a tough race for me."
Gentle beat world champion Flora Duffy from Bermuda to the finish of the 1.5km swim, 40km cycle and 10km run race with New Zealand veteran Andrea Hewitt third.
Duffy still leads the world triathlon series - which determines the sports world champion each year- with Gentle now in second place.
"We gave Ashleigh the choice to pull out or race and if she chose to race the benefits were that she could "grow a whole lot taller as an athlete",'' said coach Jamie Turner.
"Her growth today was fantastic and it actually looked effortless."
Charlotte McShane was the next best Australian in 10th place.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Densham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIO Olympian Ashleigh Gentle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Hewitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Moffatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duffy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flora Duffy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WTS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Densham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Snowsill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snowsill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlotte McShane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bermuda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moffatts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montreal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
