<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437147639460529</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/teams/essendon/john-watson-wont-tell-jobe-watson-when-to-retire/news-story/72f0fa827820f73b3fdd0d498b3c55f4</url>
  <title>Worsfold won't tell Jobe when to retire</title>
  <content>
JOHN Worsfold is adamant he will not a force a decision on Jobe Watson's future despite admitting he "struggled" in the .
Watson was defended by Joe Daniher this week, who said his influence around the club had been "incredible" this season.
He has racked up solid numbers with little impact this year but had only 11 possessions against Carlton.
LONG RIVALRY:
CLUB LEGEND:
He has amassed the lowest numbers since he emerged as a Bombers regular, with just two kicks as the Dons fought back to keep their season alive.
But Worsfold said he had no plans to expedite any discussion on retirement, saying only if Watson came to him would that status change.
It seems his position in the side is safe as the Dons take on Adelaide (Etihad Stadium), Gold Coast (Metricon) and Fremantle (Etihad) to attempt to qualify for September.
Watson is averaging 24 possessions (his least since 2007), 195m gained (his lowest ever), 9.6 contested possessions (his fewest since 2007) and has kicked only one goal.
"We will (have that discussion) in the post-season after the dust has settled. We will get a better idea of how Jobe is feeling when we get through the full season," Worsfold said on 3AW.
"That is still the plan. If anything changes in the meantime, if Jobe was really clear in indicating he wanted to play on or hang up the boots he could come and see me.
"Right at the moment we are leaving it until the season finishes. There is no urgency on our behalf and we will let it run its course."
On Saturday Worsfold had said that while Watson had "struggled" he was still a super footballer who had simply played poorly.
Daniher told the Herald Sun earlier in the week .
"He is incredible. He has got an incredible footy brain and great knowledge and thinks outside the square with a lot of things," he said.
"For the young guys he's an incredible leader but also as a person and footy brain. His stats old up, you know when he's around the ball he's going to win more contests than he loses.
"But that's not really what he's in the side for - to get the ball - he is there to be a strong communicator around the ball and through the week.
"He makes sure guys like Zach Merrett and Darcy Parish do their job, he's been huge for us."
The Bombers will have to replace Orazio Fantasia (three week hamstring), while Zach Merrett will face MRP heat for his punch on Lachie Plowman.
His most likely punishment would be a $1500 fine for an intentional but low-impact strike.
Worsfold said James Kelly and Andrew McGrath will return against Adelaide after being rested against the Dons.
Josh Begley, taken at pick 31 in last year's draft, could make his debut after impressive VFL form.
"I expect both have recovered well and are pretty pumped about the game. With Fantazia going out it opens up one spot so we have a chance to look at a forward like (Jayden) Laverde or someone like Begley who is in good form and might get an opportunity."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday Worsfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metricon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Worsfold</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Begley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Parish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fantazia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orazio Fantasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Plowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Begley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLUB LEGEND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Worsfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
