<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436370250373448</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/crusaders-australian-prop-michael-alaalatoa-shows-all-black-potential-20170805-gxq6i7.html</url>
  <title>Crusaders' Australian prop Michael Alaalatoa shows All Black potential</title>
  <content>
1. The former Waratahs tighthead is now a Super Rugby champion with the Crusaders but big decisions lie ahead with regards to Test eligibility. The Crusaders clearly rate him, and when the Crusaders rate a tight forward, you know that All Blacks interest is not far away. 
They demanded a big shift from the big man in the final against the Lions in Johannesburg, throwing him on at half time, and he responded in defence and with ball in hand. Alaalatoa will know that longer-term, the All Blacks are looking for depth in his position after the departure of Charlie Faumuina and he's probably in the world's best environment for props, learning from the likes of Owen Franks.Photo: Mark Baker
By the second half of next year, the 135kg Sydneysider could be getting a call from Steve Hansen. How did he slip through the Australian system?
2. Lions will regret the final until their graves. They froze, the South Africans. In front of a massive crowd that was supposed to inspire them they went into their shells in the first half, with Elton Jantjies completely outplayed by Crusaders No.10 Richie Mo'unga, who is likely to be an unlucky omission from the All Blacks squad named on Monday. 

The Lions looked nervous, their handling was poor, their exit strategies were disorganised, Jantjies looked rattled and then Kwagga Smith foolishly charged into an airborne David Havili to collect a red card. What will sting is that they could still have won the final had they performed at even 60 per cent of their ability.
The massive factors of travel and altitude caught up with the Crusaders from about the 55-minute mark, and even with 14 men the Lions started to find some holes. There now have to be some serious doubts about whether the Springboks can really improve with Jantjies at No.10.

3. Joe Moody's scrummaging will worry the Wallabies. The Wallabies will think that Moody's technique is sometimes less than square but they will have to take the ref out of the equation, because scrum interpretations vary from week to week.

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

My own view is that Moody has developed into possibly the world's best No.1 because although he does work the angles (who doesn't?) he also has massive power to win the contest when he keeps square and then drives in.
His scrum penalty against Lions tighthead Ruan Dreyer just before half time was a huge moment in the match and allowed the Crusaders to keep accumulating the points they would need at the back end.
4. Ryan Crotty was my man of the match. I still expect the Crusaders No.12 to wear No.13 in the first Bledisloe test to accommodate Sonny Bill Williams at No.12 but regardless of his position he is likely to be the key defensive organiser the Wallabies will have to outwit.
His ability to create tries as well as stop them should not be underestimated. He played a key role in Crusaders tries in both the semi final and the final and has also added a cross-kick to his armoury.
He is clearly the best midfielder in New Zealand, although it says a lot about Ruan Ackermann's power and potential that the young Lions No. 8 was twice able to bump him off in the final.
5. South Africa's drought continues. It is now seven years since the South Africans won Super Rugby, and in that period the Wallabies have twice performed better at World Cups than the Springboks and won two Super Rugby titles.
There will now be the traditional exodus of South African players and coaches (such as the Lions' Johan Ackermann) to greener pastures in Europe and Japan, while the Cheetahs and Kings (one of the bright spots of South African rugby this year) join the Pro14 tournament.
The Lions aside, these are difficult times for South African rugby. Super Rugby's format change next year means that South Africa is only guaranteed of hosting one quarter-final, instead of two under the current format. This era of Kiwi dominance isn't likely to change. 
Team of the Season
1. Joe Moody (Crusaders)
2. Malcolm Marx (Lions)
3. Owen Franks (Crusaders)
4. Sam Whitelock (Crusaders)
5. Franco Mostert (Lions)
6. Jaco Kriel (Lions)
7.  Matt Todd (Crusaders)
8. Luke Whitelock (Highlanders)
9. TJ Perenara (Hurricanes)
10. Richie Mo'unga (Crusaders)
11. Seta Tamanivalu (Crusaders)
12. Ngani Laumape (Hurricanes)
13. Jack Goodhue (Crusaders)
14. Israel Dagg (Crusaders)
15. Damian McKenzie (Chiefs)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hansen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Todd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seta Tamanivalu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owen Franks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydneysiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crusaders No.12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Whitelock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Havili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Marx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lions' Johan Ackermann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel Dagg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Goodhue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Alaalatoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highlanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damian McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lions No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Crotty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crusaders No.10 Richie Mo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jantjies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ngani Laumape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richie Mo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elton Jantjies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franco Mostert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TJ Perenara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owen Franks.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwagga Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alaalatoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRO14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruan Dreyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springboks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOHANNESBURG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crusaders' Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Faumuina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Moody</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moody</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaco Kriel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruan Ackermann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Whitelock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
