<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437143344493148</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/teams/gws/toby-greene-working-overtime-to-learn-how-to-deal-with-niggle-says-leon-cameron/news-story/7f1c8d798694addd28a76cee43c920c4</url>
  <title>Greene 'working overtime' to handle niggle</title>
  <content>
LEON Cameron says Toby Greene is working overtime to deal with opposition niggling as he prepares from his latest return from suspension.
Greene has again worked with Greater Western Sydney's sports psychologist after his latest two-match ban for punching Alex Rance.
He has now missed four weeks with suspension this year - he also hit Western Bulldog Caleb Daniel - and will return against the reigning premiers on Friday night.
MATCH REPORT:
DELEDIO RETURN:
Dawson Simpson is likely to replace Shane Mumford, set for a suspension after his elbow to Demons ruckman Max Gawn.
But Brett Deledio pulled up well from his first senior Giants game and will take on the Dogs off a six-day break.
Cameron said Greene had been making progress before his explosion against Richmond, which means he has an applicable bad record for two years.

"I want him to play the way he needs to before that is what makes him a good player. But there is no doubt we can't afford to lose him again for the rest of the year," he said.
"It would be stupid to say he should go out an play in an aggressive manner. The consequences are huge.
"Toby is working really hard behind the scenes and people don't understand that in terms of the right sports psychologist and handling those moments when they come around.
"After the Dogs suspension he was absolutely terrific for seven or eight weeks in a row amid some intimidation to try to upset his game.
"He handled it well and then we came up against Richmond. He needs to constantly get two or three per cent better and that is what I am after."
GWS leadership group mentor Nick Maxwell fiercely denied claims out-of-contact star Josh Kelly had started to mentally check out at the club.
Cameron told 3AW that while he would love a decision on his future by the finals he will give Kelly all the time he needs.
The Giants have offered top ten pick Jacob Hopper a two-year deal worth over $800,000 but he is yet to commit to the club as Geelong and Carlton circle.
Mid-sized forward Devon Smith has also been offered a multi-year deal worth around $500,000 a season but is understood to want a more lucrative deal
Hopper is content to wait until later in the year to decide his future, but Kelly's uncertainty affects the club's ability to offer Smith more money.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Rance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devon Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldog Caleb Daniel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greene</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mid-sized</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawson Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DELEDIO RETURN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
