<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436151207039420</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/afl-2017-its-time-for-the-afl-to-go-for-the-hard-ball-with-new-footy-boss-20170805-gxq1bq.html</url>
  <title>It's time for the AFL to go for the hard ball with new footy boss</title>
  <content>
Sometime between now and the end of the year, the AFL will have a new boss of footy. Expressions of interest closed last Monday for the position left vacant by the departure, three weeks ago, of Simon Lethlean.
When the executive search for a replacement began, the AFL stated its commitment "to a thorough process, ensuring it can unearth the best candidate, man or woman, to lead the game's football operations department across both the AFL and AFLW".Photo: Joe Armao
So what does the best candidate actually look like?
If you consider the credentials brought to the table by the last five incumbents, you wouldn't be much the wiser as to the specific qualities the AFL considers most important for one in this role.
Ian Collins brought playing and administrative experience, a fix-it mentality, an intimate knowledge of where every last body in the industry was buried, and a reputation for knowing every rule - and every loophole - in the system. When he left, Andrew Demetriou came from the players' association, also bringing a playing pedigree, along with what was arguably a more refined version of Collo's skill-set.
Then things changed. When Wayne Jackson left the CEO's position, Demetriou was appointed as his replacement and immediately had to deal with the matter of who should succeed him as head of football. He appointed Adrian Anderson, a media lawyer. Although Anderson played amateur football, he brought no prior experience from within the AFL system.

When Anderson resigned in late 2012, there was a reversion to orthodoxy with the appointment, from club land, of Mark Evans. Then, when Evans returned whence he'd come (albeit to a different club) after three years in the job, an AFL House insider, Simon Lethlean, was appointed.
The AFL's recent media release announcing the commencement of its search for Lethlean's replacement listed the following key aspects of the role:

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

• Ensuring all AFL and AFLW matches are delivered in accordance with AFL rules and regulations.
• Overseeing the delivery of National AFL Talent programs to develop and support the best male and female players, coaches and umpires.
• Overseeing AFL umpiring to ensure the game is well officiated.
• Leading a large, high-performing team across the following portfolios:
• Talent pathways
• AFLW
• Player education and welfare
• Ground operations
• Coaching
• Umpiring
• Laws of the Game, Match Review Panel and the AFL Tribunal
All of these are, without doubt, important. Yet, to me, this job description fails to spell out strongly enough that the new football boss will be world chief (hey, Melbourne is AFL global HQ!) of on-field management for this sport.
What about the guiding, the nurturing, the overseeing of the game, moveable feast that it has become? What about the successful applicant being required to have a demonstrable and vital interest in ensuring the game remains true to an abiding philosophy? What about an expectation being required of the appointee that ensures the game isn't dragged totally from its moorings by the regular urging of coaches, clubs and emotive fans? Isn't this all the stuff of primary responsibility for the AFL football boss?
Nowhere is any of this this better, or more clearly, reflected than in the forever-fluid concept of 'prior opportunity'. The matter of how to deal with the player caught in possession of the ball has been a problematic issue for the code for as long as anyone can remember. Yet, in all that time, I don't recall better than glib attempts being made to solve the riddle.
Last weekend on 3AW, Leigh Matthews spoke of a growing tide of opinion (presumably from around the table of the Laws of the Game Committee) that the concept of prior opportunity may soon be scrapped. Not because it's too punitive ... no, because it isn't tough enough!
In other words, there is a possibility the game will soon be played in a way which offers absolutely no priority to the ball-player vis-a-vis the tackler. This, of course, would make life simple for the umpires (just like scrapping the bounce!), as no interpretation would be required. It would also validate fans in their mindless bellowing of 'Baaaaalllll!!!'
But such an idea represents a total inversion of the philosophy on which the Australian game was formed. It would, more than ever, reduce the differentiation between our game and the rugby codes, something actively encouraged in the Australian game's formative years. As such, it shines a light on the questions raised above about the need for serious reflection on the game we have and the one we want.
Little guidance on these matters of philosophy appears to come from the AFL Commission. Chris Judd, from his perspective as a member of the Laws Committee, wrote earlier this year that rule changes tend to be more commonly initiated by market research than via conventional channels. If this came from anyone else, you'd say 'nonsense'. But there are few more credible modern voices on the game than Judd's.
If nothing else, this offers some understanding as to how the game's rule-making has for too long been so fluid. But it also indicates that the AFL, on the game over which it has assumed total rule-making and management control, has been guilty of a significant lack of leadership.
The fact that a new football operations manager, or football maintenance manager - call it what you will - is about to be chosen, provides a window of opportunity. This isn't a job for any old market researcher or club administrator. It isn't for any old lawyer or inhabitant of AFL House. It's a job for someone with a serious interest in what the game should be, and who has some serious ideas about taking it there.
It's time for the AFL to go for the hard ball.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baaaaalllll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Armao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Lethlean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laws of the Game</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Judd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Demetriou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demetrious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National AFL Talent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFLW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JUDD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lethlean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
