<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437139049525805</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836510/bench-presses-and-deadlifts-for-charity-in-wollongong/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Ladies of Lifting powerlifting competition takes place in Wollongong, raises funds for homelessness services</title>
  <content>
WEIGHTS: Brooke Redman in action during the Ladies of Lifting powerlifting competition/fundraising event in Wollongong on Sunday. Picture: Robert Peet

It was the definition of a physically challenging fundraiser on Sunday. 

Established in 2016, the Ladies of Lifting powerlifting competition aims to give novice female lifters an opportunity to lift without the pressures of large competition. Gyms in Wollongong, Merimbula, Canberra and Perth hosted competitions.

Almost 200 lifters participated across the events. 
RAW Athletic in North Wollongong was the venue for the Illawarra event, which was also a fundraiser for Supported Accommodation and Homelessness Services Shoalhaven Illawarra. 
"We're trying to encourage women to lift by removing as many barriers as possible," Wollongong event organiser Anna Brown from The Barbelle Club said. 

"There are so many positive benefits in this training method for women of all ages. We are focused on keeping the day fairly low-key and as relaxed as possible for the women who are competing."

Ms Brown said 15 lifters ranging in age from 18 to 50 took part, with some competitors travelling from Sydney and Canberra, and many achieving personal bests.

She said funds were still being tallied, but estimated more than $500 was raised at the Wollongong event.
Ms Brown said they were trying to create a platform for women to try out the sport of powerlifting without feeling intimidated or excluded. 

"By holding Ladies of Lifting we hope women will feel comfortable enough to give it a go, test themselves and see what they can do," she said.  

"This is a perfect opportunity to try out the sport in a friendly, supportive environment or to come along and see what it's all about."

READ MORE: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brooke Redman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supported Accommodation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBERT PEET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homelessness Services Shoalhaven Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merimbula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbelle Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladies of Lifting</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
