<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437057445146546</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/studs-and-duds-from-west-coast-eagles-loss-to-st-kilda-at-etihad-stadium/news-story/bf1f75c0c150e3a8c0e4870ddab21f8d</url>
  <title>Studs and duds from Eagles' loss</title>
  <content>
JOSH Kennedy had five majors in a losing cause, while Jack Steele and Blake Acres dominated for St Kilda.
Who Impressed
Josh Kennedy
Reached a couple of milestones - 500 career goals and 50 for the season - on his way to a game-high five majors. Still a huge chance of winning a third straight Coleman Medal, despite missing five games with a calf problem. Has 20 goals in four matches since returning from injury in round 17.
Jack Steele
The former Giant starred for the home side with an impressive all-round performance. Provided his usual defensive pressure with a game-high 11 tackles and stepped up with a couple of important goals in the first and final quarters.
Josh Kennedy's 500th AFL goal

Blake Acres
What a performance from the WA-raised Saint. Reached his career-best disposal count (30) to go with five tackles and a goal. Has found form after getting dropped earlier in the season.
Shannon Hurn
The Eagles skipper fought hard down back against a talented St Kilda forward line. One of his team's most consistent players with eight marks and four tackles to go with 22 possessions.
Dom Sheed
One of the Eagles' best, Sheed continued his breakout season. The classy left-footer finished with 23 possessions and a brilliant long-range goal.
Sheed's silky finish

Who Didn't
Chris Masten
Recalled ahead of Brownlow medallist Matt Priddis, Masten failed to make the most of his opportunity. In his first game since round 17, the 28-year-old looked slow and got caught holding the ball twice in the opening term. A big chance of playing out the season in the WAFL.
Will Schofield
Had a nightmare down back and was regularly beaten in one-on-one contests against the likes of Josh Bruce, Tim Membrey and Nick Riewoldt, who finished with five goals and 20 marks between them. The Eagles sorely missed young defender Tom Barrass, who was out with a groin injury.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Masten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Barrass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Membrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Acres</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Hurn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA-raised Saint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy's 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Steele</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
