<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436709552792305</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/movies/director-george-lucas-reveals-princess-leia-wasnt-just-a-princess-she-was-also-a-doctor/news-story/3ed83485ca40d0bc6898cf5e0550310d</url>
  <title>Princess Leia's surprising backstory revealed</title>
  <content>
WHEN it comes to Star Wars, few characters in the monumental franchise hold a candle to Princess Leia.
Not only was Carrie Fisher's character an incredible fighter and fair ruler, it turns out "princess" wasn't the only title she had.
In recently unearthed commentary from the 2004 movie Star Wars: A New Hope, director George Lucas speaks about Leia's backstory, revealing she was quite a gifted youngster.
Lucas goes as far to reveal that, when Leia's twin Luke Skywalker was busy being "an idealistic, naive farm boy", the princess was out getting her PhD.
Meaning that, just Leia could've gone by either princess or doctor.
And not only did Leia score a PhD before becoming one of space's greatest heroes, she also managed to earn the title at the ripe age of 19.
"She's like a very sophisticated, urbanised ruler, a senator, so she's a politician," Lucas said.
"She's accomplished, graduated, got her PhD at 19 and she rules people and is in charge," he added.
Fisher was cast as the gutsy princess after Lucas revealed he wanted an actress that could do the part justice.
"[I needed an actress] who could be young and play with a lot of authority ... and push these guys around".
The exciting titbit was  in Carolyn Cocca's book Superwomen: Gender, Power and Representation.
"Hang on wait ... Leia had a PhD in Star Wars? Christ can you imagine having everyone call you Princess when you were actually Dr Organa," Harrison tweeted.
Fisher, who died in December last year after at the age of 60, will posthumously star in Star Wars: The Last Jedi, due for release later this year.
The film will be the eight instalment of the hugely successful franchise and is the second in the revival trilogy starring actors Daisy Ridley and John Boyega.
At last month's D23 Expo in California, Star Wars fans were treated to a behind-the-scenes video of the upcoming movie that featured the late Carrie Fisher in her final appearance as Princess Leia.
"It's about family," Fisher says in the video. "That's what makes it so real".

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>D23 Expo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Jedi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daisy Ridley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Boyega</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Hope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Wars</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrie Fisher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PhD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Skywalker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Leia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Organa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolyn Cocca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Lucas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
