<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437143344493200</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/mural-of-missing-teen-siriyakorn-bung-siriboon-created-in-hosier-lane/news-story/8be3477c93ac25ce83b15796a1785139</url>
  <title>Mural hope for missing girl</title>
  <content>
FOR six years, the family of Boronia teenager Siriyakorn "Bung" Siriboon has lived with her disappearance and the anguish of not knowing what happened.
Bung, who was 13, was last seen walking to school on June 2, 2011, before vanishing without a trace.
Police have analysed more than 1200 pieces of information in the notorious case, and, despite a $1 million reward for leads, are no closer to finding out what happened to the schoolgirl.
Now, Bung's stepdad Fred Pattison and his wife Vanidda are clinging to hope that a new project will provide answers.

A mural of Bung by artist Ashley Goudie has been painted at popular street art precinct Hosier Lane to raise awareness of her disappearance.
It's part of the Unmissables Project, run by the Missing Persons Advocacy Network, in which artists and writers help families reignite their search for loved ones.
Mr Pattison said he hoped the mural would connect with people who didn't know Bung's story or didn't keep up with mainstream media.
"(Hosier Lane) is a pretty famous sort of area from what I know, it's another avenue to get the story out there, maybe people know something or have heard something," he said.
Mr Pattison said dealing with Bung's disappearance over the last six years had been very hard.
"It's frustrating, annoying, lots of different emotions. Not knowing anything is a lot harder than maybe knowing something," he said.
"We really miss her, it's affected a lot of people - it's not just me and my wife, it's her sister, grandparents, it's friends, it's the community."
"A whole lot of people want some answers so hopefully anyone with any ideas will come forward, you're always just waiting for that one phone call."
More than 100 Australians are reported missing daily and while most are found within a week, there are currently over 2000 long-term missing people.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siriyakorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unmissables Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hosier Lane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pattison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Goudie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred Pattison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missing Persons Advocacy Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanidda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siriboon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boronia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bung</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
