<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437139049525836</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/queensland-mps-on-smashing-the-ceiling-in-politics-20170804-gxphr4.html</url>
  <title>Queensland MPs on smashing the ceiling in politics</title>
  <content>
So you want to be a woman in politics? You'll probably cop comments about your clothing and hair and occasional abuse.
Female politicians shared their wisdom with 50 young women in Queensland Parliament on Friday at an event designed to encourage them to consider a career in politics and "smash the ceiling".
Labor member for Waterford Shannon Fentiman said comments were still made about how she dressed and did her hair.
"I'm asked more often than my male colleagues how old I am, whether I'm married, why I don't have children," she said.Photo: Glenn Hunt
"I have been described in the Queensland Parliament as a banshee and as a mean girl.
"When men speak up in Parliament during debates they are praised for being ambitious and authoritative, but sadly when women do the same thing, we're labelled as bossy or pushy or a banshee."

Ms Fentiman said she had to develop a thick skin. 

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"You have really great mates and mentors that you talk to you about it and you vent to about it and then you realise the bigger picture is in the work that you're doing," she said.
Labor member for Lytton Joan Pease she had never experienced any form of discrimination or felt inequality until she became a member of Parliament.
"I'll be in a committee ... and I can ask a question of someone and they don't look at me to reply, they'll look at the male chair sitting beside me," she said.
Ms Pease said everyone was entitled to be treated with respect and it was important for people to call out poor behaviour.
Tasmanian Labor deputy leader Michelle O'Byrne said when she was elected in the federal Parliament in 1998, some of her first headlines were "She's in Parliament and she's in love" and "How our MP met her man".
"My local radio station had an entire morning talkback show on whether or not I could do my job when I was pregnant," she said.
Labor member for Bulimba Di Farmer said it was "wrong on so many levels" for New Zealand Labour leader Jacinda Ardern to be .
Ms Farmer said women in politics often received comments about their appearance, weight or how they dressed, whereas that did not happen to the men.
Ms Farmer conceded: "Yes politics is a tough game".
"But if you want to do it, you've kind of got to get over that, and it is the most rewarding job that you could possibly have," she said.
Women make up 33 per cent of politicians in Australian parliaments, an improvement on the 20 per cent figure of the late 1990s.
But Australia is slipping down the ranks in terms of gender in politics.
In 1999, Australia was ranked 15th in the world by the Inter-Parliamentary Union for the gender representatives of our lower or single houses of Parliament. 
Australia now stands at 50th. 
So how do we get more women in politics? 
Liberal National Party MP Ros Bates said the rules were the same for men and women in the LNP and people needed to understand the rules, rather than show up too late for the pre-selection or without doing the ground work.
"You've got to have the support of the branch members around you and to put it crudely you have to have the numbers to win a pre-selection," she said.
"You just have to know how to play the game."
LNP member for Broadwater Verity Barton said she was lucky to have supportive family and friends, and she said the women in the opposition got together often to support each other.
"So that we can talk about things, whether it's personal things or whatever it is, so there's a support base," she said.
Ms Fentiman said affirmative action had created cultural change in Queensland Labor, where the party actively sought out talented women candidates.
"I think honestly, it's only been used two or three times since it's been used since it was introduced," she said.
"So just the rule change has actually led to a huge cultural shift."
Ms Farmer said women should know their strengths and not be afraid to talk about them.
"We hear too many stories of women thinking 'oh maybe I'm not quite good enough'," she said.
"If you want to be a politician, put your hand up, say I'm really good at this, I'm going to be the best person for this job and go for it."
Ms Fentiman said women needed to see female leaders.
"You can't be what you can't see," Ms Fentiman said.
Queensland Commonwealth Women Parliamentarians hosted the event with Queensland Youth Parliament.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inter-Parliamentary Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lytton Joan Pease</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle O'Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Parliament</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Farmer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Pease</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulimba Di Farmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Youth Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterford Shannon Fentiman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda Ardern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal National Party MP Ros Bates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Commonwealth Women Parliamentarians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fentiman</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadwater Verity Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
