<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437139049525816</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/musicals/paulini-hits-the-big-time-playing-the-role-whitney-made-famous-in-the-bodyguard-20170801-gxmqmw.html</url>
  <title>Paulini hits the big time, playing the role Whitney made famous in The Bodyguard</title>
  <content>
In the world of musicals, there has traditionally been a Look. The hair. The teeth. But most of all - let's face it - the skin. It's why Paulini Curuenavuli was never interested in music theatre. "It was very white, shiny, all of that. It was very white. And musically, it just didn't touch my soul or speak to me in any way."
Never in her wildest imaginings did Paulini picture herself in a musical. But look at the shows playing Melbourne this year, and you'll find different faces in the frame. Aladdin. Kinky Boots. The Book of Mormon. All rest on the talents of performers who don't meet the cookie-cutter criteria of old. And there's Paulini, soon to hit Melbourne playing the lead role in The Bodyguard. The Look isn't what it used to be.Photo: Jeff Busby
Journalistic convention states that I should be referring to Paulini Curuenavuli by her surname, but it feels like using Ciccone for Madonna or Graham for Drake. Paulini is Paulini, or has been since she was thrust into the public eye at 20. Paulini was a contestant in the original Australian Idol, a reality star before anyone knew what that meant. Her life in music began much earlier.
The Curuenavulis arrived in Australia from Fiji when Paulini was only four. She is the youngest of six children, and while none were classically trained in music, all of her family were singing and playing instruments from a young age. Her Dad was a choir conductor who taught the kids how to harmonise, and Paulini got her public start in the church choir when she was 10.Photo: Jeff Busby
Like most children of her era, the young Paulini watched Video Hits and Rage like an obsessive. She remembers the day she turned to her Mum and pointed to the TV. "One day I want to do a video clip like that," she said. "One day, Mum. One day."
You and half the pre-teen population of Australia, kid. But - and this will become a theme - the idea that you have to jump on any opportunity that presents itself was already cemented in Paulini's outlook in these early years. She would scour local newspapers for talent quests. "I'd go 'right, I'm going to go to this one, going to this one, do this one,' and seriously, every opportunity I used to go for it. I used to do so many talent quests growing up."

At RSL clubs and community halls across Sydney she let her voice soar, and she never won a thing. You might think all that rejection would dampen an aspiring singer's enthusiasm, but it only pushed her to try harder. "You've just got to take every opportunity, even though you don't always get anything out of it."

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

What kept her going - and this is the second theme Paulini returns to repeatedly - was the unconditional support she found in the people around her. "My parents used to always tell me, 'look, even though you haven't won any of these talent quests, you have a gift.' The amazing thing was that I had such a supportive family and still do today. We encourage each other all the time, that the talent was given to us by God and we should share it."Photo: Nic Walker
Success finally arrived when she was 16 and came first in the talent contest, StarStruck, (prophetically, singing Whitney Houston's When You Believe). She recorded the song for the show's official CD and went back to high school, forming a band with her sisters and jamming with friends.
A few years later she was slinging cargo pants and polo shirts in a retail job. She had just turned 20 when friends and family began encouraging her to try out for  a new TV song contest, Australian Idol. "I think if it was just up to me I wouldn't have done it." But her home team hadn't let her down yet.
"Having that support there and knowing that whether the outcome was good or bad, I always had them there to catch me ..." she says. "Even on Idol it was embarrassing when I went through that whole gold dress thing but my family were there and said, 'look, don't worry about it, just keep on'. "
That whole gold dress thing. It's an indictment on  the media that reporters still go back to a comment made 14 years ago whenever talking to Paulini. Back in the day, Australian Idol judge Peter "Dicko" Dickson was publicly excoriated after the singer appeared on stage in a gold dress he found unflattering. He told her to "choose more appropriate clothes or shed some pounds". The real takeaway, however, should have been Paulini's reaction: she smiled and thanked the judges for their comments.
Backstage, she cried. Then she got over it. She is the one who raises the incident, now, and it's clear there are no scars. In fact, having spoken to half a dozen veterans of Idol's first season, it seems none came away burdened with the lasting damage sudden fame can inflict on a person. "To be honest, I didn't get affected by it. At all."
The reason is simple: "We didn't have Facebook back then. We didn't have all of these social media sites so for us if you didn't read the paper or watch the news, you didn't really know what was happening. And we were told not to really look at things like that, just to concentrate on what we had to do."
Idol's original season came along when reality TV was still taking its infant steps. Now the form is full of cynical formulas and concocted drama, hashtaggable relationships and social media optimisation. Then the Idol producers put all of the contestants in a house and - get this - didn't even put cameras in there with them.
"The amazing thing about our group is that we just had fun," Paulini says. "None of us expected to get a record deal ... Nobody in that house expected to get anything out of it. We all just went in there with our daggy clothes and daggy hairstyles and did the show. We thought it was all about the voice. The thing that's missing now is that a lot of young people think they've got to look a certain way or dress a certain way or talk a certain way, or come up with an emotional story to get people's attention. Back then, none of us did that. We took every day as it came and didn't really think too far ahead."
Paulini came a respectable fourth on Idol and, in the 14 years since, has recorded three solo albums and two with the Idol supergroup, Young Divas. Her first solo record debuted at number one and single Angel Eyes spent several weeks in the top spot, granting Paulini two ARIA No. 1 Chart Awards.
She is businesslike about her achievements. "My first album was successful because I had just come off a show, and I had the support of a huge record label and the viewers that voted for me. But after that, that's when you really have to work at it. Once you get off that stage and off that TV show, that's when the hard work starts."
Her second solo album, Superwoman, failed to match the success of her first. "It didn't do well at all. It totally flopped because we had released another album with the Young Divas at the same time, and I don't know whether it was bad timing but it just didn't do well. That was a massive disappointment. All of the Young Divas albums were great, they worked, so I had that. But it was almost bittersweet having them at the same time because the success was in the group, but my solo stuff wasn't going so well."
There were low points when Paulini questioned whether she was really on the right track, or whether she should try something else. No prizes for guessing what kept her keeping on. "It really does depend on the people around you. I sound like a broken record but they either build you up or pull you down.
"Even with my third album (2015's Come Alive), that didn't go well. Still, I love music too much to leave it. I've gotten to a place where I can't actually live without it so I have to keep going. I'm always working at it, trying to find opportunities and that's what led me to this, to musical theatre."
It was while recording her last album in London that Paulini and her manager caught a performance of The Bodyguard on the West End. Despite her disinterest in musical theatre, "I told my manager, 'if this ever comes to Australia, I'm going for that role'."
A few months later, back in Oz, there were rumours that various companies were trying to secure the rights to the show. The Gordon Frost Organisation eventually landed the deal and Paulini's people shot off an email expressing her interest, emphasising that even though she had never been in a musical, she was "willing to do the work and all that jazz".
They didn't hear back for two years. Then, like a bolt from the blue, the call came. The script is on its way. They want Paulini to audition. In four days.
"I was freaking out. I was like, oh my god, no way." After four rounds of callbacks, her manager phoned her to confirm that she had made it. His news was met by silence - she couldn't speak through the tears.
She might not have the acting and dance background of other music theatre stars, but in the case of The Bodyguard, casting Paulini is like calling in the artillery. When the show opened in Sydney, every review had unreserved praise for the singer's ability to meet the demands laid down by Whitney's memory.
But if you're going to climb your first mountain, why not make it Everest? Like Tina Turner or Janis Joplin, Whitney Houston's voice is baked into the DNA of her songs. You can sing your own version of a Katy Perry or Lady Gaga tune, but every rendition of a Whitney Houston track is in part a tribute act.
"It is Mount Everest," Paulini says. "They're massive songs. They're songs that a lot of female singers try to stay away from just because they're such big songs. The way she sings them is extraordinary and she has such a huge range. How she interprets and sustains her notes is unbelievable."
Musicals might have left her cold in the past, but exploring them from the inside has left her with a new respect for her fellow performers. "The work ethic is just amazing, they're just such hard workers and I take my hat off to them. Being a triple threat is massive. To get up there and dance and sing and act, you really have to be tough."
Paulini's tough, too. She is stoic when an album flops. She takes opportunities that might go nowhere. And 14 years after responding to a TV judge's insults with grace, she is there on posters for The Bodyguard in a gold dress.
The Bodyguard opens at The Regent on August 24. 
A STAGE THEY'RE GOING THROUGH
Paulini isn't the first Australian to cross over into musical theatre from elsewhere. The ability to sing, dance and act requires astounding discipline from musical performers, but some of the most popular stage stars have put in the effort and passed the test.
Fellow Idol season one alumnus Rob Mills is a staple on the Australian musical scene today. Like Paulini, Mills has made no bones about the fact that he arrived without the same formal dance and acting background many music theatre stars possess, but he has proven himself a tireless worker to make up for it. Lead roles have included several Grease tours, Wicked, Legally Blonde and the current season of Jesus Christ Superstar in Melbourne.
Long before Wolverine was carving up screens, Hugh Jackman was making a name for himself in local flicks such as Erskineville Kings and Paperback Hero. He was also trying his hand at music theatre, though, in Sunset Boulevard and a Disney production of Beauty and the Beast. His passion would eventually score him an Olivier Award nomination for best actor in a West End production of Oklahoma!, a number of Broadway shows of his own and a chance to marry both forms in the film adaptation of Les Miserables.
Lisa McCune was a household name thanks to Blue Heelers for much of the '90s, but a role in The Sound of Music soon after the show ended saw an unexpected career transformation. Now she is perhaps as well known for her stage performances as her TV work, having played leading roles in productions ranging from South Pacific to Cabaret to The King and I.
Jason Donovan is another TV star who successfully reinvented himself on the stage. His post-Neighbours breakout role was as Dr Frank N. Furter in a British production of The Rocky Horror Show, with subsequent roles in shows such as Sweeney Todd, Chitty Chitty Bang Bang and Joseph and the Amazing Technicolour Dreamcoat confirming his new position.
Another TV star to step into Dr Frank N. Furter's heels is Craig McLachlan, who has several times reprised the role internationally to great acclaim. McLachlan's other musical exploits have included roles in Chicago, Grease and Chitty Chitty Bang Bang.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aladdin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Frank-N-Furter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STAGE THEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curuenavulis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Everest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kinky Boots</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Miserables</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Jackman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janis Joplin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Video Hits</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sound of Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Heelers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Donovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa McCune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Come Alive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIA No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Frost Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Idol</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolverines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legally Blonde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katy Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Gaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocky Horror Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chart Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Divas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tina Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweeney Todd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus Christ Superstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunset Boulevard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dicko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erskineville Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulini Curuenavuli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitney Houston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivier Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madonna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ciccone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paperback Hero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitney Houston's When You Believe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chitty Chitty Bang Bang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GOING THROUGH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Busby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angel Eyes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Book of Mormon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulini</name>
    <count>25</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
