<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436323005732760</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/entertainment/music/whispering-jack-jnr-spreads-his-wings-20170804-gxpe78.html</url>
  <title>Whispering Jack jnr spreads his wings</title>
  <content>
When you're the son of 'The Voice' and you embark on a career in music, there's some expectation that follows you around.
Rob Farnham, the eldest son of John Farnham, has been chipping away at the music industry since he was a teenager.
Now the 36-year-old, along with bandmates from his group Rival Fire (Matthew Darcy, Tim Smyth, Zac Connelly and John Zambelis), has signed his first record deal with Sony Music and his debut album is about to drop.
But, surely, the mere mention of the Farnham name should have seen doors flinging open with recording opportunities from the outset.
Not, as it turns out, if you refuse to trade off that name and do everything you can to distance yourself from the very large shadow cast by your very famous father.
"I learned very quickly not to use my last name to open doors," Rob said. "One of the things I pride myself on is not doing that.

"We wouldn't have signed to Sony had that been the case ... I wouldn't be able to look in the mirror if I knew that was the reason why."
The decision to not use the Farnham name to secure an easier path to music glory was a conscious one made early, and made for very personal reasons.
"You have to earn your place," he said. "I probably could have gone a bit of an easier route, but it's about self-respect and the respect of your peers.
"I want to be known for my music. Obviously there's someone great in the family as well, and that can be difficult sometimes."
The difficulties come from the expectations that he will look, sound and act just like his famous father, but the reality couldn't be more opposite.
Rob's music is about as far from his dad's styling as music can get.
Pop ballads are out, rock ballads are in. Soaring vocalises are replaced with driving guitars (although there is a charming moment, Memories, on the album that Farnham snr might smile about) and there's more driving guitar than bagpipes.
"I never set out to (sound different), it just sort of happened. The music we make is just what happens," Rob said. "The album is quite eclectic ... there's ballads and heavier songs ... I would personally like to go heavier, but sometimes that's just not what happens."
What he has taken from his father is an inherent understanding of what it takes to succeed.
"I have seen what it takes, the sacrifices you have to make," he says.
"That was instilled in me from a very young age.
"I can look at myself at the end of the night and know I didn't cut any corners and that is very important to me."
Rob formed his band with musicians he had worked with in the various incarnations of his career and worked with people in Australia and LA to get the album happening. 
The group delivered the album finished to Sony Music to encourage them to offer a recording contract.
"We did an EP but the resounding message we got back was that we needed more songs," Rob said.
"So we went back to LA and recorded some more songs with Mark Needham, who has worked with people like The Killers."
After dropping their first track earlier this year, fans will have the chance to hear the full album when it is released this week.
Rival Fire's War is out through Sony Music on August 11.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Zambelis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire's War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony Music</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Farnham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farnham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Smyth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Needham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Darcy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Farnham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Connelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rival Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
