<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436065307692849</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/health/eddie-mcguire-shed-20kg-on-extreme-diet-where-he-didnt-eat-for-two-weeks/news-story/b1b301a3aecd4d6df5a41fd3e3837698</url>
  <title>Eddie's extreme weight loss</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN media personality Eddie McGuire has shed a whopping 20kg in a matter of weeks following an extreme diet that saw him eat nothing for two weeks.
The slimmed-down president of the Collingwood Football Club, who will be returning to The Footy Show this Thursday, followed the rigorous 101 Wellbeing Program - the same diet used by Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull several years ago.
The intensive 12-week program is based on Chinese herbs and involves not eating or drinking anything other than three cups of herb tonic a day for the first two weeks.
In the third week, according to McGuire, he was able to introduce half a cucumber and a meagre 50g serve of chicken into his daily meal plan.

The results were immediate, with McGuire dropping 15kg in those first three weeks,  Herald Sun .
However, he also claimed he didn't experienced any negative side effects - never feeling lethargic or hungry at any stage.
The 52-year-old has now lost a total of 20kg since committing to the program in May, despite going on an overseas holiday where he says he "ate for Australia".
The 101 Wellbeing Program by Sydney-based Dr Shuquan Liu was described by health and travel blogger Skye Gilkeson as "the toughest, most extreme diet I've ever done", saying it was as much a mental challenge as it was physical.
She said daydreaming about food became her "new occupation" during the fasting period.
"It occupied my mind and my time for large parts of the day. I would find myself consumed by food videos hitting my Facebook feed," .
"Initially, I just stopped to watch them as they passed amid a sea of baby photos and status updates. Soon I was actively seeking food accounts, becoming completely absorbed by their mouth-watering creations."
However, like McGuire, Ms Gilkeson claims she didn't experience any negative side effects. In fact, she said she felt "full of energy".
The 101 Wellbeing Program consists of three phases: Cleanse and Release, Repair and Recover and Whole Body Recalibration. The time spent in each of the phases depends on the clinic's assessment of your health needs.
Generally, the minimum time spent on the whole program is 4 to 6 weeks, but for others it may last the whole 12 weeks.
The program also involves daily massage, weigh ins and acupuncture.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footy Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skye Gilkeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based Dr Shuquan Liu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gilkeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whole Body Recalibration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellbeing Program</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
