<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436675193053672</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/why-meghan-markle-will-never-be-princess/3209291/</url>
  <title>Why Meghan Markle will never be a princess</title>
  <content>
WHEN Prince Harry and Meghan Markle were spotted hugging at the airport before the start of their summer holiday, the pair seemed besotted with each other.

The 32-year-old royal and the Suits star arrived in Africa for a romantic getaway at a destination said to be popular for engagements and newlyweds on honeymoon, The Sun reports.

So it's no wonder that speculation that Harry is set to pop the question to Meghan is at an all time high.

But even if he were to ask for her hand in marriage and the pair tie the knot - the 36-year-old actress would not be known as Princess Meghan.

This is because, due to rules governing the British crown, only those born into the royal family can use the title Prince or Princess, followed by their first name.

Therefore if Meghan and Harry do end up getting married, she will be officially known as Her Royal Highness Princess Henry of Wales.

Despite that, it is almost guaranteed that if we do hear royal wedding bells, the Queen will instead bestow the couple a Dukedom before their wedding.

And it has been tipped that if the pair make it down the aisle they would become the Duke and Duchess of Sussex, meaning Meghan would then be known as the Duchess of Sussex - much in the same way Kate Middleton has become the Duchess of Cambridge.

Titles the Duke and Duchess of Clarence and Buckingham are also available - as the line has died out so they are the Queen's gift to bestow on the couple if she wants to.

Pictures of Prince Harry and Meghan jetting off on their African holiday come just a day before unseen tapes featuring his mum Princess Diana will be broadcast in the UK.

The footage, where Diana talked about her doomed marriage to Prince Charles, was recorded in 1992 by her voice coach Peter Settelen.

But the bosses of Channel 4, the UK network airing the documentary, have been blasted for planning to screen the "tawdry" tapes as it could cause pain to her sons.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dukedom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Settelen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Meghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Middleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duchess of Sussex</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duchess of Cambridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duchess of Clarence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Highness Princess Henry of Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
