<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437181999199200</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/greater-western-sydney-giants/gws-giants-young-gun-harry-himmelberg-causes-leon-cameron-huge-selection-headache-20170806-gxq8gi.html</url>
  <title>GWS Giants young gun Harry Himmelberg causes Leon Cameron huge selection headache</title>
  <content>
  GWS Giants coach Leon Cameron admits it will be "very, very hard" to dislodge young gun Harry Himmelberg after the AFL Canberra export made the most of a late call up at his old stomping ground on Saturday.
Himmelberg played against Melbourne after Jonathon Patton was a late scratching and the 21-year-old impressed with a goal and 12 touches in the Photo: Craig Abercrombie
The second-season star can play at both ends and after signing a two-year contract extension last week he wants to feature in the Giants' finals run.
The second-placed Giants welcome back Patton and Toby Greene for their clash against reigning premiers Western Bulldogs on Friday night and Cameron said he has a selection headache brewing.

"He had a big week Harry, for him to commit to our club for a couple of years when there was big plays from opposition sides coming after him, it's just fantastic," Cameron said.
"He's had a few little issues with his injuries but he's played seven games this year which is a great effort for a second year player in a key position and he's still growing and finding out what he can do.

"Him being able to flip from forward and back it's going to be very, very hard to dislodge him because he's a competitive player and it's great decision for me to have, but the way he played today [Saturday] it's going to be pretty hard."
The former Eastlake Demons gun said it was "awesome" playing in front of family and friends at his old home ground and added it's crucial he makes the most of every opportunity he's given.
Photo gallery
"I love playing at Manuka, I used to train here every week and play here so the ground here is familiar and it was good to kick a goal in my old famous pocket," Himmelberg said.
"[Being on the selection fringe] it sort of adds that extra motivation just to come in and play my role. Playing AFL footy is the goal so coming into the side was great and I think I took my opportunity and played an alright game for the team.
"I'm really happy to be here for the next two years and I just want to keep improving each week and asking questions of older guys who have been doing it for years."
The Giants can secure a finals double chance with two wins in their remaining three games but Himmelberg says there's still plenty to improve on if they want to be genuine premiership contenders.
"It was good to get the win and we got a lot right but there is still a long way to go for us, lots of things we still need to improve on if we're going to be a competitive team and we need to keep this pace going forward," Himmelberg said.
"It was an important win but we're not going to get ahead of ourselves, we need to finish the season strong so we can put our best foot forward for finals."
The Giants played in front of a bumper sell-out crowd with14,274 fans pouring through the gates and Himmelberg believes Canberra is becoming an AFL town.
"Footy is starting to really grow in Canberra, the link with Giants is great and the AFL are really starting to take over down here," he said.
"If we can keep getting games down here I'm more than happy to keep playing in front of these awesome crowds," Himmelberg said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Abercrombie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Himmelberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Himmelberg</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastlake Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
