<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436752502465703</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828742/questions-over-2009-report/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Questions over 2009 report</title>
  <content>
Port Stephens MP Kate Washington, NSW Labor leader Luke Foley and Labor's mayoral candidate for Port Stephens Council Des Maslen.

Mystery surrounds a government report that argues against the need for a new public high school at Medowie.

The report has a publication date of December 2009 on its title page, but the document refers to an event that took place in late 2010.

The NSW Department of Education failed to respond to repeated requests for clarification by Fairfax Media over the past week, as to how the report could have included details of an event that occurred after its publication.
Parliamentary Secretary for the Hunter Scot MacDonald used the report last month to  of misleading her party and the community, after .
Mr MacDonald alleged Ms Washington, who served on the Department of Education's working party that produced the report before she was elected to Parliament, knew the document argued against a new school.

Ms Washington has repeatedly denied the allegation.

She said she had seen a draft of the report that contained different information and had not previously seen the document Mr MacDonald produced.

"It's not a report I've ever seen, so for Scot MacDonald to make allegations about me is really rude and very wrong," she said.

"For Scot MacDonald to be waving around a report that purports to be in 2009, in any event, when we're now in 2017, and for this to be the authority - the only backing they have for their position - is ridiculous."
Ms Washington said she was trying to obtain the draft through freedom of information legislation.
Meanwhile, former Port Stephens MP Craig Baumann responded to a report that Hansard documents showed he had advocated for a new Medowie high school in Parliament in 2010.
He said he had not seen the 2009 report at the time he made the comments, while in opposition.

He said he became aware of the report's findings after his party formed government in 2011.

"I discussed the report with the then [education] Minister, Adrian Piccoli, and it was agreed to keep a watching brief on local population increases that would justify a new high school," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Scot MacDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr MacDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medowie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Piccoli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens MP Kate Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scot MacDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Washington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens MP Craig Baumann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens Council Des Maslen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
