<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436709552792293</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/john-holland-to-develop-take-stake-in-200m-maroochydore-cbd-project-20170804-gxpb3c</url>
  <title>John Holland to take Maroochydore stake</title>
  <content>
Chinese-owned John Holland will get a third asset in its growing investment portfolio after agreeing to take a stake in the planned $200 million Maroochydore city centre.
The builder, which in June purchased  and is close to buying its  - both in Sydney - is in exclusive negotiations with Sunshine Coast council to develop and then own three of five lots in the commercial precinct.
"This is another example of our focus on becoming a fully integrated infrastructure and property company," said Tom Roche, John Holland's executive general manager for development and investments. "We are now involved in significant developments in Sydney, Brisbane and Adelaide and focused on a number of other opportunities across the country."
John Holland is likely to end up owning the three mixed-use commercial lots in the development that will also create new council facilities and a separate building for University of the Sunshine Coast.

Supplied

This first release of commercial lots forms part of the overall  - a project headed by former Queensland Investment Corporation chief executive Doug McTaggart - that seeks to create an administrative and commercial centre for the disparate former councils including Mooloolaba, Caloundra and Maroochydore, which were combined by the former Beattie Labor government in 2008.

In 2012 Noosa residents voted to demerge and revert to independent administration.
John Holland said it hoped to have negotiations completed by the end of the year to determine a timeline for the development of the site. Matters still to be resolved include who owns the land and under what arrangements. The company said it could not confirm the likely value of the assets it would end up holding.
"The core commercial precinct in the Maroochydore city centre includes lots for commercial office buildings, retail space and approximately 600 residential apartments, as well as a new waterway, parks and plazas," Mr McTaggart said.
"John Holland's proposal for the Maroochydore CBD is certainly impressive and discussions with their representatives are well advanced."

beat rival Infrastructure Capital Group in the race to win the 99-year operating contract of the council-owned Sunshine Coast Airport, which is investing in a new runway and which  from 900,000 to as many as 2.5 million over the next two decades.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beattie Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Investment Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Roche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doug McTaggart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese-owned John Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Holland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McTaggart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infrastructure Capital Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
