<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436237106385944</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/swoop/soul-surfer-bethany-hamilton-mick-fanning-in-surfers-hall-of-fame/news-story/c83d2f5699bdb89aeb31228e20af0144</url>
  <title>Surf Hall of Fame for shark attack survivors</title>
  <content>
THEY'VE both had encounters with sharks and both have overcome potentially career-ending injuries so it seems right Bethany Hamilton and Mick Fanning were inducted into Surfers Hall of Fame together at Huntington Beach.
Both put their hand print into the wet cement at the famous surf spot as they joined a list of legends as inductees.

after first capturing headlines when attacked by a shark and losing her arm as a teenager then for fighting back to surf on the World Series.

Now a mother and subject of the Soul Surfer movie, Hamilton continues to surf select events around the world.
Fanning, who remarkably escaped without a scratch from his encounter with a shark two year ago, had overcome a hamstring torn from the bone before going on to win three world titles in 2007, 2009 and 2013.

Earlier this year
"When you get recognised for awards like this you feel very honoured. And to do it alongside Bethany ... she is such an inspiration. I've very honoured to be receiving this with her," Fanning said.
Both Fanning and Hamilton are involved in charity work with the later backing Friends of Bethany, a foundation which helps amputees.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surf Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bethany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fanning</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Fanning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soul Surfer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bethany Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfers' Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friends of Bethany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
