<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436232811418614</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/fremantle-dockers-hand-back-control-of-fremantle-oval-to-city-of-fremantle/news-story/54456b52ce7e001d611a2a21719ddf24</url>
  <title>Dockers hand back their home</title>
  <content>
THE Dockers will this week hand back control of Fremantle Oval to the local council, paving the way for a transformation of the 122-year-old ground.
The AFL club has agreed to relinquish its 37-year head lease on the oval in exchange for $1.5 million, to be paid by the City of Fremantle over three years.
The deal, which has been months in the making, is expected to be ratified at a special council meeting tomorrow night.
It comes after Fremantle Football Club moved into their purpose-built headquarters at Cockburn in February.
"We are pleased to have finalised the lease negotiation with the Dockers, which means we can get on with transforming the oval and surrounding precinct into a valuable community asset with cultural and sporting events all year round," Fremantle mayor Brad Pettitt said.
"After many months of negotiations, council has made a robust commercial decision which provides the best value for ratepayers and maintains a healthy ongoing relationship between the City and the Fremantle Football Club.
"Securing this outcome now is the best possible option for the City and the local community."
Mr Pettitt said Fremantle Oval could now be used for a range of activities, including festivals.
In the shorter term, the City would use the oval buildings as temporary offices later this year.
Temporary administration offices would be required when the current council administration building is demolished and new offices built as part of the $270 million Kings Square cultural precinct redevelopment.
"We've looked at multiple options for temporary staff accommodation, including the adjacent Stan Reilly site, but relocating to Fremantle Oval is by far the cheapest and best option," Mr Pettitt said.
"Relocating to Fremantle Oval also provides an opportunity to bring forward plans to deliver more than 160 new car bays at the Stan Reilly site which will provide inner-city parking and a new revenue stream.
"This carpark will be under construction in coming weeks."
Dockers president Dale Alcock added: "It has been a very collaborative process to arrive at this outcome with the City of Fremantle and we look forward to the City's formal endorsement of the agreement at Monday night's council meeting.
"We are also pleased that our building at Fremantle Oval will continue to be an important asset for the City."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cockburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Pettitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pettitt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Alcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle Football Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle Oval</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan Reilly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
