<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436018063052147</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-06/search-for-survivors-of-us-marine-corps-osprey-crash-called-off-as-operation-shifts-to-recovery/1691552</url>
  <title>Search for survivors of US Marine Corps Osprey crash called off as operation shifts to 'recovery'</title>
  <content>
United States authorities have confirmed they do not expect to find three marines alive, with a rescue operation shifting to a "recovery effort" after a military aircraft crashed off the Queensland coast yesterday.
Twenty-six crew members were aboard the MV-22 Osprey , US authorities said.
The search for the crew members continued throughout the night
but was called off this morning.
"Operations have now shifted to recovery efforts," a statement from the III Marine Expeditionary Force (III MEF).
"The next of kin for the three missing marines have been notified."
The III MEF said recovery efforts would continue "as the sea state permits" with assistance from the Australian Defence Force.
"Recovery and salvage operations can take several months to complete," the statement read.
"The circumstances of the mishap are currently under investigation, and there is no additional information available at this time."
Earlier, III MEF said the Osprey aircraft had launched from the USS Bonhomme Richard and was conducting "regularly scheduled operations" when it "entered the water".
Twenty-three people were rescued within an hour, including one marine who was taken to Rockhampton Hospital.
"Please keep the families of those involved in the Osprey mishap near Australia in your thoughts and prayers," Commandant of the USMC Robert Neller tweeted.
Defence Minister Marise Payne confirmed no Australian personnel were involved in the mishap.
Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk said the state's prayers were "with those US military personnel involved in the incident".
The aircraft had been in Queensland as part of .
A post on the USS Bonhomme Richard's Facebook page on Saturday said the landing helicopter dock had begun "amphibious integration training ... exercises out here on the Coral Sea".
The Osprey is a tilt-rotor aircraft that takes off and lands like a helicopter, but flies like an aeroplane.
They have been involved in a series of high-profile crashes in recent years.
In December, five crewmembers of an Osprey had to be rescued after their craft conducted a shallow-water landing off Okinawa after a training mishap in which a rotor blade cut a refuelling hose, according to the Marine Expeditionary Force.
In January, three US soldiers were injured
in the "hard landing" of an Osprey in Yemen.

ABC/wires

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yemen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-six</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Neller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>III MEF</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Bonhomme Richard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Expeditionary Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coral Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-three</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marine Corps Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commandant of the USMC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Minister Marise Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Bonhomme Richard's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV-22 Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>III Marine Expeditionary Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okinawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
