<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436499099393198</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-league/rugby-league-match-centre/nrl-round-22-manly-sea-eagles-v-sydney-roosters-20170806-gxqaa1.html</url>
  <title>NRL Round 22: Manly Sea Eagles v Sydney Roosters</title>
  <content>
Manly have been gifted an early advantage after a careless high shot early in a set. A couple of hit-ups later and Cherry-Evans will have a shot at rustling up some points.

The football comes from under the posts instead to Blake Green, who pops in a grubber.

Mitchell Pearce picks it but isn't able to control the ball, knocking on. Manly will have another shot.
An interesting opening contest this afternoon as Manly host the Sydney Roosters.

It wasn't so long ago that all the talk was Manly could be contenders this year, with some wondering whether a 'dark horse' tag was unfair on the men from the Northern Beaches at the top end of the ladder.

A few weeks can be a long time in the NRL, and suddenly there are question marks over whether or not the Sea Eagles will finish up in a finals spot come the end of the season.

They come off a 52-22 loss to the Dragons and a 40-6 drubbing against the Storm. Now they are forced to turn things around against second-placed Roosters.

Despite the negativity coming across here, the bookies place the two sides pretty evenly matched. 

I wouldn't look past the Roosters looking to cement their authority at the top, especially knowing Manly's defence has been leaky of late. 

Manly may be playing to reinstate some level of pride today, but they'll need more than that to best what is a strong outfit.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Beaches</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL ROUND 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Roosters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
