<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436675193053652</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/breaking-news/liberals-plot-path-forward-on-gay-marriage/news-story/e26f5f9939e2a3106d1a85bdcec93fa7</url>
  <title>Liberals plot path forward on gay marriage</title>
  <content>
A group of Liberals MPs is hoping a pitch to protect religious freedoms will satisfy their colleagues' concerns about a free vote on gay marriage.
Backbenchers Dean Smith, Trent Zimmerman, Warren Entsch, Trevor Evans and Tim Wilson have circulated a private members' bill ahead of a special party room meeting on the issue in Canberra on Monday afternoon.
The legislation would allow two people to marry regardless of their sex or gender.
It also would protect all religious ministers and civil celebrants from legal action if they refuse to marry same-sex couples, and covers service providers - such as bakers, florists and photographers - if they can prove their business is linked to a religious body.
"(It's) the most comprehensive bill the parliament has ever had in regards to not only providing for same-sex marriage but, importantly, respecting community attitudes that would like to see religious freedoms protected," Senator Smith, the proposal's architect, told ABC TV on Sunday.
The co-chair of advocacy group Marriage Equality, Alex Greenwich, said it was an exciting time, labelling Senator Smith's proposal the strongest they've seen.
"It is a bill that is designed to pass the Senate," he told reporters in Sydney.
The five backbenchers want the party room to sanction a free vote on the bill.
Mr Zimmerman said he would "forcefully" argue for a free vote and hopes the draft bill will convince colleagues.
"So much of the debate has been about process rather than substance of what legislation might look like," he told Sky News.
Senator Smith insists the push is not a revolt against Malcolm Turnbull and said the issue shouldn't be viewed through the prism of leadership.
John Howard used the conscience vote mechanism several times as a "very effective political management tool" in his 11 years as prime minister, he said.
Manager of Opposition Business Tony Burke gave an "absolute guarantee" to any Liberal member that Labor wouldn't jeopardise their pursuit of a free vote on gay marriage.
"We will not use this issue as an issue of confidence in the government," he told Sky News.
Senator Smith labelled a postal plebiscite - the other alternative being considered - an even worse idea.
Marriage equality advocates have legal advice that the government would need specific legislation to hold a postal vote on the issue and allocate sufficient funds, meaning if it pushed ahead without parliament's approval the vote could be subject to a High Court challenge.
Crossbench senator Nick Xenophon - who helped shoot down the plebiscite - said the Smith bill seemed a sensible way forward and he would support it if it got up in the Senate.
"This shouldn't be subject to such contortionism by the Liberal and National parties, we should just get on with it," he told reporters in Canberra.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Business Tony Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
