<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436584998739764</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836069/home-units-evacuated-after-crane-collapses-onto-penthouse-video/?cs=4219</url>
  <title>Home units evacuated after crane collapses onto penthouse | Video</title>
  <content>
Workers are rescued from the crane via a basket. Photo: Felicia Nguye

Commuters have been warned to prepare for extensive delays during the Monday morning peak hour rush, with fears the train line to Sydney Airport could remain closed after a crane crashed into a block of Wolli Creek apartments on Sunday morning.
The crane is believed to have been in the process of being set up when it fell backwards, slamming into the penthouse apartment and causing structural damage to the upper levels and roof of the building.
A Wolli Creek resident described how another crane was forced to rescue the stranded driver.
"The man from the white crane (which crashed), he jumped over to the rooftop of the penthouse. So they (the second crane) went to the rooftop and picked him up," Felicia Nguyen said.
As a result of the collapse, police have shut down a number of roads surrounding the apartment while train services have also been affected.
"It just crushed the black (penthouse) balcony," Ms Nguyen said. "All the glass fell out onto the road and that's why they blocked the road from the station to that building."
No trains are running between Central and Turrella on the T2 Airport Line, the Transport Management Centre said. Replacement buses are currently operating between Sydenham and Central.
"Depending on the good work that the emergency services is going to do with the engineers, we have to be careful about tomorrow morning. Over 50,000 people may be trying to access the railway and to get into the airport," Sydney Trains chief executive Howard Collins said.
"I ask people to check before you travel, allow some extra time, there may not be rail services to both international and domestic airports tomorrow morning."

A crane crashes onto the penthouse of a block of apartments at Wolli Creek Photo: Felicia Nguyen
Emergency Services are currently assessing the scene and are taking caution so as not to cause further damage to the building or surrounding buildings.
"We currently have search and rescue teams from Fire and Rescue in attendance and in consultation between them and an engineer, they'll have a look at the extent of the damage before we can actually start looking at a plan to remove the crane," Superintendent Josh Turner from Fire and Rescue NSW said.
"We have a secondary mobile crane on site which will obviously be required to take the weight of the crane and be an integral part of the removal process. But we won't do that until we ensure that all areas are safe around it and no further damage is done by removing the crane."
Mr Turner assured residents there was no threat of the building collapsing.
"No, the building itself is quite stable, the damage is just up to the roof area."
However, concerns that the crane may shift position and fall onto the street or surrounding buildings saw four other buildings evacuated.

The collapsed crane. Photo: Sally Du
Investigators from SafeWork NSW have arrived at the site to determine the cause of the incident.
Probuild, the construction company responsible for the building the crane was anchored to, could not be contacted for comment.
Paramedics treated three men at the scene for minor injuries before they were transported to St George Hospital. One of the men has a suspected fractured leg. They are all in stable conditions.

Emergency services have closed the roads surrounding the area.
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T2 Airport Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Probuild</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felicia Nguye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Nguyen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felicia Nguyen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Du</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Management Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turrella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rescue NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Josh Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Trains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SafeWork NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
