<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437018790440505</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/chris-burch-nihi-best-hotel-in-the-world-2017-7</url>
  <title>Fashion mogul Chris Burch built a five-star resort on a remote Indonesian island  --  and it's officially the best in the world</title>
  <content>
Nihi Sumba Island (formerly known as Nihiwatu) was voted the best hotel in the world by  for the second year in a row.

The luxury island resort in Indonesia even beat the Brando, Obama's .

Nihi was created by Chris Burch, best known for founding or cofounding several internationally known retail brands - C. Wonder and Tory Burch - and .

Burch, together with hotelier James McBride, bought a beach hostel on the Indonesian island of Sumba in 2012. The duo spent $US30 million renovating the hostel, then reopened it as a five-star resort in 2015.

In an interview with  in 2015, Burch said, "I bought it for my children and as a piece of something that I hope we can preserve and give back to the community. When you're in a place where the palette is so beautiful, you can do things that you can't do in other places: build a spa under a waterfall, go to places where no others have been, have a butler in every room."

According to the , Burch splits his time between Miami, the Hamptons, and his resort in Indonesia. Nihi has 27 private villas, including Raja Mendaka, Burch's private home. That particular section has a main house and four additional villas, each with its own private plunge pool.

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James McBride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Burch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nihi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIAMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nihiwatu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nihi Sumba Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sumba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory Burch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raja Mendaka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burch</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C. Wonder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
