<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436580703772458</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/darwin-mother-jo-jamieson-writes-book-about-coping-with-tragedy-after-sons-brutal-murder-in-scotland/news-story/67ea996429e1fc4860aed9a077314d4b</url>
  <title>Back from the brink after son's brutal murder</title>
  <content>
"WE found a body covered in tattoos and we believe it to be your son, Dean."
The words didn't make sense to Jo Jamieson.
Her fun-loving son Dean, 30, wasn't "covered" in tattoos. He just had the names of his children around his neck and on his arm.
"I was in total disbelief," Jo said.
The horror sank in when she saw her other adult children, Paul, Gareth and Kerrie.
"If someone stabbed me, it couldn't be more painful," Jo said.
Dean's wife Carol had to tell his children, Lauren, Liam, Keelan and Tyler, that their father wasn't coming back to their home in the bitter Scottish winter.
For Jo, who now lives in Darwin, the loss of her son in 2006 was painful enough, but the way in which he was taken from her thrust her and her family into the media spotlight and stole any chance they had to grieve privately.
Dean had been out for a few drinks when he went to hail a cab home in Aberdeen, Scotland.
Instead of a taxi, he was picked up by an 'unofficial taxi service' with four men in the car - Colin Cowie, Kevin Leslie, Shaun Paton and Colin Stewart.
The four men drove Dean to the countryside, stripped him of his shirt and jumper in subzero temperatures, robbed him and set upon him like savages.
He tried to flee, only to be chased down, stabbed, punched, kicked and stomped on.
His body was found the next morning.
The brutal murder made headlines instantly, and the media set upon the grief of his family.
"It was first thing the next morning - they were just there," Jo said.
"It was like Dean became their property.
"There was no way you could physically grieve because you're in the public eye."
When Jo went to identify Dean's body, she was confronted with a camera in her face again.
"I was totally distraught," she said.
"That was the time they asked, 'Ms Jamieson, can you tell us how the family is feeling?' and I just wanted to tell them, f--k off, how the f--k do you think we're feeling?
"Your pain was just there, it was raw, it was right there for everyone to see.
"They sensationalised things; they were saying he had his genitals cut off and things like that.
"It was exhausting and so traumatic."
For days there were no leads. It wasn't until Jo willingly shared her grief to the media that the information came pouring in, and the four men were caught.
The court case that followed was "like a circus", with hoodlums eyeing off witnesses and general disrespect for the judicial system.
"I couldn't believe how it was that these thugs were allowed to come in and intimidate the witnesses," Jo said.
"I actually thought when you go into court everyone has to be respectful - and it was nothing like that.
"I was really disgusted in the behaviour. I couldn't believe how the prosecutors spoke to witnesses - they were really intimidating and horrible.
"It was like being in a movie."
The four blokes involved all tried to blame each other, but it soon became apparent that Stewart was less involved than the others.
He crossed over and testified against the other three in the five-week trial in the High Court of Aberdeen.
Leslie was sentenced to 20 years, Cowie for 18, and Paton only 10, for the lesser crime of culpable homicide. Paton was released after just six years.
All three had a long string of previous violent offences.
At the time, Judge Lady Paton said: "To assault and rob a complete stranger, who was simply looking for a taxi home after a night out, was evil enough.
"The continued attack on Mr Jamieson amounted to sadistic and sickening savagery, almost beyond comprehension."
Once the dust settled, Jo was consumed by her grief, but put on a mask to get through the daily humdrum of life.
There was always someone there looking out for Jo, even if she couldn't see it at the time.
"I craved peace and quiet, I craved for silence, I craved to be on my own," she said.
Thoughts of suicide took over.
But it was when her daughter said to her, "what about us Mum, do we not matter?" that she realised she needed to make a change.
"I was so selfish ... you're just consumed by how you feel," she said.
"You don't think about how everyone else is - it's at that point all you can feel is your pain."
It took five years for Jo to escape the black hole.Last Touch
One day she made a conscious decision to let go - to forgive.
She knew she needed to lose the rage and anger that controlled her life.
"The only person I was hurting was myself and the people around me," she said.
"I just consciously said 'that's it'.
"I decided I would laugh the loudest and I believe in the afterlife so if my son comes to visit, he'll want to come and visit.
"He does not want to come and see someone moping and crying and being upset.
"He was a happy go-lucky guy, he enjoyed life. And I was determined that he would come and see a happy mum."
Six years ago, by a pure coincidence, Jo was offered a job in Australia and she moved to Darwin.
The peace and time to reflect allowed her to put pen to paper, something she always knew she would do.
"Books were my saviour - people use many methods for support. Some see a councillor, others go to groups, people use family, friends - I used books," she said.
Her book Last Touch, was never meant to just tell her story.
While searching for answers during her ordeal, Jo found there was no guide for what to do when someone is ripped so brutally from your life. There were no words about what was normal to feel, no words on how to deal with the intrusive and insensitive media, or how a police investigation or court trial works.
"You're stepping into the unknown," she said
"I think I (wrote Last Touch) for other people, so if they've experienced what I experienced they can know what to expect.
"In every book I read they had a really bad relationship with the police. I wanted to show you can have a really good relationship with them but you have to work with them and understand what they're doing."
Putting words on paper in Darwin, a world away from home where Dean lay at rest, was like reliving the worst moments of life.
"I think when you're telling a story you can detach a bit. But when you're physically writing, you've got to get inside your head and think about what you're writing - you have to relive the pain.
"Writing it certainly wasn't cathartic, but I know it's helped people. That's the part that's cathartic."
Eleven years on from the event that changed Jo and her family's world, things are going well. Dean's children have grown into wonderful teenagers.
And Jo continues her important work as a child protection worker, living a quieter life for the time being.
A tattoo of Dean on her shoulder is the constant reminder he might pop over and say 'hello' from the afterlife at any time - and she's determined that her story is one of survival.
A story that can help others also living through a nightmare.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Paton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Leslie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aberdeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Lady Paton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gareth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deans</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court of Aberdeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Touch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Cowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
