<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436151207039425</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/brent-harvey-says-essendons-zach-merrett-should-be-suspended-for-a-week-for-his-gutpunch/news-story/7800d16ebbcd1512b06e83e0db283c15</url>
  <title>'He's got to get a week for it'</title>
  <content>
AFL games record-holder Brent Harvey says Essendon's Zach Merrett should receive a week's suspension for his gut-punch on Carlton's Lachie Plowman.
Merrett and Plowman were in a scuffle in the first half, when the Essendon midfielder lashed out at the Blues defender with a closed fist.
Harvey said given the circumstances - two weeks after Brisbane's Dayne Zorko copped a one-week ban for a similar incident - Merrett could expect a similar stint on the sidelines.
"Well, he gets a week for it, it's simple as that," Harvey said on Fox Sports News' Gameday Live.
"If you're going on the past, I think he's got to get a week for it."
Harvey said while Merrett was clearly frustrated with other incidents off the ball, the Brownlow Medal smoky didn't need to lash out at Plowman.
"There's no need for that, we've all done it a few times," Harvey said.
"But there's no need for that - they look like they could play finals and is he going to miss a week for it?
"It doesn't derail his season, he's had such an amazing season. He just doesn't need to do that - they were clearly frustrated with a couple of little things going on off the ball."
A one-week suspension would see Merrett miss Essendon's crunch game with Adelaide - a tough prospect given forward Orazio Fantasia looks certain to be sidelined with a hamstring injury.
The Essendon midfielder was hopeful of receiving a fine, rather than a suspension for the act.
'There's probably guys who have done similar things and gotten away with fines," Merrett said on Sunday.
"So hopefully I can get away with that."
There have been mixed penalties for gut punches this year - Richmond skipper Trent Cotchin received a fine for hitting St Kilda's Jack Lonie, as did Ben Cunnington for punching Bernie Vince, while Zorko's
Harvey said the AFL needed to crack down on punches off the ball, as the behaviour was starting to be seen in junior football.
"The juniors see it on TV and they actually do it," Harvey said.
"I'm the assistant coach of my son's under-13s team and you see kids - they're doing it all the time now.
"So I think the AFL do need to crack down on it - whether that's a week's suspension or a fine, I probably still haven't worked out yet."
Melbourne midfielder Dom Tyson said players were better off avoiding punching opponents, given the AFL's focus on "eradicating" that part of the game.
"I guess you've just got to stamp it down," Tyson said on AFL Today.
"The AFL's made it pretty clear to us that they're trying to really sort of eradicate that from the game.
"So you're better off just not doing it."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zorko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda's Jack Lonie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Vince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Dayne Zorko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plowman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Tyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Today</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Lachie Plowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orazio Fantasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon's Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRENT COTCHIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Cunnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrett</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News' Gameday Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
