<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437181999199193</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/health/bubs-australia-rockets-on-infant-formula-demand-20170806-gxq72h</url>
  <title>Having a celebrity influencer on Chinese social media is helping Bubs Australia</title>
  <content>
Infant formula and organic baby food company Bubs Australia wants to strengthen its Australian domestic presence even though its share price has rocketed 70 per cent in the past week largely on demand for "white gold" from Chinese customers.
Bubs shares climbed from 30¢ on July 27 to close at 51¢ on Friday as investors focus on some of the smaller ASX companies supplying infant formula to China. It is a sector which has experienced sharp volatility and caused heartburn for one of the bigger player's,
Bubs chief executive Nicholas Simms said on Sunday that an agreement signed in June with major e-commerce platform company kaola.com in China had been very important from a strategic viewpoint because the site had the highest market share among China's cross-border retail import e-commerce businesses.
"It has significant reach in the Chinese marketplace," Mr Simms told The Australian Financial Review. The customer base, made up largely of 18 to 35-year-old "upwardly mobile" people, augured well for future growth and repeat business across a range of products for Bubs.

"It's probably not just a great customer today, but into the future," he said.

Bubs also has a large shareholder, Zhang "Nancy" Zetian, who is the celebrity wife of Chinese billionaire Richard Liu, who founded one of China's most popular e-commerce sites, JD.com.﻿
Highly influential

Zhang Zetian is highly influential on social media in China, and was dubbed "milk tea sister" when a photograph of her sipping a beverage when she was still a high school student was an internet sensation.
Mr Simms said Bubs still generates more than 85 per cent of its sales in Australia, where its major retail customers include Coles, Chemist Warehouse and Costco.

The Bubs surge mirrors that of another ASX-listed infant formula company, Wattle Health, which jumped a further 15 per cent on Friday to close at 91¢. This followed an even bigger rise by Wattle the previous day, or 37 per cent. Wattle last week through an institutional placement priced at 56¢ and has delivered vast paper profits to investors who took up shares in the original float of the company at 20¢ per share in mid-March.
Bubs undertook a backdoor listing in January  through the shell of Hillcrest Litigation Services, raising $5.2 million at an issue price of 10¢ per share. It was in the spotlight very early when its stepped down as chairman of Bubs just over a week after it listed on the ASX, startling investors.
But it has righted itself in the eyes of most investors, and in the past week in particular, has taken off on the ASX.
Trusted brand

Mr Simms, who was elevated to chief executive officer of Bubs in June from his previous role as commercial director for infant milk formula with the company, previously worked with international consumer goods firms such as Mars Inc, Heinz and Cussons.
​He said Bubs was acutely aware of the important of having a strong and trusted brand in Australia, because that gave it a springboard into China.
"We know that obviously people see Australia as a clean and green destination," he said.
"The knock-on effect that comes to our brand is gratefully received."

That was why building more presence as a brand in the Australian retail market was one of the key planks in the growth strategy.
Mr Simms said it was difficult to assess how much of the local buying of Bubs also found its way on to Chinese e-commerce sites through . But Bubs hadn't deliberately set out to pursue the daigou traders, which have been an important part of the success of vitamins brands such as

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bubs</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillcrest Litigation Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bubs Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhang Zetian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Simms</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Simms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mars Inc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattle Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nancy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Liu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heinz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cussons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zetian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
