<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436580703772420</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/tab-figures-fall-again-in-victoria-20170806-gxq9kx.html</url>
  <title>TAB figures fall again in Victoria</title>
  <content>
Financial returns to the three codes of Victorian racing from its joint venture with TAB have dipped for the second successive year.
The release of wagering giant Tabcorp's annual results to the stock exchange highlighted 2016-17 returns to Victorian thoroughbred, harness and greyhound racing were figures $325 million, down more than $6 million.
Proceeds from the joint venture are the Victorian racing industry's primary source of revenue. Returns have declined almost $25 million in the last two years.
In contrast, TAB payments to the NSW industry grew 7.3 per cent to $312 million in 2016-17, helped by new tax arrangements the NSW racing industry has been able to lock in.
Tabcorp said its total return of $813 million to Australian racing included $76 million from Sky broadcast fees and the sale of Australian racing overseas amounted to $100 million in race field fees.
Race field fees were secured in Australia after Racing NSW won a bitter high court victory over Sportsbet and Betfair in 2012.

Total wagering with Tabcorp in 2016-17 was $1.69 billion, in line with the previous year. But, its business was hurt by wet weather during the autumn and the under-performance of the cartoon racing game Trackside where revenue dipped 15 per cent.
The Victorian racing industry receives a share on betting on Trackside with the TAB, as well as sports betting on all racing - not just Victorian.
The second successive decline in returns to Victorian racing is bound to concern industry chiefs.
Participants have been questioning a recent deal struck by Victorian racing broadcaster Racing.com with South Australian racing. Not only did the deal cost Racing.com $6 million, the channel is now promoting betting on South Australian racing with corporate bookmakers such as Bet365 from which Victorian racing does not earn a cent.
And, in William Hill's Tom Waterhouse-led Australian operations declined 85 per cent to just $1.1 million in the first six months of the year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sportsbet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bet365</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Hill's Tom Waterhouse-led Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
