<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437139049525813</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/what-if-a-royal-commission-just-went-after-cba-20170805-gxq6v0</url>
  <title>What if a Royal Commission just went after CBA?</title>
  <content>
All the banks are bastards, or so the saying goes. But if going after them with a Royal Commission would look like a capitulation to Bill Shorten and his merry band of populists in the Labor party, recent allegations by financial intelligence regulator AUSTRAC against CBA have given some on the conservative side of politics a new perspective on how to capitalise on growing anti-bank sentiment. 
In recent days, one idea being increasingly and broadly floated in Liberal circles is that of a Royal Commission into banking, but with a rather specific target. Just the one bank, in fact - the one spectacularly accused of breaching the Anti-Money Laundering and Terrorism Funding Act (53,700 times): CBA.
It's all early stages at the moment - nothing, as far as we know, is planned or being seriously discussed, and nothing is likely to happen quickly given the matter is before the Federal Court. But a CBA-only inquiry could provide Malcolm Turnbull and his government with a nice compromise solution. People's bank CEO Ian Narev isn't popular in Canberra - politicians are predisposed to dislike anyone getting paid over $10 million a year, let alone anyone who breezes unscathed through Senate questioning despite a string of scandals under his watch. And while any Royal Commission into CBA and its culture would undoubtedly drag in the other banks, if only for the sake of comparison, there could be some grudging support from the other big three,  for what the most recent scandal does to bank standing overall.
CBA's name has been linked to the lion's share of banking scandals in recent years. Last week's money-laundering allegations add to a string of issues including , the earlier , and the relatively little-known . And it doesn't help that during last year's AGM season, CBA was the only big-four bank to cop a first strike from irate shareholders - a hefty . It's certainly enough to keep a Royal Commission busy. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA-only</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrorism Funding Act (53,700</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
