<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436116847300856</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/recipe-sweet-spicy-simple/3208807/</url>
  <title>RECIPE: Sweet, spicy, simple</title>
  <content>
THIS dish can be found on almost every menu in Sri Lanka. It is a recipe that was morphed by the influence of different residing cultures over the centuries. The term "devilled" is derived from the traditional country "devil dancers," known for their colour and ferocity. Sweet, sour, spicy and simple to make. Goes down perfectly with a cold beer!

Devilled tuna

INGREDIENTS: 300g tuna steaks, cut into bite-size pieces

1 tsp chilli powder

1 sprig curry leaves, plus extra to serve

1 lime, juice only

2 tbs vegetable oil

1 medium onion, peeled, quartered

2 garlic cloves, peeled, finely chopped

2 leeks, chopped

3 banana chillies, chopped

2 long red chillies, finely chopped, plus extra to serve

2 green chillies, finely chopped, plus extra to serve

2 tomatoes cut into wedges

For the sweet and sour sauce: 3 tbs tomato sauce

3 tbs vinegar

METHOD: Place the tuna in a bowl with salt, chilli powder, curry leaves and lime juice.

Stir to coat the tuna and set aside to marinate for 10 minutes.

For the sweet and sour sauce: combine the tomato sauce and vinegar and set aside until ready to use.

Heat the oil in a wok over high heat. Once it reaches smoking point, add the onion, garlic and leeks.

Once the mixture is fragrant and the onion is translucent, add the chillies and fry for a few minutes, stirring occasionally.

Add the tuna and toss to coat in the spice mixture. Stir in the sweet and sour sauce and cover. Leave to cook for a few minutes, or until the tuna is just cooked.

Stir through the tomato wedges, season with salt and pepper and serve sprinkled with curry leaves and the reserved chilli.

For all the latest and special events at Peter's restaurant, Noosa Beach House, go to .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Beach House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
