<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436967250832399</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/nick-xenophon-crackdown-on-bank-executives-money-laundering/8779284</url>
  <title>Nick Xenophon calls for jail terms for banking bosses complicit in money laundering</title>
  <content>
South Australian senator Nick Xenophon wants bank executives and board members who are complicit in money laundering or fraud to face jail terms.
His comments come after the  of anti-money laundering and terrorism financing laws.
The Australian Transactions Reports and Analysis Centre (AUSTRAC) alleges the Commonwealth Bank breached the law more than 53,000 times, allowing criminal syndicates to funnel money overseas through deposit machines.
Senator Xenophon said the only way to change the culture at big banks after a serious of scandals was to put a possible jail sentence on the table.
"There has been an almost contemptuous disregard of the law, and if the consequence of that is to allow drug dealers to launder money and terrorist operations to be funded by this, then that's very serious," he said.
"If you want to have a cultural shift in financial institutions that are doing the wrong thing, there is nothing like a jail term for their chief executive and board of directors to sharpen their thinking."
CBA is accused of failing to report cash transactions of $10,000 or more made through intelligent deposit machines to AUSTRAC in time for assessment, as required by anti-money laundering laws.
The transactions in question had a total value of around $624.7 million.
If the breaches are proven, the .
That is about seven times the bank's market value, but Senator Xenophon is not convinced financial penalties will be enough force compliance.
Scandal renews calls for banking royal commission

Nationals senator John Williams will again call for a royal commission into the banking industry at the Coalition party room next week.
"We seem to go from catastrophe to catastrophe with some of the institutions, and it doesn't help their cause in the public opinion arena and that's why you hear so many people call for it, as I've said, I wished we had it years ago when I first called for it," he told the ABC.
"It's a message to all financial institutions - keep an eye on the money, do the right thing or they may be assisting accidentally of financing terrorist organisations overseas, that is a big worry."
So far, scandals involving the  have not prompted a royal commission.
Senator Xenophon said Parliament should consider new criminal laws.
"We need to change the law to ensure senior bank executives and the directors of a bank could face criminal penalties and jail if they are shown to be reckless in the way they have dealt with issues of money laundering," he said.
"It is damning in terms of the appalling lack of risk management that the Commonwealth Bank was involved in.
"They made a lot of money out of this and sometimes a fine is not enough - sometimes a jail term needs to be on the agenda."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Transaction Reports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Analysis Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
