<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436365955406107</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/pregnancy/the-biggest-losers-tiffiny-hall-on-why-she-wont-be-back-at-the-gym-following-the-birth-of-her-baby/news-story/798feac43f20f26172c0c11bc0890895</url>
  <title>The Biggest Loser's Tiffiny Hall on why she won't be back at the gym following the birth of her baby</title>
  <content>
Tiffiny Hall on why she's not going to hit the gym straight after having a baby.

Share

SHE'S known for her rock hard abs and defined guns, but The Biggest Loser's Tiffiny Hall said she's not prepared to "sacrifice" time with her newborn baby just to get her famous body back.
Hall, who is expecting her first child in September with comedian husband Ed Kavalee, said while she's "put on weight", she will not yield to the pressures of an immediate bounce back.
"There's a lot of effort that goes in to the bounce back," Hall told news.com.au.
"Hours at the gym and calorie restrictions. I'm not up for sacrificing time with my new baby to be pumping it out at the gym.
"It's so much pressure on new mums. My body has changed, and that's all right. I have put on weight, but it's beautiful, glorious weight."

Tiffiny Hall says she won't put pressure on her body to get her abs back.Source:Instagram

Tiffiny Hall says she won't sacrifice time with her newborn to get her pre-baby body back.Source:Instagram
Hall, who is the founder of the said her pregnancy had been a bumpy ride - especially in the early stages.
"It hasn't been a smooth Instagram pregnancy at all ... I've been horrifically sick from day one," she said.
"I knew I was pregnant the day after conception - I was so sick, like nothing I'd ever felt."
Hall, 33, said because of her fitness, she thought she'd be able to continue an active lifestyle throughout her pregnancy.

But instead - she was forced to spend time in hospital and only do "pilates a few times a week".
"I loved being active, and I loved my routine," she said.
"But at the end of the day, all that matters is the baby. They have a plan, and I can't interfere.
"I know bodies are adaptable, and when I need to get fit again I will."

Tiffiny Hall said she's been craving "lots of carbs" throughout her pregnancy. Picture: Splash NewsSource:Supplied
"My priority will be to breastfeed and look after the baby, and not do anything that will bring about drastic body changes.
"You have to think of your mental health. Baby blues can set in. I have wonderful members [at TIFFXO], who I don't think would connect with me if I was all about getting my body back.
"My number one concern is this baby and feeding it well. The body can come later."

Tiffiny Hall is due to give birth in September.Source:Instagram
Hall said she'd experienced new cravings during her pregnancy, saying she was completely turned off by the foods she'd normally consume.
"All the foods I normally eat I went off," she said.
"I've craved hot chips every now and then, and just wanting carbs like oats, toast and eggs.
I haven't craved many sweets - just energy foods, and lots of dairy.
"You have to go with the flow and surrender. But I'm not worried. I've seen so many women get back.
"I will have to start low impact, so it won't be high intensity. But it's about when you're ready. "Some are good at 12 weeks and some at 12 months."

Tiffiny Hall says she won't be putting her body ahead of her baby.Source:Supplied
Speaking to The Daily Telegraph, fellow Biggest Loser trainer Michelle Bridges - who gave birth to her son in Axel in 2015, said her body hadn't bounced back to the way it once was.
"I'm really happy, but fitness-wise my body's nowhere near what it was," she said.
"You spend nine months being pregnant and you need at least another nine to get back on your feet."
Three weeks after giving birth to her son, Bridges was slammed by experts for advising new mums on
The regimen, which was posted on Instagram, detailed her post-natal workout, which entailed 56 minutes of jogging and walking.

'I'm really happy, but fitness-wise my body's nowhere near what it was.' Picture: Supplied/ChicSource:Supplied
At the time, Lyz Evans from Sydney's Women in Focus Physiotherapy, shared a lengthy post about the "irresponsible" advice given by Bridges.
"For a woman who has just had a vaginal birth or caesarean delivery it is quite simply irresponsible, and would NOT be recommended by an experienced health professional," Ms Evans wrote.
"As a public figure encouraging women whose body types, birth and fitness histories are unknown, to start jogging is quite frankly concerning."

A post shared by Tiffiny Hall (@tiffhall_xo) on

Speaking of childbirth, Hall said all she's heard are horror stories - but will treat the experience "like a sport".
"I used to be an athlete, so I'm treating it [childbirth] like a sport," she said.
"I'm used to being coached, so just coach me through it!"
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Bridges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Axel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall, 33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September-sources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TIFFXO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffiny Hall</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Splash NewsSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyz Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggest Loser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supplied/ChicSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Focus Physiotherapy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Kavalee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggest Loser's Tiffiny Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
