<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436537754099181</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/brent-harvey-says-brodie-grundy-would-be-harshly-done-by-to-get-in-trouble-for-the-perfect-tackle/news-story/58bb25fa8b5464546d8443e6b6198ab3</url>
  <title>'I can't see what Grundy's done wrong'</title>
  <content>
NORTH Melbourne great Brent Harvey says Collingwood's Brodie Grundy would be extremely unlucky to be suspended for "the perfect tackle" on Ben Brown.
Grundy is set for a nervous wait for the match review panel's verdict on the tackle that left Brown with concussion.
But Harvey said despite Grundy pinning Brown's arms, his tackling technique was sound - with Brown ultimately harmed by the fact his attempt to kick the ball put him off balance.
"Ben Brown's a really big boy and had a position of strength ... Grundy's got him and then Ben Brown lifts his leg to kick the ball, just so literally there wasn't a free kick," Harvey said on Fox Sports news' Gameday Live.
"Then all of a sudden he weighs 30 kilos because he's on one leg and the momentum's going.
"Grundy did everything that we've practiced as tacklers, as a junior and as senior footballers as well. So it's tough."
The Kangaroos confirmed Brown was okay - other than his concussion - during the match.
Harvey said he believed it was unlikely Grundy would be cited had Brown not suffered a concussion.
"I am a little bit (confused), yes. If Ben Brown doesn't get concussed, I think it's alright and no-one talks about it," Harvey said.
"The fact that he gets concussed says there's a duty of care to look after the head.
"I can't see what Grundy's done wrong and neither can the umpire because he's got a free kick and I think nine out of 10 people will say 'that is the perfect tackle' and there'll be one critic that says 'well, he's got to protect the head.'"
Grundy's tackle came in a week where Patrick Dangerfield was suspended for a dangerous tackle that saw Matthew Kreuzer concussed.

AFL: Brodie Grundy tackles North Melbourne's Ben Brown, pinning his arms - and Brown's hit his head and ended up being stretchered off.

Grundy leaves Brown stunned
Harvey said the fact players were attempting to turn their opponents in the tackle - to avoid giving away a free kick for a push in the back - was contributing to the number of players hitting their heads.
"I think the rule's changed since the push in the back law's come in," Harvey said.
"Everybody's turning the player and not trying to give away a free kick and it's created more headaches - literally because of all the concussion stuff."
The games record-holder said Grundy was in a difficult position as it was hard for him to know how close Brown had gotten to the ground - or whether he had disposed of the ball.
"I don't think Grundy knows. I don't think he knows that the tackle's so close to the ground," Harvey said.
"His head's on the side and when you tackle, your cheek ends up on the back - you don't know if they've got the football. Dangerfield didn't know that Kreuzer had the football last week.
"There is a duty of care, I do agree with that with all the concussion stuff coming out of late but I still think it's the perfect tackle."
Melbourne footballer Dom Tyson said while players knew the risks of pinning arms in the tackle there was a degree of confusion given Grundy received a free kick for holding the ball over the incident, yet could ultimately end up suspended for the tackle.
"It's difficult because watching that tackle, obviously Brodie doesn't know if the ball has been dislodged," Tyson said on AFL Today.
"So he's thinking 'if I don't carry through with this tackle, then Brown could potentially handball it or get a kick away', so I've got sympathy for him in that situation.
"But at the same time, the umpires do tell us when they visit us in the pre-season - the minute you pin arms and (involve) a second motion, you're going to be at the mercy of a match review panel.
"But you do have to feel that there is some confusion through the fact that it is a free kick, live game day and then obviously it might get reviewed by the match review panel come Monday."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gameday Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne's Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grundy</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Tyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Today</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood's Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
