<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436494804425857</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/policy/education/macquarie-university-launches-new-medical-degree-which-offers-students-experience-in-india-20170803-gxolmw</url>
  <title>Macquarie University launches new medical degree which offers students experience in India</title>
  <content>
Macquarie University will launch its new medical degree on Monday and break new ground for a public university by charging full fees to students.
The university will begin marketing the four-year, graduate-entry degree immediately, and will enrol its first cohort of 60 students in 2018.
The new course also has another unique quality - third-year students will spend five months in Hyderabad, India, doing clinical training in a local hospital to give them a global perspective on their medical training.
"Our students will be global citizens, they will be experienced beyond their own home town, their own home cultures," said Patrick McNeil, the university's executive dean, medicine and health sciences.

"We are interested in doing distinctive things. We have designed a very high-quality program to deliver an exceptional student experience."

Domestic students will pay $64,000 a year for the course and international students, who will make up about one third of the total, will pay $70,000 a year.
Facing reality

The university had no alternative but to charge fees to domestic students in the course because the federal government has declined to offer course subsidies to the new medical degree, making it the only public university which does not have government funding for medicine.
"I think we are facing the reality that the appetite for introducing more Commonwealth-supported places for medical education in Australia is not high," said Macquarie University vice-chancellor Bruce Dowton, himself a medical doctor.

However, Macquarie's medical course, at a total of $256,000 for the four years, is cheaper than the only other full-fee medical degree at the private Bond University which costs $361,872.
Students will be able to ease the cost burden using the federal government's FEE-HELP loan scheme which allows them to borrow up to $126,101 for course fees at a zero real interest rate, and only make repayments when they are earning over a threshold income.
The university will also offer scholarships to students, with two for Indigenous students worth $50,000 a year, up to five for graduates of Macquarie's bachelor of clinical science worth $30,000 a year, up to two equity merit scholarships worth $30,000 a year, and one Medical Leader of the Future scholarship worth up to $50,000 a year.
"We will have the most generous scholarship program of any medical program in Australia - 15 per cent of our domestic places will be accessible by scholarships," Professor McNeil said.

Professor Dowton added that other postgraduate level courses in many disciplines were fee paying, including MBAs, and qualifications in engineering and science.
Natural next step

He said the medical degree was a natural next step for Macquarie University, which already teaches extensively in health science, and offers health services to the public through an extensive network of clinics. It is the only university in Australia .
Medical students will be used in the hospital and the clinics in their training, and internships will be available for medical graduates' after graduation.

Professor McNeil said there was room to increase the number of medical graduates in Australia because universities graduated about 3700 people a year from medical courses while about 2800 doctors entered from overseas each year.
"If you add those together then the need for new graduates every year is well over 6000 and universities only produce about two thirds of those," he said.
However, the Australian Medical Association (AMA), which represents doctors, strongly opposes the new degree saying that graduating more people from medical courses will not automatically lead to new doctors because of the shortage of one-year internships for newly minted doctors and the shortage of training places for doctors to become GPs or specialists.
Last December AMA president Michael Gannon wrote to Assistant Health Minister David Gillespie saying: "The establishment of a medical school at Macquarie University will simply divert training resources away from where they are needed, ie postgraduate medical education, and feed more graduates into a training pipeline that is already being overwhelmed by existing graduate numbers."

Professor McNeil agreed that there is a shortage of specialty training places for medical graduates, including general practice.
"We are aware of that and we have actively tried to address that challenge by starting postgraduate places in our own Macquarie university hospital," he said
"We are trying to provide solutions to the issues in the medical workforce in Australia rather than compounding them."
The Macquarie University medical course has just received formal approval and accreditation from the Australian Medical Council and the Medical Board of Australia.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia, 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FEE-HELP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Health Minister David Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor McNeil</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth-supported</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyderabad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick McNeil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Dowton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bond University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medical Leader of the Future</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Dowton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medical Board of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December AMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
