<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436838401812618</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/independent-report-into-qld-towing-industry-goes-to-heart-of-dodgy-business-model-20170806-gxq9z7.html</url>
  <title>New laws target tow-truck sharks ripping off Qld drivers</title>
  <content>
After hundreds of complaints from Queensland drivers, an independent investigation into the towing industry has been finalised and promises to get rid of tow-truck sharks.
The report, led by former District Court Judge Michael Forde, was revealed on Sunday and included a suite of recommendations to stop drivers from being ripped off by rogue tow-truck operators. Photo: Louie Douvis
Acting Main Roads and Road Safety Minister Steven Miles said that Queensland motorists can now "breathe a sigh of relief".
"The comprehensive report makes a range of recommendations and highlights some related matters for further consideration by government," he said.

"They (drivers) can be confident that their government will act ... to get rid of this rort, to get rid of the sharks who built a business model ripping off motorists."
The government ordered an investigation into the removal of vehicles from publicly accessible private car parks, in response to community anger over alleged shady and intimidating towing operators.

The tow-truck hotline (1800 681 636), which will continue to operate, received more than 700 calls since the May 9, with more than 450 of those being registered complaints.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Complaints included rogue tow-truck operators charging exorbitant fees to release vehicles, almost 75 per cent of callers reported fees in excess of $500, there were also concerns raised about sharks intimidating and threatening motorists.Photo: Darren England - AAP
The hotspots for these incidents included Fortitude Valley, Albion, Newstead, Ascot, Hamilton, Eagle Farm, Herston and Bowen Hills.
"Most of the callers wanted private-property towing fees to be capped. And the government will do that," Mr Miles said.Photo: Tony Moore
"Queensland will take the lead, with no other state having capped fees for private-property towing."
The key report recommendations include a crackdown to ensure tow-truck drivers have the proper accreditation, and increased penalties in excess of $20,000 for unlicensed operators.
The investigation also proposed setting maximum fees of $250 for vehicles towed from private property, and $150 if the vehicle is released on-site after being loaded onto the tow truck.
Other recommendations included imposing conduct requirements on tow-truck operators, developing guidelines for signage outlining parking conditions, as well as education programs to awareness of regulations around private-property parking.
However, opposition transport and main roads spokesman Andrew Powell accused Labor of stealing the LNP's "homework" and said there were still grey areas for tow-truck sharks to exploit. 
"The LNP said back in June that we would introduce a private member's bill at the next sitting of Parliament to crack down on dodgy tow-truck drivers to stop motorists being ripped off," he said.
"The Palaszczuk Labor Government are simply handing in the LNP's homework as their own by adopting our position to cap fees for towing and storage.
"Labor still hasn't acted on parking signage, on maximum towing distance or on a formal complaints management process, which are addressed in our Private Member's Bill.
"No Queenslander should be ripped off by a dodgy tow-truck operator and this is why the LNP has listened to concerned motorists, planned and forced Labor into making a decision."
Mr Forde's final report and recommendations, which can be accessed in full , will be presented to cabinet on Monday morning.
.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court Judge Michael Forde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ascot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newstead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortitude Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EAGLE Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk Labor Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Road Safety Minister Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Powell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Private Members' Bills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Forde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
