<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435979408345999</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4835956/austinmer-girls-gear-up-for-city2surf-in-honour-of-grandfather/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Austinmer girls gear up for City2Surf in honour of race legend Barry Clunas</title>
  <content>
A matter of honour: Austinmer's Georgia and Abby Clunas are gearing up for the 2017 City2Surf to honour their grandfather Barry Clunas. Picture: Sylvia Liber

When Georgia and Abby Clunas undertake the City2Surf for this first time next Sunday, they'll be doing it in honour of their grandfather - a legend of the event.
Barry Clunas completed 46 consecutive City2Surf events - the last in 2016, just two months before he lost his battle with cancer.
For his granddaughters, from Austinmer, it will an emotional day but one on which to celebrate their beloved grandfather's courage.
''He was a very determined and inspirational man,'' Georgia, 19, said.
''Last year his doctor told him he couldn't enter the event, and that he wouldn't finish it. He told us 'I'll finish it if it takes my last  breath'.
''He took that attitude and he completed it, though my dad almost carried him over the finish line.''
Mr Clunas, a toolmaker by trade and dedicated family man, features on the The Sun-Herald City2Surf  'Legends' page.
- Georgia Clunas
The event has raised over $32 million since 2008 when the fundraising tally was first recorded; this year it aims to help raise another $5,000,000 for more than 900 charities.

Georgia and Abby, 15, are hoping to raise a substantial amount towards that tally, while carrying on the family tradition.
''He just loved running it and raising money for charity,'' Georgia said.

Georgia and Abby have been busy training for the 14 kilometre event.
''He used to run all the time, and even when he got sick I think running became a real escape for him.
''He encouraged my dad and his brother and my cousin to run with him over the years and it really ended up being all about family.''
Georgia, a teacher's assistant at Elonera Montessori School, and Abby, a student of the Wollongong school, have been busy training for the 14 kilometre event.
The 2017 course will start in Sydney's Hyde Park and follow the same route through to Bondi Beach as it has done since the start line moved to College St in 1977. 

''We are really looking forward to it,'' Georgia said.

''While it will certainly be an emotional day, it will be a great day to remember our granddad and his achievements.''
They will join around 80,000 participants in this year's event, which also includes fun and entertainment for everyone with a festival from August 10-12 at Darling Harbour.

Details: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Hyde Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elonera Montessori School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abby Clunas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>College St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun-Herald City2Surf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City2Surf</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Clunas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Clunas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austinmer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Clunas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abby, 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austinmer's Georgia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
