<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436361660438806</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:38</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/less-than-half-wa-voters-satisfied-with-mcgowan-government-performance-since-election/news-story/5a7a7f6ec9c4a5b1cfdaebc4b916f890</url>
  <title>Honeymoon over: Poll blow to WA Labor</title>
  <content>
LESS than half of West Australians are satisfied with the McGowan Government's performance, an exclusive poll for The Sunday Times shows.
The Galaxy Poll shows 48 per cent of voters were satisfied with the Labor Government, while 35 per cent were not and 17 per cent were uncommitted.
The findings come four months after Labor's historic landslide victory and signal an end to Premier Mark McGowan's post-election "honeymoon period".
The poll, conducted on July 26 and 25 and based on the opinions of 850 WA residents, asked: Are you satisfied or dissatisfied with the performance of Mark McGowan's Labor Government in that time?
It showed while 71 per cent of Labor voters were satisfied with the Government's performance, 16 per cent were not and 13 per cent were uncommitted.
Thirty-five per cent of Coalition supporters were satisfied, while 47 per cent were not and 18 per cent were uncommitted.
The results follow a tough few months for Mr McGowan and his government who inherited a set of books which showed State debt was rocketing towards $40 billion and a Budget forecast to be in deficit for years to come.
Since winning power, the government has implemented a number of controversial strategies, such as limiting pay rises for public servants to $1000 a year and increasing power charges by 10.9 per cent.
Mr McGowan yesterday remained unapologetic about his government's tough stance heading to the September 7 budget.
"West Australians elected my government to get on with the job and fix the mess left behind," he said.
"This is exactly what we are doing, with our focus on creating jobs, delivering on our election commitments and repairing the State's finances.
"People understand the difficult task ahead - turning around the State's finances and getting the WA economy back on track.
"We have had to make tough decisions to help pay for the Liberals' and Nationals' out-of-control spending.
"With over $5 billion in revenue written down since the election, fixing the mess we inherited will take time.
"We weren't elected to sit on our hands and do nothing, we're getting on with the job and there is renewed confidence in the WA economy."
Respected political analyst Dr Harry Phillips said Labor's convincing victory provided the Government with a mandate to reduce debt.
As reported last weekend, the poll also showed support for Federal Liberals had collapsed 10 percentage points and predicted WA ministers Michael Keenan, Christian Porter and Ken Wyatt would lose their seats at the next election.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy Poll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA's Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark McGowan's Labor Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirty-five</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Harry Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
