<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437139049525824</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/newcastle-masseur-caught-taking-and-sharing-photos-of-female-clients-20170806-gxqdx7.html</url>
  <title>Newcastle masseur caught taking and sharing photos of female clients</title>
  <content>
A Newcastle masseur has been caught taking naked photos of his female clients and sharing them among a secret group of male strippers known as "the big fellas".
In public Josh Hewitt, a Mayfield-based masseur, topless waiter and male stripper, boasted that whether he was "stroking your hair or massaging your body" his "pampering" massages would "make you feel just as you should feel, special".Photo: Newcastle Herald.
But in reality Mr Hewitt, who is not registered under the Australian Health Practitioner Regulation Agency or the Association of Massage Therapists, took photos of his clients as they lie undressed and face down on his massage table and shared them with other male strippers in a private Instagram group called "the big fella's" (sic).
Mr Hewitt, who has deleted his Newcastle Relaxation Massage Therapy and Newcastle Male Stripper Facebook pages in recent days, has ignored repeated requests for comment.
When the Newcastle Herald visited his Mayfield home on Friday he said "sorry" before closing the door.
But the Newcastle Herald has obtained screen shots from the "big fella's" in which Mr Hewitt shared explicit images and contact details of his female clients and encouraged the other men in the group to contact them.

In one post made in December last year Mr Hewitt, under the Instagram name newcastle_relaxation_massage, posted a photo showing a woman's bare leg and buttock with the caption "up to inner girls thighs atm with oil.. tough gig lol".
In another he sent a photo of a partially undressed woman laying face down from behind with the caption "hard day at the office [at the moment] boys lol".
The conversation includes lewd comments about Mr Hewitt's clients, and in one instance a "big fella" encourages Mr Hewitt to "set up some hidden cameras" to which he replies "i shud lol".
Despite the other "big fellas" at times complaining that the women Mr Hewitt was encouraging them to message "didn't write back", he bragged about his ability to set his friends up with clients.
"I know these girls.. they love to party.. and they love the male strippers," he wrote in one post.
But Fairfax Media has spoken to a number of Mr Hewitt's ex-clients, who have labelled him a "creep" and say they feel "disgusted and violated" after being made aware of his secret social media habits.
One woman, who spoke on the condition of anonymity, said she had "caught him with his phone in his hand" during a massage but avoided confronting him.
"I thought at the time he was taking [photos] ... he put it [the phone] down really quickly but I saw the camera on his screen," she said.
"I didn't say anything to him ... I wish I knew at the time what I know now."
Another woman whose details Mr Hewitt shared in the Instagram group said she had only been massaged by Mr Hewitt on one occasion and had no idea he had encouraged other men to contact her.
The woman said that she had initially asked for only a neck massage, but Mr Hewitt had given her a whole body massage.
"People say 'why didn't you tell him to stop' [but] you just feel like, he must know what he's doing, this must be normal, so I didn't want to say anything," she said.
"I just felt really uncomfortable, it gave me a bit of anxiety and I felt really awkward."
After the massage the woman said Mr Hewitt had continued to contact her, sending text messages and commenting on her Instagram photos.
But after she discovered what he had done Mr Hewitt sent her a text message in which he apologised "that this has happened and for the stress it has caused everyone".
"I am deeply sorry for any distress I have caused," he said.
"I assure you this was and is not my intention."
Newcastle Herald
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Association of Massage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hewitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Relaxation Massage Therapy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Male Stripper Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hewitt</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfield-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Health Practitioner Regulation Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
