<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436408905079284</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/stage/looking-glass-review-theatre-in-the-key-of-anxiety-20170804-gxphvt.html</url>
  <title>Theatre in the key of anxiety</title>
  <content>
THEATRE
LOOKING GLASS ★★★ 1/2
FortyFive Downstairs, until August 13
Reviewed by Cameron Woodhead
 Melbourne's indie theatre scene has a communitarian ethos and creative charge that consistently enrich our city's culture. The latest outfit to emerge from this ferment is New Working Group - a loose collective of 11 designers, writers and directors, all dedicated to exploring new frontiers on the contemporary stage.Photo: Hopwood PR
They kick off with Louris van de Geer's Looking Glass, a one-act play offering a clinical dissection of a nuclear family.
Through brief scenes, a Mother (Daniela Farinacci), a Father (Peter Houghton), and Child (Daniel O'Neill/Thomas Taylor) play-act their way through everyday life. Suddenly, Child lies face down on the floor and refuses to get up, and a mercurial outsider (Josh Price) intrudes to observe and guide, mock and manipulate the parents' response.Photo: Hopwood PR
Overwhelmingly, it's theatre composed in the key of anxiety.
Farinacci's Mother - etched into a brittle mask of maternal worry - has every "natural" instinct towards her son undermined or gainsaid. When Child swallows Lego, a disembodied voice directs her conversation with him. A playful game of catch with her family carries a bitter undercurrent of emotional competitiveness. A bearded stranger with a bun in the oven challenges the Mother's own experience of pregnancy.

The Father, too, chafes at his imposed role - slipping from concerned dad to puerile man-child in several scenes, having his competence queried by a pizza delivery guy - though Houghton could lend more intricacy and emotional valence to the ways in which that authority gets evacuated from without.
The child actors are a revelation, hardening from moments of intimate flow into an uncanny, defiant kind of negative presence - accusing postures of alienation and trauma (somewhere between Village of the Damned and a Munch painting) you just can't look away from.Photo: Hopwood PR
And Price's interloper develops an almost Pinteresque sense of comic menace.
Excellent design amplifies the unsettling text: Kate Davis' sparse white set cages the action, with Ian Moorhead's grating electronic sound, and Amelia Lever-Davidson's intensely textured lighting, deepening our sense of alarm.
Perhaps the performances don't quite cut deeply enough into the flesh of this play (which feels, in any case, a touch underwritten) to prevent it sometimes approaching a histrionic exercise, yet director Susie Dee does draw deceptive depth from the deliberately constrained performance style.
Looking Glass speaks directly to an age where parents are under siege from external expectation, and the more you think about it, the more intriguing it becomes.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Working Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houghton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FortyFive Downstairs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GLASS ★★★ 1/2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farinacci's Mother</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geer's Looking Glass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susie Dee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel O'Neill/Thomas Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Moorhead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniela Farinacci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Village of the Damned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinteresque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Houghton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hopwood PR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelia Lever-Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Woodhead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
