<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436408905079246</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/this-little-fella-is-a-long-way-from-home/news-story/9ccf16f8606928687627f75f42706320</url>
  <title>A big journey for a tiny chick</title>
  <content>
THIS is Emoo and he is lost.
Emoo is a baby emu who was found in a mystery location in western Queensland or even as far away as the Northern Territory and brought to Billabong Sanctuary late last week by a passing traveller.
His dad had been hit and killed and Emoo was found alone sitting next to the body.
The little chick is now back in safe hands with NQ Wildlife Care bird co-ordinator Sarah Luke, who said he won't be able to stay for long.
"This is something we don't see often in Townsville and my kids have asked if we can keep him," Ms Luke said.
"He doesn't have any injuries and is slowly getting over his trauma.
"He is too young to go back into the while just yet but he won't be able to stay with me long term, he needs the company of other emus in the wild and needs a lot of space."
Ms Luke said she had only been given a vague description as to where Emoo came from so was desperate to find out anymore information that might lead to his original location where he could be released or cared for closer to home.
"The lady who dropped him to Billabong said he was found at the 'Threeways' and the only reference I can find is in the NT," she said.
If you have more information about where Emoo may have been found call NQ Wildlife Care on 0414 717 374 and ask for Sarah.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billabong Sanctuary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NQ Wildlife Care</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emoo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billabong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Luke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
