<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436198451680055</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/gold-coast-residents-in-some-of-the-citys-busiest-areas-are-scalping-parking-permits-by-targeting-tradies/news-story/7440b90994aba76ca9630d55c378fe1b</url>
  <title>This piece of paper is worth a fortune</title>
  <content>
THEY could be the most prized ticket in town and scalpers have moved in to take advantage.
With more of the Gold Coast set to be covered by regulated parking accusations are flying that in at least one of the Coast residents are cashing in demand for car parking spaces by selling their rare on-street parking permits.
The lucrative trade is hitting tradies in Varsity Lakes where a combination of narrow streets and a construction has made parking spaces a premium commodity.
Area councillor Hermann Vorster said the new parking regulations in the area had eased congestion and returned the streets to long-suffering local residents.
"But I'm told a small minority ripping off their neighbours by selling 'visitor permits' that would usually be used by friends, family and carers," he said.
"This isn't allowed under the rules and is a total abuse of a system designed to improve safety and put locals first."
"Residents shouldn't profiteer on the space at the front of their neighbours - it's just disgusting and I won't stand for it."
"I've asked City officers to contact permit holders with a reminder of their obligations."
Broadbeach councillor Paul Taylor, who recently called for the popular beachside suburb to be covered by a reparking scheme, said the prospect of residents scalping there permits was a concern.
"Naturally it would be a worry because that's not the intention of the scheme and I think the residents who are doing that are defeating their own purpose," he said.
Cr Taylor said while he felt the situation was one where very few people would do it, if they did he didn't think there was much council could do about it.
"No matter what you will always have someone who will try and be different."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbeach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hermann Vorster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Varsity Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
