<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436713847759641</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/nathan-buckleys-cheeky-dig-at-david-schwarz-after-exdee-slams-perfect-tackle-comments/news-story/1c180b76c96f7eb7de761f166225e24b</url>
  <title>Whack! Bucks' cheeky clip for Dees great</title>
  <content>
COLLINGWOOD coach Nathan Buckley has taken a cheeky dig at David Schwarz, after the Melbourne great questioned his comments on Brodie Grundy's tackle on Ben Brown.
A tweet from the SEN Radio football account - which quoted Schwarz saying that Buckley's call that Grundy had laid a "perfect tackle" was "his stupidest comment of the year" - seemingly caught Buckley's eye.
And the Collingwood coach didn't hold back.
"I suppose it is Ox's area of expertise ..." Buckley tweeted in response.
Whack.

I suppose it is Ox's area of expertise...
That said, Schwarz wasn't fazed by the cheeky clip, sticking to his guns on his original comments.
"He's flying the flag to stand up for his players, and he's got to do that," Schwarz said on SEN Radio.
"I stand by it."
On Saturday night, Buckley defended Grundy over the tackle that left Brown concussed, saying it was a "perfect tackle", despite the ruckman coming under fire for pinning Brown's arms.
"I don't think there was any malice in the tackle," Buckley said post-match.
"He was tackling to dispossess, tackling to get the free kick the way the rules were written, so what more do you do?
"There's a massive grey area there and we're all swimming in it at the moment. We saw three or four dangerous tackles tonight. A couple were paid free kicks and a couple were paid holding the ball.
"It was a pretty good tackle rewarded with a holding the ball and clearly when you're tackling someone from behind with momentum ... it's pretty hard to put yourself in reverse."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grundy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Schwarz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schwarz</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN Radio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
