<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436494804425795</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/butt-squeeze-victimisation-wins-prison-officer-20k-compensation/news-story/5b0659c06f265e8d84e08f113685bd27</url>
  <title>Butt squeeze 'victimisation' wins prison officer $20k compensation</title>
  <content>
A woman who received a "squeeze" on the bottom from her boss at a night out at Bavarian Bier Cafe has won $20,000 in compensation.

EXCLUSIVE, Linda Silmalis

Share

A FEMALE prison officer got nothing for an alleged "squeeze" on the backside from her boss during a night out at a Bavarian Bier Cafe - but has won $20,000 in compensation for victimisation during the investigation.
Rita James took Corrective Services NSW to court over alleged victimisation, including the department failing to reinstate her into the position she had held prior making a complaint.
While a police investigation concluded there was no reasonable prospect of a conviction, the NSW Civil and Administration Tribunal ruled Ms James had been hurt and distressed by the treatment she endured after making a complaint.
This included having to sit before her old boss who was part of an interview panel for an alternate job.

Rita James' former boss Ivan Calder was never the subject of any charges in relation to the alleged incident. Picture: Jonathan NgSource:News Corp Australia
Ms James' former boss Ivan Calder, who was the director of the John Morony Correctional Centre Intensive Drug and Alcohol Treatment Program (IDATP) director at the time, has since become the governor.
The Tribunal heard Ms James lodged a bullying and harassment complaint with the department in December 2015, which referred the alleged incident at the popular Parramatta beer hall in August that year.
After losing the complaint, Ms James was found an alternative position at Silverwater while an investigation was undertaken.
Despite later being given medical clearance to return to work in May the following year, Ms James alleged she was advised by email that she would not be able to come back while an investigation was underway into the indecent assault.
Ms James alleged it was around the time of receiving the email that the victimisation began.

The court heard the department's failure to allow Ms James to return to her old position had caused her to have a breakdown at work in October.
RELATED: CCTV CATCHES MOMENT WORKER STAGED FAKE ACCIDENT

Workers' compensation fraud caught on tape

2:27

CCTV catches the moment an office worker staged a fake accident to claim compensation from her employer after a piece of metal dropped from the ceiling. Courtesy: FOX 13

May 4th 2017
3 months ago
/video/video.news.com.au/News/

In affidavits provided to the Tribunal, Corrective Services NSW said Ms James stopped attending work in November 2015 after going on sick leave for anxiety and depression.
A departmental report recommended Ms James be transferred at the same grade from the Windsor complex, to ensure the safety of both herself and her director.
In September last year, the department's Professional Standards Branch (PSB) of Corrective Services ruled the indecent assault were unsubstantiated.
The Tribunal heard Ms James was informed in January this year that the role she had previously held at John Morony would not necessarily be the same in the future due to a review underway of all jobs at the drug unit.

She was given a position at Silverwater jail, but the Tribunal found that not letting her resume work back at the Windsor complex brought a loss of quality of life. Picture: Adam TaylorSource:News Corp Australia
In ruling in Ms James' favour, Tribunal senior member Anne Maria Scahill said Corrective Services NSW could have investigated Ms James' complaint about Mr Calder, without subjecting her to "a substantial detriment".
She said it was understandable Ms James had become upset when told she would not get her old job back, as all the barriers to her return such as medical clearance and the completion of the investigation had been removed.
"The Tribunal is satisfied that refusing to return Ms James to the Windsor complex and her transfer to Silverwater because she had made a complaint against Mr Calder, brought a loss of quality of life for Ms James in a number of ways," she said.
"Her travel time to work increased substantially and she was diminished in her status in the organisation.
"After her transfer to Silverwater, Ms James made efforts to be interviewed for other positions. At one of these, Mr Calder was present at the interview - again, to Ms James' distress."
The Tribunal ordered Corrective Services NSW pay Ms James $20,000 for distress and "loss of enjoyment of life" following its victimisation of her.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Calder</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Calder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rita James</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bavarian Bier Cafe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silverwater</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam TaylorSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrective Services NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IDATP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administration Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan NgSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alcohol Treatment Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Morony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Maria Scahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms James $20,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms James</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Morony Correctional Centre Intensive Drug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV CATCHES MOMENT WORKER STAGED FAKE ACCIDENT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSB) of Corrective</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Silmalis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professional Standards Branch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
