<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436494804425841</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/book-delivery-service-in-outback-nsw-a-saviour/8770840</url>
  <title>Book delivery service in outback NSW a 'saviour' for residents on remote properties</title>
  <content>
Distance, isolation, limited services and patchy internet makes the book delivery service in far west NSW just as important for residents today as it was when it started 40 years ago.
The Outback Letterbox Library operates out of Broken Hill City Library where staff pack books based on the residents' interests and sent them to their remote properties by mail or freight.
The coverage area spans across to the SA, QLD and VIC borders and far east as Brewarrina.
Members of the Hill family join more than 500 members of the free service which is funded by the Library Council of NSW.
Rachel and Bodie Hill and their children Ethan and Edward live on Waka Station near Cameron Corner and the closest library is at Broken Hill, which is a five-hour drive.
While life is fun and busy on the station, Bodie Hill said it would be dull without receiving a bag full of books at their door.
"Wherever we go, if we are going into town [to Tibooburra] it's an hour so [the children have] always had to entertain themselves," Mr Hill said.
"I think it was going to be natural that they were going to either like books or learn to cope with being bored.
"I don't know if it's a good thing or a bad thing when we actually have to ban our boys from reading books.
"In the morning they get up, grab a book and sit in front of the fire and we've made a rule in our house that they're not allowed to read a book until they're dressed."
Libraries a universal right

Broken Hill Library coordinator Tracy Fraser said all sorts of people use the service.
"It varies from station owners, governesses, children studying out on stations, right through to town dwellers that don't have a library service," Ms Fraser said.
"It provides wellbeing, mental stimulation ... it's not reliant on your income and it's a connection to the outside world so we're bringing the outside world to them in a very small package every six weeks."
Ms Fraser said it was a human right for all communities to have access to a library for free.
"People that use this service say ... it's been their saviour, that they would not have enjoyed their experience living in the outback as much without this vital, vital service," Ms Fraser said.
Snail mail beats the internet

Ms Fraser said the service was even more important for residents in the modern day.
"In far west NSW, there is very limited internet coverage and ... spasmodic so they don't have as an ideal coverage as a town site or a city."
There are ongoing reports of problems with the National Broadband Network's (NBN)  with some Australians going to  to get a good connection.
However, the NBN is adamant that connectivity has improved and recently announced that it would .
Sally Bright lives on Mount Woowoolahra station about 120 kilometres north-west of Broken Hill has used the Outback Letterbox Library for about 20 years.
"We always say ... if it's not too sunny, if it's not too windy, you have a good day on the internet so it's pretty unreliable at times," Ms Bright said.
Broken Hill library has considered delivering e-books and streaming story time services or workshops to remote residents as telecommunications improve in the bush and technology advances.
Nothing beats a book

But Outback Letterbox Library members said they hoped the traditional service did not change too much.
"Having a bag of books is like getting Christmas every six weeks," Ms Bright said.
"If I get sent good books sometimes there's a lack of tea being cooked, or housework being done, or I just say 'just one more page and I will come out to the paddock' ... and it sometimes ends up being a chapter."
Ms Bright said she would be reading less without the Outback Letterbox Library.

Mr Hill said nothing could beat holding a book.
"Even if the internet was super dooper, I think you would still want to read a book," Mr Hill said.
Ms Hill said she loved seeing her children enthralled by books.
"If my kids were sitting down with iPads in front of them reading books off the screen - I just don't know if I'd love that," Ms Hill.
"[I love that] they grab a book and go sit out on the verandah in the sun."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracy Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outback Letterbox Library</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Broadband Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Corner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bright</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ethan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broken Hill City Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broken Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bodie Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fraser</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Woowoolahra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Bright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Library Council of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waka Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brewarrina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tibooburra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
