<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436194156712725</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/12/39/seinfeld-proves-hes-still-got-it-at-adelaide-leg-of-australian-tour</url>
  <title>Seinfeld proves he</title>
  <content>
Even at 63 years old, Jerry Seinfeld has still got it.
Returning to Adelaide for the first (and most likely last) time in 19 years, there wasn't an empty seat at the Adelaide Entertainment Centre last night.
Best known for his self-titled show in the 1990's, the nostalgia was no surprise.
A sea of New York Yankees caps filled the arena (forget the fact he's a Mets fan). It wasn't hard to pick out the many t-shirts adorned with George Costanza's face. And you couldn't even count the number of men sporting the iconic combo of white Nikes and blue jeans- all an ode to the man on stage.
As the lights dimmed and the stage fell to black, an excited murmur filled the arena, before silence. 
Suddenly, Seinfeld arrived on stage, and it was like you were part of the crowd from his TV show. A simple black curtain, a microphone stand, and Jerry Seinfeld, front and centre. 
"I'm in ADELAIDE!" he shouted, and the crowd was in raptures. 

Related Articles

His trademark observational comedy was as sharp as ever, especially relevant when touching on Adelaide's own coffee culture, marriage, work, and the many pet peeves that have come to define his personality. 
And he's yet to lose a step in the most underrated part of his routine: physical comedy. Seinfeld ran, hopped, jumped, and at one stage, even lied down on stage, all without skipping a breath.
Seinfeld's voice remains his greatest weapon, his variety of pace, pause and pitch continually striking blows with the audience. The hour long routine was as precise as ever, flawlessly moving from one topic to the next. 
The only disappointing moment?
Seinfeld wishing the adoring crowd farewell, bowing, and running off stage.
Here's hoping we don't need to wait another 19 years. 
Seinfeld will perform in Melbourne tonight and August 8, before taking his tour to Brisbane on August 9. His final Australian performances will be in Sydney on August 10 and 11.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Yankees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seinfeld</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerry Seinfeld</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Costanza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Entertainment Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
