<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436709552792320</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/cricket/big-bash/sydney-thunder-eye-three-international-signings-in-wbbl-20170804-gxpcyj.html</url>
  <title>Sydney Thunder eye three international signings in WBBL</title>
  <content>
Big Bash franchises have turned their attention to signing players after Thursday's resolution of Australian cricket's lengthy pay war, and the Sydney Thunder are confident of landing three international stars for the WBBL.
The Thunder are in negotiations with India's Harmanpreet Kaur, who destroyed Australia's women's World Cup dream last month, and West Indies allrounder Stafanie Taylor - both of whom played for the Sydney outfit last season.

Up Next

Bolt defeated by Gatlin in final 100m race

00:23

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Plays of the Week

Nail-biting finishes, ripping yorkers and hat-trick heroes, these are the plays of the week.

A third megastar of the women's game also is being eyed off by the inaugural WBBL premiers, who have freed up some room in their roster after telling Erin Osborne, Claire Koski and Stef Defarra their services would not be required this season.
No players could be signed during the pay war, with domestic talent only able to agree in-principle deals throughout the dispute between Cricket Australia and the ACA.

and has indicated her desire to return to Sydney, although the Board of Control for Cricket in India will have the final say on whether she comes back.
She bludgeoned an unbeaten 171 off 115 balls in the World Cup semi-final in England to help beat defending champions Australia, and has been lauded a hero since returning to India

Since returning to India the Punjab government has begun the process of inducting her as a deputy superintendent of police. When she applied for a job with the Punjab police about six years ago her application was turned down.
Asked whether she would return to the Thunder after the World Cup semi-final, Harmanpreet said: "I enjoyed [it] because I had a really good team, they always gave me good confidence and my captain [Alex] Blackwell, she's a very motivated girl and she always appreciated my innings. It was great fun for me to play [at the] Thunder."
the Australian having blasted a courageous 90 from 56 balls for a final-wicket stand of 76 with Kristen Beams in a late bid to steal victory.
Harmanpreet battled a shoulder problem throughout the World Cup, and has been ruled out of England's T20 Super League - where she was due to play for the Surrey Stars - to let the injury heal. She's expected to be fully fit for the start of the Australian summer should the Thunder secure her signature.
India looms as a fertile recruiting ground for WBBL franchises after the BCCI last week ruled out starting its own women's premier league, despite the urgings of captain Mithali Raj for the country to capitalise on its World Cup success.
Only Harmanpreet and young opener Smriti Mandhana (Brisbane Heat) have featured in the WBBL so far.
Raj believes a women's IPL would rapidly improve the domestic standard of cricket in India, but a top BCCI board official last week told Sportstar Live a lack of depth would stunt any potential new competition. The concept is unlikely to be revisited for another five years.
"A tournament on the lines of the Indian Premier League may not be immediately practicable," the official said.
"The board welcomes the idea, but there are many hurdles and the biggest involves having a pool of players who would meet international standards.
"You would need at least 60 players, of which 15 could be drafted from overseas. Where are the players? Honestly, how many players do we have like Mithali, Harmanpreet, Smriti, Veda [Krishnamurthy] and Jhulan [Goswami].​"
Meanwhile, the International Cricket Council next week will release its latest cycle of international fixtures in the women's game for 2018 and beyond, with an Australian tour of India before the end of next year on the cards.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England's T20 Super League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sportstar Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mithali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Indies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBBL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smriti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Board of Control</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vedas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Koski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punjab</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surrey Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harmanpreet</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stef Defarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Heat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCCI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smriti Mandhana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jhulan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India's Harmanpreet Kaur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goswami</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristen Beams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mithali Raj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Cricket Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Thunder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stafanie Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunder</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Krishnamurthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
