<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437147639460549</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/spring-races-in-kendricks-sights-after-claiming-go/3209316/</url>
  <title>Spring races in Kendrick's sights after claiming gong</title>
  <content>
RACING: With a fourth straight Sunshine Coast trainers' premiership in hand, Stuart Kendrick is taking aim at some prominent spring feature races.
He finished the 2016/2017 campaign with 47 winners, ahead of Brisbane's Robert Heathcote.
"I think it was a good season again and what was so pleasing about it was that we did very well state-wide (third on the standings) and we almost doubled our winners in Brisbane.
"We're really building up a good team of horses and owners and staff. It's a big team effort."
Kendrick moved to Caloundra from Mackay in 2013 with a 20 horse-stable which has since burgeoned to 55 runners.
"And we've probably increased our quality. We've brought some really nice young horses in and we have some excellent owners," he said.
Rare Occurrence, Banda Spice and Italia Bella enjoyed strong outings during the season.
The latter was runner-up in a Listed 1350m two-year-olds' race in June and a runner-up in a Group 2 1200m two-year-olds' in May, both at Doomben.
She's been nominated for some marquee races, including next month's $1million Group 1 Golden Rose (1400m), for three-year-olds, in Sydney, along with the Group 1 Thousand Guineas (1600m), for three-year-old fillies, in Melbourne in October.
"And if good enough, towards a race like the VRC Derby hopefully," Kendrick said of the famous $1.5million Group 1 race (2500m), for three-year-olds, which is held during the Melbourne carnival.
And then there's Rancho Montoya.
"He won his first start and (then) ran second in town (Brisbane)...and hopefully will go for a trip (south)," he said.
And while he's forged a consistent stable, Kendrick would relish a win on the big stage.
"If we can start being competitive in a couple of those Group 1s that's probably our goal this year."
"That (winning a Group 1 race) is the pinnacle of it (racing)."
"We haven't got the Group 1 winner yet. We've run second with Charnley River last year (the open BMW J.J Atkins over 1600m at Eagle Farm) but haven't got that Group 1 yet so we'll be trying."
Kendrick had runners at Corbould Park on Sunday and it appears he's picked up the new season where he left the last one.
He had winners with Sequalo Spirit and Raja Ampat in a maiden handicap and a class 2 handicap respectively.
Both were guided to the line by local jockey Damian Browne, who recently just missed out on a seventh straight jockeys premiership at the track.
Leads standings going into final day of action.
Local legend needs your help
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
RIVERS were fundamental to the development of the region.
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charnley River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Robert Heathcote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sequalo Spirit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW J.J Atkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doomben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banda Spice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italia Bella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VRC Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Kendrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raja Ampat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1 Golden Rose (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EAGLE Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 2 1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendrick</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rancho Montoya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1 Thousand Guineas (1600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Listed 1350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corbould Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damian Browne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
