<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436451854752517</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/awards/oscars/halle-berry-slams-the-notorious-oscars-kiss-between-her-and-adrien-brody/news-story/05e73235c32615c9f7f19de83da45677</url>
  <title>Truth about most infamous kiss in Oscars history</title>
  <content>
IT WAS at the Academy Awards way back in 2003 when Adrien Brody won the Oscar for best actor for his role in The Pianist.
As is tradition, Halle Berry, who had won the best actress Oscar for Monster's Ball the year before, was on stage to present him with the coveted statue.
But as Berry went to hand the then-29-year-old actor his Oscar, he grabbed her and surprised her with a huge kiss.
"I bet they didn't tell you that was in the gift bag," he said to her, as the whole audience laughed.
Almost 15 years since the notorious moment, Berry has finally addressed what exactly was going through her mind at the time - revealing that, just like the rest of the world, she had no idea what was about to happen.
Sitting down with Andy Cohen for his show Watch What Happens Live, Berry spoke with a caller who asked if the kiss had been planned.
"No, that was not planned. I knew nothing about it," she said, before asking Cohen, "Can I say it for real?"
After he gave her a nod, she unleashed.
"I was like, 'What the f**k is happening right now?' That is what was going through my mind," she said.
Despite Brody's undeniably weird stunt, the actress wasn't too hard on him.
"Because I was there the year before and I know the feeling of being out of your body, I just f**king went with it. But I was like, what the f**k is going on right now," she said.
"How was the kiss?" Cohen asked.
"I don't know, I was too focused on what the f**k was going on, I don't even know," she emphasised.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Can I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrien Brody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halle Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monster's Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watch What Happens Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
