<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651435975113378664</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/conservation-council-wa-boss-piers-verstegen-wants-west-australians-to-eat-more-kangaroo/news-story/3575b8f50c92ee4a0921f868beb102dd</url>
  <title>Get some roo on your fork: conservationist</title>
  <content>
WA'S top conservationist wants West Australians to eat more kangaroo.
Conservation Council WA boss Piers Verstegen said kangaroo was one of the most environmentally friendly types of meat.
"Kangaroo is a very good choice for environmental reasons and for health reasons," the head of WA's umbrella conservation organisation said.
"Certainly there is a move towards vegetarianism, but if people are going to eat meat, then kangaroo is better for the environment than other sources of red meat."
Mr Verstegen said kangaroos were well adapted to our landscape and did not require the extensive land clearing needed for sheep and cattle.
"Kangaroos also have a totally different digestive system. They actually harvest the methane in the digestive process instead of releasing it, unlike cows and sheep which release significant amounts of methane and contribute to greenhouse gas emissions and climate change," he said.
According to gourmet game supplier Macro Meats, kangaroo is one of the leanest types of red meat with less than 2 per cent fat, is high in iron and free of hormones and antibiotics.
Kangaroo is not farmed in WA but a quota system allows licensed shooters to take animals from the wild, supplying a niche meat industry.
About half of WA falls within the State's commercial kangaroo harvest zone, and the latest Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions estimates put the combined population of western grey and red kangaroos at almost 2.5 million.
Fifteen per cent, or almost 380,000 kangaroos, can be harvested this year, according to the department's commercial kangaroo harvest quota submission estimate.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piers Verstegen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservation Council WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Verstegen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macro Meats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Biodiversity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
