<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437568546258953</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/world-athletics-championships-usain-bolt-beaten-in-farewell-race-by-arch-rival-justin-gatlin/news-story/4e2dbeb2a66836bbc02b887151deb40a</url>
  <title>Rival's revenge as Bolt upstaged in farewell</title>
  <content>
IT'S always been the one chink in the armour.
Usain Bolt has been a poor starter all of his career but through freak natural ability he's managed to deal with it.
BOLT HOLE:
That was until his final race.
As the dust settled on his heart-breaking loss to American Justin Gatlin in the 100m world championships final, the eight-time Olympic champion only had himself to blame.
He'd had issues with the blocks in the first round heats and then was slow out again in the semi-final where he was beaten by American Christian Coleman.
The final was the same story. Bolt was horribly slow out, Coleman zoomed to the lead before Gatlin bloused both of them on the line.
"It's just one of those things," Bolt said.
"My start is killing me. Normally it gets better during the rounds but it didn't come together.
"And that is what killed me. I felt it was there.
"It was rough. A little bit stressed. But I came out like at any other championships and did my best.
"I am not fully comfortable in those blocks but you have to work with what you have. I can't complain about that."
Bolt, who turns 31 this month, admitted he knew he was in trouble 30 metres into the final.
"I needed to be in a better place after 30 metres but I just wasn't in that super-shape I needed to be in," he said.
"I gave it my best shot but my body's telling me it's time to go."
The fact it was two-time drug cheat Gatlin who rained on his farewell parade made it even worse although as always Bolt showed his class in defeat.
"He (Gatlin) is a great competitor. You have to be at your best against him. I really appreciate competing against him and he is a good person."
According to Gatlin, the 11-time world champion even commented on the booing which rang out around the stadium when the American was introduced before the final.
"He congratulated me and the first thing he said was I didn't deserve all these boos," Gatlin said.
"I tuned it out (the boos) through the rounds and stayed the course. I did what I had to do.
"The people who love me are here cheering for me and cheering at home."
The 35-year-old, who won the 2004 Olympic gold medal and the 2005 world title, paid tribute to the Jamaican after his victory in 9.92sec.
Coleman clocked 9.94sec for second while Bolt equalled his season's best of 9.95sec for bronze.
"It is Bolt's last race and he's the man so it's not about beating him," Gatlin said.
"I have had many victories and many defeats down the years, he's pushed and inspired me to be the athlete I am today.
"It's surreal really to come across the line first - it's still his night."
Gatlin was suspended for four years in 2006 for taking steroids, the second time in his career he'd been busted for taking drugs.
Many believe he shouldn't be still competing but over the past three years he's been Bolt's closest rival.
At the 2015 world championships in Beijing, he got within .01sec of the Jamaican and was also the silver medallist in Rio last year.
Despite the shock result, Bolt did a victory lap as he savoured the second-last race of his career.
He will return later in the week in the 4x100m relay, seeking his 20th gold medal.
The last time Bolt wasn't the owner of a 100m crown in the past decade was at the 2011 world championship in Daegu where he beat himself, false-starting in the final.
There had been signs all year that he was struggling.
Leading into London he'd only ran three 100m races and only once went under 10 seconds with a workmanlike 9.95sec in Monaco last month his best result.
Bolt had also been forced to visit his doctor in Germany after issues with his troublesome back.
The upset result is a PR disaster for the sport which was already nervous about life without Bolt.
Given the drug scandals which have engulfed track and field of recent times, including the banning of Russia from competition, having a convicted drug cheat claim the sport's biggest crown is as bad as it gets.

2001 - Banned for two years after testing positive for amphetamines. Reduced to one year on appeal

2004 - Wins Olympic 100m gold medal in Athens and silver in 4x100m relay.
2005 - Wins 100m and 200m at world championships in Helsinki.
2006 - Tests positive to steroids. Banned for eight years but has it reduced to four on appeal.
2010 - Returns to track and wins race in Estonia, clocking 10.24sec.
2011 - Makes semi-finals of world championships in Daegu.
2012 - Bronze medal at London Olympics in personal best 9.79sec.

2013 - Defeats Usain Bolt in Rome Diamond League meet by one hundredth of a second.
Wins silver medal behind Bolt at Moscow world championships.
2014 - Lowers personal best to 9.77sec in Diamond League final.

2015 - Sets new PB in Qatar, clocking 9.74sec.
Silver medal behind Bolt at world championships in Beijing.

2016 - Silver medal behind Bolt at Rio Olympics
2017 - Wins world title in London at the age of 35. Bolt finishes third.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Justin Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estonia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wins Olympic 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defeats Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Christian Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daegu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Win 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helsinki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOLT HOLE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
