<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437611495932293</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/big-power-told-to-curb-high-prices-or-face-more-regulation-20170806-gxq7ea</url>
  <title>Deal with high prices or face regulation</title>
  <content>
Federal Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg said it would be up to energy retailers to show how they can help households get a better deal to provide relief from high electricity prices or they could face greater regulation.
As one of Australia's largest energy retailers said it was not shifting customers on to its most expensive tariff, Mr Frydenberg said the Turnbull government was expecting action over high prices from seven retail electricity executives summoned to Parliament House in Canberra on Wednesday.
With focus groups showing energy prices were rated as one of the biggest concerns of households, Mr Turnbull and Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg believe they are on to a winner by going after energy retailers.
, with South Australia (47.13 cents per kilowatt hour), NSW (39.10 cents per kilowatt hour), Queensland (35.69 cents per kilowatt hour) and Victoria (34.60 cents per kilowatt hour) among the worst offenders.

Mr Frydenberg said the issue of power prices was a "barbecue stopper" and the Turnbull government wanted to hear how retailers would help simplify the current system, which is confusing for households and often leaves customers stranded on the highest tariffs.

"When it comes to getting low-income households on to the best available deals, the federal and state governments are one. And while obviously there are regulatory options available, we want in the first instance to hear from the retail companies as to what they are doing to help low-income households," Mr Frydenberg said in an interview with The Australian Financial Review.
Confusing offers

"The current system of discount offers is complex and confusing with more to be done to simplify the process. Thousands of Australian families are stuck on more expensive standing offers when they should be saving hundreds of dollars per year by accessing more attractive market offers."
Some of the options being considered at Wednesday's meeting are a standardised approach to discounts as part of an overhaul of National Electricity Market rules.

EnergyAustralia admitted the current system of tariffs was complex, but it denied it pushed customers on to standing offer tariffs to boost their profitability.
"EnergyAustralia does not move customers on to standing offer tariffs at the end of their benefit period. In fact, we don't offer standing offer tariffs by choice, we're regulated to do so," a spokeswoman said.
"Less than 5 per cent of our mass-market customers nationally are on standing offer tariffs."
EnergyAustralia also said the profit margins of energy retailers had been overstated in recent media reports.

Margins overstated

"The margins we do achieve need to cover the full cost of running a business [eg, bearing the risk of energy market prices, marketing, customer management, wages, leases] - this has not been appropriately considered in the analysis we've seen," the spokeswoman said.
"The reality is energy retailers are operating in really competitive markets; in Victoria and NSW, for example, there are over 20 retailers competing for a customer's business. No one disagrees the industry needs to do more to reduce cost and complexity, but we're disappointed at how industry profitability is represented."
It comes as the British government announced it had launched an independent review into how to reduce long-term energy costs for businesses and households.

Similar to the Finkel Review in Australia, the review by Britain's leading energy expert, Peter Helm from Oxford University, will look at all aspects of the nation's  energy supply chain, from generation to customers.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW (39.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Helm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Electricity Market</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria (34.60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia (47.13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland (35.69</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnergyAustralia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Frydenberg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
