<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437478351945021</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/search-for-missing-us-marines-off-the-australian-coast-now-a-recovery-operation-20170806-gxq953</url>
  <title>Search for missing US Marines now a recovery operation</title>
  <content>
Three US Marines missing after their aircraft crashed into the sea off the Queensland coast are not expected to be found alive.
US officials , switching to recovery efforts and notifying the missing soldiers' next of kin.
"As the sea state permits, recovery efforts will be conducted to further search, assess and survey the area in coordination and with assistance from the Australian Defence Force," the Marine Corps said in a statement.
"Recovery and salvage operations can take several months to complete but can be extended based on several environmental factors.

Australian Defence Force

"The circumstances of the mishap are currently under investigation."

Twenty-three Marines were rescued when an MV-22 Osprey "heli-plane" crashed on Saturday just after 4pm off Shoalwater Bay north of Rockhampton.
No Australians were involved in the mishap.
Recovery operation

Defence Minister Marise Payne, who spoke to her US counterpart James Mattis in the immediate aftermath, said Australian ships, aircraft and personnel were supporting the US-led recovery operation.

Survey ship HMAS Melville had left Cairns to sail to the area while a Navy clearance diving team was travelling to the area. Army aviation assets were also on stand-by.
"These recovery operations are complex in nature and are affected by a range of factors including weather conditions, water depth, debris and water current," Senator Payne said.
"The US military is working with the ADF and other Australian agencies to conduct thorough assessments and planning prior to the formal commencement of any salvage or recovery. The incident is currently being investigated by US authorities and Australia will assist in these investigations where appropriate."
US President Donald Trump was informed about the accident just as he began a 17-day holiday.

Exercise Talisman Sabre

US forces have been in Australia for the last couple of months participating in joint military training operations with Australian forces for Exercise Talisman Sabre.
The Osprey had taken off from USS Bonhomme Richard and was "conducting regularly scheduled operations" when it entered the water, the Marine Corps said.
US TV network NBC reported the Osprey had been trying to land on USS Green Bay, damaging the amphibious transport dock's flight deck.

One of the survivors was treated for a broken leg at Rockhampton Hospital.
The Osprey is designed to take off like a helicopter, with its rotors then able to tilt so it can fly like a plane but the complex design means the aircraft has a patchy safety history and has been involved in multiple fatal crashes.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Corps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exercise Talisman Sabre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Bonhomme Richard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-three Marines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talisman Saber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalwater Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Minister Marise Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Green Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Melville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV-22 Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Mattis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
