<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437392452598517</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/accommodation/putting-groupon-and-scoopon-hotel-deals-to-the-test-in-thailand/news-story/ab8ad0395903b54f4a4792cf52ea01d0</url>
  <title>Putting Groupon and Scoopon hotel deals to the test in Thailand</title>
  <content>
Make the most of your frequent flyer points
0:55

Travel Hacks: How to travel for free and make the most of your frequent flyer points.

Holiday in style using frequent flyer points to upgrade your flight, pay for your hotel and other vacation costs.

These tips will help you maximise your airline miles.

July 28th 2017
9 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Travel - News.com.au/

John Burfitt stayed at Bangkok's Playhaus Hotel after buying a travel deal online. Picture: John Burfitt

John Burfitt

Share

AH, BANGKOK. The Royal capital of Thailand where you don't need a whole lot of cash to live like a King or Queen.
Luxury stays can be had for a bargain price, offering easy comfort to lay your weary head after a day of sightseeing, shopping and soaking up the poolside sunshine.
But there's a way to enjoy all the trappings for even less. Online package deals through the discount sites like Groupon and Scoopon can make your dollars work hard in Asia's most-visited city.
We put three such deals to the test, and the result was a range of hotel experiences - fantastic, far-flung and too-tight-to-mention!

Olive Residence in Bangkok. Picture: John BurfittSource:Supplied
OLIVE RESIDENCE
Deal: Groupon
Price: $145 for three nights (average: $48/night)
"Are we there yet?" was the question running through my mind as the taxi driver drove on - and on - to what seemed the outskirts of the city.
Finally pulling up at the smart six-storey apartment hotel was a nice surprise, and first impressions were exceeded once inside.

The apartment-sized studio room had plenty of space for a bed, desk and a spotlessly clean bathroom. It was all very plush, slick, quiet and comfortable - and obviously still new.

Looks pretty swanky. Picture: John BurfittSource:Supplied
A self-serve laundry within the building, a 7/11 next door and a front desk team that were always helpful just kept adding to the good impressions. The Punnawithi BTS station was just a few minutes' walk.
Dining options were limited, but there are a few good cafes along the street and a superb food hall at the mall only a few stops away at the On Nut BTS station.
For all the great aspects about this apartment, the fact it was a long way out couldn't be ignored. From the central district of Siam Square, the Olive was at least a half-hour drive or 11 stops on the Skytrain. Not a deal breaker, but travel time was a factor.

The room was nice, but it was an effort to get there. Picture: John BurfittSource:Supplied
Verdict: This smart hotel delivered far more than the deal cost, creating so many good impressions. The catch, however, was the long journey there and back.
PLAYHAUS HOTEL
Deal: Groupon / $169 for Three Nights (Average: $56 / night)
The thought of waking up underneath Mary Poppins and her chimneysweep pals or Aladdin and his magic carpet was a special attraction for this boutique hotel in the Thonglor area.
This is a sliver-sized hotel where the movie theme runs throughout its five storeys - from the foyer Backstage Bar, through to the fully styled movie-themed rooms.

The Aladdin-themed room is great for some but isn't for everyone. Picture: John BurfittSource:Supplied
Yet the Aladdin room proved too much - not because of the decorations, but due to the traffic warden out the front, blowing a piercing whistle in front of the nearby vet clinic all day. Even through closed windows, it was deafening.
A move to a room at the back was a revelation - much quieter, but tiny. So small, all the room contained was a bed and a bathroom, with the only space for a bag in the doorway.
Spotlessly clean, but far too tiny.

Playhaus Hotel's decor was definitely very cool. Picture: John BurfittSource:Supplied
The staff were very nice, apologetic and accommodating, and the location was just okay - a 15-minute walk to the BTS Skytrain and the Sukhumvit strip, with a few good cafes along the way, which was necessary as there's no dining service in the hotel.
Verdict: Did I get what I paid for? Yes, indeed. But for all the fun of the theme and the hotel's neat and tidiness, the reality was the room was just too tight.
THE REMBRANDT
Deal: Scoopon / $299 for three nights (Ave: $99/ night)
This incredible-value deal appeared too good to pass up. Four-star luxury in a downtown area, with daily breakfast, welcome drink, 30-minute massage, a rooftop pool, late check out and return airport transfer.

It looks great on the outside. Picture: John BurfittSource:Supplied
Stepping into the foyer brought a sense of relief, as it was all smart style, and then the high-floored room with the views over the Bangkok skyline was elegant comfort. The Rembrandt
delivered close to an ideal luxury hotel stay.
True, the room was not the biggest and some aspects of the decor were straight out of the 1990s, but what made this a winner was a clean, well-maintained hotel with a great pool drenched in sunshine most of the day.

The eye-catching lobby. Picture: John BurfittSource:Supplied
Breakfast was lavish, with hot food made to order. The staff was slick and professional and when an even-later check-out was requested, it was approved with a minimum of fuss. The transfer to the airport made the final impression and proved the icing on the cake.
The Asoke area was superb for shopping, dining and getting around - there's both a BTS and a subway station minutes away. And the nearby Terminal 21 mall had everything from discount to high end shopping, as well as a cinema complex.

The Rembrandt Hotel was a winner. Picture: John BurfittSource:Supplied
Verdict: A fantastic winner! Other luxury hotels might be newer, bigger and more up to
date, but this was amazing value without ever feeling like a cheap holiday.
Would I Do It Again: In a minute! None of these were a disaster, but all came with conditions that had to be factored when paying a bargain price.
Just be sure to follow the rules of checking the fine print and doing your online homework through sites like TripAdvisor first.
There are new deals all the time, and by snapping up a bargain, you have more to spend on shopping!
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aladdin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Groupon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Burfitt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rembrandt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sukhumvit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nut BTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangkok's Playhaus Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Groupon / $169</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Three Nights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John BurfittSource</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rembrandt Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siam Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Poppins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangkok</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BTS Skytrain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olive Residence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punnawithi BTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terminal 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TripAdvisor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scoopon / $299</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thonglor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scoopon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aladdin-themed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asoke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SkyTrain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PLAYHAUS HOTEL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Backstage Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
