<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437186294166517</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/leadership/macquarie-university-medical-students-can-expect-an-eyeopening-experience-in-an-indian-hospital-20170803-gxoloj</url>
  <title>Macquarie University medical students can expect an eye-opening experience in an Indian hospital</title>
  <content>
When Macquarie University's first cohort of medical students go to the Indian city of Hyderabad to do clinical training in a local hospital they will be in a very different environment to their peers in Australia.
The clinical training, to take place in the third year of the four-year, graduate-entry medical degree being offered by Macquarie, will see students spending half the year at a 550-bed hospital in the Indian city which is run by the country's largest private health company, Apollo Hospitals.
Although it is a private institution, the Hyderabad Apollo hospital caters to a huge range of the local community, ranging from wealthy people who can afford to pay for multi-room suites during their stay in the hospital, to the far less wealthy who go into debt to be treated there, rather than in India's challenged public hospital system.
The hospital doesn't have the appearance of slick, shiny institution. Buildings have been added to over the years, parts of it look run-down, and people crowd in the corridors waiting for appointments at the hospital's many specialist clinics.

Not all of the complex is air-conditioned, even in Hyderabad's 40-degree summer heat.

Matches Western standards

But the quality of the care, and the advanced level of equipment in the Apollo hospital, matches Western standards.
It successfully carries out complex surgeries, including advanced transplants, which would be regarded as cutting edge anywhere in the world, says Stephen Deane, Macquarie's associate dean, clinical partnerships, who has spent much of his time in India this year setting up the arrangements with Apollo for the medical student training.
Professor Deane, a former head of surgery at Sydney's Liverpool Hospital and Newcastle's John Hunter Hospital, is impressed by the professionalism and dedication of the Apollo Hospital's staff as well as its surgical outcomes.

But the first 60-strong cohort of Macquarie medical students, who will start their course next year and be doing their clinical year in 2020, will still find it very different to Australia.
They will be living away from the hospital in an apartment block in the local community and navigating everyday life in a large Indian city. They will be exposed to medical cases rarely seen in Australia.
And they will be constantly reminded of the differences between the way medicine is practised in the West and the way it is done, just as successfully, in very different ways in another culture where funding and resources are not as plentiful.
Only half the 60 students in the year will be in Hyderabad at one time. During the 20-week placement, as the 30 students cycle through different learning areas, they will be in regular contact with their peers in Sydney, and will compare notes on the way treatment is given in the two countries.

Rich experience

It is designed to be a rich and reflective learning experience, and is the first time any medical course in Australia will have an extended period of study abroad.
Patrick McNeil, Macquarie's medical and health sciences executive dean, says that, in planning the overseas experience, "we chose a health care system which is quite different to Australia but still advanced enough to be a suitable location for clinical learning".
One thing that students will notice is that good quality care can be given without all the expensive extras which are considered normal in developed countries.

In Apollo Hyderabad's cheapest $US20 ($25) a day ward bed, the relatively crowded conditions, including sleeping space for relatives, would not be considered acceptable in Australia. But the care quality is high and patients have access to the same staff and facilities available to patients in the high-cost beds.
Heri Prasad, who manages Apollo's operations in Hyderabad, said the hospital's cheaper beds are subsidised by the expensive beds.
"A patient who is staying in the general ward pays significantly lower and a patient staying in a luxury ward pays significantly higher," he said.
The luxury ward patients include wealthy people from the Middle East and Africa who come for treatment to Apollo hospitals in India because of their good reputation.

Dr Prasad said the main Hyderabad hospital, where Macquarie's students will be based, is the centre of a hub-and-spoke model in the local district with satellite hospitals and clinics which, altogether, see 500,000-700,000 patients a year and do about 10,000 surgical procedures annually.
This includes tele-medicine, where specialists at the main hospital can direct patient care by video at clinics in outlying districts.
The Hyderabad hospitals and clinics are only a small part of Apollo, which was founded in 1983 by cardiologist Prathap Reddy, who returned to India from the United States infused with a mission to improve healthcare in his own country.
Although now a public company with nearly $US1 billion annual revenue, and with major hospitals like Hyderabad's in 25 Indian cities, Apollo Hospitals is still family run with Dr Reddy as chairman and his four daughters holding key management positions.
Driving force

Sangita Reddy, a joint managing director of Apollo, said one of the company's driving forces was a determination to improve health for the mass of people and make care available at lower cost.
She said that because India lacked an effective system of community healthcare, patients with serious diseases came to hospital too late, which meant the cost of treatment was high with poor outcomes.
Ms Reddy said 80 per cent of cardiac patients came with multiple blocks in their arteries and 60 per cent of cancer patients came with stage 3 and 4 cancers.

"We want to see patients when they have a single block. We can do an angioplasty in half an hour and send them home the next day," she said.
"We want to see first-stage cancers so we can do a simple treatment and send them home again."
The company is now building an app, designed for mass use, to give health advice and help people get early treatment.
But she knows that cost has always been a problem.
"The second largest reason for rural indebtedness in India was health. People sold their land, they pawned their wives' jewellery," she said.
Ms Reddy said the experience for Australia medical students, of seeing at first hand how a health system worked in a country like India, would be invaluable.
"When you see people who are so deprived, and there are a large number [of such people] in our country, you begin to see how precious life is," she said.
"By that appreciation I think you become a better clinician or a better medical worker."

Tim Dodd travelled to Hyderabad courtesy of Macquarie University.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US20 ($25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apollo Hyderabad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Reddy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Prasad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sangita Reddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Deane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyderabad</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick McNeil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Deane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heri Prasad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apollo Hospital</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyderabad Apollo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Reddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Liverpool Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prathap Reddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Dodd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle's John Hunter Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apollo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
