<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651436323005732784</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/search-for-three-us-marines-called-off/news-story/cf90aa0bff878e840ce51d57e111081e</url>
  <title>Search for three US marines called off</title>
  <content>
Authorities have called off the search for three US marines less than 24 hours after their aircraft crashed off Queensland's coast.
The US Navy and Marine Corp - with help from the Australian Defence Force - are now focusing their efforts on salvage and recovery, which they warn could take several months.
The three missing marines' next-of-kin have been notified.
"The transition comes after teams led continuous sustained search efforts supported by aircraft and ships," the US Marine Corp said in a statement.
"The circumstances of the mishap are currently under investigation, and there is no additional information available at this time."
The three were among 26 personnel onboard, all of whom have otherwise have been accounted for and are safe.
The MV-22 Osprey that crashed into the sea around 4pm on Saturday off Shoalwater Bay, where the biennial Talisman Sabre joint US and Australian military training exercise is underway.
It had taken off from the USS Bonhomme Richard, an amphibious assault ship, and was on regularly scheduled operations when it hit the water in what the US military described as a "mishap".
Small boats and aircraft from the Bonhomme Richard were immediately deployed into a search before it was called off.
The Queensland Ambulance Service says it transported one of the marines involved to Rockhampton Hospital with a fractured leg but it is not known how many others onboard were injured.
US President Donald Trump, who has just begun a 17-day "working vacation", at his New Jersey golf club, had been briefed on the incident by his new chief of staff John Kelly, a White House official told reporters.
Minister for Defence Marise Payne confirmed in a statement late on Saturday night that no Australian Defence Force personnel were on board the aircraft.
"Our thoughts are with the crew and families affected," she said.
Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk offered her government's support.
"On behalf of all Queenslanders, our prayers are with those US military personnel involved in the incident," she said in a statement.
The incident is the 10th known crash involving an Osprey, a tilt rotor aircraft that takes off and lands like a helicopter but flies like an aeroplane, since 1991, and the sixth since it officially came into service in 2007.
It is also potentially the worst military accident in Australia since the 1996 Black Hawk tragedy that killed 18 servicemen near Townsville.
The US Marine Corp said recovery efforts will be conducted to further search, assess and survey the area - as sea conditions permit - in co-ordination and with assistance from the Australian Defence Force.
"Recovery and salvage operations can take several months to complete, but can be extended based on several environmental factors," it said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Bonhomme Richard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marine Corp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talisman Saber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalwater Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Marise Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV-22 Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonhomme Richard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
