<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437615790899625</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/more-claims-of-excess-water-extraction-by-nsw-irrigators-surface-20170805-gxq2jh.html</url>
  <title>More claims of excess water extraction by NSW irrigators surface</title>
  <content>
More evidence has emerged of changes to water licences giving a handful of irrigators in north-western NSW the ability to extract huge volumes of river water even during dry periods.
Documents obtained under freedom of information and analysis of public records by the Environmental Defenders Office NSW, seen by Fairfax Media, show licences for Barwon-Darling river water extraction were sub-divided apparently in breach of the NSW Water Management Act 2000.
As part of the sub-division, the licence holder was permitted to install 11 pumps with diameters of 600-660 millimetres - as much as eight times the previous size of the nine 80-150 mm pumps used - capable of extracting significantly more water. 

Up Next
Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

01:28

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

4 Corners: Pumped

Who is benefitting from the billions spent on the Murray-Darling?

The act does not allow additional water to be taken after subdivisions.
"These licences are an integral part of water management in the Barwon-Darling, and the basin as a whole," said James Trezise, acting campaign manager of the Australian Conservation Foundation, which commissioned the EDO.

"The Australian public need to understand how these water licences were granted despite being in apparent contravention of the water sharing plan and the water management act."
In a separate matter, another irrigator on the Barwon-Darling was found to have pumped in 2014-15 five times more so-called A Class water - the most-valued class of water that can be pumped during periods of low river flows - than the licence allowed, the EDO said.

The following year was a particularly dry one, with the same irrigator permitted to extract B Class medium-flow water only on the last day, June 30. Yet up to 29 June, 2016, the farmer had already extracted 3.147 billion litres, according to WaterNSW data obtained by the EDO under FOI laws.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

An ABC report last month made claims of large-scale water theft, and called into question the NSW government's commitment to implementing the $13 billion Murray Darling Basin Plan aimed at restoring the rivers' health.Photo: Louie Douvis
The NSW government has since shunted aside one senior water bureaucrat, Gavin Hanlon, and launched an investigation, while a slew of Labor, Greens and other politicians are demanding a judicial inquiry.
A spokeswoman for NSW Water Minister Niall Blair declined to comment on the EDO's latest claims. Photo: Paul Jones
"Specific allegations of maladministration of water allocations" should be sent to Ken Matthews, the former head of the National Water Commission, who is now leading the independent review, she said.
For its part, Webster has dismissed claims the larger pumps affected the amount of water it takes. "Webster can extract the volume of water it is entitled to under strict flow conditions. It has nothing to do with the size of the pumps," it said on its website.
'Conspiracy'

Other issues to have surfaced include a Guardian report Niall Blair, the NSW water minister  - such as canals and earth walls - retrospectively. That prompted Ian Hunter, South Australia's water minister, to ask on Saturday: "How can Australians be confident there hasn't been a complete conspiracy on water use from the Darling River system?"
Tensions over water could also worsen between the states after a relatively dry spell. June was the basin's fourth-driest on record, while rainfall in July was less than half the average. (See bureau chart below for June 1-July 26 rainfall, with the basin outlined in black.)

The ACF has asked the NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption to examine the water licences.
The EDO, meanwhile, has had to go to the NSW Civil and Administrative Tribunal in its battle for the release of other documents from the regulator, WaterNSW.
"The public has a right to know how the NSW government is regulating and enforcing the use of one of our most vital natural resources, and that transparency is key to public confidence in the regulatory system governing water access and use in the Barwon-Darling Basin," the EDO said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Water Management Act 2000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Trezise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Water Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Niall Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Water Minister Niall Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-class</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environmental Defenders Office NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Conservation Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 1-July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barwon-Darling</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barwon Darling Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WaterNSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
