<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437568546258928</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/lifestyle/news-and-views/sales-of-the-century-myer-to-hold-exhibition-of-100-iconic-products-20170804-gxpetl.html</url>
  <title>Myer is taking back Carmel's television ... after 61 years</title>
  <content>
Television has always been a big part of Carmel Young's life. In her later years, it has also been her companion.
In her room at a Reservoir nursing home, Mrs Young, who turned 100 last month, watches her favourite programs, including cooking shows, Studio 10 and her beloved Dr Phil, on a modern flat-screen TV.Photo: Scott McNaughton
But her first set, a 1956 black-and-white AWA set, would still work perfectly if not for the analog signal being switched off .
"I love television, it doesn't matter what. Wimbledon - I love tennis, swimming, I can't swim but I love to watch it. I won't watch anything scary or I'd go to bed and not sleep," she said.
Mrs Young remembers watching the Melbourne Olympics on her neighbour's television, before she and her husband, Charlie, bought their own.
"People got [their own television] all of a sudden. You didn't go to anyone's place [to watch] anymore," she said.

Tragically, it was through television that Mrs Young learned Charlie was killed in an industrial accident on March 22, 1969.
Mr Young, a driver for CIG, had been aboard a gas tanker that was loading a ship at Port Welshpool, in Gippsland, when it exploded, killing himself and two others and injuring 23 men. The story was front-page news in The Age on March 24.Photo: Fairfax Archives
"I was waiting for him to come home [from work]," she said, holding back tears. "I heard it on the television ... I thought, 'Oh god, he's gone.' When the police came I already knew."
Mrs Young's old television will feature in an exhibition opening this week at Myer of 100 iconic products from the 20th century.
Although she replaced the black-and-white set with a colour television in the 1980s, her great-nephew, Anthony O'Toole, keeps the vintage set at his house in Doncaster East.
When he read about Myer's quest to track down 30 "missing" items from the 100, he immediately nominated his great-aunt and her television.
"It's in mint condition, it still works. Other than the fact they turned off the analog signal, you can still watch a picture on it," he said.
Other items on the list include the original 1940s Test Match board game, a 1900s Coolgardie Safe and a 1970s Oroton bag.
Historian Stella Barber, who has written numerous books on the history of Myer and the Myer family, helped select the 100 products.
"Some of them are rites of passage, the Glomesh bag, the platform shoes, the Test Match board game. In the days prior to television, games were so important," she said.
Ms Barber said Myer was a pioneer in allowing customers to touch samples and not keep everything behind glass, which was the norm at the time.
"We take it for granted now but it was revolutionary at the time. It made the interaction between customer and product so much more intimate," she said.
The  exhibition is at Myer Melbourne, Bourke Street Mall, from August 8-September 15.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glomesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oroton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 24.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street Mall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony O'Toole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Young</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gippsland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wimbledon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Welshpool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmel Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Test-match</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myer Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Archives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott McNaughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Barber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Phil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolgardie Safe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Studio 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8-September 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doncaster East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stella Barber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
