<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437736049985035</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/marriage/when-you-stay-because-you-cant-afford-to-go/news-story/4d1fba90a49d61cdd8aa4c8ada9543df</url>
  <title>When you stay because you can't afford to go</title>
  <content>
Domestic Abuse Call Re Enacted in Confronting Video
2:00

A domestic violence counselling service has released a confronting video re-enacting a typical call its counsellors receive every day, featuring a distressed woman experiencing abuse. The Full Stop Foundation, an initiative of the federally funded Rape and Domestic Violence Services Australia, begun a campaign to challenge the perception that domestic violence was physical or that it was indeed the worst form. The foundation's CEO Karen Willis told Mumbrella that 20 per cent of domestic violence is physical, but the rest manifested itself through emotional, mental, and financial abuse. This video shows a diverse set of people from different ages, sexes, and ethnicities listening to a re-enacted phone call of a woman calling into the counselling service. They're shown asking for the recording to stop when it becomes too distressing. The RDVSA is facing possible closure in July. Credit: Full Stop Foundation via Storyful

May 8th 2017
3 months ago
/video/video.news.com.au/News/

Finances often make divorce difficult.

Danielle Colley

Share

THE dissolution of a marriage bears legacies of sorrow and pain from the end of dreams and lives shared. On a more practical note, it also spells the dissolution of your finances. A fact which can be so daunting, it may prevent you from following your true heart.
When my own marriage was crumbling like a cake in a hurricane I had been a stay-at-home mum for nearly five years. I had no money to call my own, and had no idea of how I would support myself if I could not get this runaway train back on the tracks.
Friends suggested I stick it out until the children were older and I could stand on my financial feet. It seemed like the only solution.
It did not seem the fairest solution to my husband or my own integrity but I feared I would no longer be able to stay living where I was, continue to stay home with my babies, or even put food on the table that I would possibly no longer own.
Obviously, fearing financial upheaval is not exclusive to women, with splitting assets, and child support often weighing heavily on a man's bank account, or in instances where he was not the primary earner he may also be left quite vulnerable.

People stay in bad relationships for a myriad of reasons. But finances is a big one.Source:istock
This vulnerability can make you feel cornered, as Suzanne* tells of the demise of her union.
"I felt trapped. I felt powerless, like he could be as awful as he wanted and I couldn't do a thing about it. I hate the feeling of being dependent on anybody but when the person you're dependent on is drifting away from you and things are getting hostile, it feels vulnerable and just awful," Suzanne says.
Deciding to end a marriage is heartbreaking enough, but the related fiscal dread that may accompany the decision can be equally rending. It doesn't make you shallow; it's a matter of practicality.
"My biggest fear was - and still is - that something will happen and I won't be able to pay my rent. That I'll put my family in a situation where we have nowhere to live and nothing to eat. I'm lucky because I know if it came to that I could move in with my mother, but at the age of 43 and with three kids, of course I'd rather not do that," tells Suzanne.

Not everyone has family willing or able to help them, so returning to the relationship may be tempting as Melinda* discovered after leaving her physically abusive partner.
"One of my friends left her husband but couldn't manage financially so went back to him. One of my best friends suggested I go to counselling to get back together with my ex-husband, citing financial security as one of the reasons. These things had me thinking at the time that a lot of women's choices are made out of fear," suggests Melinda.
The unknown is a scary, multi-headed beast so arming yourself with information may help to alleviate some of this fear, suggests relationship therapist with Clinton Power and Associates, Clinton Power.
"If you decide you need to leave, but you're scared about the consequences (such has your partner hiding assets, or engaging very aggressive lawyers to bury you in litigation or custody disputes), the best advice is to get good advice from a lawyer as to your legal rights and how to handle the situation if things become acrimonious. Do this before any mention of wanting to end the relationship. At least this can put your mind at ease when you know your rights and how to best protect yourself and your children," say Power.
"Divorce is incredibly expensive and costs everyone involved. One in three marriages are likely to end in divorce, with research indicating that 97,000 Australians are still divorcing each year. Just the practicality of having to split up, buy or rent a second house, take on all the bills yourself and start to pay child support can create enormous financial stress for families."
Dividing assets and putting an action plan in place can be difficult and takes time so perhaps you may not need to do it immediately.
"One scenario I've come across in my practice is when a couple emotionally separates, but decide to continue to live together in the same house to raise their children and keep their expenses at a minimum. This avoids having to start a second household and sharing custody of the children.
"This option is not for everyone, but if the separation is amicable and the couple has good communication skills and a commitment to be great co-parents, this can work for a period of time," says Power.
One may ask if, in this situation, it's braver to stay or braver to go? Obviously, there is no correct answer. True bravery lies in being true to yourself and that always requires courage.
*Names have been changed
If you need support for family violence contact on 1800 737 732.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melinda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzanne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abuse Call Re Enacted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confronting Video</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RDVSA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Karen Willis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domestic Violence Services Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinton Power</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Full Stop Foundation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumbrella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danielle Colley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
