<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437620085866953</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-06/five-talking-points-richmond-v-hawthorn</url>
  <title>Five talking points: Richmond v Hawthorn</title>
  <content>
Toby Nankervis has been important in Jack Riewoldt's absence

1. Small forward line wins big
The Tigers utilised a vast rotation in attack without spearhead Jack Riewoldt for the second straight week, and made Hawthorn regularly look silly in the meantime. They had 11 marks inside 50 by half-time and 20 by the final siren - after 17 in total last week - spread across 14 players, with Josh Caddy (four), Corey Ellis, Toby Nankervis and Anthony Miles (two each) the multiples. Caddy, who was outstanding, Dustin Martin and even Trent Cotchin had stints as the deepest forward and each kicked goals while playing that role. Richmond's famed pressure across the ground and ability to run hard in numbers helped its forwards' cause, leaving the Hawks often unsuccessfully scrambling to cover their opponents. There are still sceptics on whether the reliance on small forwards around Riewoldt will stand up in the finals, but there is little reason to suggest not on the evidence so far.

Forward pressure pays off for the Tigers.

2. Rough game in front of goal for Jarryd
The champion Hawthorn captain was feted all week for his incredible career to date - four flags, two All Australian nods and a Coleman Medal in 2013 - but his kicking was off target in game 250. Roughead had three shots at goal in the opening half to set the tone and none went close for a total of two behinds and a gettable set-shot out on the full. He kicked another out on the full from a similar spot in the last quarter, but he did finish wonderfully from 50m in the third term and kicked a cheapie from the goalsquare in the final minute.

3. Tiger defence strangles another team
Alex Rance remains the undisputed best defender in the game, but David Astbury's ability to regularly man the opposition's No.1 key forward and Dylan Grimes' versatility are incredibly valuable. They also have good ball-users down there in Bachar Houli, Nick Vlastuin and Brandon Ellis. The result is the second-stingiest defense in the competition, keeping rivals to 78 points or fewer in 12 matches. As opposed to the forward corps, the backline has largely been a stable, consistent force without much change.

4. Dusty in vote-winning range again
Only Patrick Dangerfield has rivalled Dustin Martin for consistent excellence this season and the Brownlow Medal favourite might add to his vote tally with his effort against the Hawks. Martin racked up more than 30 disposals for the 12th time in 2017 and laced them with at least two goals for the fifth occasion in those performances. It was far from the tattooed Tiger's most dominant display of the year, but the numbers don't lie and he will be in the umpires' thinking, along with four-goal star Josh Caddy, big ball-winner Dion Prestia and the ever-improving Kane Lambert.

You can't leave Dusty by himself!

5. Langford a liability up forward?
Hawks coach Alastair Clarkson brilliantly shuffled his magnets to find a successful combination after a 1-5 start, but he may have robbed his forward line a bit too much. There were occasions on Sunday where unheralded Will Langford, Ryan Schoenmakers and Taylor Duryea were Hawthorn's deepest forwards. The brown and gold not only didn't get their hands on the ball inside 50 anywhere near as much as Richmond, but they were wasteful when they did. Langford's horrendous strike rate at goal this year - six goals from 19 scoring shots - did not take a further hit on the scoreboard, but his mental demons were on show. He courageously hauled in a mark amid a pack of Tigers in the third quarter before tugging his 45m set shot, from directly in front, out on the full.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Lambert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandon Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dion Prestia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Schoenmakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Rance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Vlastuin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Langford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Langford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Nankervis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachar Houli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Grimes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Duryea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Caddy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRENT COTCHIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alastair Clarkson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Astbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
