<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437783294625760</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/john-i-dent-cup-minor-semifinal-wests-v-queanbeyan-20170806-gxq8gt.html</url>
  <title>Wests end Queanbeyan's season with win in John I Dent Cup minor semi-final</title>
  <content>
It took them four attempts this season but Wests have beaten Queanbeyan in the only one that mattered with a 24-8 victory in the John I Dent Cup minor semi-final at Viking Park on Sunday.
Wests ended the Whites' season and now face Tuggeranong in the preliminary final next Saturday for a spot in the decider against the unbeaten Royals.Photo: Jamila Toderas
Flyhalf Te Campbell was instrumental for Wests in a man-of-the-match performance and crossed the line just three minutes into the contest after slicing through the Whites' defence.
Nick Jooste was released by the ACT Brumbies last week but it didn't affect the Australian under-20 playmaker who kept a cool head to slot 14 points off the tee.
Photo gallery
Tempers flared when Jooste was spear-tackled by Carl Elliott in the 66th-minute and Queanbeyan hooker was sent to the bin for his efforts in a move that affectively ended the contest.
Wests coach Craig Robberds said it wasn't always pretty but he was relieved to finally beat Queanbeyan and keep thier season alive.

"We've gone close a couple of times this season and I'm just really happy to get it done. It was pretty ugly to be honest, like our last couple of games against them, but we got through," Robberds said.
"We've been really focusing over the last month on taking it to another level and the boys took it to another level today which really showed at the breakdown."
Tuggeranong thrashed Wests at Viking Park in round eight but Robberds' men prevailed 35-31 when the sides met three weeks ago.
"Tuggeranong played very well against Royals in the first final so it'll be tough, but we'll be ready and we get a couple back next week, it'll be a good one," Robberds said.
Whites coach Adam Fahey said his men weren't hungry enough for the win and left their worst for last.
"We were out-enthused, Wests came to play, they wanted it a little bit more than us today and unfortunately we left our worst performance for the last game of the season," Fahey said.
"But credit to Wests, they were up for it and that's what finals footy is about. You've got to get up for finals because there's no tomorrow, they live to fight another day and we don't."
"We set very high standards and to not execute and play the way we wanted to play is what I'm most frustrated with rather than beating them three times this season and losing today."
Fahey said there were still plenty of positives from the season and that his players will now get behind the club's sides still in finals.
"We've come a long way this season in terms of blooding young players, we've still got a very young club and we're still very proud of the fact we had five grades in the finals," Fahey said.
"If you look at that I think we're going quite well, we've got some quality young kids coming through and we'll now focus on getting our other grades over the line."
AT A GLANCE:
Wests 24 (Tom Campbell, TP Luteru tries, Nick Jooste 4 pens 1 con) beat Queanbeyan 8 (Ryan Jones try, Danny Matthews pen)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John I Dent Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RYAN JONES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jooste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carl Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TP Luteru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Brumbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Te Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Viking Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Robberds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royals.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Jooste 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robberds</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Jooste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
