<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437697395279000</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-match-report/richmond-v-hawthorn-tigers-show-12-months-is-a-long-time-in-football-by-shutting-out-hawks-20170806-gxqdh9.html</url>
  <title>Richmond v Hawthorn: Tigers show 12 months is a long time in football by shutting out Hawks</title>
  <content>
RICHMOND 
5.4  6.8  9.10 13.15 (93)
HAWTHORN 
1.3  2.5   4.8   9.10  (64)
 
GOALS - Richmond: Caddy 4, Ellis 2, Martin 2, Prestia, Rioli, Soldo, Cotchin, Nankervis.
Hawthorn:  Roughead 2, Breust 2, Schoenmakers 2, Miles 2, Mitchell.
BEST - Richmond: Caddy, Prestia, Martin, Lambert, Astbury, Rioli, C Ellis, Rance
Hawthorn: Mitchell, Sicily, Breust, Roughead, Burton
UMPIRES: Schmitt,  Findlay,  Fisher.
CROWD: 58,342 at MCG.
 
A little over a year ago, 13th-placed Richmond conceded nine final-quarter goals in a 70-point loss to Hawthorn at the MCG. The Hawks - having celebrated veteran Sam Mitchell's 300th game in style - had their eyes on a record-equalling fourth straight premiership, and the Tigers were hurtling towards crisis, with coach Damien Hardwick condemning some of his side's defensive efforts late in the game as 'nothing short of shameful'.Photo: AAP/Julian Smith
Fast forward 12 months. The Tigers again played the Hawks in a Sunday afternoon game at the MCG, but Mitchell, soon to be a former West Coast player, was across town at Etihad Stadium in action for the Eagles, while Hardwick, having survived a football department review at Punt Road, led his Tigers - now a defensive juggernaut and bona fide premiership contender - to a comfortable victory over a Hawks' side whose improbable charge to the finals is surely now done.
Things could barely be rosier at Richmond, who with this win are the highest-placed Victorian club in the AFL. A home qualifying final is a distinct possibility after the Hawks - in inspirational captain Jarryd Roughead's 250th game - were repeatedly thwarted by Richmond's backline pillars, of course including superstar Alex Rance, but on this day led by David Astbury.Photo: AAP/Julian Smith
Having already been favouring the use of small forwards, Richmond again went in without Jack Riewoldt, who lost his race against time to make it back from a freak eye injury. That might have spelt trouble against a Hawthorn side that hadn't conceded a triple-figure score for more than three months, but these Tigers continue to challenge conventional wisdom about how to win football matches. Again it was Richmond's now customary fanatical pressure that underpinned their game.
In the absence of the suspended Luke Hodge, Hawthorn's inexperienced defence struggled to cope. With his father's cousin Cyril watching on from the stands rather than down the other end, Daniel Rioli buzzed about, while playing just his fifth senior game this season, Corey Ellis once more displayed his abundant class, slotting a pair of first term majors to be the only multiple goalkicker on the ground at half-time. Richmond's lead was 25 at quarter-time, and while the Hawks had their moments in the second term, the Tigers kept the ball down their end for extended periods too, working their way to a 27-point half-time break following the first goal of Ivan Soldo's AFL career.Photo: AAP/Julian Smith
The Hawks had an opportunity to make the perfect start to the second half when Shaun Burgoyne streamed from the middle and found Ryan Schoenmakers, but the forward missed a regulation chance. The Hawks were soon made to pay as Dustin Martin got on the end of consecutive Tiger chains to all but shut the gate on Hawthorn within 10 minutes of the resumption.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Martin was again a strong contributor, but perhaps pleasingly for Richmond, neither he nor captain Trent Cotchin were their side's best on the day. That mantle was instead a flip of the coin between Josh Caddy and Dion Prestia. Both recruited last October, the former Gold Coast teammates have arguably been underwhelming in their first season at the Tigers, but if they can play like they did on Sunday in September then their first years in yellow and black will have been unqualified successes. Caddy spent much of the day forward and finished as the leading goalkicker on the ground while still amassing 28 disposals, while Prestia - running with Hawks star Tom Mitchell - found a heap of the ball himself. Kane Lambert also had a terrific day, as Hawthorn, one of the form teams of the competition, were made to look second-rate.
The Hawks had entered the match as one of the form teams of the competition, and a win would have remarkably left them just half a game out of the eight. Now the September action looks out of reach. At least for a year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Lambert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prestia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Astbury.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dion Prestia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead's 250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell's 300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schoenmakers 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Schoenmakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Rance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caddy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Burgoyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sicily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nankervis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mile 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caddy 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Findlay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breust 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Rioli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellis 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schmitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Caddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Julian Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rioli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punt Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyril</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Soldo's AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRENT COTCHIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
