<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437349502925260</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/just-like-that-my-generation-is-out-of-date-20170804-gxp9ec.html</url>
  <title>Just like that, my generation is out of date</title>
  <content>
Well, my mind's blown. Firstly, because there's a new generation - Generation Z - some of whom are already 20 years old (!) and secondly, judging by the research about them, they are completely different from me and my fellow Gen Ys.
A quick recap for those who don't know about the gens: Gen Z (the newbies) were born from 1995. Gen Y, aka Millennials, were born from the late '70s to the early '90s. Gen X were 1965-1976, and Baby Boomers were mid 1940s-mid 1960s.Photo: Photographer Name + 3digit ID
People are starting to take notice of Gen Z - partly because they are starting to spend money. Gen Zs will make up nearly 40 per cent  of consumers by 2020. A quick google search of Gen Z brings up heaps of stuff telling us that Gen Z is different and that we must all alter our business models to make the most of them.
What interests me most (being the self-absorbed Gen Y that I am) is how Gen Y and Gen Z are different.
We know the stereotypes ascribed to Gen Y. We are entitled, unjustifiably confident, and lazy, but we are also unwaveringly idealistic. We want to change the world, and believe we can.
Yesterday I read an article by a generational expert. When asked to describe Gen Z in one word, he said "realistic". Realistic. As in the opposite of idealistic.

One illustration of the magnitude of this difference is jobs. My main criteria for finding a job were passion and contributing to society. My friends accept the "common wisdom" that it isn't smart to stay in a job for more than two-three, and if you don't love it, you should leave it. This is Gen Y typical.
Fascinatingly, Gen Z aren't about the passion when looking for a job - they want stability and money. In one Australian survey, more than 70 per cent of Gen Zs said they would choose a secure job without a high level of passion over a job with lots of passion that lacks security. In an American survey, more than 60 per cent said they'd stay in a company for more than 10 years!

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

This is crazily different from Gen Y. But how? Most of the analysis on Gen Z explains their characteristics as being borne out of the unique time they've existed in. They've lived in a time of terrorism - they don't remember 9/11 and don't know what it was like before (in contrast, some say that 9/11 was the single most significant event in Gen Ys' lifetimes.) Gen Z saw their loved ones losing jobs and money in the GFC. They've seen older siblings unable to find jobs when they graduate, and unable to afford houses.
Not only that, but Gen Z's parents (Gen X) are very different from Gen Y's (the Boomers). I grew up with my Boomer parents telling me I could be and do anything. To this day, my dad still says things like, "When you're the next prime minister ..."
Gen X parents are way less likely to heap praise on their kids. My Gen X friend recently told her Gen Z kid that she had "seen better" when her kid showed her some homework. That's it. No sugar coating. Instead of this approach of parenting giving Gen Zs low self-esteem (which is what I would assume) research says it has helped Gen Z be more mature and have more grit.
So are they really something new? I didn't even know about Gen Z until the other night, when my friend who works at a successful, on-trend, online company told me that they're changing their whole marketing strategy to fit Gen Z.
And it sounds like they will need to.
From what I can tell, Gen Z are different. They are more into learning - one survey found that more than 70 per cent of Gen Zs had used online videos to learn something new in the past week. They are more likely to identify as gender fluid. They are racially diverse - one study found that 40 per cent of Gen Zs will be made up of racial minorities in the US in a few years. They are mature and self-assured without being self-entitled.
Sounds like I have a bit to learn from my slightly younger gen. I can't wait until they are old enough to be my mates.
Claire Thurstans is a Fairfax Media columnist.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Z</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Y</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen X</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baby Boomers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Thurstans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Zs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Ys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Y. But</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Y. We</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Generation Z</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
