<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437306553251873</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/australia-is-maturing-on-battery-storage-says-aes-20170806-gxq7dr</url>
  <title>SA battery project will open Australian market</title>
  <content>
Global energy giant AES Corporation said scepticism over large-scale battery storage projects in Australia would be overcome once state governments showed they could boost the reliability of the grid.
Battery storage in Australia is in its infancy compared to other markets, but AES Energy storage vice-president Praveen Kathpal said the rollout of the South Australian government's 100-megawatt battery storage project be a game-changer for Australia.
While AES was unsuccessful in its bid for the SA project - losing to Tesla and its enigmatic chief executive Elon Musk - Mr Kathpal said the first large-scale battery storage project would herald a new maturity for Australia's storage market.
to tackle the world's $60 billion energy storage market.

P2 Photography

They view Australia as a significant growth market and are already in discussions with several state governments about large-scale battery projects to help boost the reliability of the grid.

The Palaszczuk government in Queensland is planning to hold a reverse auction for 100 megawatts in battery storage - as part of its push to 50 per cent renewables by 2030 - while the Andrews government in Victoria is also looking at 100 megawatts of storage.
Scepticism will be overcome

Mr Kathpal said initial scepticism about the benefits of large-scale battery storage in Australia would be overcome once they became operational.
"That is more a market acceptance issue. There is a business proposition for storage everywhere. We started in Chile, if you do battery storage there you can do it anywhere," Mr Kathpal said in an interview with The Australian Financial Review in San Francisco.

"In Australia the market activity is happening which is the best form of learning. It's natural to have a more tentative approach to adopting new technology. The good thing about South Australia is it's the beginning. The first 100 megawatts will be the first of many. We think Australia is going to be one of the more significant markets for us."
AES has 476 megawatts of battery storage projects in operation, construction or late stage development in 17 countries around the world.
It is building a 100-megawatt project in Longbeach, California, to come online in 2020, which will exceed the SA's project's capacity because it will have four hours peaking capacity at full tilt. It can run for longer at a lower capacity.
It has also developed a 37.5-megawatt battery project in San Diego which is the largest project in the world.

"The best thing about this technology is it is fully scalable so it can be adjusted to whatever project," Mr Kathpal said.
The battery storage rollout was accelerated after reliability issues on the grid in southern California and the retirement of gas-fired plants.
Mr Kathpal said battery storage technology had developed quickly over the past decade and electric batteries had gone from being used for electric vehicles to large-scale applications to help energy utilities deal with taking pressure off the grid during times of peak demand.
The reporter travelled to California with the assistance of The Climate Council.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P2 Photography</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Climate Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Praveen Kathpal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AES Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AES Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Longbeach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AES</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kathpal</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
