<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437826244299218</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/air-warfare-destroyer-hobart-sets-sail-for-sydney-to-begin-life-in-the-navy/news-story/79902063410798b824f7ab5927691c44</url>
  <title>New warship's big wave goodbye</title>
  <content>
IT'S so young it only has half a name but the first of Australia's new Air Warfare Destroyers has braved stormy weather to leave its birthplace and officially join the navy.
The Hobart set sail from Adelaide for Sydney where on September 23 it will be commissioned and earn the right to be the title "Her Majesty's Australian Ship", or "HMAS."
Until then it is simply designated "SHIP".
The 147-metre long warship was given the all-clear to leave Adelaide after platform and combat systems were tested during a 21-day at sea trial earlier this year.
It was granted provisional acceptance by the navy in June.

The launch of Australia's newest warship, the Hobart, at ASC headquarters in Adelaide

Air Warfare Destroyer Hobart sets sail
A workforce of about 5000 - including 2000 in Adelaide - have worked on the construction of the Air Warfare Destroyers.
The skills gained by local workers during the project have enabled the Government to launch its "continuous shipbuilding" program.
Hobart and sister ships the Brisbane and the Sydney will each have a crew of 186 when they become fully operational and accommodation for up to 234 people.
The Hobart is equipped with gas turbine and propulsion engines and has an operational range of over 9,000km.
The AWDs will be armed with harpoon missile systems and protected by missile decoy technology. A flight deck and hangar will house a helicopter.
In battle, the destroyers would perform a protective "bubble" to protect other vessels a taskforce.
Meanwhile, more than 6mm of rain fell over the city between 9am and 4.30pm on Sunday, while the maximum was just 13.7 degrees at 12.08pm. Mt Barker copped 30mm of rain. Showers are forecast for Adelaide on Monday, with the temperature expected to reach 16 degrees.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWDs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Warfare Destroyers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Majesty's Australian Ship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Warfare Destroyer Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
