<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437272193513176</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/canberra-raiders/canberra-raiders-hooker-josh-hodgson-says-theyre-keeping-it-simple-20170806-gxq8di.html</url>
  <title>The key to the Canberra Raiders' new-found composure? It's simple.</title>
  <content>
The key to the Canberra Raiders' new-found composure? It's simple.
Raiders hooker Josh Hodgson was back to his best in the 30-12 victory over Cronulla at Shark Park on Saturday night, but he vowed they wouldn't "pat themselves on the back" and there was still a "lot of hard work to do" before their next must-win game.

Up Next

Bolt defeated by Gatlin in final 100m race

00:23

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Judiciary charges loom as Cronulla slip to Canberra

In a night of ugly tackles from Graham, Fifita and Gallen, the Ricky Stuart masterclass inspired the Raiders to a 30-12 victory over the Sharks to keep their NRL finals hopes alive.

They travel to Auckland to take on the New Zealand Warriors needing to win their last four remaining games to play NRL finals.
The Warriors have lost their last five NRL games, and their last three against the Raiders.- although they've won 12 of 18 games against the Green Machine in New Zealand.

Canberra have been criticised this season for their game management, especially in close games, but they calmly closed out the win over the Sharks.
Those cool heads were most evident in the 10 minutes Josh Papalii was in the sin bin for a professional foul right when the game was in the balance.

Hodgson said they'd simplified things in recent weeks, which had helped the Green Machine click into gear.
He felt the way they wound down the clock, took the momentum away from the Sharks and extended their lead all while a man down showed they were heading in the right direction.Photo: Craig Golding
"I think we're getting there. It's been a funny old year, it's been a work in progress," Hodgson said.
"The past four weeks we've picked a system that we want to work with and really stuck at that, simplified a few things.
"When you're struggling a little bit and not going as good as you want to be everything goes under the microscope and you tend to look too hard at certain things that you don't really need to and we've really just learnt to relax a little bit and start to relax a bit more."
Raiders coach Ricky Stuart said this season had been a massive "learning curve", now it was up to his squad to use those lessons over the last few rounds as they look to make a charge to the top eight.
The Raiders went into the season as one of the premiership favourites, but have struggled to live up to expectations and also to close out close games.
But Stuart felt facing what's essentially a sudden-death situation could work in their favour.
"This year's been the biggest learning curve for the squad that they'll ever have and how we use that is up to us," he said.
"Last year we got to a situation where I think it had probably come a bit quick, and we hadn't had the experience of playing in tight games.
"Rugby league's a lesson every game and every season and we're getting it.
"Hopefully now on the back end of the season can put a lot of those tough lessons that we got throughout the year into practice now with our games.
"We've got four games left. We can only worry about what we do and sometimes that's a good thing."
Meanwhile, Sharks second-rower Wade Graham is free to play next week if he takes the early guilty plea for a dangerous throw on Raiders winger Nick Cotric.
NRL ROUND 23
Sunday: Canberra Raiders v New Zealand Warriors at Auckland, 2pm. Live on Fox League.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodgson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shark Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Papalii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Golding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL ROUND 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Raiders</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wade Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREEN MACHINE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Cotric</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hodgson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
