<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437783294625730</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/armed-gang-robs-three-service-stations-in-melbournes-northwest-20170806-gxqfbj.html</url>
  <title>Armed gang rob three service stations in Melbourne's north-west</title>
  <content>
Up to seven men armed with baseball bats, hammers and a knife smashed their way into three service stations in Melbourne's north-west over the weekend, fleeing with cash, cigarettes and a car.
In the first incident, seven men targeted a service station on the Melton Highway in Hillside just after 3am on Saturday.Photo: Victoria Police
The group tried to break into a cigarette cabinet but failed. Instead, they stole the service station attendant's car and escaped. 
The attendant, who was in the cool room at the time, was uninjured.
Thirty minutes later, it's believed the same men struck another service station, in Laverton North. 
Armed with a knife, baseball bat and hammers, the group entered the Little Boundary Road petrol station just before 3.30am, stealing cigarettes and a cash register.

The attendant locked himself in a back room and was uninjured.
Owner Trevor Dance told Channel Seven it was the third time in three days his service station had been attacked. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

On Friday night, an attendant at the station was chased into the back room and struck on the arm with a machete.
On Saturday, another youth attacked the store, trying to destroy as much as he could.
"No respect, no care factor, just smash windows, smash fridges, smash everything [just repeating] ... 'we'll kill you, we'll kill you, we'll kill you,' " Mr Dance said.
"First thing I think, 'Are the staff OK? Have they been injured? Are they hurt?' They are going to suffer from this for the rest of their life.
"Police are doing their jobs, but the courts are not. Even if these guys get caught tonight ... they will be out the next day."
In the latest weekend incident, six men armed with hammers attacked a Melton Highway service station at Rockbank just before 3.30am on Sunday.
According to media reports, the staff member locked himself in a safe room, but the men rushed in after him, smashing through the glass and dragging him back out into the store. 
They stole the cash register and cigarettes before fleeing in a black SUV and a silver sedan.
Police said no one was injured during the incident.
Brimbank Embona taskforce detectives said they were treating all three incidents as linked.
Police have released CCTV and images of a number of men they want to speak to.
Anyone with any information is urged to contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or submit a confidential crime report at .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Dance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brimbank Embona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverton North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melton Highway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Boundary Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
