<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437826244299201</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836248/panthers-nudge-dragons-out-of-top-eight/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Dragons in uphill battle to re-enter finals picture</title>
  <content>
LETTING IT SLIP: Dragons players await Adam Reynolds conversion attempt on Friday night. Picture: AAP

SATURDAY'S clash with Gold Coast is shaping as make or break for St George Illawarra's season after Penrith leapfrogged them into eighth spot with a 28-14 win over the Tigers on Sunday.
It's the first time the Dragons have been outside the eight this season and the battle to re-enter the finals frame looks very much an uphill one following their stunning late-game fade-out against the Rabbitohs on Friday.
The Dragons conceded two tries in the final five minutes to surrender a 10-point lead and allow Adam Reynolds to snatch an unlikely victory for his side via a sideline conversion. 
It was part of an awful round 22 for the red v, with their other top eight rivals Canberra and Manly notching upset wins over the Sharks and Roosters.

Having now dropped their past two games to sides running 16th and 11th on the ladder, a loss to the 14th-placed Titans would effectively end the Dragons season. 
Should they get the win over the Titans, they still face a pair of tough away clashes against an in-form Brisbane at Suncorp Stadium and Penrith in the penultimate round. 
"It makes next week pretty important," coach Paul McGregor said post-defeat.

"Every game's important and has been for a while. We've worked so hard to have someone to come in and take it away from us but we're doing it to ourselves at the moment."
Skipper Gareth Widdop was similarly at loss to explain his side's capitulation given what was on the line.
"We can't be losing games like that," Widdop said.
"In one set we let them roll a hundred metres and score. It's disappointing because we worked hard to get back in that game and then have a little bit of a lead.

"With 10 minutes, eight minutes or whatever it was left, we were in front and our composure in defence let us down."
The Dragons have also been hit with some untimely injury concerns, with Josh Dugan facing a lengthy stint on the sidelines with an ankle syndesmosis injury.

Key forward Russell Packer was also a late withdrawal from the Rabbitohs game having battled hip and knee injuries in recent weeks. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dugan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gareth Widdop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Widdop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Reynolds</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
