<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437912143645849</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836557/undermanned-fury-grind-out-tough-win/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Undermanned Fury grind out tough win</title>
  <content>
GUTSY PERFORMANCE: Kemblawarra's Matthew McNab holds possession in his team's win over Albion Park White Eagles. Picture: ROBERT PEET

Kemblawarra Fury all but locked down a top three spot and dented Albion Park's post-season aspirations in a determined 1-0 win on Sunday.

A second half strike from gun midfielder Shane Murray guided the 2016 league champions to a well-earned three points at Macedonia Park. 
The triumph keeps the Fury (43 points) on the heels of leading duo Bulli (48 points) and Wollongong Olympic (47 points) heading into the final three rounds.
They remain a mathematical chance of defending their League Championship title, but coach Luke McGuire again insisted it was no longer his team's radar after their latest triumph. 
He was more pleased to see his undermanned squad came away with the points against Park. 

"I thought we were outstanding," McGuire said.
"We worked for each other and it was one of those games where it could have gone either way.

"We worked our backsides off and got a result.

"Like I have said before, now we are just trying to prepare ourselves the best we can for finals."
The Fury were shaded in the first half by their rivals, but Park struggled to take advantage despite consistent pressure.
Reigning George Naylor Medalist Shohei Okuno and fellow Japanese attacker Hikaru Kawasakiya both had chances to test stand-in Fury keeper David Zufic, but failed to hit the target.
It proved costly just four minutes into the second half when Murray struck.
Moments after Matthew McNab had forced Bruce Daenell into a great save, Murray shot from distance and found the bottom corner.
Only the heroics of Daenell stopped Kemblawarra from doubling that lead.
The classy goalkeeper pulled off several amazing saves, including an acrobatic effort to deny Sam Munro's long range strike with half an hour remaining. 
His efforts drew praise from McGuire.
"I thought their keeper pulled off two or three amazing saves there which probably could have sealed the game for us," he said.

Daenell's ability to keep Park in the contest in the second half provided the visitors with some hope of snatching a point.
But, as they did in the first half, the White Eagles misfired in front of goal. 
"It was the same story as last week in the Cup final, we just can't put our chances away and then invite teams back into the game in the second half," Park coach George Antoniou said.
The loss means Park remain four points behind finals rivals Port Kembla and Wollongong United. 
Despite the gap, Antoniou is refusing to give up on a top-five finish. 
"We still have to take it game by game because I think other teams will drop points along the way above us," he said.
"We just have to make sure we can win where we can."

In other matches, Bulli fought out a gritty 1-0 win over Port Kembla, Olympic beat Wollongong United 2-1 and Tarrawanna defeated Woonona 4-2. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulli (48</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kembla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antoniou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBERT PEET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park White Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedonia Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Zufic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Daenell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Naylor Medalist Shohei Okuno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kemblawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hikaru Kawasakiya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Olympic (47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarrawanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Antoniou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kemblawarra Fury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fury (43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kemblawarra's Matthew McNab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Munro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew McNab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
