<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437525596585608</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/gold-coast-to-roll-dice-on-injured-stars-in-qclash-while-brisbane-deal-with-injuries-of-their-own/news-story/b0d77b07972ab2207182c82a5c002033</url>
  <title>Suns ready to roll dice on injured stars</title>
  <content>
GOLD Coast are planning to roll the dice with a host of big names to secure a badly needed QClash win.
If Jarryd Lyons is passed fit he will be rushed straight back into the seniors despite missing three weeks with an ankle injury.
Callum Ah Chee will also bypass the NEAFL if he passes a fitness test on the shoulder he injured two weeks ago.
MATCH REPORT:
MATCH REPORT:
ALASTAIR LYNCH:
The Suns expect David Swallow to also be available after he was a late withdrawal from the side that lost to Fremantle in Perth on Saturday night because of groin tightness.
Michael Rischitelli was rested from the trip to Western Australia and will also take his place.
The Suns will also give strong consideration to ruckman Jarrod Witts who did not make the trip across the country because of a shoulder injury.

Football manager Marcus Ashcroft said Witts would require surgery but if medical advice said he could play without inflicting any further damage he would be considered.
"We have a few who are a chance to come in,'' he said.
"Swallow only just missed on the weekend so he will come back in and we are pretty confident with Lyons too.
"Witts is a chance but is probably more unlikely than likely at this stage, we don't want to pick him and have him unable to play, but we haven't ruled him out yet.''
Speedster Aaron Hall is unavailable after injuring his hamstring against the Dockers.
Brisbane are resigned to losing Alex Witherden who left the field late in the loss to the Bulldogs with a hamstring injury.
However, utility Cedric Cox remains a strong chance to take his place.
Cox did not play the second half because of an ankle sprain but pulled up well and has not been ruled out at this stage.
"Hopefully Cox is all right and we're only looking at one change,'' football manager David Noble said.
"We don't have an update on Witherden yet, we'll wait for scans on Monday but even if it is a Grade 1 it's probably a couple of weeks.''
Ben Keays was the emergency on Saturday and played a half in the NEAFL victory over the Swans.
That win secured a top-two finish for the Lions, which is proof there are plenty of players in solid form ready for an opportunity.
Half-back Sam Mayes is also a chance of returning from a foot injury.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Noble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Swallow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Ah Chee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Lyons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Witherden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALASTAIR LYNCH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QClash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Witherden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Witt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Witts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cedric Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Ashcroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Rischitelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Keays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
