<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438083942339456</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836729/tens-of-thousands-told-to-brace-for-monday-morning-delays-after-wolli-creek-crane-collapse/?cs=7</url>
  <title>Tens of thousands told to brace for Monday morning delays after Wolli Creek crane collapse</title>
  <content>
Commuters travelling to both international and domestic airports on Monday morning have been advised to allow for extra travel time after the crane that collapsed on a building in Wolli Creek forced a partial closure of the T2 Airport line.

The line remained closed between Central and Turrella on Sunday night with buses replacing trains, according to the Transport Management Centre.
Authorities including NSW Fire & Rescue experts, engineers and NSW Police worked into Sunday evening in an attempt to stabilise the crane before removing it.
The collapse has left at least 200 people in the impacted building unable to return to their homes on Sunday night.
Fears the crane could fall onto nearby buildings have left another 300 people from 2 buildings stranded, pending an assessment about the crane's stability, Fire & Rescue spokesman Josh Turner said.
The Monday morning peak hour rush is expected to be chaotic if the train line does not reopen.
"Over 50,000 people may be trying to access the railway and to get into the airport," Sydney Trains chief executive Howard Collins said on Sunday.
"I ask people to check before you travel, allow some extra time, there may not be rail services to both international and domestic airports tomorrow morning."
The crane is believed to have been in the process of being set up when it fell backwards, slamming into the penthouse apartment and causing structural damage to the upper levels and roof of the building.
A Wolli Creek resident described how another crane was forced to rescue the stranded driver.
"The man from the white crane (which crashed), he jumped over to the rooftop of the penthouse. So they (the second crane) went to the rooftop and picked him up," Felicia Nguyen said.
Mr Turner assured residents there was no threat of the building collapsing.
"No, the building itself is quite stable, the damage is just up to the roof area," he said.
However, concerns that the crane may shift position and fall onto the street or surrounding buildings saw four other buildings evacuated.
Paramedics treated three male workers at the scene for minor injuries before they were transported to St George Hospital, with one of the men suffering a suspected fractured leg.
Investigators from SafeWork NSW spent Sunday at the site to determine the cause of the incident, but declined to comment further until investigations were completed.
Probuild, the construction company responsible for the building the crane was anchored to, could not be contacted for comment.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Probuild</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T2 Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felicia Nguyen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Management Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turrella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Trains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SafeWork NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
