<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438083942339453</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/a-league/brisbane-roar-marquee-massimo-maccarone-waiting-on-visa-clearance-to-play-melbourne-victory-in-ffa-cup/news-story/fd09f4582bb184fa64a4cff1bd1c53a3</url>
  <title>Marksman Maccarone sweating on visa</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE Roar marquee man Massimo Maccarone says he's ready for at least 45 minutes of football against Melbourne Victory on Wednesday night - now all he needs is his visa clearance.
The veteran Italian striker scored twice in his 20-minute Roar debut on Saturday as the three-time A-League champions fought back from 1-0 and later 2-1 down to beat Brisbane Premier League club Peninsula Power 4-2 at AJ Kelly Park.
Being a trial, Maccarone didn't need visa approval for his cameo.
But it's a different story for Wednesday's FFA Cup battle with the Victory at Perry Park.
Maccarone said he was hopeful he would have his visa approved on Monday.
"It's not here yet but I think it will arrive in time," the former Middlesbrough and Empoli attacker said.
"I want to play (against the Victory)."
The Roar will take a steady approach with Maccarone should he be cleared, and that's fine with the 37-year-old marksman.
"I need more time to get my fitness up because I started training less than two weeks ago and I need confidence," he said.
"But (on Saturday) it was a good 20 minutes. Next time I'll play some more minutes. We'll see day-by-day with my fitness.
"I think I can play for a half (on Wednesday night), but that's up to the coach (John Aloisi)."
Maccarone was delighted to open his account for the Roar, albeit in a friendly against third-tier opposition.
"A forward always needs confidence and when they score a goal, it's better for everybody," he said.

EPL: Kane fires in the Spurs win over Juventus.

Kane fires in the Spurs win over Juventus
"It's good start, two goals - for the fans and for me as well."
Aloisi is yet to decide on his starting team for Wednesday night.
Former Victory star Fahid Ben Khalfallah and Greek international Avraam Papadopoulos didn't play on Saturday, and are no guarantee to be involved against the Melbourne club.
A certain omission is goalkeeper Michael Theo, who has contracted the influenza A virus.
Neither Theo nor fellow gloveman Jamie Young played on the weekend, but Young will start against the Victory.
The Roar are set to announce that triallist Peter Skapetis, who scored against Peninsula, will be offered an injury-replacement deal as cover for long-term casualty Daniel Bowles (knee).
Former Newcastle and Perth midfielder Mitch Oxborrow was to have signed as Bowles's injury replacement, but he instead put pen to paper on a regular season-long contract.
The Roar have also signed teenage midfielder Emilio Martinez on a scholarship deal.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Roar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emilio Martinez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Empoli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juventus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maccarone</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middlesbrough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perry Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Victory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massimo Maccarone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Oxborrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahid Ben Khalfallah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday's FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roar</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Skapetis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Bowles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Aloisi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Theo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aloisi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AJ Kelly Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avraam Papadopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
