<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437963683253777</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/opinion/columnists/showdowns-keep-coming-for-government-20170806-gxqf25</url>
  <title>Same sex marriage showdown a taste of things to come</title>
  <content>
It might not seem like it but same-sex marriage can be more quickly and easily resolved than many of the other devilish dilemmas .
At least there's an end in sight to the ferocious political debate over same-sex marriage. That will happen either extremely messily in the parliament over the next several days or - at the latest - very soon after the next election.
The internal Liberal party argument may yet produce a near instant implosion of the Turnbull government, of course, if four dissident MPs really do proceed with their intention to back a bill from Liberal Senator Dean Smith in the House.
But they are under enormous pressure not to follow through on that threat given the implications for the Prime Minister and the stability of the Coalition.

Senior ministers don't believe the backbenchers would be willing to take such a risk with the very survival of the government. Instead, there's a scramble to come up with something that looks like a willingness to compromise as part of the .

Yet while the outcome of all this turmoil remains unpredictable and potentially lethal for Turnbull's leadership, it still has a finite life. .
The other issues bedevilling the government will remain problems indefinitely - for any government. Their common link is no simple piece of legislation possible that will suddenly alter reality - whether within two weeks or two years.
From high energy prices to high housing prices to Aboriginal constitutional recognition to low wages growth, the Turnbull government is struggling to make persuasive progress. That's mainly because the problems are so complicated they defy political fixes, let alone quick ones, when the causes have been such a long time building. But that doesn't help in an era that demands instant response from a political class finding itself so unpopular with voters.
Treading lightly

Some of this can be managed via the cautious sort of rhetoric that suggests a willingness to respond positively while also signalling any real change of policy will be a long time coming. But that also depends on the particular issue and how much of the broader community is directly affected - or cares much about it.
So Malcolm Turnbull, along with Bill Shorten, attended the Garma festival in Arnhem Land over the weekend. The Prime Minister politely made it clear the Coalition will not quickly be taking up the Referendum Council's recommendation for a "voice" via a separate representative body enshrined in the constitution.
Instead, the Prime Minister talked of the need for "careful consideration" but warned of the many questions remaining unanswered. He pointed out the obvious. Passage of any referendum is extremely difficult - and impossible if the question is not "simple, easily understood and overwhelmingly embraced". None of those pre-conditions are present despite Labor's encouragement of the idea.
The result will be no such constitutional change will occur in the foreseeable future - if ever - no matter what any current politician says about it. Turnbull knows more personally than most politicians how a failed referendum can set a cause back decades.

There's considerably more political urgency, however, about how to manage another big issue that will face the government mid-week. That is rising anxiety about rising energy prices. Unfortunately for the government, there also little immediate policy relief available for that either - just a much higher price to pay as a result.
The Prime Minister has called the heads of Australia's big energy companies to Canberra on Wednesday for what is effectively a public dressing down over their pricing regimes for residential and business customers.
For Turnbull and his energy minister, Josh Frydenberg, the recent rise in the share prices of companies such as AGL and Origin demonstrates big companies are using today's high prices to make profits for their shareholders while they can - at the expense of bills for consumers.
The government has already acted to limit exports of gas if necessary from next January.

Regulation threat

Turnbull will be using the threat of yet more regulation to try to force changes in the nature of contracts for domestic businesses needing gas at a reasonable price and in the way customers are being charged for electricity - especially in how discounts are applied.
The industry is distinctly unimpressed with the way in which chief executives were summonsed and what it likely to come out of any such "discussion" with a government keen to show results.
So companies demand the government focus on providing investment certainty by supporting the Finkel recommendation for a clean energy target as the best way of putting downward pressure on prices and encouraging the necessary new investment over the next few years.

The political price of that debate will be another huge brawl splitting the Coalition. This threatens to be even more divisive than differences over same-sex marriage. The catch is that it will not have much immediate impact on the rapidly increasing price of power and consumer anger about bills given big prices that came in from July 1.
But the determination of Tony Abbott and some conservatives to fight against a clean energy target and instead back a much bigger future for coal-fired power ensures this will become another proxy leadership fight should Turnbull and Frydenberg choose to proceed. They will probably still do so - via a modified version of Finkel's recommendation.
It means the Monday meeting may prove a precursor of other simmering political problems also reaching boiling point - just what the government doesn't need and voters don't want.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
