<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438126892012768</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/penrith-coach-anthony-griffin-draws-inspiration-from-2006-premiershipwinning-broncos-20170806-gxqhcs.html</url>
  <title>Penrith coach Anthony Griffin draws inspiration from 2006 premiership-winning Broncos</title>
  <content>
Penrith are finally where they should have been weeks ago, with coach Anthony Griffin admitting he never gave up on his side's finals hopes despite a disastrous start to the year.
Griffin has referenced the Broncos premiership-winning team of 2006, who like Penrith this year lost five in a row, admitting he always believed his team could overcome a disappointing start to play finals football.

Up Next

Bolt defeated by Gatlin in final 100m race

00:23

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Penrith move to eighth in NRL thriller

Moving into the NRL top eight after crawling to a nervous 28-14 win over the Wests Tigers at Pepper Stadium.

"A lot of teams have lost five in a row," Griffin said.
"I think Brisbane lost six or seven in a row when they won the grand final in 2006. We've got a lot of belief in our squad. Next week is another week. The fight is well and truly on now if we want to stay in it. We had a good win today but there's a hell of a long way to go.

"We have to have a harder edge about ourselves. We have to be a little bit more patient. If you earn the right to be in the fighting at this time of the year - that's why it is a 24 week long competition. You're a chance at beating anyone on your day."
Griffin wasn't happy with his team's performance, but the Panthers keep finding ways to win without looking pretty.

"We always knew it was going to be an 80-minute game today," Griffin said.
""It was just messy. They're a really tough team to play. We have to nail that down. It looked messy at times but I thought our attack was really good today."Photo: Christopher Pearce
There's been a notable improvement in the Tigers over the past month, despite only managing one win in tight contests against Manly, Parramatta, Gold Coast and Penrith.
They were pumped by the Panthers at Campbelltown earlier in the season, but they appear a vastly different football team under the guidance of Cleary.
"There were definitely better signs form the team," Cleary said.
"I thought the Panthers ere really up today. We just didn't really get a chance. There are good signs.When we had the upper hand we didn't go on with it. Sometimes you have it, sometime you don't. We absorbed all that pressure. We're getting better. There's a pretty good vibe around at the moment."
Tigers skipper Aaron Woods believes the Panthers are the premiership darkhorses, hitting their straps at the right time. While he was disappointed to leave Pepper Stadium empty handed, he highlighted the quality of the opposition.
"I thought we were coming down strong," Woods said.
"I thought we turned over too much pill. We let the Panthers off the hook. You wouldn't want to play them because they can beat anybody on their day. If they do make the eight they will give it a little bit of a shake."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pepper Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Griffin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
