<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438049582600577</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/one-youngsters-transplant-relief-but-another-faces-an-anxious-wait/news-story/6b19cf047ea4d09fa6da481c1b427267</url>
  <title>Two little girls behind one big message</title>
  <content>
LARA Corbett does not need to use her imagination to walk a mile in Elise Anderson's shoes - she has experienced first-hand what her new friend is going through.
Likewise, her parents Holly Foster and Jake Corbett know exactly how Elise's family feels.
The similarities are striking: both two years old with light-coloured eyes and fair hair, both from the Sunshine Coast and both born with faulty livers.
But it is the difference between the pair that is most affecting.
Lara is now well after receiving a lifesaving liver transplant last year, while Elise and her parents Anthea and Glenn Anderson are patiently waiting.
"She is okay at the moment," Ms Anderson said.
"She doesn't need the first available liver which is good, but she does need a liver when the right one becomes available and hopefully, her condition does not deteriorate."
Elise was born tiny - just 1.83kg - had a cleft palette and was unable to thrive.
During an operation to remove a cyst, found when she was just six months old, doctors discovered Elise's liver was full of cirrhosis and she would need a transplant.
The news came as a shock to the Maroochydore family who had hoped the operation would put an end to their daughter's poor health.
"It was terrible. My poor husband, he just about fainted at the time," Ms Anderson said.
"We had to sit down when the surgeon was telling us."
But she said meeting Lara was a "really reassuring" ray of hope for the couple.
Lara was diagnosed with biliary atresia - a disease affecting the liver and bile ducts - when she was six weeks old.
Ms Foster said before her transplant that her family would travel from Caboolture to Lady Cilento Children's Hospital in Brisbane at least every six weeks for treatment.
She said the transplant was life-changing for her daughter whose belly, at the height of her illness, was so swollen with fluid that she "looked pregnant".
Her advice to the Anderson family - "stay strong".
"This time last year we were in the exact same boat as them," Ms Foster said.
The two families are speaking out to encourage Queenslanders to sign up to be organ donors, using a new process where would-be donors need only their Medicare cards to register.
"We are so grateful to our donor, We think about them every day," Ms Foster said.
To register, visit: donatelife.gov.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elise Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Anderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Corbett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Foster</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LARA Corbett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Cilento Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elise</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
