<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437654445605652</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/west-belconnen-warriors-upset-queanbeyan-blues-to-keep-canberra-raiders-cup-hopes-alive-20170806-gxq8my.html</url>
  <title>Warriors keep Canberra Raiders Cup hopes alive with shock win</title>
  <content>
Bobby Roberts can "kill you with his kicks" and the West Belconnen Warriors will be hoping he can bag himself some Kangaroos next weekend.
The Canberra Raiders Cup is set for a thrilling final round leading into the finals with four teams still vying for third and fourth on the ladder after Wests ended the Queanbeyan Blues' hopes of going through the season undefeated.Photo: Rohan Thomson
They fought back from 12 points down in the second half to stun the Blues 31-28 to keep their finals hopes alive.
The Warriors are fifth, but equal with fourth-placed Tuggeranong on 20 points with just for-and-against separating them - the Bushrangers are +80, while West Belco are +5.
Yass Magpies are third with 21 points, while Goulburn are on 18 points and are still a chance of sneaking into the top four - but they'd need to have a massive win over Yass next week and hope both Wests and the Bushrangers get flogged by the Queanbeyan Kangaroos and the Blues respectively.
Roberts will be crucial for the Warriors if they're going to knock off the Roos, who'll be fired up after suffering a shock loss to the lowly Woden Valley Rams on Saturday.

His kicking game not only set up a crucial second-half try for Wests, but he also kicked a field goal with eight minutes remaining to make it 29-28.
He then nailed a penalty goal right at the death to seal the win.
"We spoke about it through the week that he kills you with his kicks and I think they scored a couple of tries off his kicks and the field goal, and his goal kicking was up there as well," Campese said.
"It was one of the biggest difference today. He got a couple of repeat sets as well with his bombs and stuff like that.
"Definitely something we have to work on in the coming weeks, if other teams see that."
The Blues had gone through 14 games undefeated, but have stumbled just two hurdles before finals.
Campese felt it had been coming the last couple of weeks and they'd potentially relaxed after getting crowned as minor premiers following the Rams' win.
They seemed to be cruising with fill-in fullback Tom Ruediger bagging a hat-trick and looking like scoring almost every time he got the ball.
That was until the final 20 minutes, when the Warriors' forwards started to get a roll on and outside backs like Chris Thorley (two tries) and Ricky Fulivai (one) became a threat.
Campese said the Warriors deserved their win off the back of the hunger they showed to keep their season alive.
"We've been off it the last few weeks ... I'm not sure if it's a bit of attitude mentally," he said.
"We found out last night we had the minor premiership when the Roos got knocked off yesterday as well.
"Sometimes these things play in the mind and obviously semi-finals are a couple of weeks away, the boys just trying to get through the games to make sure they're fit for that - I'm not sure what it is."
The Blues lost their leading try-scorer Brendon Taueki (ribs) early in the second half and he was taken to hospital as a precaution.
AT A GLANCE
West Belconnen Warriors 31 bt Queanbeyan Blues 28.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yass Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Kangaroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobby Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Belconnen Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Fulivai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Thorley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Ruediger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Belco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bushrangers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Taueki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Blues 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Belconnen Warriors 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Raiders Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woden Valley Rams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
