<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438045287633256</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/brisbanes-citycycle-bike-hire-scheme-tracking-for-record-usage-in-next-financial-year/news-story/4cbee9d9fba7a62bbd19c81b2357cc22</url>
  <title>Council claims spike in bike scheme usage</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE City Council insists the often maligned CityCycle scheme is far from washed up, with a record number of trips being taken in July.
The bright yellow bikes were checked out more than 57,000 times last month, in a promising start to a financial year, on the back of booming numbers for the scheme.
The 2016-17 financial year saw a 35 per cent increase in the number of trips taken, to 522,388.
That was also a 70 per cent increase on the 307,058 users two years ago.
The CityCycle scheme has been criticised, because of costs and maintenance issues since it was wheeled out in 2010.
A picture submitted to The Courier-Mail showing two men overlooking a pair of the city's bikes stuck in mangrove mud highlighted some of the issues the council has faced with the scheme.
The council said there had been no missing bikes in the past week, so, presumably the bogged bikes had been recovered.
Public and Active Transport chairman Adrian Schrinner said CityCycle was continuing to grow in popularity.
"There have been more than 1.9 million trips since CityCycle began and during July there was a monthly record of 57,256 trips taken around the inner city," Cr Schrinner said.
"CityCycle provides a clean, green and sustainable transport alternative to tackle inner city traffic congestion and boosts lifestyle and leisure opportunities for residents and visitors.
"The number of CityCycle users grew by 35 per cent last financial year to 522,388 trips which is 70 per cent higher than the 307,058 recorded two years ago.
"In the last week of July we had a weekly record of 14,461 trips and as patronage numbers continue to grow we expect to reach CityCycle's 2 millionth trip later this month.
"The warmer than usual winter weather is also helping boost patronage as locals and visitors use CityCycle to enjoy our liveable city."
Damaged bikes and disappearing helmets have been an ongoing problem for the scheme, requiring the council to distribute an extra 2400 helmets last year.
The council was asked to reveal the number of helmets and bikes that had been damaged or gone missing in the last financial year but did not reply.
"JCDecaux is the owner and operator of the scheme and responsible for the recovery and cost of misplaced bikes and the scheduled, ongoing maintenance of CityCycle bikes," a spokesman said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CityCycle</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CityCycle's 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Schrinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JCDecaux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Schrinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Active Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
