<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437521301618300</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/error-of-ineligible-horse-winning-gosford-race-foreshadowed-by-event-in-2016-20170805-gxq6yv.html</url>
  <title>Error of ineligible horse winning Gosford race foreshadowed by event in 2016 </title>
  <content>
It was just a few lines in a stewards' report last week, but the embarrassing bungle of a horse being disqualified from a Gosford race a few days after it had won and bets paid out is not the first time something similar has happened in NSW in the past year.
In case you missed it, Chris Waller's Cellarman eased to victory in a Class 1 race he was ineligible to contest. He had only won one race beforehand, but it was a listed race rendering him a Class 5 horse. Waller's stable didn't realise at the time and the trainer was subsequently fined $200.Photo: Janie Barrett
But if you backed the "runner-up" in the race, Sir Magic? How are you feeling now? You reckon you'll get a chance to collect after the fact? Sir Magic's connections might get the prizemoney they rightfully feel entitled to, but his backers are the ones left holding the can.
And, well, the story piqued the interest of this column because we remembered something similar happening only recently, believe it or not.
Trainer Craig Ritchie unwittingly nominated a mare for a Kembla Grange Class 2 race last December even though she had been a listed winner in New Zealand - the exact situation which stumped Cellarman's connections.
The mare, No Pushover, was part of the acceptances with a rider declared and, thankfully, she was pulled out of the event before actually going to the gates.

But it came very close to slipping through the system, which might have raised alarm bells and meant the Cellarman situation should have been avoided. It just adds up to another elaborate way of doing your dough.
On the flip side, if you backed Cellarman in a race he should never have contested, then thank the Punting God for a rare stroke of luck.
The issue obviously lies with the IT system in accepting entries for a horse in a race which it is ineligible. For their part, Racing NSW are not absolving themselves of blame and even handicapped the horse as a listed winner which might have raised its own alarm bells. Stewards have admitted as much. And they say an internal review has been hastily organised to ensure it doesn't happen again.
But isn't one time one too many in a case like this?
McEvoy emerges
Kerrin McEvoy's week couldn't have been much busier, but perhaps it was an early morning spin around Flemington in the middle of a foggy morning which hinted how much busier the coming months are about to become.
McEvoy's call to ride Hartnell in a Flemington jumpout on Friday - in the middle of a mad four-day expedition which took in race rides at Warwick Farm, Coffs Harbour, Wyong the same day as the Hartnell spin in Melbourne and then Randwick - probably proves he's back in the Godolphin fold in some capacity.
Given in the last week alone he has ridden for Chris Waller, Peter and Paul Snowden, Gerald Ryan, Joe Pride and still has support from Gai Waterhouse and Adrian Bott, you hardly think McEvoy would ever consider angling for a retainer like the old days.
But don't be surprised if the dual Melbourne Cup-winning rider does a lot more riding for the locally-based Godolphin operation - and not just its spring cups-hunting European trainers.
Ballooning prizemoney
There's another significant prizemoney hike on the way for a feature race with Hawkesbury's Rowley Mile set to balloon to $150,000 later this month - an increase of $50,000 from last year.
"Whilst the date of the race has shifted around over the years, we want to give it a chance as an important feature in late winter and an increase in prizemoney can assist with this aim," Hawkesbury chief executive officer Greg Rudolph said.
Rudolph also indicated that other feature races, including the listed Lander Toyota Ladies Day Cup, run on VRC Oaks Day in November, are also under consideration for prizemoney increases.
"We are in discussions with Racing NSW regarding other feature races, including our spring feature on Oaks Day and will then look to our standalone again in the autumn," he said. "Returns to owners is a high priority, but we are about to also build on course stables and our Polytrack so these have to be weighed into our budgetary considerations in this financial year."
Moody going places
No surprise to see Clare Cunningham's training career start with a bang, capped by her first metropolitan winner in her own right at Warwick Farm last week.
Peter Moody is no mug. And the fact he relied so heavily on Cunningham speaks volumes. A trainer who can improve tried horses early in their career is one going places.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Moody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Ritchie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerald Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Class 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Class 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hartnell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Farm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cellarman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Cup-winning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkesbury's Rowley Mile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Pride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Waller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godolphin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oaks Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Rudolph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Magic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polytrack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla Grange Class 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkesbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Snowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Waller's Cellarman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punting God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudolph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gai Waterhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janie Barrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Bott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VRC Oaks Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lander Toyota Ladies Day Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McEvoy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
