<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437697395278994</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/university-bounce-back-against-bulldogs/news-story/c7e191dba0029588b09672b35f3230bb</url>
  <title>University bounce back against Bulldogs</title>
  <content>
UNIVERSITY coach Zammi Rohan remains confident his team can challenge for the premiership after they bounced back from last week's top-of-the-table loss to Hermit Park by outlasting Thuringowa on Saturday.
The 14.8 (92) to 9.5 (59) win at Tony Ireland Stadium allowed University to remain behind Hermit Park only on percentage after the Tigers beat them by 36 points last week.
Rohan said that result could be a blessing in disguise for his team before heading into finals, with two rounds left in the regular season.
Last week was a bit disappointing to lose but it was perhaps good for us to realise we still have a bit of work to do," he said.
"Everyone knuckled down to try and get things back on track, and it (win over Thuringowa) was a good way to respond.
"We realise we still have a lot of work to do and are still a fair way off playing our footy, but after last week the guys have all shown they're committed and putting in the hard work and trying to get some momentum heading into the finals."
Skipper Jarryd Graham and Michael Lahey led the way for University in the midfield, while Tom Dunn and Phillip Burger booted three goals apiece.
For third-placed Thuringowa, Brodie Flude and Michael Newcombe were their standouts.
In the other AFL Townsville clash Hermit Park proved far too strong for Northern Beaches 21.15 (141) to 4.2 (26).
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Burger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Ireland Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Lahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Beaches 21.15 (141</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Flude</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hermit Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Newcombe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zammi Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thuringowa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
