<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438169841686047</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/josh-and-elyse-have-won-the-main-bathroom-reveal-on-the-block-thanks-to-a-massive-round-bath/news-story/44bd4dc817793737164509e388360549</url>
  <title>Josh and Elyse have won the main bathroom reveal on The Block thanks to a massive round bath</title>
  <content>
The Block - Josh and Elyse's bathroom design
0:30

A look at the bathroom design by Josh and Elyse on The Block. CREDIT: Channel 9/The Block

August 6th 2017
7 minutes ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

The Block contestants. Elyse and Josh from Melbourne. Picture: Jay Town

Colin VickeryNews Corp Australia Network

Share

JOSH and Elyse have won the main bathroom reveal on The Block by a mere half a point.
The Victorian couple, the youngest on this year's season of the Channel 9 renovation show, scored 27 out of 30 to narrowly beat Sticks and Wombat on 26-and-a-half.
It was a tight contest with Ronnie and Georgia scoring 25-and-a-half and Jason and Sarah getting 24 from judges Shaynna Blaze, Neale Whitaker, and Darren Palmer.

The Block - Josh and Elyse are all smiles after winning main bathroom week on The Block. Picture: NineSource:Supplied
But Queensland's Hannah and Clint crashed to a dismal 16 out of 30 because their bathroom wasn't finished in time.
Josh and  secret weapon was the first round bath in the show's 13 seasons. But the pair were on fire all week - the first to waterproof and the first to tile.
"We spent a bit of money on it (round bath) but it paid off," Elyse said after hearing the judges' scores.

The Block - Josh and Elyse's winning bathroom which features the first round bath in the show's history. Picture: NineSource:Supplied
The judges said that Josh and Elyse's bathroom, which also featured a sweeping skylight, was "dramatic". The only downfall was a vanity that was too small meaning the bathroom lacked sufficient storage.
That didn't stop Whitaker scoring the pair 9.5 points, Palmer 9 and Blaze 8.5.
Hannah and Clint, the only team with no previous renovating experience, were at the other end of the spectrum.

The Block contestants. Clint and Hannah didn't finish their bathroom. Picture: Jay TownSource:News Corp Australia
The pair had setbacks including a floor that was too high and walls that hadn't been straightened.
The end result was that a lot of the tiling and grouting wasn't finished by deadline.
"To fall short ... is deflating," Clint said, shedding a tear. "I don't want to embarrass anyone."
Whitaker said the unfinished bathroom was "a great shame because it would have been a superb room".

The Block - Hannah and Clint's bathroom was scored down because the tiling wasn't finished. Picture: NineSource:Supplied
But Whitaker was unimpressed with Hannah and Clint's separate toilet which he said looked "sad".
Sticks and Wombat won praise for the quality of the craftsmanship in their bathroom and their bespoke fittings.

The Block contestants. Wombat and Sticks from NSW. Picture: Jay TownSource:News Corp Australia
"I'm seeing a lot of personality but in an appropriate way," Palmer said.
Ronnie and Georgia were criticised for having only a single basin in a bathroom that potentially had to service three bedrooms.

The Block - Sticks and Wombat's bathroom won high praise for the quality of workmanship. Picture: NineSource:Supplied
Inadequate storage was an issue as was the weird positioning of a power point and the bath spout.
Ronnie's decision to spend $1500 on a portable speaker was derided by Palmer.

The Block - Ronnie and Georgia's bathroom was criticised for the weird placement of bath spout. Picture: NineSource:Supplied
Jason and Sarah flipped their floorplan and hit snags when they lost their tiler and couldn't find a plumber but they won praise for face-level storage, underfloor heating and a heated towel rail.

The Block - Jason and Sarah's bathroom on Channel 9 renovation show. Picture: NineSource:Supplied
"They have chosen well on the big ticket items - bath, vanity, sinks, tapware - but have let themselves down with all the little details," Whitaker said.
Teams now move on to create a guest bedroom.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NineSource</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neale Whitaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitaker</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmer 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blaze 8.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaynna Blaze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronnie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elyse</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Town</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay TownSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin VickeryNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Hannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
