<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438083942339449</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/16/55/melbourne-girl-battling-cancer-granted-football-wish</url>
  <title>A field of dreams: Melbourne girl battling cancer granted football wish</title>
  <content>
Bella Allan has a smile that makes the world brighter.
This is a little girl who has endured more than most girls her age. In fact, more than most people in their life time.
At just eight years old, she's had Leukaemia twice and undergone two bone marrow transplants.
But as long as she can remember she's wanted to play football, like her brother and sister.
Her illness, and constant hospital visits, have made it tough.
But today, she was granted her wish.
Taking to the field for the family's beloved Mt Eliza football club, Bella joined an all-girls team known as the "Fuschias".

Related Articles

As Bella ran around with her friends against a team full of boys, her mother, Alison Allan, watched her daughter blossom.
But Mrs Allan's afternoon of joy has come after just weeks after another heart breaking setback.
One hundred days into remission from her second bout of cancer, Bella was told the disease had returned-  and this time it was worse.
Her family was told it was terminal, but they're not giving up hope.
"That's just a discussion you don't want to have with you eight year old child," Mrs Allan told 9NEWS.
"I sat her down, and that was the first time, death had actually dawned on her," she said.
"But she's strong, she's an amazing girl. She's got a fighting spirit."
That she does.
The game today was the last of the season for the Fuschias,  and they wanted to make it all about Bella. The opposing side, Carrum Downs, was on board- so too the league.
The players donned yellow, Bella's favourite colour.
And after strapping on her boots, and fitting her mouthguard, she ran out through a banner, designed and made, especially for her.
Quite simply it read: "We love you Bella". The crowd did too.
When she ran onto the field at Carrum Downs after quarter time, there was excitement in the outer.
The cold wind had Bella shivering, but this was what she wanted to do.
As she lined up at full forward, her nervous mother watched. A smile grew across her face as the ball approached.
Then, a moment of magic.
Bella gathered, and the players dispersed. This was her chance.
And she took it. A goal. The crowd erupted.
This was what she had wanted, what she had dreamt of.
"It's amazing. The lengths that Mt Eliza footy club and the whole league have gone to, to get our girl out there, to make this happen, is unbelievable," Mrs Allan said.
Just to get her here has been a journey.
For her latest round of treatment she travels to the Peter MacCallum cancer centre every day.
And every day her mum said she turns up with a smile.
"She surprises her oncology team all the time. The path that they think that she's going to follow and the path she chooses to take are different roads," Mrs Allan said.
"She's just tackles everything head on and does exactly what she needs to do to get through each stage."
During her earlier treatments she'd sing Justin Bieber to the nurses. The pop star's management sent a bag of goodies when treatment meant she was unable to attend his concert.
But Bieber is no longer Bella's favourite singer- Ed Sheeran is now the musician of choice.
"She tries to put the cancer thing aside as much as she can. We try to bring her everyday some little bits of normality," Mrs Allan said.
"She went back to school last week for two days. Today she's playing footy. When we can between her treatments we try and bring that normality to her life because that's all she craves."
The community has rallied around the Allan family, raising more than $100,000.
There's more fundraising events in the pipeline, along with a special trip that's promised to wow Bella.
Today, briefly, was a sense of normality.
But it was her day. The crowd cheered her name. The score wasn't counted and it didn't matter.
Even her opponents cheered for her in a heartfelt thanks at the end of the game.
This was Bella's field of dreams, and she was in a field of her own.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrum Downs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Sheeran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter MacCallum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bella Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Eliza</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Bieber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Allan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bella</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bieber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
