<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438182726587993</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/blocks-first-bathrooms-wow-judges/3209232/</url>
  <title>The Block's first bathrooms wow the judges</title>
  <content>
THIS year's season of The Block is shaping up to be the most competitive yet.

Just half a point separated the top two scoring teams in tonight's first room reveals.

It was a tough challenge to deliver a wet room in the first week as the teams were finding their feet on the construction site.

'Model' couple Josh and Elyse took out the top prize with their secret weapon - a massive circular bathtub.

"Let's all have a swim in it," judge Darren Palmer joked. "The design is at a professional level."

But their extra-large main bathroom also featured impressive floor-to-ceiling tiles, a floating ceiling and sky lights.

"If you read these bathrooms as a sign of things to come, then I think we're in for a hell of a ride," Neale Whitaker said.

Sticks and Wombat proved that they shouldn't be underestimated, finishing second by just half a point.

Their symetrical, 'zen' bathroom was a vast improvement on their 48-hour challenge bedroom. The best mates copped a spray for styling their challenge room with the children's book Old Macdonald Heard a Fart.

"Sticks and Wombat have gone from fart to zen in seven days," Darren said.

Neale said the bathroom's bespoke details - a feature tile wall and industrial towel racks - would appeal to buyers.

"Top marks to these guys for giving it a go and doing something different," he said.

"I can't wait to see what these guys do next week."

Feisty renovators Ronnie and Georgia finished third with their classic black, white and gold bathroom.

The judges praised their design and styling, but Shaynna Blaze flagged some practicality issues for the room, which will service three bedrooms, including the single sink, no eye-level storage and a lack of accessible power points around the vanity.

But it was a fancy gold speaker sitting in the corner that divided the judges. Neale said he didn't mind the piece, but Shaynna and Darren worried about such a superfluous purchase.

"In terms of spending on a bathroom week when things are already expensive, I just think it's overkill," Darren said.

"From a budgetary point of view it's not smart."

Melbourne locals Jason and Sarah finished fourth after racing to finish and style their main guest bathroom in the final 10 minutes. 

While the bones of their room were good, the couple was slammed for over-styling.

"What frustrates me in here is they have chosen well on the big ticket items... then they've really let themselves down on all the little details," Neale said.

"They need a serious lesson in styling. I want to move all the clutter out to see the bathroom laid bare."

Hannah and Clint's baptism of fire as the show's renovation newbies continued. Despite a valiant effort, the couple failed to finish their bathroom.

Their big risk of swapping their main bathroom and third bedroom didn't pay off, with issues snowballing throughout the week.

"To fall short over two rooms, yeah, (it's) deflating because you work so hard," a teary Clint said.

But the resilient couple took the criticism from the judges on the chin.

"It would be a nice bathroom if it was finished," Neale said.

"It's a great shame because it would have been a superb room.

"I'm pleased to see this week they've upped the ante and delivered a bathroom that is bold in its intention."

But Neale wasn't so diplomatic about Hannah and Clint's separate toilet, calling the room with its small, strange splash back "mean".

This upcoming week the teams will renovate their first guest bedroom.

The Block week 1 room reveal scores

Josh and Elyse: 27

Sticks and Wombat: 26.5

Ronnie and Georgia: 25.5

Jason and Sarah: 24

Clint and Hannah: 16

Rescue helicopter, SES, firies on scene at Mt Beerwah for rescue
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Leads standings going into final day of action.
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah: 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neale Whitaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah: 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaynna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaynna Blaze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronnie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neale</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elyse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wombat: 26.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Macdonald Heard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elyse: 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia: 25.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
