<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437912143645869</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/lifestyle/judith-jones-the-woman-who-started-the-cookbook-revolution-20170803-gxoh3q</url>
  <title>Judith Jones, the woman who started the cookbook revolution</title>
  <content>
by
Kim Severson

Judith Jones wielded her green editing pencil like a knife. With it, she moulded the manuscripts of a generation of cookbook authors and gave the food world a literary spine, insisting on airtight recipes and visceral prose.
In 1961, when she published Julia Child's much-rejected manuscript for Mastering the Art of French Cooking, Jones could see what others could not: that cooking would soon become a cultural touchstone.
Jones, who died on Wednesday, took a deeply personal interest in her authors in a way that is nearly extinct in today's publishing world. Any food trend that smelled like a fad was dismissed out of hand. Stern, serious and often unmoveable, Jones approached cookbooks like works of literature that happened to contain recipes. Still, the books had to be practical.
"She did not have that sort of abstract, fake literary-tone-poems-about-food thing. She was interested in a real sense of a real cook in the kitchen," said Rux Martin, the cookbook editor who once edited the master herself.

Paul Child/WGBH

"I was terrified," Martin said. "Wouldn't you be?"

It was a sentiment shared by many in her stable at Alfred A. Knopf, where Jones worked from 1957 until she retired in 2013.
Over the years, her roster included fiction writers like John Updike and Anne Tyler, as well as chef Jacques Pepin.
"You did not want to raise her ire," said chef and author Scott Peacock, the chef who would go on to co-write The Gift of Southern Cooking.
He recalled a story that Marion Cunningham, another of Jones' authors, liked to tell about the time she went to Jones' Episcopal Church. Cunningham was a lapsed Roman Catholic, but still mindful that Catholics should take communion only from a Catholic priest.

Supplied

"Once communion commenced, Judith turned to Marion and said, 'Now you know, Marion, you can go up with me and take communion,'" Peacock wrote in an email. "In that moment, Marion said she had to decide who she was more afraid of, God or Judith Jones? Needless to say, she took communion."
Though Jones was an agile fiction and non-fiction editor whose break came when she flagged The Diary of Anne Frank as a book that should be published in English, she built her reputation on finding well-educated, under-appreciated cooks like Cunningham, Marcella Hazan and Madhur Jaffrey, turning them into stars at a time when home cooking and those who practised it were looked down upon in a male-dominated publishing world, and celebrity chefs had yet to grip the nation's imagination.
Ruth Reichl, the author and former editor of American Gourmet magazine, remembers her kindness to the women she edited. Jones, she said, was even kind when she rejected her first memoir, Tender at the Bone.
Jones sent Reichl a note saying that she loved the book because she saw it as a bookend to the works of M.F.K. Fisher. But, she said, she would not buy it because her bosses at Knopf didn't have an appetite for food memoirs at the time.

"I don't think it would be good for you or the book," Jones said. Reichl took her advice and went to another publisher. The book became a best-seller and ushered in the era of the modern food memoir.
"She knew what would be best for the book and she was realistic about it," said Reichl, who called Jones "wonderfully indignant" on matters of food.
"Food started getting serious respect largely because of her," Reichl said. "When you talk about the cookbook revolution, she was the revolution."

Richard Drew/AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marion</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judith Jones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Tyler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred A. Knopf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Updike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Gourmet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gift of Southern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diary of Anne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rux Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cunningham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones' Episcopal Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madhur Jaffrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peacock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacques Pepin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knopf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Catholics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marion Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Drew/AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Child/WGBH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Peacock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reichl</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M.F.K. Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Severson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth Reichl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcella Hazan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art of French</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
