<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438217086326624</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/attempted-armed-attack-at-eiffel-tower/news-story/ff3ee8f2ca12fef6d829690700e207e0</url>
  <title>Attempted armed attack at Eiffel Tower</title>
  <content>
An attempted attack by an armed man at the Eiffel Tower caused police to evacuate the famous Parisian landmark.
The man was arrested on Saturday night and is being held for questioning, police say.
The incident occurred about 11.30 pmlocal time.
The tower, which lets visitors enter until midnight, was evacuated an hour later in what the police source said was a standard precaution.
The company that runs the Eiffel Tower said that a man with an "arme blanche" - a French term for any weapon that is not a firearm - attempted to force his way through one of the security checks at the entrance to the tower.
He was "quickly overcome and arrested," the company said, and there were no injuries.
France has been on high alert since a series of terrorist attacks in 2015 and 2016 that left more than 230 people dead.
Security forces have been attacked several times this year at tourist sites in Paris, which they patrol intensively.
In June 2017, a man attacked police officers with a hammer outside Notre Dame cathedral, injuring one of them.
In April, a police officer was shot dead on the Champs-Elysees by a man with a long criminal record.
In January, a man attacked soldiers on guard near the Louvre museum in Paris with a machete, causing a slight injury to one of them.
Authorities are treating all three of those incidents as terrorism.
City authorities plan to replace the makeshift barriers currently surrounding the Eiffel Tower with bullet-proof glass walls on two sides, and metal fences on the other two.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parisian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Notre Dame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eiffel Towers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louvre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champs Elysees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
