<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437959388286452</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-match-report/showdown-43-adelaide-crows-crush-port-power-to-close-on-top-spot-20170806-gxqhkv.html</url>
  <title>Showdown 43: Adelaide Crows crush Port Power to close on top spot</title>
  <content>
ADELAIDE 
1.9  5.15  12.18 18.22 (130)
PORT ADELAIDE 
1.1   1.3     4.4     7.4    (46)
GOALS - Adelaide: Jenkins 4, Betts 4, Walker 3, Jacobs 2, Sloane, B. Crouch, Laird, Greenwood, Lynch.
Port: Westhoff, Ebert, R. Gray, Polec, Dixon, Homsch.
BEST - Adelaide: Sloane, Jacobs, Walker, M. Crouch, Smith, Betts Laird, Jenkins.
Port: R. Gray, Ryder, Ebert, Boak, Wines, Pittard.
INJURIES: Adelaide: Mackay (corked thigh).
UMPIRES: Dalgleish,  Stevic, Stephens.
CROWD: 45,028 at Adelaide oval. 
 
It's a rare event in the 43-game history of Showdowns that Port Adelaide are made to look like they're dancing with their sisters - cautious about getting too close - and allow the Crows to dominate them for most of the contest.Photo: AAP/David Mariuz
Missing were the constant rough 'n tumbles (outside of the ground, too) and ferocious tackles these sides had nearly always produced, and it was only Adelaide's appalling kicking for goal in the first half that prevented an all-out slaughter.
The Crows were magnificent in their crushing win over Port, and as the records tumbled the impact of this result became greater for both sides.Photo: AAP/David Mariuz
Adelaide have all but sealed top spot - guaranteeing two home finals. In Showdowns, Adelaide have now won a club record five straight - every contest since the death of their coach Phil Walsh in 2015, and for the first time since 2008 lead the ledger - 42-41. The Crows also held Port to their equal lowest half-time score 1.3 - to 5.15.
Port are now one of seven clubs separated by just one win and fighting for a probable three remaining finals spots and face Collingwood (AO), Western Bulldogs (Canberra) and Gold Coast Suns (AO) in the run home.

Given the obvious rewards at stake, it seemed puzzling why Port persisted playing three extra defenders at the centre clearances. It didn't work because the Crows were too focused, worked incredibly well as a team, hit their targets more often, played more intelligent football and for most part were more aggressive. A change of tactics came too late to have any real effect on the end result.
The Power also spent so much effort on trying to curtail the effectiveness of Rory Sloane at the stoppages that they seemed to lose focus on getting their own game going. The results were remarkable - Sloane had more disposals than any Port player up to half-time, and Adelaide smashed the Power up to this stage with 93 more disposals, 32 more inside-50 entries, 32 more contested and 63 uncontested possessions.Photo: AAP/David Mariuz
And again, imagine if Adelaide kicked straight. The game was all but over by half-time.
The Crows were as brilliant in miserable conditions as Port were awful, and one questions whether the Power would deserve to a finals spot given their inability to rise to heights of competitiveness that Showdowns have long promised and delivered.
Teams often have horror starts, but Port never really responded. Their second goal came eight minutes into the third quarter, and from the centre bounce Brad Crouch replied with a goal from inside the square.
Port's best showing of pace was by a ground invader, seconds after Eddie Betts kicked one of his freakish goals from a pocket, this time at the southern end. The subtlety of the contrast was not missed by the Crows' home crowd. Forgive the sarcasm.
Angus Monfries had a tough night - understandably given that this was his first game for almost two years - but nonetheless it will be interesting whether Port persists with him in the run home.
Adelaide had a host of outstanding contributors, including Taylor Walker. His exemplary on-field leadership, especially marshalling his troops and tempering the play when required, was significant, as were his goals.
The Crouch brothers were very good again, as were Richard Douglas and the superb defenders, especially Rory Laird, Brodie Smith and Jake Lever.
Paddy Ryder has been widely touted as an All-Australian ruckman this year, but for most part he was beaten by Sam Jacobs. Also, for a side that has been widely condemned for having a weakness midfield the Crows certainly showed a lot in this area.
Adelaide is obviously an exciting and brilliant side at their best. Their pressure was again phenomenal and after their 1.9 opening term were able to find a host of goalkickers. And they slaughtered Port with continued impressive efforts of rookies from other sports, Hugh Greenwood and Alex Keath.
Another remarkable thing about this game was that 45,028 fans turned up despite the cruel winds and rain. For most, it was worthwhile, but not for the ground invader in the Port top, who faces a $5000 fine.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M. Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/David Mariuz</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Sloane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B.Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betts 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ebert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westhoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stevic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sloane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Keath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R. Gray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Laird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenkins 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pittard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacobs 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angus Monfries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betts Laird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Greenwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalgleish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
