<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438311575608164</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/queensland-towing-reforms-to-bar-violent-sexual-criminals/news-story/b8c082e832320f7f8455911a26bd7d64</url>
  <title>Criminals locked out of industry</title>
  <content>
PEOPLE convicted of violent, sexual and drug-related crimes will be banned from working in Queensland's towing industry under a long-awaited crackdown.
Acting Main Roads Minister Steven Miles said the Palaszczuk Government will rush new laws through Parliament based on recommendations from retired District Court judge Michael Forde's investigation into dodgy towing practices.
Cabinet is on Monday set to sign off on a new licensing system that would prohibit certain people from working in the industry and would fine or ban those found to be breaking new laws through intimidation and predatory practices.
Mr Forde recommended authorities consider a person's character, including any criminal offences, in handing out licences.
"One matter that I was concerned with was young female drivers at night-time having to retrieve their cars from these holding yards in the darker parts of the city, that those tow truck operators not be convicted of those sorts of offences, violence included," he said.
Mr Forde said his changes - including capping impound release fees at $250 - would make the industry less lucrative for seven or eight problem companies.
But the retired judge resisted recommending new laws prescribing signage to warn parkers they risked being towed.
He said it was still up to drivers to check but property owners risked legal action if they allowed cars to be removed from lots without providing clear signs warning people when they would be towed.
"If they are not clear, they may be prosecuted criminally, or they may be prosecuted civilly," he said.
Dr Miles said the Government would move "as quickly as we can" to get the laws through Parliament, adding that Mr Forde had already provided drafting instructions for the Bill.
"These are all very sensible recommendations," he said. "I'll certainly be recommending to Cabinet that we accept all of them."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads Minister Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Forde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Forde</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
