<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438307280640768</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/canberra-prodigy-annerly-poulos-wants-to-become-the-next-serena-williams-20170803-gxp3d0.html</url>
  <title>Canberra prodigy Annerly Poulos wants to become the next Serena Williams</title>
  <content>
 Canberra's tennis prodigy Annerly Poulos is only 14 but she knows what she wants - to become the next Serena Williams.
The teenager is in Europe for the first time and getting a taste of the professional circuit as she prepares to represent Australia at the world junior tennis titles in the Czech Republic on Monday.Photo: Graham Clews
Poulos blitzed the Asian qualifying rounds earlier this year with an unbeaten record as the Australian number one seed and now gets her chance against the world's best.
"This is my second time representing Australia and it's a great feeling. You're just really proud of yourself and what you've achieved and knowing that this is something to get you used to for what's ahead," Poulos said.
"I don't really focus on that stuff [expectation]. I just go day by day and train hard and hopefully if I keep working hard enough I'll continue to achieve my goal of playing for Australia.
"All the tournaments here are so professional and all of the top players in the world right now have played in these tournaments, so it's a really special moment."

Poulos has been touted as Australia's next great tennis hope and the teenager said she wants to emulate her favourite player Williams.
"In the women's my favourite player is definitely Serena Williams, I love her game a personality and everything she does is so inspiring," Poulos said.
"At this tournament I just want to learn from our matches that we play so we can build on the things we need to work on and improve as tennis player so I can hopefully be like Serena one day.
"It's nice to experience difference players around the world and see how they play and getting a taste of what it's like to travel and play different tournaments like on the pro circuit.
"It's not about winning the tournament, it's about learning from this experience and bettering our personality and skills in tennis and doing everything to become a professional tennis player."
Tennis Australia coach Todd Lakrham - who mentored Nicky Kyrgios for a decade - said Poulos has the ability to make it and a professional career is there if she wants it.
"She's very talented and has been very good from a young age. She's proved she's the best in asia in the under-14 category and now we'll see where's she's at against others in the world," Larkham said.
"We see a lot of talented kids around this age and there's a lot of water under the bridge between 14 and 20, she has the tennis ability but the difference will be how bad she wants it and how hard she's willing to work.
"It's a bit too early to call, particularly with girls, she's won a lot of matches and tracking really well but we'll see hwo she goes over the next few years, she can make it but it'll be up to her."
Larkham said Tennis Australia provides young athletes with all the tools they need to make it at the professional level and the rest is up to them.
"We make it very clear to all the players we coach that we're providing an unbelievable opportunity and great facilities and hours on court and the ability to travel around the world, but it's up to them how far they want to take it," Larkham said.
"Our philosophy at Tennis Australia is to create good environments for athletes to develop in and then they decide how determined they are to make it."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Czech Republic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serena Williams</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Lakrham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Clews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annerly Poulos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larkham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poulos</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennis Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicky Kyrgios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
