<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438302985673401</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/national/south-east-australia-warned-to-brace-for-a-major-winter-storm-this-weekend/news-story/562979609985c5b6cf6be61b2a0802d4</url>
  <title>Flood warning for Adelaide Hills</title>
  <content>
THE SES is warning of localised flooding for parts of the Adelaide Hills as creeks and rivers rapidly fill after strong winds and rain lashed parts of. The worst isn't over yet, with more warnings of wind and rain.
Strong winds and rain have lashed many parts of SA - including Adelaide - uprooting trees and damaging buildings as a secondary strong cold front swept in during the weekend.
The SES says there is a risk of localised flooding for the Upper Onkaparinga River, impacting on roads and homes upstream of Verdun.
They said people in the area should follow their emergency flood plan now and prepare your family or home for flooding in the area. If it is safe to do so, clear drains and gutters around your home.
To see all current flood alerts,
Several trees have been uprooted, including one at West Lakes that crashed on to the roof of a home on Sunday morning. Further south, strong winds have damaged the roof of the West Beach Surf Life Saving Club.
Footy fans heading forcopped a heavy drenching as gates opened but the wild weather didn't seem to keep the crowds away.
About 1000 homes lost power earlier but most of those homes have now had electricity restored.

An elderly man has collided with tram in Adelaide during wild storms. Courtesy: Sunrise

Elderly man collides with tram during Adelaide storms
The SES has received dozens of calls for help this weekend as gale force winds, thunderstorms and heavy rains moved across the state.
A new severe weather warning for damaging winds and heavy rainfall was reissued this afternoon for Adelaide Metropolitan, Mount Lofty Ranges, Yorke Peninsula, Mid North, Kangaroo Island, Riverland, Murraylands, Upper South East, and Lower South East districts.
Bureau of Meteorology senior forecaster Tom Boeck also warned that the low-pressure system could bring thunder and hail.
The bureau says damaging wind gusts of more than 90km/h are possible - associated with showers and thunderstorms. A wind gust of 90 km/h was recorded at Cape Borda and Parndana on KI this morning, while winds averaging 63 km/h were recorded at Minlaton during the early afternoon.
Warnings for the Lower Eyre Peninsula and parts of the Eastern Eyre Peninsula districts are no longer current.
The threat of destructive winds south of Port Pirie has also reduced.
The SES advises the threat to exposed or elevated parts of the state south of the Mid North town has been downgraded.
However, the organisation says safety risks remain and urges people to keep clear of fallen trees. power lines and damaged buildings.
There have been numerous reports of damage to trees through the Mount Lofty Ranges.
Heavy rainfall in the Mount Lofty Ranges may lead to flash flooding, and the SES issued a flood watch for the Upper Onkaparinga, especially around Verdun.
Locations that may be affected include Adelaide, Kingscote, Maitland, Mount Gambier, Port Pirie, Clare, Murray Bridge, and Naracoorte.
Once again the SES has advised those affected to stay indoors and away from windows, warning "you are in danger from flying debris, falling trees and downed powerlines".
"Roads may be dangerous, do not travel unless absolutely necessary."
The Bureau advises you should:
■ Move vehicles under cover and away from trees
■ Secure or put away loose items around your property
■ Stay indoors and keep away from widows when conditions are severe.
Over the weekend until Tuesday, Mt Lofty is expected to receive up to 70mm rainfall in total, with 40mm over the south coast district.
The wet weather will ease on Monday.
During last night's wild weather, a car hit a tram at the Bonython Park station just after 8pm.
No one was injured and the tram had minor damage.
The wild winds also led to a rainwater tank breaking its moorings and crashing into the roof of a Sandergrove house in the state's south east.
The owner of the home, who didn't want to be named, said the half-full tank rolled down a hill, through a fence before smashing into their roof.
"It's horrendous, absolutely horrendous," the woman said. "It is like being in a cyclone".
Fortunately no one was hurt.
Meanwhile, Port Elliot resident Abbie Milnes returned to her home from Adelaide on Saturday afternoon to find a veranda had partially collapsed.
"It can't be fixed at the moment, but the worst of it seems to have passed, so so far all good,'' she said.

Netballers brave the storm on Kangaroo Island. Credit: Facebook/Shauna Black

Netballers brave the storm on Kangaroo Island
Locals reported fallen trees across the metropolitan area, including Bedford Park, Meadows, West Beach, Noarlunga and Aldgate while there was localised flooding in Aberfoyle Park, Para Vista and O'Sullivans Beach.
A tree fell across Shepherds Hill Rd at Eden Hills, prompting SES and MFS to ask motorists to avoid the area, and about 300 properties lost power.
A wind gust of 91 km/h was reported at Strathalbyn at 5:30 pm.
Neptune Islands recorded damaging winds averaging 69km/h with gusts reaching 106km/h on Saturday afternoon.
Cape Borda on Kangaroo Island received nearly 23mm of rainfall since 9am on Saturday while closer to Adelaide Kuitpo 14mm.
State Emergency Service volunteers spent Saturday filling sandbags in preparation for strong winds and possible flooding later today.
The SES received more than 61 phone calls, mainly before 8pm Saturday, and is gearing up for another busy day.
Sandbags will also be available at 10am on Sunday across six SES units.
■ Enfield SES Unit - Hoods Rd, Northfield
■ Noarlunga SES Unit - Corner of Lindsay and Brian roads, Londsale
■ Metro South SES Unit - 33 Beagle St, Lynton
■ Campbelltown SES Unit - 141 Montacute Rd, Campbelltown
■ Mount Barker SES Unit - 14 Simper Cres, Mount Barker
■ Port Adelaide-Enfield council depot - Willochra St, Largs North
On Saturday, SES Mt Barker unit operations response manager Stuart Catt said they had 30 cars come through in the first two and a half hours.
"Today is actually rather busy," he said.

SES volunteers at Mt Barker fill sandbags in readiness for a cold front that was expected to bring damaging winds and cause flooding in the Adelaide Hills on Saturday.

SES volunteers fill sandbags at Mt Barker
"We've gone through roughly four tonnes of sand already."
Mr Catt said the SES was encouraging people to prepare for 80mm of rain across the Mt Lofty Ranges as predicted by the Bureau of Meteorology.
"There could be localised thunderstorms with severe wind as well," he said.
"We're actually really glad that people are turning up and being prepared because it means the workload during the storm will be less for us."
Mr Catt said during the storm, people should stay indoors and away from trees.
"If it does get wet, call 132500 or if there is water in your house call triple-0," he said.
"We are on standby for tonight and tomorrow and possibly into Monday morning at this stage.
Mt Barker resident Terry was at the SES collecting sandbags and said she experienced flooding in her garage a few weeks ago as well as last winter.
"I thought I should do something about it," she said.
Stirling father Michael Newbury, 41, said his family were preparing for the heavy rainfall by using sandbags to prevent water run-off from the road going down their driveway.
"Last September we lost an entire cliff at our house and we spent seven months not living at home and having a team of bulldozers rebuild it," he said.
"We're just making sure it doesn't collapse again.
"We've got hoses on the lawn siphoning the water off to stop the water building up there and we've tried to clear away anything that could get blown away in the wind me do damage.
Mr Newbury had also cleared away trees and branches from around his house so "nothing could hit it".

SKY NEWS Weather: Major winter storm

SKY NEWS Weather: Major winter storm
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verdun</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Barker SES Unit - 14 Simper Cres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Gambier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper South East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Lofty Ranges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Beach Surf Life Saving Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corner of Lindsay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enfield SES Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorke Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News Weather</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingscote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willochra St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbie Milnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Emergency Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Lofty Ranges</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Sullivans Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Metropolitan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Island</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook/Shauna Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Eyre Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Newbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro South SES Unit - 33 Beagle St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper Onkaparinga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Para Vista</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Boeck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoods Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedford Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Newbury, 41</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown SES Unit - 141 Montacute Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Eyre Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Pirie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minlaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Borda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Elliot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Catt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES Mt Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Kuitpo 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower South East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noarlunga SES Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neptune Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide Enfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EDEN HILLS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murraylands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Lofty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Londsale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonython Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Largs North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shepherds Hill Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldgate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper Onkaparinga River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noarlunga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathalbyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mid-North</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aberfoyle Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandergrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Barker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naracoorte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Catt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parndana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
