<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437482646912329</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836231/raising-historic-flag/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Raising historic flag</title>
  <content>
Happy: Andrew Smith greets Amiia Kelly. Aliah, 11, Alyssa, 7, Helen Cummings, Kate Washington and Nuatali Nelmes. Picture: Max Mason Hubers

FORMER Newcastle lord mayor Joy Cummings' landmark decision to fly the Aboriginal flag from City Hall has been celebrated 40 years later as a turning point in the Indigenous community's fight for recognition.

A crowd of about 60 - including representatives from the Awabakal and Worimi tribes; current lord mayor Nuatali Nelmes; and other politicians - gathered at Civic Park on Sunday morning to pay tribute to the late Mrs Cummings and again raise the red, black and yellow flag.
Awbakal Ltd board member Ray Kelly Senior said Mrs Cummings was "incredibly brave" to make Newcastle the country's first council to fly the flag from a civic building and said it heralded "the dawning of a new time". "People thought 'We've been agitating for a long time, we've been talking and somebody is finally listening'," Dr Kelly said. "The raising of the flag was acknowledgement we were there. We honour the older people who have gone before us, but we also recognise we are still fighting for justice, for appropriate rights, for the individuals who can't fight for themselves."
Cr Nelmes said Mrs Cummings "made history" and put Newcastle "forever on the map". "We know Joy met significant resistance from a number of Aldermen on council and she did not have majority support to raise that flag above City Hall but she did it anyway," Cr Nelmes said. "The history of the Aboriginal flag and the flag's relationship to the city of Newcastle is long and rich and intrinsically linked to our city's history as a progressive city, with people who care deeply about social justice and equality."
Mrs Cummings' daughter Helen was joined by about 17 family members to mark the anniversary. She said her parents had a "sincere and deep respect" for Aboriginal people and raising the flag had been the most "emotional and meaningful" milestones of her mother's career.
"We must listen hard and learn because you have so much to teach us," she told Indigenous attendees. "I'm sorry we have not achieved more, but from my mob to your mob thank you for who you are and for caring for this land for over 60,000 years."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amiia Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyssa, 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Awbakal Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aliah, 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Kelly Senior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joy Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Awabakal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nuatali Nelmes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Cummings</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Worimi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Nelmes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
