<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438479079334181</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/adelaide/adelaide-coach-don-pyke-says-crows-still-have-room-to-improve-after-showdown-demolition/news-story/871d70b7c568d513406f2a1cf7c78eae</url>
  <title>Pyke says Crows not getting carried away</title>
  <content>
CROWS coach Don Pyke hailed his team's record Showdown 43 demolition job on Port Adelaide and then sent an ominous warning to the rest of the competition.
"We can play better,'' Pyke declared after .
"We're not sitting here (thinking that they've peaked) because self-satisfaction doesn't lead to progress.
"We understand that we played some really strong, powerful footy tonight but I'll go back seven days and we were 50 points down against Collingwood.
MICHELANGELO RUCCI:
"The competition is that even and we've got to continually strive to get better because if we don't and stand still others will go past us.
"These guys (players) are driven to get better, so our challenge from a coaching viewpoint is to look at where we are going well and where we need to get better because the challenges will keep coming.''
With a top-four spot officially locked up with three rounds to play, top-of-the-table Adelaide is keen to finish minor premier to "give ourselves the best opportunity come finals''.
Adelaide's record Showdown win, which beat the 83 points it won the only SA derby final by in 2005, was achieved on the back of a remarkable 81-31 inside-50 count.
"That's pretty unusual,'' Pyke said of the statistic that emphasised the Crows' complete control of the match.
Adelaide, which won every quarter, had 40 scoring shots to Port's 11 and won contested possession by 46 just a week after being smashed by 50 in that area in the draw against Collingwood.
"It was a pretty solid performance all-round,'' Pyke said.
"I thought our intent and pressure was back to a level, we dropped away a bit last week, but to the players' credit they responded really strongly.
"We've been working on consistency through games and over the four quarters there wasn't a let-off, we maintained the intensity around the ball and the pressure that allows you to get the outcome.''
Pyke praised his side's total team performance.
While Port coach Ken Hinkley said his side had only one good player, midfield-forward magician Robbie Gray, the Crows had strong contributions from all but injured David Mackay, who was hurt in the first quarter.
"That's how we play our best footy,'' Pyke said.
"If you look back on our performances this year, when we've had a really even contribution we generally get a pretty good result.
"This was no exception. It would be hard to find too many guys who didn't contribute in some way towards that result - and that's how we want to play.''
Pyke was buoyed by the performance of his midfield group, which has been labelled as the Crows' biggest weakness.
"Our midfield is an area that's grown,'' he said.
"At the start of the year there were questions about our midfield but they just keep taking on the challenges and keep getting better and better. It's been good to see their growth.''
Adelaide, which plays Essendon at Etihad Stadium on Saturday night, suffered just the one injury - a corked thigh to Mackay.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyke</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHELANGELO RUCCI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Pyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port's 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
