<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437740344952344</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/sa-pole-vaulter-kurtis-marschall-set-for-world-athletics-championships/news-story/94d9629ce1db0b6c9185350128ecb075</url>
  <title>Ready to take on the world</title>
  <content>
THE man behind Kurtis Marschall's journey to the world athletics championships says the SA pole vaulter feels at home alongside the superstars of the sport.
Marschall, 20, will line up for qualifying at London Stadium on Sunday night as he continues his emergence on the international stage.
His Adelaide-based coach Kym Simons said his star pupil was in peak physical and mental condition after setting a new personal best of 5.73m in Switzerland last month.
"He's quietly confident," Simons said from London.
"He has been vaulting in good form in the recent meets he's been in and he's loved competing with the best in the world.
"Upon arrival here in Europe, he's grown quite comfortable in their presence and believes he belongs competing with them."
Marschall, of Happy Valley, announced himself to the world last year when he qualified for the Rio Olympics after winning his first national senior title in April.
The Western Districts Athletics Club member narrowly missed the final in Brazil with a clearance of 5.6m, but has since taken his craft to new heights.
Marschall's PB at the IAAF Diamond League event in Lausanne earned him a fourth-place finish behind Olympic silver medallist Ranaud Lavillenie and world No.1 rank Sam Kendricks.
Simons said Marschall was solely focused on obtaining a top-12 qualifying mark in London to advance to Wednesday's final.
"It's almost suicide to treat the qualifying round as a formality, you can never afford to do that," said Simons, who began working with Marschall seven years ago.
"You must always treat it with the seriousness that it deserves and Kurtis will.
"He's got an air of confidence about him.
"You wouldn't call it cocky - it's the confidence that athletes of any sport have when they have self belief.
"Without that you would fail."
Marschall and Simons have spent the past month competing and training in Europe.
The pair last week moved into the Australian team camp at Tonbridge, one hour south of London.
Long-term athletics mentor Simons, himself a national-level vaulter in the 1980s, said his young charge had the ability and dedication to challenge for the highest honours.
"He was a good pole vaulter when he started, but he didn't naturally beat everybody," Simons said.
"But he's always applied himself, not just physically but mentally, so he can improve to get that little bit better.
"He doesn't half do it, he does it completely.
"He knows what he wants and goes that little bit extra to get the extra result."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lausanne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ranaud Lavillenie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonbridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kym Simons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Districts Athletics Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAAF Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall, of Happy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kendricks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Switzerland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall's PB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
