<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438268625934629</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-06/bulldogs-defender-hopeful-his-season-isnt-over</url>
  <title>Bulldogs defender hopeful his season isn't over</title>
  <content>
Easton Wood is hopeful his hamstring injury won't stop him playing finals

WESTERN Bulldogs defender Easton Wood hasn't given up hope of playing again this season, with scans to reveal how bad his latest hamstring injury is.

The Bulldogs vice-captain has a history of hamstring problems, but hadn't been affected this season until the first quarter of Saturday's win over the Brisbane Lions at the Gabba.

The 27-year-old missed six weeks with the injury last season before returning to lead the club to the flag in the absence of captain Robert Murphy.

Speaking at Melbourne Airport on crutches upon returning from Brisbane, Wood conceded he was "a little bit sore", but hopeful his 2017 campaign wasn't over.

"I'm disappointed but we don't know what the extent of the injury is yet," Wood told Channel Seven.

"I've done a few (hamstrings), and it didn't feel great, so we'll wait and see how bad it is."

With the Dogs needing to win at least two of their remaining three matches to qualify for finals, that scenario would give Wood a month to recover for a possible elimination final in the second week of September.

Like in 2016, the bye round before the first week of finals could again aid Wood in a tilt at the flag.

The extra time off last year allowed him to recover from an ankle injury - and several other teammates from varying concerns - in time for the elimination final win over West Coast.

"(The week off before finals) does give you that extra little bit of a cushion," Wood said.

"Once we find out what the damage is, hopefully there will be enough time to get back."

While the loss of the 2015 All Australian is a massive blow to the Dogs' chances of going back-to-back, it's likely to be offset by the return of Jake Stringer.  

Sidelined for the past three weeks, the dynamic forward was also struck down by a hamstring injury but is likely to be available for Friday night's huge encounter against fierce rival Greater Western Sydney.

Midfielder Josh Dunkley could also come into consideration to face the Giants, after collecting 26 disposals and a goal in his VFL return from a long-term shoulder injury.

Premiership defender Fletcher Roberts has been dropped twice already this season, but he may be given a reprieve after the injuries to Wood, Dale Morris (broken arm) and Marcus Adams (fractured foot).
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dunkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton Wood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
