<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438302985673397</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/opinion/voters-concerns-about-housing-affordability-reflects-a-political-disconnect-20170806-gxqa35</url>
  <title>Voters' concerns about housing affordability reflects a political disconnect</title>
  <content>
The thing that most exercises Australians, according to the Fairfax-Ipsos focus groups, is housing affordability.
There is some sort of irony that the thing that concerns voters most is an issue about which neither side of politics really has any answers: not on the scale voters want to see.
Labor has talked about negative gearing and capital gains. There have been subtle changes - which many voters would be oblivious to - to the rules governing banking and foreign investment.
But the sheer demands of a growing population and a tax system that shifts the weights in favour of housing investment - whether owner occupied or as investment property - makes these pretty paltry influences.

Yet while our focus groups say this is the thing that concerns them most,  - except perhaps for one voter who said a government could just put a "massive tax on foreign investment in housing".

And this reflects the very, very deep disillusion and disconnect between voters and the political debate reflected in these groups.
At the one end is the housing affordability issue.
At the other end is .
Gay marriage: 'It has to happen'

Voters' views on this were summed up by one participant who said "obviously it has to happen". "I feel like it's coming. Why is this such a big deal? It's just such a non-issue, right?"
In a policy sense, Labor would have drawn a lot more comfort from the issues concerning voters than the Coalition, simply because the opposition appears to better talking voters' language: housing affordability, childcare, schooling, infrastructure, public transport. alternative energy, hospitals, marriage equality.
Widespread anger about electricity privatisations - and the promises that were made that these would reduce energy prices - is striking.
The policy issues that aren't discussed - or which are discussed in terms of people feeling they are either not relevant or have been overplayed - are equally striking: terrorism, tax cuts, innovation. A few people said they had changed their votes because they were concerned about debt and deficits but are now dismissive of the idea the Coalition has any better grip on this than Labor.

So much for the policy concerns. The message about our political system and our political system is even more dire.
Disillusion, cynicism, disconnection are all good descriptors, whether it is in the way voters link housing affordability to rich politicians renting from their wives, or in the general sense that politicians are working for themselves not voters.
Just lead

But it is striking in this conversation that, while the media and Parliament house conversation revolves so much around leaders, voters don't particularly think that way.

They are disappointed with Malcolm Turnbull but they don't like or trust Bill Shorten. And contempt is the only word to describe their view of Tony Abbott's destructive contributions.
Voters want a leader to do that: just lead. They give points to Donald Trump and Pauline Hanson for saying what they think even if the voters think it's nuts.
Somebody needs to take charge, our voters tell us.
"Malcolm Turnbull is a brilliant man encumbered by his party", one voter says. "I think he needs to be able to say 'OK, enough is enough'. This is my policy and I'm the head of the government."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax-Ipsos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
