<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438298690706040</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/geelong-captain-joel-selwood-to-have-ankle-surgery-but-expected-back-for-finals-20170806-gxqg53.html</url>
  <title>Geelong captain Joel Selwood to have ankle surgery but expected back for finals</title>
  <content>
Geelong's hopes of a top-four finish - and perhaps a shot at a premiership - have been rocked with skipper Joel Selwood to undergo ankle surgery.
The Cats revealed on Sunday Selwood would have surgery on his left ankle, having suffered a syndesmosis injury during Friday night's loss to the Swans at Simonds Stadium.

Up Next

AFL plays of round 20

01:33

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Swans slay Cats to make finals statement

Sydney have maintained control over their finals destiny with a convincing 107-61 win over Geelong at Simonds Stadium.

He will miss the final three home-and-away matches and is no guarantee to return for the start of the finals. The bye between round 23 and the opening week of the finals could prove to be crucial in his recovery.
"Selwood will not be available for the remaining three home-and-away games but is expected to be able to return for the finals series," the Cats said in a statement.Photo: AAP
He initially hurt the ankle when he stood on the foot of teammate Zac Smith in a marking contest approaching half-time. Having passed a fitness test at the main break, he returned in the third term but more trouble was to come when he aggravated the injury when his foot was caught under a Lance Franklin tackle. He started the final term on the field, but soon went to the bench and remained there for the rest of the game.
Coach Chris Scott said on Friday night he expected Selwood would be able to play this week.

"I'm actually confident enough now to say he'll be fine," he said.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

However, the diagnosis changed over the weekend when the hardnut midfielder was on crutches and sent to see specialists. It was felt the best move was to have surgery.Photo: AAP/Julian Smith
A syndesmosis injury is described as a high ankle sprain, involving the lower tibia and fibula just above the ankle joint.
Selwood will miss the blockbuster against Richmond on Saturday at Simonds Stadium, a clash against Collingwood at the MCG and the round-23 home match against heavyweight Greater Western Sydney.
The Cats are fighting for a top-four spot and the loss of Selwood will hurt. They will regain Patrick Dangerfield this week from a one-week suspension but could lose key forward Tom Hawkins who faces scrutiny for a jumper punch on Swan Dane Rampe. Hawkins was suspended for a week for a similar incident on Adelaide Crow Matt Crouch earlier this year.
The Cats already had injury concerns for Steven Motlop, Daniel Menzel, Nakia Cockatoo and Mark Blicavs were absent over the weekend.
Cockatoo has a "significant" hamstring tear but the Cats hope he will still be a factor this season.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan Dane Rampe. Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cockatoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Motlop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Blicavs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Julian Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crow Matt Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nakia Cockatoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Menzel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
