<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438384590052918</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/northern-fury-thrilled-with-stylish-victory-over-brisbane-roar-youth/news-story/0db3d7b616d3b8433efd5de1d533c8ff</url>
  <title>Fury thrilled with big win over Roar</title>
  <content>
PROUD Northern Fury coach Paul Roncato says his side gave the Brisbane Roar Youth an "absolute soccer lesson" on their way to a crushing 5-1 victory in Brisbane on Sunday afternoon.
Jarrod Green scored a double while captain Corey Waples also found the net in his 100th NPL appearance as the Fury outclassed the young Roar across the park.
Kyren Walters opened the scoring in the 14th minute as he pushed in behind the Roar defence before Hamish Cassady got in on the action and Waples nailed his strike from the penalty spot.
Nathan Yoon finished off a cut back to give the Roar some hope in the 38th minute, but Green came up with an immediate reply from close range to give the Fury a 4-1 halftime lead.
Green then made it a double when pounced on a nice ball across the face of goal shortly after the break and they never let the home side get back in the contest.
It was a satisfying victory for the Fury after they were denied full points in Townsville earlier this season when the Brisbane side couldn't field a team for the trip north and chose to forfeit.
Roncato was still beaming when he spoke with the Townsville Bulletin after the game, describing it as a well-deserved victory for the Fury.
"We give them an absolute soccer lesson," the coach said.
"We came down very determined because we got ripped off the first time when they said couldn't come down with competitive side and we wanted to spank the Roar.
"We missed five or six really good opportunities so it could have easily gone into double figures.
"The Roar were full strength with squad of about 25 players and even the assistant coach for the A-League side was there watching our great display.
"It was just an outstanding performance all over the park from everybody. I couldn't have been any prouder."
The Fury will need to refocus before a huge challenge against third-placed Brisbane Olympic in Ayr this weekend, but Roncato said they had a renewed sense of confidence after thumping the Roar.
"It's been a bit of rollercoaster ride for us this year, but it's great to see what we're capable of doing when we do play the football that we know we can play," Roncato said.
"To come down (to Brisbane) and win away is a great achievement and we believe now we can go into our last two games with a heap of confidence."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Yoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Roar Youth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NORTHERN Fury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Roncato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Cassady</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Waples</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roncato</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roar</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyren Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waples</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
