<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438393179987541</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/tough-calls-to-be-made-for-falcons/3209415/</url>
  <title>Tough calls to be made for Falcons</title>
  <content>
RUGBY LEAGUE: Frustrated coach Craig Ingebrigtsen says there will be changes to his team after an upset loss to Mackay.
The Falcons' roster is set to get a shake-up following the 30-26 state league defeat in north Queensland on Saturday night.
"If you do the same you get the same," he said.
"So, at the end of the day, we've got to make some changes in our group and they are going to be tough changes to make but we've got to go there and make a call and be tough enough to do that."
And no-one in the team is safe.
"Every player now, I don't care who they are, they are on alert," he said.
"If their performance isn't good enough we'll just make changes and we'll look forward to whatever happens."
The Falcons headed into round 22 of 25 in a confident and positive mindset, placed in second spot on the 14-team ladder, but the loss has severely hampered the run to the finals.
The side is now third and in line to miss out on a first-round bye in play-offs.
"The players just don't get the opportunity that presented itself (Saturday) and now, instead of having one game to win to get to the grand final, they have got to win three (in finals)," Ingebrigtsen said of his team.
"There's no sugar-coating it, we are now in trouble."
It was a rough night for the Falcons, which not only started slow again to be down 24-4 at half-time but the side may lose Tui Kamikamica and Harrison Muller for coming games after they were placed on report.
"Both have been really good for us so it's going to hurt our footy team but again, it is what it is," Ingebrigtsen said.
"Our discipline is poor, our footy is poor, our defence is poor and our start is poor.
"There's no pulling any punches, we're just being honest and realistic."
Ingebrigtsen believed the Falcons had the talent and were 'a good bunch of blokes' but needed to be accountable for the poor performances.
The Falcons have lost four of  their past seven games, with the side's slow starts becoming a familiar weakness.
"It's something only the playing group can fix and they've got to fix it and be accountable for it," he said.
"We've only got two games of footy left (in the regular season) so they need to fix it and fix it in a hurry."
Ingebrigtsen took comfort in the fact the Falcons' three-week long stint on the road had come to end.
He hoped supporters would turn out in force in a sign of support for the side.
"We've been on the road for a long time and we've been on a plane every weekend, and it's no excuse, but it'd be good to be at home and get around some familiar surrounds," he said.
The Falcons will take on the Devils at the Sunshine Coast Stadium on Saturday (4.30pm).
"We've got a real tough finish - Norths have got nothing to lose and then we've got the Blackhawks so we are in for a tough, torrid time," he said.
The Redcliffe Dolphins are now second after defeating Norths Devils.
Nearly 4000 people attend concert at stadium
Rescue helicopter, SES, firies on scene at Mt Beerwah for rescue
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Netflix health doco slammed for scaremongering, 'cherrypicking' data
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Ingebrigtsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackhawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norths Devils</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redcliffe Dolphins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingebrigtsen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tui Kamikamica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday (4.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrison Muller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUGBY LEAGUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
