<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437783294625744</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/passengers-forced-to-wait-three-hours-in-townsville/news-story/3dc0cb9939c4ece6e218f710360eeace</url>
  <title>Engineering issues ground flight</title>
  <content>
TIGERAIR passengers were left waiting on the tarmac in Townsville for about three hours today after the plane suffered engineering issues.
The service from Townsville to Melbourne was supposed to leave at 11.45am however a fault indicator appeared twice in the cockpit during the "push back" process.
The flight was then cancelled and is scheduled to depart at 9.30am tomorrow.
Townsville resident Bernadette Smith, who had purchased $69 airfares earlier this year, said it was disappointing.
"We planned a four-day trip down, we booked it months ago," she said.
"We were staying at the Hilton in Melbourne tonight."
Ms Smith said shortly after boarding, passengers were told there were steering problems.
"We were on the plane for a few hours, we didn't get off until about 3pm," she said.
"Everyone had to take their luggage off.
"Then we get a text saying the flight had been delayed until tomorrow morning."
Ms Smith said while she was fortunate to be able to go home for the night, accommodation wasn't immediately offered for others.
"It's better to air on the side of caution," she said.
An engineer is currently on route from Melbourne to Townsville to perform maintenance on the aircraft overnight.
A spokesman from Tigerair said the airline sincerely apologised to affected passengers for the inconvenience however safety was always the number one priority.
"We have done everything possible to assist passengers to get to where they are going as soon as possible, with a recovery flight scheduled for early tomorrow morning and hotel accommodation overnight for those who reside outside Townsville," he said.
"On occasions when a disruption occurs, getting our passengers to where they are going as soon as possible is always our first priority as we truly dislike disappointing our customers."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigerair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernadette Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
