<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438470489399525</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/06/20/25/fire-erupts-in-dubai-residential-highrise</url>
  <title>Fire erupts in Dubai residential highrise</title>
  <content>
A fire erupted in a residential highrise in Dubai Sunday, authorities said, days after a blaze tore through a tower across the street.
Dubai Civil Defence said Sunday it had put out the "minor fire" that broke out on a balcony in the 78-storey Tiger Tower, which opened to residents in 2010. No injuries were reported.
The building is across the street from The Torch, an 87-storey residential tower which was engulfed by a fire in early hours of Friday, with no reports of injuries.

The Torch was also the scene of a 2015 fire that triggered a mass evacuation of surrounding buildings.
In January, Dubai announced tougher rules to minimise fire risks after a series of tower blazes in the emirate mostly due to flammable material used in cladding, a covering or coating used on the side of the buildings.
In the early hours of January 1, 2015, on New Year's Eve, 16 people were injured when a fire broke out in one of Dubai's luxury hotels.

In November 2015, fire engulfed three residential blocks in central Dubai and led to services on a metro line being suspended, although no one was hurt.

Related Articles

In just over a decade, Dubai has built dozens of futuristic skyscrapers which have transformed its skyline.
The city is home to the world's tallest building, Burj al-Khalifa, which stands 828 metres (2,700 feet) tall, as well as iconic palm tree-shaped, man-made luxury residential islands.
(C)  AFP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Year's Eve, 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai Civil Defense</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiger Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khalifa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
