<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438298690706049</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/david-leyonhjelm-wants-changes-to-union-anticorruption-laws-20170805-gxq6qy</url>
  <title>David Leyonhjelm wants changes to union anti-corruption laws </title>
  <content>
The Turnbull government's crackdown on corrupt payments between union bosses and employers has hit a speed bump, with a key crossbencher warning innocent people could go to jail as the draft legislation currently stands.
While supportive of the thrust of the , Liberal Democrat David Leyonhjelm fears some businesses may be inadvertently caught out in their dealings with unions.
He will push for amendments to protect employers who make what they think is a legitimate payment, with the bill listed for debate in the Senate this week.
The laws are being introduced in response to the Heydon royal commission into union corruption, which exposed how some . 

Under the bill, it would become a criminal offence to make, receive or solicit a payment with a corrupting intent to encourage a union or union official to act improperly. A business or union faces a maximum fine of $4.5 million while individual company executives and union officials could be hit with $900,000 in fines or up to 10 years in jail.

For any payment to a union or a union official other than for clearly legitimate purposes, parties could face up to two years in prison or $90,000 fines for an individual and up to $450,000 for businesses and unions.
Strict liability

Legitimate transfers such as union membership fees or genuine training services charged at market rates and actually delivered would be still be permitted.
Senator Leyonhjelm is alarmed though by the bill's provision to treat offences on a strict liability basis. 

"The intention of the bill is ostensibly to crack down on union corruption and signal the end of the brown paper bag economy, which is an intention I support," Senator Leyonhjelm said. 
"But a closer look shows that if an employer engages in what they believe is a legitimate financial transaction with a relevant union official but they were unaware of that fact, they would still be committing a criminal offence. This contradicts the government's own policy that an offence punishable by imprisonment should not be an offence of strict liability. "
'Trampling' rights

The senator is also concerned the employment minister will have power to make a regulation so allowable payments could be subjected to prosecution. 

"We now have a government threatening its citizens with imprisonment based on a strict liability offence, merely through regulation," Senator Leyonhjelm said.
"This is by no means a simple case of incompetent or sloppy lawmaking. This is an intentional trampling on our legal heritage and principles, designed to draw Labor into a fight over unions and paint them as soft on union thuggery."
With the ACTU calling for the laws to be opposed, the government probably needs the crossbench to get them through Parliament.
Employment Minister Michaelia Cash said the government was committed to the legislation. 

"We will protect workers to ensure that any deals between  unions and employers are transparent and only in the workers best interests," she said. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACTU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Michaelia Cash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Democrat David Leyonhjelm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Leyonhjelm</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heydon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Leyonhjelm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
