<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438483374301489</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-06/fantasy-form-watch-round-20</url>
  <title>Fantasy form watch: First final brings more carnage</title>
  <content>
The 10: round 20's best moments
Some huge highlights, what will be number one?

Max Gawn was back to his best with a massive 140

THE FIRST round of the AFL Fantasy finals has come and gone. And what a mess it has left in its wake. If there wasn't enough carnage leading into the round, this week could be a whole lot worse with Joel Selwood already ruled out, rookie hero Alex Witherden under a cloud and your guess is as good as mine as to what will happen with Mitch Duncan, Zach Merrett and Brodie Grundy with the Match Review Panel.
Fantasy pig

Lachie Neale exploded against the Suns, absolutely dominating with 32 possessions, nine marks, 10 tackles and a goal for a round-high 152. He is certainly one to watch for the remainder of the season and he would be a worthy candidate of any finals contenders looking for an underpriced premium.

•

Honourable mention: Max Gawn confirmed that last week wasn't a fluke and he is officially back in form following his long layoff. The big fella could find himself having a huge spike in ownership if Grundy is suspended after a dominant display against the Giants where he scored 140 which included a goal and a whopping 52 hit-outs. He is heavily underpriced and ripe for the picking.
Rage trades
 

Buddy Franklin was in my rolling 'best 22' until his shocking effort against the Cats which left many of his coaches high, dry and out of the finals. He has left me no option but to search for a replacement in the top six forwards after scoring just 37 points from eight possessions and a goal. Hopefully for his owners, they get repaid in a favourable matchup with the Dockers next round.

•

Honourable mention: Joel Selwood was on the chopping block last week after scoring just 59 but has to be traded now after he played through injury to score 64 from 20 hard earned touches. He has been ruled out for the remainder of the Fantasy season so has to go.

Piglet

Luke Ryan gets the nod for the second week running after once again holding down the scoring friendly 'switcher' role in the Dockers backline. In the absence of Connor Blakely, Ryan bettered last week's 14 marks with 16 and scored a massive 126. What an absolute legend.

•
The top five
 

Lachie Neale: 152

Josh Caddy: 142

Max Gawn: 140

Dyson Heppell: 138

Nat Fyfe: 132
Trade targets

Max Gawn

Lachie Neale

Nat Fyfe

Sam Menegola

Robbie Gray

•
Fantasy mailbag

So many guys in the 70 - 85 bracket who should be making easy 100s 😭

Absolute rollercoaster this year mate! Players who seemingly ticked all boxes to trade in have dropped the ball too frequently once ownership spiked.

any news on Witherden yet? Is he likely to miss? Cheers boys!

Not be as bad as first thought, but I can't see them playing him if there is the slightest doubt. Fingers crossed.

Thanks for all your help Legends, current rank 2444

Cheers, good work!

I Traded Danger to Beams last week. Turns out it was a bad move! I can go Blakely to Ryan and then trade Jelwood to get back Danger.Thoughts

Yep, lock it in. For more, follow myself @RoyDT

Get expert advice from The Traders in the . Follow AFL Fantasy on  and 'like' the  page to join in the conversation.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RoyDT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nat Fyfe: 132</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Blakely</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dyson Heppell: 138</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Neale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piglet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jelwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Witherden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn: 140</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Traded Danger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Menegola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blakely</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Neale: 152</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Witherden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Fantasy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danger.Thoughts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Caddy: 142</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddy Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nat Fyfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
