<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438302985673436</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/breaking-news/wa-to-sell-naming-right-for-stadium-arena/news-story/2cfb3771c909fb0b5a7a351378b9ba34</url>
  <title>WA to sell naming right for stadium, arena</title>
  <content>
The WA government has confirmed it will sell the naming rights to the new Perth Stadium and the popular Perth Arena, but the opposition is calling on Labor to break the election promise in the interests of the state.
The state government expects to generate $10 million or more over four years.
Treasurer Ben Wyatt said mining companies, banks and supermarkets might place bids, but the state government was not interested in selling the rights for either venue to a tobacco, fast food or alcohol company.
"I think it's an opportunity not just to increase the revenue source, but to hopefully promote a WA brand that is known well in WA as being from WA," he told reporters on Sunday.
Mr Wyatt said the state government would request to keep "Perth" in the name and said he was not worried about losing the WA identity.
But Opposition Leader Mike Nahan said selling the naming rights was a mistake and he asked the state government to break its election promise.
"The value of the stadium is in the name, that's why someone's going to pay millions of dollars for it, and the best name is Perth," he told reporters.
"They will make more money by attracting tourists from interstate and internationally here and getting the rewards from that."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Mike Nahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Ben Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
