<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437912143645832</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836134/united-bay-take-lead-in-semis/?cs=305</url>
  <title>United, Bay take lead in semis</title>
  <content>
United, Bay take lead in semis

BIG GAME: Elodie Dagg was a standout for Rosebud in the first leg of their Herald Women's Premier League semi-final with Merewether at Adamstown Oval on Sunday. Picture: Simone De Peak

GOAL: Merewether celebrate after taking a 1-0 lead through Tayla Braithwaite on Sunday. Picture: Simone De Peak

Adamstown goalkeeper Olivia Sneddon grabbed the ball after Merewether launch at attack on Sunday.

Adamstown captain Clare Cummings, left, and Merewether striker Rhali Dobson vie for the ball.

Adamstown v Merewether in opening leg of Herald Women's Premier League semi-final on Sunday at Adamstown Oval.

Adamstown v Merewether in WPL semi-final on Sunday.

Merewether's Grace Macintyre releases the ball.

Merewether striker Rhali Dobson goes on the attack.

exit

Merewether and Warners Bay hold the ascendancy going into the second leg of the Herald Women's Premier League semi-finals after wins over the weekend.
Minor premiers and defending champions Warners Bay beat Mid North Coast 4-2 in Taree on Saturday after leading 3-0 at half-time.
It was much closer at Adamstown Oval on Sunday, when United beat Rosebud 2-1 in a game which was delayed for 20 minutes when the hosts' goalkeeper Olivia Sneddon was concussed.
Sneddon made a brilliant save in the 15th minute of the game when Grace Macintyre smashed the ball at goal only for the keeper to touch it over the bar.

Merewether scored from the ensuing corner when Tayla Braithwaite headed into the net.
The goal gave the visitors momentum but Adamstown played with a lot of hunger and desire and were rewarded for their efforts when Isobel Cootes chipped United keeper Alison Logue in the 34th minute to level the score.
Both sides had chances to score after the break before Merewether found the winner through Macintyre off a Jamee Ellis free kick in the 67th minute.
Sneddon got the ball in a goalmouth scramble but dropped it as she fell to the ground and Macintyre was on the spot to finish from close range.
It was only after the goal that players realised Sneddon was still down.
The game was delayed while an ambulance was called and the keeper finished the game on the sidelines.
Adamstown coach Lou D'Amico was encouraged by the performance ahead of the second leg at Myamblah Oval on August 12.
"Now we've got to go out and attack and we'll be going for the win," D'Amico said.
Merewether coach Cassie Koppen said "it wasn't pretty but a win's a win".
"Obviously we're going into the second leg with a head start but we need to be better at finishing and we need to start a lot faster," Koppen said.

Warners Bay host Mid North Coast at John Street Oval on August 13.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison Logue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether's Grace Macintyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Women's Premier League</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grace Macintyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koppen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Sneddon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassie Koppen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MacIntyre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhali Dobson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamee Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adamstown Oval</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lou D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sneddon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myamblah Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adamstown</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mid North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isobel Cootes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Street Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amico</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elodie Dagg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone De Peak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tayla Braithwaite</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
