<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437869193972560</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/nick-riewoldts-courage-inspired-st-kildas-crucial-win-over-west-coast-alan-richardson-20170806-gxqfow.html</url>
  <title>Nick Riewoldt's courage inspired St Kilda's crucial win over West Coast: Alan Richardson</title>
  <content>
An inspirational moment of attack on the football and the contest by retiring champion Nick Riewoldt propelled St Kilda to victory over the West Coast Eagles and kept the Saints' finals hopes alive, according to coach Alan Richardson. 
As the Saints trailed by five points midway through the final quarter, Riewoldt charged to reach a loose ball on the wing, in the act creating a clash of heads with the oncoming Eagle Dom Sheed.Photo: AAP/Tracey Nearmy
From Riewoldt's effort, St Kilda went inside 50 and won a boundary throw in which resulted in a Jack Steele goal to put the Saints ahead.
Riewoldt was taken from the field looking groggy and played no further part in the game after the incident. But the Saints  held on to win by eight points, surviving one last West Coast surge. Jack Billings' goal with 30 seconds on the clock ensured the win.Photo: AAP Image/Tracey Nearmy)
Richardson said the Saints medical staff expected Riewoldt to play next week despite initial concussion concerns.
He likened Riewoldt's effort to spoil Sheed to the famous back-with-the-flight mark he took against Sydney at the SCG in 2004.

"It was a big moment," Richardson said of the effort. "It was something we have come to expect from Rooey.
"There was a lot of vision of Nick's career during the week, not necessarily pushed out internally, but for all the right reasons a lot of media outlets showed that mark that he took years ago at the SCG.Photo: AAP/Tracey Nearmy
"It was nowhere near as dramatic as that but for him to stay in line when the opposition were coming, you know as a player you have to open yourself up to have to spoil a player like that.
"He did that, he wore the knock, we ended up getting in front on the back of that play."
Richardson said he made a point of the former skipper's effort after the game.
"He'd be really proud of that. There is the potential that those sorts of moments inspire some of his younger teammates.
"That contest was a big one. [It was] disappointing not to have him late in the game ... He has a cut on his lip and needs some stitches ... it'd be a lip he'd be proud of."  
Richardson was delighted his Saints were able to hang on in a close finish against the Eagles after last week letting slip a lead against Port Adelaide in the final moments of the game.
"Yeh [it was] hard way to learn but absolutely the review found most of our game last week was really positive but we were shattered as a team and as a group that we weren't able to get the job done.
"It was a great opportunity for us to learn and it wasn't quite the same scenario today but yeah we had the opportunity to put that into practice tonight and the guys did a good job."
The win moved the Saints sit 11th on the ladder after the win, equal on 40 points with Melbourne, West Coast and Essendon who are eighth.
"Ten wins and nine losses, it is good to be positive to keep heading forward but every week is a real challenge," Richardson said. "We have Melbourne next week so we now need to rest up and get our bodies right and our minds right and whack away again. That's our focus.
"There was a little bit of talk about the game and the opportunity the game presented but very quickly you get onto how are we going to get it done.
"We didn't get our defence right today, that was an area that wasn't great ... but it was really pleasing the way they went after the physical part of the game."
West Coast coach Adam Simpson said his players were gallant in defeat and refused to relinquish hopes of making the finals.
"We did a lot right. I though the boys were pretty brave. We couldn't sustain it in the end and just got out supplied in the last quarter.
"I'm going to look at the glass half full on this one. I think the effort and intent is there, the ability to execute all day is obviously something we are working on.
"The group is pretty galvanised and despite all the outside noise they're still having a go. We are still going with a real positive mindset next week."
He said Matt Priddis would play next week and was hopeful Tom Barrass would be fit to join the veteran in the side. Simpson also said he would look at brining Nathan Vardy back into the side for the clash with Carlton after Drew Petrie was forced to ruck all day. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Image/Tracey Nearmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rooey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle Dom Sheed.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Barrass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Tracey Nearmy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Vardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Richardson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Billings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
