<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437267898545816</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/workplace-relations/meet-the-boss-ben-pfisterer-of-square-20170802-gxnp4o.html</url>
  <title>Meet the boss: Ben Pfisterer of Square</title>
  <content>
When Ben Pfisterer started his career, his initial expertise was in project management: an area where success depended in large part of his ability to focus intensely for a finite period. Then, he moved on to strategy consulting, where the diversity of jobs and the fast pace both appealed. Still, something was missing.
"I got sick of not being around to see the results of the strategy or the implementation: you do the strategy and move on," he says.Photo: Supplied
He switched tack and ended up as part of Jetstar's management team in the company's early days.
"Although I was part of the management team, I was a bit more of a passenger in terms of learning from some strong leaders," he says.
One of those leaders was Alan Joyce: "He's an incredibly intelligent person, but he had a huge challenge on his hands to build the airline up. The way he was able to rally his team to perform was always impressive: he always did it in a humble way, he was very approachable," he says.
Next came two roles which fit neatly with Pfisterer's current position as Australian CEO of Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey's payment technology company Square.

At NAB, he managed to convince the company to roll out chip technology on their cards, as well as contactless payment, while as the head of innovation and emerging products at Visa Pfisterer led the growth of products like payWave in Australia.
"It's a logical path in hindsight but at the time it was learning lessons and experiencing new things [as I went]," he says.
Just over a year ago, Pfisterer became Square's first local hire, tasked to build a team that would give the $426US million (net revenue) company a local presence. Growth has beaten internal targets (over 60,000 local sellers are now using Square's products and services), and taken a different approach to that used at Square's San Francisco headquarters: the company has around 25 staff in Australia, but over᪀0 staff worldwide.
"You can bring the products...[but] you can't transplant a culture," says Pfisterer. "For me, culture is just a collection of personalities. I try to build a team with as much diversity as possible," he says.
As for managing that diverse team? Pfisterer's approach is to manage the way he'd like to be managed.
"The main thing is you stay true to what you believe. What I believe is that if I am going to put together an amazing group of talented individuals, I can't change them or over manage them. If you're going to be a good leader and manager, you have to maintain the direction and the overall strategy, but let [people] do what they do best," he says.
CURRICULUM VITAE
Name: Ben Pfisterer Current position: Country Manager Square Australia.
Responsibilities: Build Square's presence and operational capabilities in the Australian market.
Education: RMIT University, Bachelor of Applied Science (Honours).
Additional training/courses: I've done a lot of training courses but in my view nothing compares to the learnings and skills you gain from working in a challenging role pushing for high growth.
Strength: The common theme in roles I enjoy is ensuring that they're challenging, which is why working with innovative products and technology at Square appeals to me. Two strengths that help me here are persistence and passion.
Weakness: I struggle working within companies that aren't constantly pushing themselves to evolve or grow, I'm also notoriously bad at submitting my expenses on time.
Management style and tips: I am a firm believer that no single management style works in all situations - I just try to manage the way I like to be managed, which involves transparency, fairness, recognition, autonomy and humility. If you have a passionate and talented team, management should be all about creating a positive work environment to help your team perform at their best.
Work motto: If I go to bed on a Sunday dreading work on Monday then I'm in the wrong job.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Pfisterer of Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Dorsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Manager Square Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Pfisterer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Pfisterer Current</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pfisterer</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visa Pfisterer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Square's San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian CEO of Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor of Applied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Build Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>payWave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
