<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438169841686068</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/television/josh-and-elyse-have-won-the-main-bathroom-reveal-on-the-block-thanks-to-a-massive-round-bath/news-story/44bd4dc817793737164509e388360549</url>
  <title>The Block couple's bathroom blitz</title>
  <content>
JOSH and Elyse have won the main bathroom reveal on by a mere half a point.
The Victorian couple, the youngest on this year's season of the Channel 9 renovation show, scored 27 out of 30 to narrowly beat Sticks and Wombat on 26-and-a-half.
It was a tight contest with Ronnie and Georgia scoring 25-and-a-half and Jason and Sarah getting 24 from judges Shaynna Blaze, Neale Whitaker, and Darren Palmer.
But Queensland's Hannah and Clint crashed to a dismal 16 out of 30 because their bathroom wasn't finished in time.
Josh and  secret weapon was the first round bath in the show's 13 seasons. But the pair were on fire all week - the first to waterproof and the first to tile.
"We spent a bit of money on it (round bath) but it paid off," Elyse said after hearing the judges' scores.
The judges said that Josh and Elyse's bathroom, which also featured a sweeping skylight, was "dramatic". The only downfall was a vanity that was too small meaning the bathroom lacked sufficient storage.
That didn't stop Whitaker scoring the pair 9.5 points, Palmer 9 and Blaze 8.5.
Hannah and Clint, the only team with no previous renovating experience, were at the other end of the spectrum.
The pair had setbacks including a floor that was too high and walls that hadn't been straightened.
The end result was that a lot of the tiling and grouting wasn't finished by deadline.
"To fall short ... is deflating," Clint said, shedding a tear. "I don't want to embarrass anyone."
Whitaker said the unfinished bathroom was "a great shame because it would have been a superb room".
But Whitaker was unimpressed with Hannah and Clint's separate toilet which he said looked "sad".
Sticks and Wombat won praise for the quality of the craftsmanship in their bathroom and their bespoke fittings.
"I'm seeing a lot of personality but in an appropriate way," Palmer said.
Ronnie and Georgia were criticised for having only a single basin in a bathroom that potentially had to service three bedrooms.
Inadequate storage was an issue as was the weird positioning of a power point and the bath spout.
Ronnie's decision to spend $1500 on a portable speaker was derided by Palmer.
Jason and Sarah flipped their floorplan and hit snags when they lost their tiler and couldn't find a plumber but they won praise for face-level storage, underfloor heating and a heated towel rail.
"They have chosen well on the big ticket items - bath, vanity, sinks, tapware - but have let themselves down with all the little details," Whitaker said.
Teams now move on to create a guest bedroom.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neale Whitaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitaker</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmer 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blaze 8.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaynna Blaze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronnie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elyse</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Hannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
