<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438345935346917</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/more-news/showdown-43-wild-wet-weather-cant-deter-45000-people-at-adelaide-oval/news-story/9f525f6add4d8f3211faac9a765d6b71</url>
  <title>Rain? What rain? The Showdown's on</title>
  <content>
ADELAIDE'S wet and wild weather has led to a Showdown wipe-out as the Crows dismantled the Power at a soggy Adelaide Oval.
With so much on the line in the 43rd contest between the fierce rivals, passionate fans of both teams ignored the wintry conditions to support their clubs in the season-defining clash.
The Power carrying a Crows fan checklist including chardonnay, knitting needles and a rule book. But on the field it was all Adelaide as they secured a record 84-point win in front of a dedicated crowd of 45,028
Port fan David Cardone, 41, of St Peters, brought along his Crows-supporting daughter, Sophie, aged 7, and said they couldn't remember another Showdown like it.
"This is the wettest, the windiest, the greyest Showdown we've ever been to, but it's great," he said. "We're all rugged up and we wouldn't want to be anywhere else."

Showdown in the rain

Sophie said she started following the Crows because her "big sister was a fan".
"There's nothing like a bit of rivalry in the family to make things interesting," Mr Cardone laughed.
Heavy jackets, scarfs, beanies and ponchos were the must-have fashion accessories of the day, with an afternoon storm front drenching the ground and everyone unfortunate to be sitting without cover.
Among those braving the heavy rain before the first bounce were sisters Luka Chandler, 14, Stella Chandler, 8, and Levi Chandler, 12, from Cummins on the state's Eyre Peninsula.
The Crows fans made the 14-hour round trip with parents Martyn, 42, and Tanya, 40, and the family admitted they would have preferred undercover seating.
"But we all love the rain, we work with farmers and it's obviously great for the farming community," Mr Chandler said.
"It's not that cold so it's just awesome to be here, we love coming across for the big games, plus it's great to see Eddie (Betts) back playing. And Showdowns are extra special - we've been to about three in the past and you just can't beat the atmosphere."
Eddie Betts showed he was just as capable of bagging miracle goals without his appendix, sending Crows fans into raptures with multiple goals from tight angles on his return from surgery.
A pitch invader in the third quarter halted the game momentarily but it did little to stop the Crows' momentum, as they carried on piling on the misery for Port supporters.
Rarely had so much been riding on a Showdown, with the Crows sitting top of the ladder and Port Adelaide just outside of the top four heading in the big game.
The result leaves Adelaide six points clear on top of the AFL ladder and in the box seat for two home finals on the path to a possible Grand Final appearance.
The prospect of a Showdown final - and possibly Grand Final - has some salivating, including Mr Chandler.
"That would incredible, we'll definitely try and make it over if we can," he said.

AFL: Listen in to the Adelaide Crows post game press conference.

Crows press conference
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stella Chandler, 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luka Chandler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi Chandler, 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cardone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crows-supporting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cardone, 41, of St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Chandler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya, 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eyre Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cummins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
