<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438221381294037</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/fine-way-to-finish-for-phoenix/3209405/</url>
  <title>Fine way to finish for Phoenix</title>
  <content>
BASKETBALL: It may have been a season full of mixed results but the Phoenix has managed to finish the year on a high.
The Sunshine Coast put in a solid performance at home for the final fixture of the season on Saturday to topple Townsville Heat 91-69.
Although finishing the state league in 12th spot on the 14-team ladder, Phoenix talent Tom Fullarton said it had been good to cap off the year with a win.
"I think we just came out ready to play and played the style of basketball that we've wanted to put in all season."
It was an extra-special win for the Phoenix, which donned retro Clippers 1997 CBA national title colours to mark the 20th anniversary of the milestone.
Reflecting on the season, Fullarton, 18, said the Phoenix had battled hard on the courts but wasn't able to convert efforts into points.
"It was kind of a roller coaster season," he said.
"We were struggling to close out games and we were in a lot of close ones throughout the season but just struggled to put wins on the board."
Although walking off the court near the bottom of the ladder, he believed there was still plenty of positives to come out of the season.
He said the year had been a "good first step" to building the Phoenix back into a finals threat in coming years.
"We didn't finish where we wanted to (but) I think it was a great environment to be around and I know the club is building a great culture and hopefully we can build on that next season," he said.
Despite the season being over, Fullarton's time on court may not be.
The teenager has been training with national league side Brisbane Bullets as a development player during pre-season.
The Bullets will travel to the United States in October to take on NBA side Phoenix Suns, but Fullarton wasn't sure if he'd join the trip.
In other games, finals-bound USC Rip City men lost to Townsville Heat 83-78 on Friday night and to the Brisbane Capitals 97-91 on Saturday.
The Phoenix women lost to Townsville, and USC Rip City women lost to Townsville on Friday but claimed a win against Capitals on Saturday.
Rescue helicopter, SES, firies on scene at Mt Beerwah for rescue
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Leads standings going into final day of action.
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Netflix health doco slammed for scaremongering, 'cherrypicking' data
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clippers' 1997 CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fullarton, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fullarton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC Rip City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Fullarton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
