<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437267898545724</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836461/wait-nearly-over-for-a-special-flight-photos/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Wait nearly over for a special flight | photos</title>
  <content>
Wait nearly over for a special flight | photos

PREPARING FOR LAUNCH: An adult black-necked stork with its young in a nest at Tomago, the furthest south a chick has been seen. Observers say the chick will fledge any day now. Picture: Bill Anderson

PREPARING FOR LAUNCH: An adult black-necked stork with its young in a nest at Tomago, the furthest south a chick has been seen. Observers say the chick will fledge any day now. Picture: Bill Anderson

MISNOMER: A female black-necked stork with its young at Port Douglas in 2003. The storks' necks actually have an iridescent blue-green sheen. Picture: Brian Cassey

exit

AT the top of a tree in Tomago, flattened against the weekend's howling winds, a pair of endangered birds and their chick have been preparing for a historic flight.
The family of black-necked storks were discovered by bird enthusiasts who have kept their location secret, and watched each day as the chick has grown.
"It's significant because this is the most southern confirmed breeding event for this species," Hunter Bird Observers Club life member Ann Lindsey said.
"We've never had a chick this far south."
The black-necked stork is Australia's only stork and is classed as endangered in NSW, though they are often seen flying over Hexham Swamp. Nests have also been found in Bulahdelah. But the past 80 days watching the stork chick grow up before her eyes have been a unique privilege, Ms Lindsey said.
"They're supposed to fledge around 80 to 81 days, so I've been there at 6.30am the last three mornings," she said.
"I would really like to see it leave the nest."
Wetland rehabilitation projects at Hexham Swamp, Kooragang and Tomago have aimed to attract the storks and the fish, small crabs and frogs they eat.
The storks are thought to pair for several years, and perhaps for life. Their nests are dense platforms of sticks and leaves, usually in tall trees close to water. The birds are secretive and isolate themselves in pairs, and both parents care for the young.
The Hunter's bird-watchers have also been excited in the past two months by seveal sightings of critically-endangered regent honeyeaters near Cessnock.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lindsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomago</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Anderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Cassey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulahdelah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ann Lindsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Bird Observers Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kooragang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hexham Swamp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
