<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437869193972524</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/obituaries/joan-kellett-a-life-spent-promoting-swimming-20170803-gxonor.html</url>
  <title>Joan Kellett spent her promoting swimming</title>
  <content>
Joan Kellett OAM
2 May 1929 - 20 June 2017
Joan Kellett was a respected and influential participant in the life of the Canberra community. Her early volunteer involvement was in support of the local school, recreational and neighbourhood activities as her young family grew up in the newly established suburb of Dickson in the early 1960s. This extended over time into her taking on significant leadership roles in several ACT organisations, particularly in the areas of public education and the sport of swimming. Mastery of administration and governance coupled with a warm and gracious persona made Joan a strong and effective advocate whose efforts helped achieved outcomes of lasting value. Her capacity to bring people together and generous mentorship of others was legendary. In 2003 Joan was awarded an Order of Australia Medal for service to swimming as an administrator and official and her service to the community.
Joan Mary Bell was born in Brisbane in 1929, the older daughter of Gert and pharmacist Alec Bell. For most of her childhood the family lived above the pharmacy in Logan Road, Greenslopes. After completion of her secondary education at All Hallows School she studied science at the University of Queensland, going on to a career in pathology laboratories including at the Mater in Brisbane and the Lewisham Hospital in Sydney. In 1957 Joan married Harry Kellett and in 1960 with a young son they came to Canberra, moving into the new house in Dumaresq Street, Dickson, to establish the home they never left and adding three daughters to the family over the next few years.Photo: Fairfax
Joan was deeply committed to the importance of high-quality public education and the founding values of the ACT school system. She served as chair of the school board at North Ainslie Primary School, Lyneham High School and Dickson College. Engaging in broader education issues, from 1984 she served for nearly 30 years as an executive member of the ACT Council of Parents' and Citizens' Associations and was awarded life membership in 2003 in recognition of her outstanding service which continued well beyond this date. Joan was involved in policy formation, the development of submissions and advocacy, representing Council views on several government advisory committees and appointed as its elected nominee on the ACT Schools Authority (later restructured as the ACT Education Council) from 1984-1989. Two outcomes she took great pleasure in were the securing of funding in 1977 for North Ainslie Primary School's "Afters" initiative which was one of the first after-school care programs in Australia and the departmental acceptance of the principle of parent participation in ACT government schools. She was a founding member of the Council's Disability Working Group. Most recently, Joan was the Council delegate member of the Turner School Board including a period as theboard chair, serving continuously until 2015 for a period of 12 years in all.
In 1967 the Kellett family joined the Dickson Swimming Club with both Harry and Joan taking leadership roles in its administration and volunteering in coaching and officiating duties. The association with the club was maintained well beyond the period of their own children's involvement in the sport, in Joan's case for 50 years. She helped the club make the transition from a primarily competitive focus to a more community-based and inclusive participative group. An office-bearer from 1973 in the local peak swimming bodies of the time and then president of Swimming ACT for 18 years, Joan's promotion of the sport of swimming in the ACT for its physical, social and safety benefits encompassed input into the construction of ACT public recreational facilities including the learner's pool at Dickson and lobbying for pools in Tuggeranong and Belconnen. She was instrumental in the development of the Swimming ACT program for people with disabilities which has run for more than 20 years. An accredited race official, Joan was to be found on the pool deck at swimming events from local club competitions and school carnivals through to Special Olympics meets and country, state and national swimming championships. She was a volunteer at the Sydney Olympic Games and Paralympic Games in 2000. In recognition of her dedication, Joan was awarded Life Membership of Dickson Swimming Club, named Volunteer of the Year at the ACT Sportstar of the Year Awards in 2010 and inducted into associate membership of the ACT Sport Hall of Fame in 2011.

A strong believer in the importance of community input into the ACT's planning and development process, Joan was chair of the North Canberra Community Council in 1994-1995 and again in 2004 as well as a member of the Majura Local Area Planning Advisory Committee (LAPAC). She attended hearings by the Assembly and represented the Council in a variety of forums leading up to the Neighbourhood Plans produced in 2003. In 2010, Joan helped form the Dickson Residents Group and remained a core group member up until the very end of her life, taking an active interest in recent and proposed redevelopment activities in the area and seeking to have community input to achieve a balance between improved and updated access while preserving the character and amenity of the neighbourhood. She valued Canberra's heritage and served as committee member of the Friends of the Albert Hall for several years.
Joan's other significant volunteer activities include 20 years of service in the Girl Guides movement as a Brownie unit leader and later Division Commissioner and the acceptance of appointment to the Board of the YMCA from 2002-2016. Her involvement as a volunteer with the social program run by Alzheimer's Australia ACT began in 2009 and lasted until 2016: she found this a particularly meaningful and rewarding activity.
Joan had a positive and progressive outlook and maintained a lifelong interest in local and national politics. She appreciated the significance of Canberra's national cultural institutions and had long time memberships of the Friends of the Australian National Library and the Australian National Gallery.
Exceptional skills as a listener, an empathic and encouraging nature and unassuming personal style made Joan an effective and influential agent in her various spheres of action. Despite the level of her commitments, Joan was a dear and kind friend to many and a well-loved neighbour whose deep ties to the original Dumaresq Street inhabitants lasted until her recent death. Joan is survived by four children and nine grandchildren.
There will be a community gathering to celebrate Joan Kellett's life on Saturday, August 19, at Leumeah Lodge, 48 O'Hanlon Place, Nicholls.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council's Disability Working Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dumaresq Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Kellett OAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Sport Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyneham High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson Swimming Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citizens Associations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson Residents Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Kellett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Membership of Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Hallows School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friends of the Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Council of Parents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Mary Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenslopes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paralympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Board of the YMCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Education Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volunteer of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Kellett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friends of the Albert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner School Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Sportstar of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swimming ACT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alec Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Canberra Community Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Order of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alzheimer's Australia ACT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAPAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swimming Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 1929 - 20 June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neighbourhood Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leumeah Lodge, 48 O'Hanlon Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewisham Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Majura Local Area Planning Advisory Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Girl Guides</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Ainslie Primary School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Schools Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belconnen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
