<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437650150638324</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836326/magic-win-knocks-valentine-maitland-out-of-npl-finals-race/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Magic win knocks Valentine, Maitland out of NPL finals race</title>
  <content>
Magic win knocks Valentine, Maitland out of NPL finals race

exit

Some of the Broadmeadow Magic players were in tears after Wednesday's FFA Cup defeat, but they ended the week with a hard-fought 2-0 win over the Jets and a guaranteed place in the Northern NSW NPL finals.

The victory was a double celebration for Magic on their old boys' day as retiring stalwart Peter Haynes scored a second-half penalty in what might have been his last game on home turf.

Hamilton Olympic dominated Lake Macquarie 4-0 at Macquarie Field to wrap up second spot, two points behind Edgeworth, with one game to play.  

The results render the final-round derby between Hamilton and Broadmeadow largely meaningless, although Magic could climb to third above Lambton, who have won only once in the past four games. Valentine and Maitland are now out of the running.

Magic coach Ruben Zadkovich said his side had struggled on Sunday after their emotional midweek trip to Queensland, where they lost 4-2 in extra time to Moreton Bay.

"The only thing that anyone's disappointed about at the moment is just that we probably did enough to win that game on Wednesday and we didn't," he said after Sunday's game.

"It was a huge disappointment. I haven't felt anything like it for a while. We had boys in tears after the game because they're just working really hard for each other.

"It was horrible as a coach. To see boys in tears after the game. The boys went out after the game and I had to drag myself along because I just wanted to go to my room and sulk."  
Zadkovich said defenders Josh Piddington, Jon Griffiths and Luke Virgili had taken injuries into the game against the Jets Youth.

"We just had dead bodies out there. I really wanted us to go up two or three with the wind in the first half, and it didn't happen and I was like, 'Here we go.'
"You could feel that it was going to be a long half, so I was proud of their resilience."
Scott Pettit gave the home side a deserved lead in the 29th minute when he evaded his marker and tapped home a corner from two metres out.

The Jets dominated the first 15 minutes of the second half and should have equalised in the 61st minute, but Magic keeper Nick Giantsopoulos reacted well to deny Cameron Joice a tap-in after parrying a long-range shot from Tyson Jackson.

Haynes then won a penalty in the 78th minute when he appeared to commit a foul before being dragged down in the box by Jets defender Daniel Alessi, who was shown a straight red.

The striker slotted home the spot kick then ran over to the bench to hug Zadkovich.    
"You could hear it in the crowd. Everyone was so stoked for him. He means so much to our club. He means so much to us as mates," Zadkovich said.

"However lucky it is, and whatever it is, a penalty, it doesn't really matter. He deserves everything he gets."

Haynes said he was relieved to score the penalty and get the three points after a "tough" week. 
"It was probably the most nervous I've been taking one for a long time," he said. "Probably a good way to finish in front of a lot of family and friends as well. Good way to go out.

"I was pretty emotional after the FFA Cup game the other night, and that was probably the first time it's sunk in it was finishing. The boys got around me and there was a lot of love in the dressing room."

Charlestown beat Weston 2-1 at home in a game that had no bearing on the finals.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haynes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Haynes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadow Magic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zadkovich</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Pettit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Piddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday's FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jets Youth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edgeworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern NSW NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Joice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Giantsopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Alessi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Virgili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruben Zadkovich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
