<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438307280640833</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-06/hinkley-slams-unacceptable-performance</url>
  <title>Hinkley slams 'unacceptable' performance</title>
  <content>
Port Adelaide lost the Showdown by a record margin

SHATTERED Port Adelaide coach Ken Hinkley has hinted at a few changes for next week's crunch clash against Collingwood after an "unacceptable" performance in Sunday's Showdown.

The Power were pulverised in all areas by ladder-leader Adelaide as they slumped to an 84-point loss - the biggest margin in Showdown in history.

Port lost the inside-50 count by a record 50 (81-31) with Hinkley describing his side's effort as "inexplicable".

Port remains fifth on the ladder at 11-8, but are now only percentage clear of seventh-placed Western Bulldogs with a further three teams just a win behind.

"We were dominated from the start to the end," Hinkley said.

"It was unacceptable. We got smashed everywhere. 

"We can acknowledge that the opposition are a very good side but that was unacceptable."

The Power lost the contested possession count by 46, which continued a "worrying" trend that began against Melbourne in round 18.

"It's being worrying our form line, particularly around the contest," Hinkley said. 

"Our ability to handle heat hasn't stood up as well as we would like it to stand up. We've got enough size in their to do that. I think we haven't got a hardness about us that you require to play high level football.

"(Our contest work) has been a real strength for 15 or 16 weeks. The last few weeks have been a bit of a worry for us."

HInkley said the club would be brutal in its assessment of the loss, but added he will be reluctant to make "wholesale" personnel changes this late in the season. 

"We have to be prepared to look at some of the positions that are in there and say 'if you're not getting it done, we'll make some change'," Hinkley said. 

"Your depth is exposed at this time of the year. You know who your players are who are capable of possibly helping you out. 

"But it's a few in, a few out, type stuff. It's not wholesale."

Hinkley expected star forward-midfielder Chad Wingard (hamstring) to return against the Pies and hoped Matthew Broadbent (ankle) would also be available. 

He said Robbie Gray was the only Power player who could hold his high against Adelaide. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday's Showdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinkley</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
