<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438470489399515</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/mum-of-murdered-balga-man-makes-emotional-plea/news-story/279ec01a8e94a625c7cb69867998195b</url>
  <title>Mother's plea for 'murdered' son</title>
  <content>
THE grieving mother of a Balga man found dead in suspicious circumstance inside his home has urged detectives to find her son's killer.
Police were called to the house on Dallington Crescent about 8.30pm on Friday and arrived to find 36-year-old Dejan Dimitrovski fatally injured inside.
Mr Dimitrovski's mother Liljana described him yesterday as a loving son, father and brother who had an enthusiasm for life.
She said the family had been completely heartbroken by his death and did not understand why it has happened.
"I promised my son I would do anything possible ... and if there is anyone who knows anything in connection with his murder please come forward," she said.
Mr Dimitrovski's sister, Natalia Dimitrovska, is serving a 17-year prison sentence for a 2012 attack on Perth woman Dana Vulin that left the victim with serious burns.
Dimitrovska said from prison yesterday her brother was "full of life" and "generous" and that she was devastated by his death.
Homicide detectives and police forensic investigators spent a second day at the property yesterday, examining two luxury cars parked out the front. They also door-knocked surrounding homes to speak to residents and check for CCTV footage from the area.
Police are yet to reveal how Mr Dimitrovski was killed or who called them to the house.
He was treated at the scene by paramedics but died a short time later. Tributes to Mr Dimitrovski were also posted on social media while flowers were left outside the Balga property.
"Sorry to see you go like this. My heart goes out for you and family," Jade Holtom wrote on Facebook.
Ira Sehovic posted: "I'm so shattered and heartbroken to know that when I get back from the holiday that you made possible for me I won't get to see or speak to you again.
"You had a heart like no other and looked out for the ones close to you like I've never seen before. You were that one friend I could always count on (no) matter what. I'm still hoping that I'm going to wake up and this is all a bad nightmare."
Detectives investigating Mr Dimitrovski's death are appealing for anyone who saw or heard anything suspicious in the area on Friday night to contact them.
Anyone with information should call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or make a report online at www.crimestopperswa.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallington Crescent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jade Holtom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dimitrovski</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalia Dimitrovska</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dejan Dimitrovski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ira Sehovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balga</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimitrovska</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dana Vulin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
