<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438427539726260</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/reality/mark-tarzan-h-got-dysentery-after-being-evicted-from-australian-survivor-2017-20170803-gxoz70.html</url>
  <title>Tarzan got dysentery after being evicted from Australian Survivor </title>
  <content>
Mark H, who has been coined Tarzan by his fellow Australian Survivor competitors, has no regrets about leaving the show when he did, otherwise it may have been "in a body bag with the zipper open".
The 51-year-old grandfather sees it as a blessing because two days later he was struck down with terrible dysentery and left bedridden for a week.

Up Next
Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

01:28

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Bitchiness on The Bachelor, Dr G Yunupingu's marvelous career, talk shows take on Trump's transgender ban, fans' anger at Australian Ninja Warrior and Ringo and Paul back together again.

"It manifested two days after I got home and I was just crook as a dog, like I had dysentery and was nauseated and sick," he said after the show.
"Like if I was in that condition and still on the island, here's the thing I guarantee, like I was sick like that for a week, so physically they would have pulled me out of the game because my health went south.Photo: Nigel Wright
"And if that had of played out I would have been very disappointed to be going out, basically, in a body bag with the zipper open."
He believed he could have picked it up from the water well provided,  because "it's just out in the open ... and everyone's dipping in and out of it so anything's possible, but I could have picked it up in the mud challenge".

Tarzan said many of the women competing also got sick while they were toughing it out in Samoa.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I think you'll find the Survivor game we play is far truer than Bear Grylls' game, we don't go in with anything," he said.Photo: Nigel Wright
"We basically have got nothing and we really only ended up with the one thing that was of any use to us, that you could say was given to us, was a machete and there was one of those amongst 12 and it was blunt!
"It's a hell of a lot tougher than it looks."Photo: Nigel Wright
Despite his wife Natalie being surprised to see him home so early, Tarzan has enjoyed the continued and unrivalled camaraderie he has experienced with his fellow contestants.
"I think my timing was right ... and I loved [being on the show] and I thought that was all that matters," said the Queensland lime farmer. "I've never felt better."
I would have been very disappointed to be going out in a body bag with the zipper open
Tarzan

The fan favourite was voted out on Sunday night after being stabbed in the back by superfan and strategic player A.K. after Tarzan revealed his plan to remove their tribe's leader Locky in a bid to save his adopted "show daughter' Tessa.
By taking the noble approach and finding an idol for soon-to-be-evicted Tessa while hatching a plan that went against the majority, Tarzan was left vulnerable and in his words, "the fury of the god has come upon me".Photo: Nigel Wright
So why help the 29-year-old Victorian doctor?
"It was only because Tessa came down to me on the beach and asked for help, that was it. That was all she had to do."Photo: Nigel Wright
Tessa, whose crumbling alliance left her on the outer among the tribe, shared with Tarzan a clue about the location of the idol, which gave the player immunity from being eliminated.
Giggling like a schoolgirl on Sunday night, Tarzan was elated at discovering the idol's hiding spot, saying "I love this game".
But his happiness was short-lived when AK, 29, revealed his plans to 27-year-old adventure guide Locky, instead of recruiting others to Tarzan and Tessa's side.
Still, that's all part of the game. "Here's the devil in the detail, I'm probably not as a smart as the other guys and I'm not a superfan," Tarzan admitted. "Basically, my lack of experience in the game itself was my downfall."
Interestingly, he remains in the dark over who goes all the way to the end, having asked that no one spoil his viewing of the show.
But not-so-surprisingly, he wants Tessa to win.
"Mate, if Tess wins then I've won," he said. 
"Tess wouldn't have been there on basically two occasions ... I saved her the other night, I saved her tonight. I did that because I felt compelled to do it but she's got to win it. But I'd say Locky is going to give her a hell of a run for her money."
Yet he wasn't despondent that his attempts to save Tessa may yet be thwarted by the majority.
"I think we're setting new bars and reaching for new heights. Mark my words ... we will set it on fire," he said.
"I have a really strong feeling this will be a really amazing season and set a benchmark for seasons to come."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tessa</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Locky</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarzans</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AK, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIGEL WRIGHT</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitchiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bear Grylls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark H</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TESS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
