<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437396747565840</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/melbourne-rebels-believe-they-are-safe-after-confirming-victorian-rugby-union-has-bought-their-licence-20170806-gxqdz7.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Rebels believe they are safe after confirming Victorian Rugby Union has bought their licence </title>
  <content>
The Melbourne Rebels are adamant their future in Super Rugby is secure after confirming owner Andrew Cox has sold the franchise's licence to the Victorian Rugby Union. 
Cox told players via email on Friday he had sold the licence to the VRU, which now makes the ARU job of cutting the Rebels even tougher. 
In the email he said he would continue to support the Rebels in the future. 
While getting rid of the Rebels is still a possibility, albeit a very small one, the ARU is now sweating on the result of arbitration between itself and Rugby WA, which has now concluded after beginning on Monday. 

It is understood an announcement will be made later in the week regarding the outcome of arbitration. 
Even if the arbitrator determines the ARU has the legal right to cut the Force from next year's Super Rugby competition, this does not mean the trigger will be pulled simultaneously. 

If things don't go the Force's way, they will fight for survival in the Supreme Court and that is something that will drag on and only add to the uncertainty of Australian rugby. 
The VRU said it notified the ARU of the change of ownership but it is believed the ARU did not hear from the Rebels during the process. 
The game's governing body wants to establish whether the process was carried out within the terms of a participation deal whereby the ARU has to give the green light for a change of owners. 
"It's exciting for the Melbourne Rebels and local rugby that, with the VRU, we've been able to secure the future of the Super Rugby club," Cox said in a statement. "After two rewarding, productive, and at times challenging seasons, Imperium Sports Management is pleased to hand over control of the Melbourne Rebels to ensure their future is in the hands of the Victorian Rugby community. 
"We are pleased that this secures the future of the Melbourne Rebels in Melbourne.
"The team at Imperium will remain passionate Rebels fans and we look forward to celebrating much success in the future."
Rebels chief executive Baden Stephenson said: "The contribution of Imperium Sports Management, led by Andrew, to the Melbourne Rebels and Victorian rugby over the last two years can't be underestimated. 
"During this incredibly challenging period, we've worked closely with Andrew and the Imperium team to ensure that we have built a strong squad for 2018 with the re-signing and recruitment of some great players to deliver the club some much-deserved success." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperium Sports Management</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VRU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Rebels</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baden Stephenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
