<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437912143645840</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/gungahlin-united-blow-31-lead-in-final-10-minutes-to-draw-with-canberra-olympic-20170806-gxq8hf.html</url>
  <title>Gungahlin United blow 3-1 lead in final 10 minutes to draw with Canberra Olympic</title>
  <content>
 Gungahlin United kept the NPL Capital Football title race alive for another week but they'll a rue missed opportunity as Canberra Olympic salvaged a 3-3 draw thanks to a late hat-trick from Stephen Domenici.
United were up 3-1 with just eight minutes remaining before Domenici netted twice in the dying stages to steal a point.Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong
Victory would have handed Olympic the minor premiership but after Tim Bobolas went off injured in the first two minutes, coach Frank Cachia said it turned into "one of those days".
United continued with their high press attack and were rewarded on 28 minutes when Phil Yarnold brought down Jack Green inside the box and Anthony Giorgi made no mistake from the spot.
Michael Rinaudo doubled the lead in the opening stages of the second half, before Domenici got Olympic back into the contest with a sharp finish on 62 minutes.
Gungahlin looked to have the three points wrapped up when Giorgi found his brace on 81 minutes but the late fightback from the league-leading goal scorer ensured the contest finished in a draw.

United coach Marcel Munoz said Olympic's class, defensive mistakes and the referee cost his side victory.
"They came back very well, they have quality players, especially in attack and essentially their creativity up front caused us problems towards the end and unfortunately a few errors on our end cost us the win," Munoz said.
"The referee conditioned the game, there were two clear send off opportunities and I believe because Olympic is a big club the ref didn't do as much as they could have in those moments.
"The tackle on Jack was a clear penalty which the referee gave but he was the last man before the goalkeeper, I'm not a referee but in my opinion that's a clear red card.
"I'm not looking for an excuse for Olympic getting back into it, I'm not after that, but had those decisions gone in our favour then it completely changes the game."
Olympic coach Frank Cachia said he was pleased his men found a way to grind out a tough draw in testing conditions.
"I don't think Gungahlin will get a better chance at beating us, being 3-1 with 10 minutes to go and playing for a finals spot, so we'll take the draw," Cachia said.
"We know we need to improve on that performance be we were playing arguably the best coached local side in the competition.
"I rate Marcel highly and how he goes about it and how organised they are, he always has a good plan and they executed it today. We'll take the result and move on."
The coaches echoed each other praising the attacking style of the game with both emphasising the spectators got their money's worth.
Meanwhile, Canberra thrashed Cooma 5-1 making it 10 goals in two weeks as their championship run gets back on track and Tuggeranong United accounted for Woden Weston 4-1 on Saturday night.
NPL CAPITAL FOOTBALL ROUND 16:
Gungahlin United 3 drew Canberra Olympic 3
Canberra FC 5 beat Cooma Tigers 1
Tuggeranong United 4 beat Woden Weston 1
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Olympic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL CAPITAL FOOTBALL ROUND 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong United 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domenici</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL Capital Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Yarnold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Olympic 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giorgi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woden Weston 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra FC 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Giorgi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Rinaudo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcel Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Bobolas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Cachia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooma Tigers 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggeranong United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sitthixay Ditthavong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin United 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cachia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Domenici</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
