<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438083942339468</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/richard-roxburgh-and-toni-collette-brilliant-in-blue-murder-killer-cop-20170727-gxjob9.html</url>
  <title>Richard Roxburgh and Toni Collette brilliant in Blue Murder: Killer Cop</title>
  <content>
BLUE MURDER: KILLER COP
Miniseries premiere ★★★★

Up Next
Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

01:28

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Trailer:
Blue Murder: Killer Cop

Richard Roxburgh reprises his role as former NSW detective Roger Rogerson in the sequel to Blue Murder.

Sunday (August 6), 8.30pm, and Monday (August 7),  Seven
The 2014 execution of drug dealer Jamie Gao inside a Sydney storage unit was a postscript to the story of a crooked cop that you just couldn't write.  It had been some years since Gao's killer, Roger "the Dodger" Rogerson, had hit the headlines. Two decades since the ABC miniseries, Blue Murder, had enraged and enthralled audiences with the retelling of corruption and gangland escapades. And there it was in newsprint - a fitting conclusion to a high-profile criminal career. In the end, the remorseless anti-hero was brought down as many crooks are, by greed and stupidity.Photo: Seven
Reprising his original performance, Richard Roxburgh slips so effortlessly back into the role, he's barely recognisable from devilishly handsome barrister, Cleaver Greene, of ABC legal drama, Rake. Time has also passed for the actor, but the magic of hair and make-up nicely replicates the septuagenarian Rogerson as we first encounter him, addressing the camera from inside prison, where he, along with former detective Glen McNamara, is serving a life sentence for Gao's murder.
It's entirely plausible that the real Rogerson would give such a speech. In his latter days of freedom, he reclaimed the "disgraced former detective" tag bestowed on him by the media and hit the pub circuit to relay anecdotes of his thuggery, and appeared in a show called The Wild Colonial Psychos with Mark "Jacko" Jackson and Chopper Read. So it's unnerving watching the fictional incarnation of the man in his prison greens, bitterness fizzing from his rigid shoulders as he derides the "midgets" who put him there. He insists, even now, that, "You slept easy because people like me kept things neat and tidy".

The story is brought to life by original miniseries director, Michael Jenkins, producer Carol Hughes, executive producer John Edwards, and Gold AWGIE-winning scriptwriter, Peter Schreck. This chapter of Rogerson's life concerns his friendship with the late crime boss Michael "Mickel" Hurley (expertly portrayed by Dan Wyllie), his dealings with murdered bikie Alan Abrahams (Damian Walshe-Howling), and his romance with the woman who was to become his wife. In that role, Toni Collette is superb. She nails the strident Sydney accent and strangely sensual frump of the printing shop worker whose heart Rogerson stole.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

On what is supposed to be the "right" side of the law, standout performances include Matt Nable as former NSW Crime Commission boss, Mark Standen. Nable revels in the glorious juxtaposition of his role - the power-drunk crusade against Rogerson masking the weakness that would be Standen's spectacular undoing. Emma Booth is perfect as Standen's colleague and lover, Julie Weinthall. The marvellous Aaron Pedersen plays detective Joe Kensell; Underbelly star Robert Mammone is in his element as ecstasy boss, James Henry Kinch. Roxburgh's fellow Rake cast member, Andrew Ryan is mule, Wayne Crofton. And Justin Smith embodies a doughy interpretation of McNamara.Photo: Seven
With the deceptively laconic speech rhythms, outrageous stories of lawlessness and the sinister yet amusing lexicon peculiar to Australian criminals, it's little wonder our stories from the dark side have titillated since the Ned Kelly gang roamed the bush. It is in this tradition that Blue Murder: Killer Cop recounts a modern tale of skulduggery, without a skerrick of the tendency to glamourise favoured by some of the Underbelly spin-offs. The violence Rogerson inflicts, including one unforgettable scene of prison-yard retribution, is ugly. But the most frightening thing by far is the man himself, his murderously indignant death stare that of the righteous psychopath. Never has a balding, liver spotted, bespectacled man in a casual beige jacket appeared so utterly menacing.
CRITIC'S CHOICE
THE HOUSE WITH ANNABEL CRABB
Series premiere ★★
Tuesday (August 8), 8pm, ABC
Sporting her trademark 1950s Dior silhouette, politics tragic Annabel Crabb skips through the hallowed halls of Parliament House dispensing with historical factoids and meeting  MPs before their 2016 inauguration. Thus far it seems only Labor and independent MPs are willing to talk in detail (Derryn Hinch, Linda Burney and Anne Aly feature), but the teaser for future episodes shows some interaction with Malcolm Turnbull and Tony Abbott. Crabb also goes literally underground to explore a mysterious cavern.
OFFSPRING
★★★
Wednesday (August 9), 8.30pm, Ten
Eccentric head of obstetrics Martin Clegg may still be on hiatus in the outback, but his stepson Ray (who, somewhat alarmingly for viewers on board from the start, turns 10) is a living example of the influence of nature over nurture as he hosts a black-tie dinner party for himself. Naturally this is the scene for yet more skeletons to emerge from the family closet but mercifully none involving matriarch Geraldine (Linda Cropper) and her (shock!) bisexuality.
VERSAILLES
★★★★
Thursday (August 10), 9.35pm, SBS
Proving our appetite for extravagant historical drama is indeed insatiable, the second series of this Louis XIV melodrama continues on its merry way, embellishing the recorded facts of the megalomaniacal French king's rule with great flourish and aplomb. This chapter of life inside the royal court ensconced at the country palace includes a hugely entertaining scuffle between Monsieur Philippe d'Orleans (Alexander Vlahos) and his jealous lover, Chevalier (Evan Williams); and a distressing, if no doubt realistic, rape scene between newlyweds.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orleans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleaver Greene, of ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chevalier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Standen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Versailles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Wyllie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Pedersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Vlahos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Cropper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Crofton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Kensell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rogerson</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Clegg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8), 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Henry Kinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dodgers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10), 9.35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mickel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Crime Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Booth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geraldine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Nable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Abrahams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOUSE WITH ANNABEL CRABB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wild Colonial Psychos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crabb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Gao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Mammone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9), 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Standen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louis XIV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen McNamara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Weinthall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monsieur Philippe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Burney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6), 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chopper Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gao</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annabel Crabb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Killer Cop</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Schreck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni Collette</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Aly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold AWGIE-winning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McNamara.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evan Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hurley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damian Walshe-Howling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
