<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437912143645880</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-life/music-and-art-warm-hearts-at-national-portrait-gallerys-winter-festival-20170803-gxolhj.html</url>
  <title>Music and art warm hearts at the National Portrait Gallery's Winter Festival</title>
  <content>
The cosy comforts of music, art and good company provided a warm antidote to a chilly weekend at the National Portrait Gallery's Winter Festival on Sunday.
The yearly celebration of culture and community was a good match for women artists from Tjanpi Desert Weavers, who showed crowds how they made woven bowls and animals from native grasses.Photo: Jamila Toderas
The social enterprise was created to enable Indigenous women in remote central and western deserts to earn their own income from fibre art.
Among the artists was Tjunkaya Tapaya, who worked on a carefully crafted artwork of herself, made from natural and dyed grasses, that had so far taken three weeks to create.Photo: Jamila Toderas
Fellow weaver Loira Heffernan, who lives in Alice Springs, said the woven pieces told family stories, often depicted animals such as lizards and goannas, and skills were passed down through generations of women.
Visitors to this year's festival took part in landscape drawing, wool weaving, origami-making and enjoyed performances by Nomad the Magician and alternative pop band Betty Alto.Photo: Jamila Toderas
Crowds also watched as sculptors from Down Under Ice Designs chipped an eagle and kangaroo from large blocks of ice that had taken four days to freeze.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tjunkaya Tapaya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Portrait Gallery's Winter Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loira Heffernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tjanpi Desert Weavers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nomads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Alto.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ice Designs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
