<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437272193513217</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/donald-trumps-bird-world/3209323/</url>
  <title>This Donald trumps the bird world</title>
  <content>
Normally it would be headline news across the world - Donald Trump in Huonville, Tasmania - except in this case the famous tweeter is a bird, which bears a remarkable resemblance to its more famous namesake.

With a streaming mane of golden feathers adorning his head, the golden pheasant was quickly christened Donald Trump by owner Rowen Carter.

Mr Carter, who is part-owner of the Huon Valley Caravan Park, said when he got Donald two years ago the bird soon started fitting the persona of the US President.

"He even has a girlfriend named Melania but adding to that, he has a roving eye for the females and chases them fairly hard. He really ramps up the tweeting during mating season," he said.

"Our Donald Trump thinks he's quite beautiful and delights in showing off his golden mane and plumage.

"We even asked him his opinion of Malcolm Turnbull, and Donald our pheasant turned his head away."

Mr Carter said his golden-feathered friend is not domesticated either.

"Our Donald has quite a high opinion of himself, expecting others to feed him the best grain and clean his pen,"  he said.

"He is also a prolific sire with about a dozen offspring."

Mr Carter said the golden pheasant bird was native to Malaysia but had been in Australia for many years.

Rescue helicopter, SES, firies on scene at Mt Beerwah for rescue
Leads standings going into final day of action.
Local legend needs your help
Weather Bureau backtracks on severe storm prediction
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowen Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Carter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huon Valley Caravan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huonville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
