<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437272193513164</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/teenager-bags-second-place-in-pro-junior-event-in-/3209325/</url>
  <title>Teenager bags second place in pro junior event in US</title>
  <content>
SURFING: Moffat Beach's Reef Heazlewood has snared second spot at a pro junior event in California.
The teenager won his four-competitor semi-final and was right in the hunt in the four-rider final at the Vans US Open of Surfing.
He finished with 14.93 points, just behind Hawaii's Cody Young (15.46).
Heazlewood made a late charge, chasing a wave score of 8.63, but just fell short.
It's another promising performance from the reigning Australasian Pro Junior champion, who will compete at the junior world championships in New South Wales early next year.
For Young, the victory was a breakthrough,
"To win this event in my last year as a pro junior is the best thing ever," he told World Surf League.
"This is my first major win of my career so far. I'm just so stoked on this right now.
"This will give me a lot of confidence going to the back half of the year and especially trying to get back to the world junior championships since all these guys are there.
"I'm looking forward to the rest of this year and hopefully carry this momentum into Kiama next year."
Rescue helicopter, SES, firies on scene at Mt Beerwah for rescue
Leads standings going into final day of action.
Local legend needs your help
Weather Bureau backtracks on severe storm prediction
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
A supernatural sleuth shares some of his strangest experiences
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
Since moving to the Bay four months ago, Wendy hasn't looked back.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii's Cody Young (15.46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasian Pro Junior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vans US Open of Surfing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Surf League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heazlewood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moffat Beach's Reef Heazlewood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
