<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438436129660900</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-union/wallaroos-can-win-a-world-cup-with-proper-investment-says-president-of-australian-womens-rugby-20170804-gxp5zd.html</url>
  <title>Wallaroos can win a World Cup with proper investment, says president of Australian Women's Rugby</title>
  <content>
Josephine Sukkar, the president of Australian Women's Rugby, believes the Wallaroos can win a World Cup in four years time provided they are properly invested in like their sevens counterparts. 
Before that can happen, Sukkar wants answers, and she plans on getting them sitting alongside ARU chief executive Bill Pulver in Belfast later this month. 

Up Next

Bolt defeated by Gatlin in final 100m race

00:23

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Crusaders beat Lions to break super title drought

The jubilant Crusaders are once again the kings of Super Rugby.

"I'll be attending a forum with Bill Pulver in Belfast around women's rugby internationally," Sukkar said. "I'm really interested to see what other nations are doing with their women's XVs teams. 
"The English [RFU] have just decided to not continue their XVs women's players' contracts and I'm very keen to understand what that's about. In New Zealand they contract their sevens players but not the XVs players. 

"I'm very keen to go over and understand what other countries are doing and see if we can bring best practice back here." 
Sukkar is regarded as the fairy godmother of Australian women's rugby, a title given to her for the donations made by her company Buildcorp that she co-founded with her husband Tony, as well as her tireless pursuit of giving women XVs footballers the exposure they deserve.  

Both Josephine and Tony will fly to Dublin to watch the Wallaroos in action at the World Cup. 

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Why? Because they love it. Photo: Karen Watson
"We attend club rugby all the time and that's part of our family's DNA," Sukkar said. "The girls just need a little bit of advocacy and I guess a woman at my age and of my stage in my career ... I have to do a bit of missing property where you don't see a lot of women builders running around, women doing men's jobs. So I'm accustomed to advocating for and supporting women who are entering traditionally male-dominated professions.
"You get to know the girls pretty well. You see them working so hard." 
Sukkar has high hopes for the Wallaroos down the track but knows they need far greater support than they are getting at the moment, hence why she organised $1000 grants for players before the World Cup. 
"I can't think of a single reason why if we have a look at the women's sevens and if we invest in the women's XVs game properly, why we would not win a World Cup," Sukkar said. "The men have won two. If we can begin to put the same focus as we do on the women, we don't need the same investment, but we'll do OK if we get a bit of investment.
"It's the last piece of the puzzle for the ARU. The Wallabies and the women's and men's sevens are all contracted players. Whether the XVs women will end up there I don't know but it's exciting having some focus on them and some celebration and recognition." 
Sukkar made headlines in June when it was revealed Buildcorp had pulled its sponsorship of the NRC because the ARU was not committed to an equivalent women's XVs competition. 
The company's co-founder is sticking by the decision. 
"You've got to be careful sponsors don't start dictating what competitions look like, that would be the worst outcome ever," Sukkar said. "However, when companies invest sponsorship money, those competitions have to reflect who the businesses are. 
"We did say early in the piece we hoped to see a women's NRC within the three years of that sponsorship agreement and there wasn't going to be one this year, so we chose not to renew it. We wanted to invest in other areas of rugby." 
While it might appear Sukkar is at loggerheads with the ARU, that is far from the case. 
She is on a nominations committee that recommends directors for the ARU but has no desire to one day come in and shake things up, even if she believes there is far too much governance in Australian rugby at present. 
"As a sponsor I'm better keeping my distance," Sukkar said. "I'm very happy sponsoring rugby and if I just do that and nothing else I'm happy. And to look after the girls.
"The ARU are working really hard to understand how to best service the women's game but the reality is they don't control a lot of the local competitions, that happens through the provinces. 
"We are over governed in rugby and we need to understand how to restructure rugby to make it governable."  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josephine Sukkar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Pulver</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RFU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Women's Rugby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belfast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buildcorp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XVS</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josephine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sukkar</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
