<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437783294625764</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/gold-coast-has-plenty-to-play-for-in-seasons-second-qclash-writes-andrew-hamilton/news-story/22b2596c3b67d81983f8d11be5dd80bb</url>
  <title>QClash Judgement Day for Eade, Suns</title>
  <content>
JUDGMENT Day has arrived for the Gold Coast Suns.
Neither side has lost both QClashes in a season and although a win won't automatically save Rodney Eade, a loss to the Lions underlines another wasted year for the Suns that will cost him his job.
And as the author of the last comprehensive review of the Suns, head of football Marcus Ashcroft's fate, in his current role, is aligned with Eade's.
ANOTHER LOSS:
ALASTAIR LYNCH:
LOST GAMES:
It is obvious Eade senses the magnitude of this game, which is why he rested Michael Rischitelli from the trip to Perth to play Fremantle and took no risks with David Swallow.
A win doesn't save him but it could delay a decision.
The review into their football department was commissioned in the lead up to Round 16 which means the Suns have not won in five attempts since being told very publicly everyone was fighting for their futures.
It is an incomprehensible response.
Something about the place sucks the spirit out of people. Footy staff who have see the writing on the wall are already talking to AFL and NEAFL clubs. The politicking has been steadily ramping up.
It cuts straight to the core of the problem with the Suns that the instinct for too many is to search for the parachute when it should be to fix the engine.
Every week there is an excuse why the Suns are losing. It's injuries or inexperience.
Saturday at the Gabba is surely the opportunity 'Rocket' has been hanging out for.
There will be no valid excuses against the Lions who are younger, less experienced and sit below them on the ladder.
And they have injuries of their own. Allen Christensen is in their top five players and Mitch Robinson is their fiercest competitor. In a skinny young side they are major outs yet we haven't heard them mentioned by Chris Fagan.
Unless there are drastic changes to the two sides, the Lions will have three players with over 150 games experience in Tom Rockliff, Daniel Rich and Ryan Bastinac while the Suns will have Gary Ablett, Rischitelli, Jarrod Harbrow and Matt Rosa.
Ablett has played over 300 and Rischitelli more than 200.
The Suns are also better served in the 100 to 150 game range with Tom Lynch, Steve May, Pearce Hanley, Trent McKenzie and Swallow while for Brisbane Ryan Lester plays his 100th joining Dayne Beams, Dayne Zorko and Stefan Martin in that bracket.
Mark Evans was given a tough assignment when instructed to review good people he knows well and works closely with.
However the reality is his own tenure as CEO and the future of the whole organisation hinges on the football side achieving success.
In light of that, a loss to the Lions should make his decisions simple.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Rosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eade</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Ablett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Swallow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ablett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Rich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QClashes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen Christensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Ryan Lester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALASTAIR LYNCH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefan Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Ashcroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Bastinac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Beams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Rischitelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce Hanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Zorko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QClash Judgement Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rischitelli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Harbrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
