<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438470489399528</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836263/lions-into-the-top-five-after-defeating-lakes/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Lions into the top five after defeating Lakes</title>
  <content>
Lions into the top five after defeating Lakes

exit

South Newcastle have set up a season-defining clash with Cessnock this weekend after comfortably accounting for Lakes at Cahill Oval on Sunday. 

The defending premiers kept their finals aspirations alive with a 36-18 victory, moving into fifth spot on the competition ladder and within striking distance of the Seagulls approaching the business end of the year.

With two full rounds remaining the Lions now sit two points behind fourth-placed Lakes and two in front of the sixth-placed Goannas, who they meet in a crunch catch-up game at Townson Oval on Saturday.
"This was a must win for us and so is next week," Souths coach Ben Cross said.
"If we're serious and if we're any chance of having a good tilt at it, regardless of where we finish in the top five, obviously we need to win again next week to consolidate that spot." 

Lakes coach Dean Noonan was left to rue a missed opportunity to kick clear on the overall standings and cement an elimination semi-final at home next month.

Instead, after having this week off, the Seagulls tackle Kurri Kurri away and then host Cessnock on their run home to make the play-offs.
"We really could have skipped away with that one today, but we have't done that," Noonan said. "Now we've got to pay the price."  
Noonan said Lakes expect to have NSW Country under-23 centre Jacob Gagai back from a hamstring injury for the rest of this campaign.

"He [Gagai] has been out for an extended period but he'll be back against Kurri and that's great news for us," Noonan said. "He's worked really hard on his game this year and we've probably missed him a little bit."
Lakes were forced to play catch up for most of the round 13 fixture after Souths opened the scoring with tries to centres Mitch Knowles and Tim Christie on either side of the field in the opening 13 minutes.

The hosts replied shortly after and levelled proceedings at 10-all with two tries of their own courtesy of back-rower Dylan Hartin and five-eighth Cody Robbins.

Following end-to-end exchanges, including an incredible one-on-one strip by Lakes winger Callum Guest over the tryline after a full-field chase of Lions wideman Jacob Afflick, the visitors crossed twice before the break via Christie and skipper Brendon Simpson.  

Souths' 20-10 half-time advantage was reduced to six in the 50th minute when Hartin nabbed his double.

The Lions again responded with converted tries to five-eighth Ryan Glanville and hooker Liam Higgins either side of the hour mark.

Seagulls second-rower Chris Randall made the most of a short-side play from a drop out to make it 32-18 with five minutes left.   
Right on full-time Souths forward Faitoa Faitoa ensured the final margin was 18.
Elsewhere on Sunday and fullback Jake Maizen took his season-try tally to 14 after scoring four times in Central Newcastle's 40-20 win over Kurri Kurri at St John Oval. 

It means the Butcher Boys, who led 24-0 at the break, have all-but sealed a qualifying semi-final position and can still catch second-placed Macquarie while the Bulldogs slip to last based on for-and-against.  
Central's main injury concern was Steve Gordon (groin).
​LADDER: Western Suburbs 24, Macquarie 20, Central Newcastle 18, Lakes 14, South Newcastle 12, Cessnock 10, Maitland, Kurri Kurri 6.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Suburbs 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cahill Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hartin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Maizen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Glanville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butcher Boys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Newcastle 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townson Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Gagai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seagulls</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Newcastle 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Country</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Afflick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakes 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goannas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cody Robbins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Guest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Hartin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Knowles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Christie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gagai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Randall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noonan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faitoa Faitoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakes</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
