<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437521301618284</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/the-age-editorial/insecurity-risks-rising-as-falling-wages-shackle-australian-economy-20170804-gxpv77.html</url>
  <title>Insecurity, risks rising as falling wages shackle Australian economy</title>
  <content>
T
The biggest threat to the wellbeing of Australians is that falling real incomes will trigger a crisis of confidence and thus undermine the economic growth needed to create jobs and opportunity. That is the distillation of The Age's three-day analysis of the state of the nation, the final instalment of which we present today.
The majority of Australians have not had a real increase in wages in years, and the typical Australian family is earning less now than it did in 2009. Many households are getting by week to week. So our collective unease is understandable. Politicians and policymakers are struggling for solutions. The Reserve Bank of Australia has cut its forecast of economic growth. Its chief, Dr Philip Lowe, says "the crisis is really in real wage growth". Treasurer Scott Morrison says the nation's toughest challenge is "to ensure what Australians are earning every week is increasing".
Consumers cannot spend what they do not have, and with household spending being the biggest component of economic growth, it is in everyone's interest that the slump in incomes is arrested. The insecurity has crimped workers' confidence to negotiate even slim pay increases.
There is, though, capacity to stimulate the economy through the wage growth Mr Morrison, Dr Lowe and so many policy experts argue is crucial. Productivity and profits have outpaced wages. The share of national income going to wages is the lowest it has been for half a century, while the profit share has been rising. So far this year, profits are up almost 40 per cent, wages by less than 1 per cent.
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten is seeking to portray the problem as rising inequality, and it is true, as Dr Lowe has pointed out, that the decline in purchasing power does feed into inequality. Depending on the statistical measures used, it can be argued inequality has increased - and that it has fallen. So, that is an unproductive argument. The pressing issue is low growth in wages.

The woes cut across all generations. Home ownership is out of reach for most young people. Many breadwinners must work multiple jobs. Older people are delaying retirement, and have insufficient means to live securely when they do stop work.
Falling wages and slower economic growth contribute to multiple miseries, including poor mental health, family violence, broken relationships and substance misuse.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

During Bill Clinton's tilt at the US presidency in 1992, his campaign manager urged him to focus on one key message: "It's the economy, stupid." The language of economics is impersonal, but the economy is purely about people. And right now, a lot of people are struggling and resentful. 

 A note from the editor - Subscribers can get Age editor Alex Lavelle's exclusive weekly newsletter delivered to their inbox by signing up here: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Lavelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lowe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
