<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438049582600596</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/music/death-of-indigenous-musician-dr-g-yunupingu-was-preventable-according-to-his-doctor-20170806-gxqbzz.html</url>
  <title>Death of indigenous musician Dr G Yunupingu was preventable, according to his doctor </title>
  <content>
The loss of Australia's most prominent indigenous musician Dr G Yunupingu to kidney disease has shone a light on the "largely preventable" renal health nightmare afflicting remote communities, his doctor says.
singer died last month in Darwin while undergoing dialysis treatment, as there were no services available in his Galiwink'u community on Elcho Island.

Up Next
Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

01:28

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

The musical life of Dr G Yunupingu

The individual musical style of Dr G Yunupingu became an international sensation. Vision courtesy ABC

His specialist, Dr Paul Lawton told Garma Festival that many indigenous Australians have to travel hundreds of kilometres for end-stage renal therapy, which he describes as a "nightmare" akin to purgatory.
"You're neither alive nor dead," he said.

A similar diagnosis forced Yirrkala woman Gundimulk Wanambi to live 700km away from her coastal Arnhem Land community to access dialysis services.
"We want to come back home to our own country, our family ... so we can enjoy ourselves, go hunting and get our own food ... and feel healthy again," she said.

"Darwin is not my home."

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Aboriginal people are up to seven times more likely to need treatment for the chronic illness than their non-indigenous Australians.
This inequity is even worse for kidney transplants, Dr Lawton says.
"Compared to a non-indigenous patient in Surry Hills in Sydney, an indigenous patient with the same age and illness in Redfern right next door has a third of the chance of a kidney transplant," he said.Photo: Peter Eve
"An indigenous patient from east Arnhem... has a 10th of the chance of transplantation of a non-indigenous person from east Arnhem."
Emotional scenes at Garma Festival Photo: Peter Eve
This year's Garma Festival opened to emotional scenes on Friday: grief at the loss of indigenous musician Dr G Yunupingu, hope that Australia can pave a future towards reconciliation and outrage at a "lack of leadership" from politicians on constitutional reform.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull, Opposition Leader Bill Shorten and hundreds of guests joined hands at Gulkula's Bunggul grounds in northeast Arnhem Land to remember Australia's most prominent indigenous musician. Photo: Peter Eve
"He brought the Yolngu language to all Australians, his music will be forever cherished," Mr Turnbull said.
The coalition leader's wife Lucy Turnbull wept with grief-stricken female Gumatj clan members after a minute's silence was held and Yolngu traditional owners sang one of Dr G Yunupingu's songs about their gurtha or sacred fire.
Gumatj clan leader Galarrwuy Yunupingu pointed to the Referendum Council's recent Uluru Statement from the Heart and report, which calls for changes to the nation's founding document to allow an indigenous advisory body in parliament, a treaty-making mechanism and a reconciliation commission.
"At Uluru we started a fire. A fire that we hope burns bright for Australia," he said.
"We live side by side but we're not yet united ... this is the perfect place for us to find our path to a settlement."
Last year, four Arnhem Land Aboriginal community organisations raised $680,000 to expand on-country dialysis support in the region, and are calling on the Northern Territory and federal governments to match that funding.
"Sadly, the rollout of this life-saving service across Arnhem Land will come too late for our beloved singer, the late Dr G YunupiNGu, but we have a chance to make a difference for hundreds of other people now," Miwatj Health Chief Health Officer Dr Lucas de Toca said.
'The greatest voice'
Dr Yunupingu became the highest-selling Indigenous artist in history, selling more than half a million copies of his albums, which were sung in a mix of Yolngu and English.
He had been battling chronic liver and kidney-related problems for years prior to his death. 
Dr Yunupingu was once described as "the greatest voice this continent has ever recorded" and toured across the world, playing for audiences that included former US President Barack Obama, the Pope and Queen Elizabeth II. 
He was awarded an honorary degree of Doctor of Music by the University of Sydney in 2012. Dean Professor Anna Reid said Dr Yunupingu had made an "outstanding contribution" to music. 
In 2009 he was made the Northern Territory's Australian of the Year. Nominated nine times, he has received five ARIA awards. Last year he was named Artist of the Year at the NAIDOC awards. His daughter Jasmine collected the award on his behalf and ."
A film on Dr Yunupingu's life was due to premiere at the Melbourne International Film Festival later this month. The most recent post on the singer's Facebook page said the musician had been listening to audio from the film, scheduled to debut August 19.
He finished his last, and what promoters described as his "most powerful album", in May. 
The singer's management  at Royal Darwin Hospital, where he died, in 2016, and questioned whether he had received delayed care in the emergency department after being racially profiled - a suggestion the hospital firmly denied. 
Skinnyfish managing director Mark Grose said at the time that Dr Yunupingu's liver problems stemmed from contracting Hepatitis B as a child.
'Empty platitudes'
Referendum Council co-chair Pat Anderson slammed the "empty platitudes" made by Mr Turnbull and Mr Shorten in their "disrespectful" response to Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu.
"Most of us were really distressed," she said.
"I don't really know where to go from here. The lack of leadership is just devastating."
Mr Shorten called for a bipartisan joint parliamentary select committee to finalise a referendum question, while Mr Turnbull failed to commit bipartisan support.
"I understand that people feel politics has failed them and I think people have the right to be cynical," he said.
But Ms Anderson said it would be the fifth committee in as many years, and stressed the need for urgent action over words.
"We need another committee like a hole in the head," she said.
Mr Turnbull said he was heartened to see the Yolngu concept of makarrata or coming together after a struggle was the theme of the four-day festival.
"Our journey of reconciliation is made up of many steps, practical and symbolic," he said.
"From little things, big things grow."
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miwatj Health Chief Health Officer Dr Lucas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulkula's Bunggul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Yunupingu</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Paul Lawton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yirrkala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galiwink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolngu</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skinnyfish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elcho Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Eve</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Galarrwuy Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAIDOC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Darwin Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctor of Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redfern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gundimulk Wanambi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galarrwuy Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Professor Anna Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Artist Of The Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasmine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumatj</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hepatitis B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne International Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory's Australian of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lawton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Grose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
