<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438642288093004</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/on-giving-michelle-and-laurie-a-degree/news-story/2808507ff16631d1e097e3b55683eb14</url>
  <title>ON GIVING MICHELLE AND LAURIE A DEGREE</title>
  <content>
The lack of self-awareness is stunning.
Let's start with the obvious - that here are sanctimonious group-thinkers denouncing "brand" journalists while accepting brand accolades themselves:
A panel of Australia's top journalists gathered on Saturday night to discuss, amongst other things, the rise of "brand" journos who prefer to voice their own opinions and "exaggerate things" rather than sticking to the facts.
[Michelle] Grattan, chief political correspondent at The Conversation, told the audience: "We're getting into more and more opinion journalism, and people who make their reputation on opinion. People like [Alan] Jones, [Ray] Hadley and [Andrew] Bolt.
"Their whole cache is not only to reflect grievances but also to have distinct views. It's all black and white, and they are people who provide answers with not too much complexity. In a sense, it helps them if they exaggerate things rather than deal with facts."
The comments took place at Sydney University's honorary degree ceremony on Saturday night, an event which celebrated excellence in Australian journalism.
The panel consisted of Grattan, Laurie Oakes, Sarah Ferguson, Ray Martin and Caroline Jones, all of whom were awarded with honorary doctorates by the university.
Sarah Ferguson, a veteran ABC journalist, agreed with Grattan's sentiment: "... I loathe the word brand when it comes to journalism. I like the idea that The Economist has no bylines.
"Laurie, and Ray and Caroline and Michelle are entitled to their bylines because they have done decades of extraordinary work. But if I'm starting out in journalism, I don't need to have a profile..."
What astonishing sanctimony - and hypocrisy.
Ray Martin isn't a "brand"? Laurie Oakes isn't a brand?
Even more ironic is that here they all are, denouncing other journalists as brands while accepting honorary doctorates in the ultimate branding exercise.
These people have also accepted Walkely Awards, Logies and other brand-enhancing prizes. In contrast, I refuse to enter such awards, and the only time in 30 years I was entered it was against my knowledge or will ().
And then there's that solemn chin-stroking by these "top journalists" over commentators (allegedly including me) who "exaggerate things" and see everything in "black and white".
But here's Grattan at the very same discussion herself seeing the world of commentators in black and white - virtuous truth-telling Leftists over here, and snarly, exaggerating conservatives over there. I haven't seen such nuance since the last Punch and Judy show.
But let's speak now of exaggerations and seeing things in black and white.
Which commentator claimed the Liberals in 2009 would be ruined if they rejected the nice global warming policies of Kevin Rudd? And which saw this in such black and white terms that he abused one Liberal opponent as an "alien" simply for being sceptical of global warming alarmism?

Kevin Rudd and Company can hardly believe their luck... Unless (Opposition Leader Malcolm) Turnbull can bring the climate change dissidents to heel, the Liberals will face humiliation at the polls...

Laurie Oakes argued on 21 November [2009] that 'if Senator Minchin wins [in getting the Liberals to oppose Rudd's policy], the Liberal party loses' and accused Minchin of doing 'massive damage to the party'. His prediction that 'Mr Abbott would be electoral poison if he came to the leadership as the creature of Senator Minchin' has been somewhat undermined by a string of results from all major published opinion polls since Abbott was made leader. Oakes went even further in a later column, calling Minchin an alien 'from another planet' because of his climate change scepticism.
And which commentator saw global warming and Julia Gillard's carbon tax in such black and white terms that he exaggerated the cost of being sceptical and played down the price of falling for them?

IT should be possible to sell Julia Gillard's climate change package to voters. Despite Tony Abbott's alarmist claims, it can be portrayed as a good news story... I can reveal that work done by Treasury in final preparations for Sunday's big announcement shows that over a million more households will benefit from over-compensation via tax cuts and extra payments than was first thought.
And which commentator saw the detention of very troubled and violent children in the Northern Territory in such black and white terms that she wildly exaggerated the lawful measures that authorities took to restrain them?

Four Corners screened a highly emotional report claiming juveniles in detention in the NT were being abused.
This report, a month before the NT elections, opened with a shot of a young man being shackled by guards to a chair and with what seemed a bag over his head.
The ABC failed to tell viewers this hood was mesh and used to prevent the guards being spat on.
Host Sarah Ferguson then made clear that this was torture of the kind infamously demonstrated at Iraq's Abu Ghraib jail: "The image you have just seen isn't from Guantanamo Bay or Abu Ghraib but Australia in 2015 ... This is juvenile justice in the Northern Territory, a system that punishes troubled children instead of rehabilitating them."
I've written before that much of what you were told was false or outrageously one-sided.
The ABC failed to tell viewers the young man being strapped down, Dylan Voller, was not being tortured but restrained after threatening to hurt himself.
The ABC failed to tell viewers the hood was a mesh to stop him spitting on guards, as he'd done hundreds of times. And it failed to give a true picture of Voller's background.
It glossed over the threat he posed, claiming: "Voller has been in and out of juvenile detention since he was 11 years old for car theft, robberies and, more recently, assault."
False. The ABC failed to tell viewers that Voller's first convictions for assault actually dated back seven years and that of his more than 50 convictions, 23 were for assault or other attempts to hurt people, often police and warders.
And which commentator sees Australians in such black and white terms that he exaggerates our collective evil?

Now, while our political leaders like to insist that Australians are not racist, especially at election time, the report concludes that when it comes to Muslim/non-Muslim relations, we are racist.
"We"? Speak for yourself, Ray.
Which commentator sees politics in such black and white terms that he falsely accused the Howard Government of censoring his election night coverage?

The worm, that squiggle at the bottom of the television screen that tracks audience reaction to the leaders' debate, has ensured its place in history... Channel Nine had agreed not to use the worm during its live broadcast [of an election debate].
When its program began, complete with worm, the National Press Club, which was hosting the debate, cut the supply of vision and sound to the network... The Press Club's Vice-President Glenn Milne says Channel Nine clearly broke the agreement...
This morning Ray Martin told Nine's Today Show there was no agreement on the worm... "It's not the Prime Minister's election, it's our election and we could do it."...
He's accused the Liberal Party of cutting the broadcast but the Prime Minister's office says the Press Club CEO Maurice Reilly rang the Liberal Party's Federal Director Brian Loughnane during the broadcast and Mr Loughnane told him not to pull Channel Nine's feed.
And which commentator saw our border laws in such black and white terms that she cheered Kevin Rudd's reckless dismantling of them and for many months afterwards failed to see or refused to report on the mounted number of boat people lured to their deaths at sea?
And when one boat did actually sink within camera range of Christmas Island, which commentator - so black and white in her thinking - then lashed out at the only journalist to have listed from the start each known drowning and warned of more to come?

The Age's Michelle Grattan on Saturday accused me of "not a little distasteful triumphalism about prior warnings", but I don't know how else to prove that the Government was warned its policies were costing lives without quoting earlier warnings, and I also don't know which other journalist issued warnings I could quote.
If Grattan had warned the Government before last Wednesday that it was luring men, women and children onto sinking boats, I'd have quoted her instead of me. But she never did. Not once.
But as the death toll mounted, first five, then 14, then 25, then more than 40 and then - even before last week's tragedy - as many as 170 or even more, I did try to warn. Again and again and again, I wrote of these deaths and warned of more to come unless Rudd and Gillard changed policies that were tempting boat people to risk not only their own lives but those of their children.
But Grattan and Oakes and Ferguson and Doogue and Martin and the rest of the magic circle of group-thinkers, now awarded their honorary doctorates, never raised a murmur of protest against Rudd's lethal changes until it was too late.
Nor have any defied the prevailing group think and called out the global warming scare-mongering that has wasted billions of dollars and cost hundreds of jobs. None have called out the coal-seam gas scare that has left us short of cheap gas to heat homes and power factories. None called out the madness of replacing cheap coal-fired stations with expensive and unreliable wind farms that has helped to give us some of the world's highest power prices, leaving the poor unable to heat their homes in winter.
None have called out the mass immigration and refugee programs that have cost us so much and given us so little. None called out the folly and the danger of mass immigration from the Muslim third world. None warned against the refugee programs that have brought us the men behind our last four jihadist attacks.
None have called out the identity politics and new racism that is killing reason and dividing us so dangerously.
It is so comfortable to always go with the flow. Your errors are written off as virtues, and your critics as evil. Indeed, your errors are rarely noted because so many of your colleagues made them, too, that you do not stand out.
In fact, never challenging the pieties of the elites - no matter how wrong-headed or dangerous - wins you the gratitude of the institutions most devoted to them.
In fact, promote them long and loudly enough and you, too, could one day get an honorary doctorate, too. The formal membership of The Club.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grattan</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Minchin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walkely Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Rudd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Press Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Malcolm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minchin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voller</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GIVING MICHELLE AND LAURIE A DEGREE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Press Club CEO Maurice Reilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine's Today Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Ghraib</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guantanamo Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Press Club's Vice-President Glenn Milne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Age's Michelle Grattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Voller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hadley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Martin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party's Federal Director Brian Loughnane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Gillard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq's Abu Ghraib</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Ferguson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Loughnane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oakes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
