<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438595043452339</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/business/companies/gina-rineharts-wheelchair-mystery-at-the-end-of-the-fina-world-swimming-championships/news-story/b90a62e6da5392e65aeca9c02edd4e11</url>
  <title>Gina Rinehart</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIA™S richest woman Gina Rinehart was temporarily confined to a wheelchair after an undisclosed incident overseas.

Mrs Rinehart appeared in photos while in a wheelchair at the FINA World Swimming Championships in Budapest, where she supported the Australian Dolphins Swim Team as their patron.

In pictures published to Mrs Rinehart's website, the billionaire mining mogul can be seen mixing and mingling with members of the team including Olympic 400m freestyle champion Mack Horton. He was the only male medallist, picking up silver in the 400m and bronze in the 1500m.

She was also seen in pictures with Australia's Bronte Campbell, Emma McKeon, Taylor McKeown and Emily Seebohm after they won bronze for the women's 4x100m medley relay final.

Other photos show Mrs Rinehart attending the championships without the need for a wheelchair, confirming the incident happened towards the end of the event.

A note on her official website stated: "Congratulations to the Australian swim team. Those present, including Patron (and acting hon president, Gina Rinehart), witnessed how hard our swimmers tried at the FINA world championships, and their superb behaviour on and off the podium, making our country proud.

"On Sunday night, the last night of the swimming championships, Australia won bronze in the Women 4x100m Medley Relay. While accepting their bronze medal the girls waved to their Patron who was invited to see from the podium area. Rio gold medallist Mack Horton won bronze in the men's 1500m freestyle, after a gruelling race."

Swimming Australia President John Bertrand AO told News Corp Australia that she saw the final night of the championships in a wheelchair, but the incident did not happen poolside.

"I had left by the time it happened," he said.

"She saw the last night in a wheelchair but there's no cause for concern."

A spokeswoman for Mrs Rinehart told News Corp Australia that she still went along to watch the team as she did not want to let them down while she was in Hungary.

"She was there as a patron and she did not want to let the swim team down," she said.

"The wheelchair was only temporary."

When asked why she needed the wheelchair, her spokeswoman did not explain it further.

Days after the championships, she said that Mrs Rinehart was back on her feet and had boarded a train for North Yorkshire where she was visiting Sirius Minerals, a UK-based natural fertiliser business she invested $395 million in through her company, Hancock Prospecting.

Mrs Rinehart's undisclosed incident comes after she tripped down a set of stairs while leaving the Emirates Marquee at the Melbourne Cup last year.

Mrs Rinehart has been involved with the sport of swimming since 1992.

More recently Mrs Rinehart's Georgina Hope Foundation and Hancock Prospecting came on board as major partners of Swimming Australia with financial support in late 2012.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Rinehart</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Yorkshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FINA World Swimming Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic 400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor McKeown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gina Rinehart</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medley Relay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma McKeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emirates Marquee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia President John Bertrand AO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Rinehart's Georgina Hope Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack Horton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swimming Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hancock Prospecting</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FINA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Dolphins Swim Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirius Minerals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Seebohm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Bronte Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
