<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438822676720893</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/cost-of-living-fake-politicians-drive-voter-disenchantment-research-20170806-gxqb2q</url>
  <title>Cost of living, 'fake' politicians drive voter disenchantment: research</title>
  <content>
among swing voters in Australia's two largest cities according extensive focus group research which also reveals widespread disillusionment with federal political parties and their leaders.
It finds a general sense of disappointment with Malcolm Turnbull, a lack of trust and belief in Bill Shorten, and anger against  who was generally described as a "sook" and a "spoiler".
This extended beyond the major parties with no-one in the four groups tested being able to name the Greens leader, Richard Di Natale.
There is a consensus desire for leaders that are "real", who have conviction and vision and a commitment to seeing their vision through.

And while the Liberal Party fights among itself, there is no appetite for more turmoil and uncertainty.

"They all just fight. They just don't get on with the job. The minute someone gets in, someone's trying to topple him and they haven't even got the seat warm," was a typical response.
"If someone replaces him, it just repeats the cycle."
The research, conducted for Fairfax Media in Sydney and Melbourne last week by Ipsos Australia, reveals most feel their politicians are out of touch. While good at articulating the problems people face, they have no solutions. The words "disillusioned" and "disheartened" were among the most commonly mentioned.
Rich and overpaid

There was a general perception politicians were "rich" and overpaid and therefore unable to truly empathise.
Concern about house prices did not discriminate across age, political leaning or gender with older voters despairing for their children and the younger generation in general.
Following a close second is concern about energy prices, health, and education, both school and university.
People of all ages tended to blame foreign investment for the house price crisis and wanted stronger government intervention.

Andrew Meares

"It could be controlled by the federal government it could have a massive tax on foreign investment in residential housing," was a representative response.
Showing how difficult it can be sometimes for politicians to respond, the research shows voters either do not care or are not aware of the divided responsibilities between state and federal governments. Older swing voters in western Sydney, for example, mentioned motorway tolls, the drug ice, law and order, and ambulance waiting times among their chief gripes.
This week's resumption of Parliament after the Winter break will be dominated by the internal Coalition spat over same-sex marriage. This, along with the environment and social inequality, was more of a concern among younger voters than their older counterparts. Among the latter group, it was something they were tired of hearing about.
'A big let down'

Justin McManus

"Obviously it has to happen. I feel like it's coming. Why is this such a big deal, it's just such a non-issue, right?" said one.
The harshest criticisms were for the leaders themselves. Mr Turnbull is still well-regarded but was described variously as "a big let down" and "not as principled" as he was when he took over the leadership.
"He is talented, and he could have been, if he just had the guts, the political will," said one respondent.
Said another: "He had to pull so many levers when he took over from Abbott and now he can't move."

"He's a brilliant man but he's turning out to be an idiot because of the party behind him."
Mr Shorten is seen variously as too negative, untrustworthy, and unconvincing.
Unauthentic

"He's so unauthentic, he plays this working man ... he thinks it's to his advantage but I think it is totally transparent."
Said another: He isn't engaging to listen to, there is nothing positive, the way he looks there is nothing warm about him, his tone, everything."
One voter called him "a snake" while another said Mr Shorten could make a good prime minister.
"They can really blossom. Kevin [Rudd] was a dickhead until he got into power."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Di Natale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipsos Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
