<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439076079793724</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/we-have-exceeded-all-expectations/news-story/05dce85f426a8542e70202bb3868582b</url>
  <title>Music festival scores a success</title>
  <content>
THE Australian Festival of Chamber Music has welcomed record crowds with the 27th annual event's box office income having increased by about 10 per cent compared with last year.
Executive director Justin Ankus said he was thrilled with the success of the renowned event.
"We have exceeded all expectations with our box office income up by approximately 10 per cent on last year and attendance up by around 4 per cent on last year to well over 16,500. We will have final box office figures later this week," he said.
Two-thirds of attendees were from interstate with visitors contributing more than 28,000 bed nights and an estimated spend of $5.2 million in the region.
"We have achieved exceptional houses at all concerts with 10 concerts, a third of our events sold out over the 10 days, and we are ecstatic with those results," Mr Ankus said.
"The concert in the stunning Queen's Garden was one of my personal highlights but it's hard to select just one event.
"The magical concert in Sacred Heart Cathedral was very well received, the closing night concert was a blast, and the trip to Orpheus Island was spectacular, with an amazing concert and whales spotted.
"Where else would you rather be in winter?"
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queens Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orpheus Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sacred Heart Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Ankus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Festival of Chamber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ankus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
