<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438088237306772</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836757/liberal-mps-pushing-for-gay-marriage-have-voters-on-their-side/?cs=4219</url>
  <title>Liberal MPs pushing for gay marriage have voters on their side</title>
  <content>
Liberal MPs pushing for gay marriage have voters on their side

SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA - AUGUST 6:  Marriage Equality Rally from the Town Hall to Taylors Square, Oxford St on Auhgust 6, 2017 in Sydney, Australia.  (Photo by Ben Rushton/Fairfax Media)

exit

Liberal MPs pushing for a free vote on marriage equality will go into a special party room meeting armed with the authority of their own constituents, who overwhelmingly believe it is the job of politicians to decide on the reform.
The issue, which is being viewed as a serious threat to government solidarity and Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull's leadership, will come to a head at the Monday meeting in which reformers will push for a free vote in Parliament and conservatives will attempt to put another delay into the process with a voluntary mail-in aimed at testing public support.
Five rebel backbenchers - Dean Smith, Trent Zimmerman, Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Warren Entsch - have put their names to a private members' bill circulated to government MPs at the weekend. They hope the comprehensive set of religious protections in the bill will help persuade colleagues to support a free vote rather than a postal plebiscite.
The split could yet see the rebels cross the floor to support an opposition-led suspension of standing orders to facilitate the marriage equality debate and consideration of the bill drafted by Senator Smith, from Western Australia.
Research by ReachTEL for the Australia Institute think tank has found that voters in seven key seats - including two whose MPs have advocated a legislatively superfluous non-binding plebiscite - think their representatives should just get on with it.
The numbers cut the ground from those who say the Australian people are demanding a say in a reform that has been enacted in many comparable countries.
In Mr Turnbull's own Sydney seat of Wentworth, 72 per cent said the MP should vote on the question according to personal belief when asked: "Do you believe that your federal member of Parliament should be allowed to vote according to their own opinion and conscience on marriage equality or should be bound to vote according to his political party's position on the issue?"
In the electorates of Brisbane, Goldstein, North Sydney, and Leichhardt - represented by four of the five rebels - voters are strongly supportive of an immediate conscience vote, at the rates of 66.1 per cent, 77.1 per cent, 71.4 per cent, and 67.5 per cent, respectively.
In La Trobe, in Melbourne's outer east, Liberal Jason Wood has indicated he would regard a vote as a conscience matter if it arises in Parliament and that he would back change. His voters endorsed his right to do by 72 per cent to just 20 per cent who opposed him having a free say.
Even in the National Party heartland seat of Mallee, held by the fiercely conservative Andrew Broad who has threatened to defect to the crossbench if Parliament votes without a plebiscite, 63.7 per cent favour him using a conscience vote.
"These results are further demonstration that momentum is building for a conscience vote in the Parliament, with the MPs wanting change having history on their side as well as the full backing of their electorates," said the institute's executive director, Ben Oquist.
Senator Smith said the Marriage Amendment (Definition and Religious Freedoms) Bill would enshrine protections and exemptions for religious communities.
"None of the other bills that have ever come before the Parliament - we've had in excess of 15 of them - have more comprehensively dealt with the issue of religious freedoms or religious protections," Senator Smith told ABC's Insiders on Sunday.
"Now, this is important because there might be some people in my own party that would like to legislate for same-sex marriage but want to be satisfied that those religious freedoms will be in place. This bill does that. People cannot be guaranteed that if a future Labor government is elected, these religious freedoms will be there."
Under the bill, both religious ministers and civil celebrants who refuse to marry same-sex couples will be protected from legal action. The bill will create a new category of "religious marriage celebrants" who can legally refuse to officiate a same-sex ceremony.
Business owners and service providers such as bakers, florists and photographers would need to prove they are linked to a "religious body" to reject a same-sex wedding.
Senator Smith says a mail-in vote would be worse than the original plebiscite proposal, costing up to $100 million but lacking in any force or authority. It would disenfranchise younger voters and Australians overseas, and , he said.
A postal vote would likely be struck down by the High Court unless it was underpinned by specific legislation - which would almost certainly be rejected by the current Senate - according to the legal advice obtained by marriage equality advocates.
Opposition frontbencher Tony Burke says even if the government splits Labor "will not use this issue as an issue of confidence in the government - in no way, shape or form".

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Insiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Religious Freedom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auhgust 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wentworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Oquist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Amendment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rushton/Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylors Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Trobe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mallee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ReachTEL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Equality Rally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leichhardt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
