<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438994475414276</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/im-coming-out-gay-elders-embrace-new-dance-club-20170806-gxqep4.html</url>
  <title>I'm coming out: gay elders embrace new dance club  </title>
  <content>
After a lifetime of guilt and secret longings, David Morrison came out as gay at age 76.
He and his wife, Margaret, had raised a family together. "I loved my wife. I'd have laid down my life for her. But it was not a soul relationship, you know?" he says, adding, "But what marriage is perfect"? Photo: Daniel Pockett
When Margaret died in 2006, he felt able to explore that suppressed part of himself.  He joined Vintage Men, an older gay men's social group.
Now aged 87, he is the oldest regular of the , at Fitzroy Town Hall. He says now: "I do feel quite happy in myself." Photo: Bryony Jackson
Members travel from across Melbourne - to dance, but also to eat, drink, and laugh in a safe space.
Some have been "out of the closet" for years. Others are taking their first steps.

Mr Morrison claims he isn't much of a dancer. But once the music gets going, he's swaying in wicked time, a wide smile on his face.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

A father of two and now grandfather of five, he was raised Catholic and as a young man in the air force, homosexuality was not tolerated. Photo: Bryony Jackson
In the early 1970s, when he working in technical support for a university physics department, a colleague baldly asked, "You're gay, aren't you"?
"I said, 'Yeah, I guess', but it was a bit of a surprise."Photo: Daniel Pockett
The man took him to clubs "although nothing happened ... I couldn't tell my wife. I was just having a look around. I was intrigued."
"In the 1980s I used to go to the Laird Hotel and I did a lot of line dancing and I loved it. And progressive dances, when you're dancing with guys, like a barn dance." 
Now he likes "dancing individually waving your arms around doing side steps and that sort of thing. Twists and twirls.
"But on a couple of occasions I've had to stand aside, I can find myself not being steady, I have a little break.
"That's how life goes. We accept ourselves as we are now."
Mr Morrison said the LGBTI Elders Dance Club could help people "to be involved with the LGBTI communities. To not just be alone, to be willing to mix with others."
The club is the idea of entrepreneur Tristan Meecham, who says it's a place to connect with others in a supportive environment. 
On October 7, Mr Meecham's company, All the Queens Men, will stage the inaugural at Melbourne Town Hall for 600 LGBTI elders, with performers including Robyn Archer, Carlotta and Deborah Cheetham. 
It will be free for over 65s LGBTI elders. Mr Meecham said the idea is for elders to "to have a wonderful evening to feel part of the broader community".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robyn Archer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Meecham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI Elders Dance Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vintage Men</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laird Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tristan Meecham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlotta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deborah Cheetham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pockett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queens Men</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzroy Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryony Jackson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
