<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439071784826329</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/origin-energy-joins-smart-meter-sale-queue-network-ten-bid-date-approaches-20170804-gxpu1r</url>
  <title>Origin Energy joins smart meter sale queue, Network Ten bid date approaches </title>
  <content>
Another week, and another industry giant has put its smart metering division on the block.
Street Talk understands Origin Energy is the latest company to consider a sale of its smart meter business which spans its specialist Acumen unit as well as other areas including installations. Bank of America-Merrill Lynch has been appointed to manage the process.  
More than 90,000 smart meters had been installed by Acumen as at Origin's interim results and shareholders will get a clearer read on growth when the company reports its full-year numbers on August 16.
, so it will be interesting to see if the financial services group emerges as a suitor.

The two companies already have close ties on the advisory side and share a common director Gordon Cairns. He is Origin's chairman and a Macquarie non-executive director.

Macquarie claims it is the largest smart meter funder in the UK and the biggest independent meter funder in Australia. It defines independent as separate to retail energy producers.
Last week, , which could be worth around $100 million. 
New Zealand's electricity giant Vector, Macquarie and KKR & Co's Calvin Capital are among parties that are in-and-around an auction. 
AusNet Services had been considering its options for its metering business Select Solutions, but it's understood a sale process is not underway.

Elsewhere, Network Ten's long list of suitors have under two weeks to lodge bids for the free-to-air broadcaster with a view to have a deal in place by the end of August.
It's now understood offers for Ten are due by August 18.
The guarantee of from Ten's billionaire shareholders - Bruce Gordon, Lachlan Murdoch and James Packer - for an extra $30 million on top of the $97 million Ten had drawn down from its original $200 million loan, backed by the trio, which was frozen when the company went into administration, runs out at the end of August.
Sources said PPB Advisory and Moelis & Co, who are running Ten's sale process, are keen to get a deal in place by then.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Ten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KKR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AusNet Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Select Solutions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moelis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co's Calvin Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPB Advisory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrill Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin Energy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
