<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439080374761117</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-east/glow-winter-arts-festival-promises-to-light-up-stonnington/news-story/05fac1c5b29a305bf629877d65a4ce96</url>
  <title>Festival aims to spread winter glow</title>
  <content>
THE Glow Winter Arts Festival is back for another year to light up darkened streets and bring laughter in the midst of dreary winter.
On from August 10 to 20, the annual Stonnington Council family-friendly event celebrates arts, culture and community.
This year promises a jam-packed line-up of activities, entertainment and interactive installations in streets, parks and other venues.
Mayor Jami Klisaris said the festival was a chance to explore the area's nooks and crannies after dark.
"This is an opportunity to discover our city in new ways," Cr Kilsaris said.
Highlights will include an illuminated installation of giant flowers at Central Park in Malvern East and the antics of the comedy ensemble Dislocate, who tie together slapstick theatre, storytelling and circus skills.
Butterflies perched on light posts will whisper words of advice to passing guests as they admire light projections played across the walls of old buildings.
And BK Opera brings its moving opera performance to Greville St.
For more information about the free and ticketed festival events, visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malvern East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greville St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Kilsaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Jami Klisaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glow Winter Arts Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BK Opera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
