<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438350230314257</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/redbacks-relish-training-camp-at-maroochydore/3209411/</url>
  <title>Redbacks relish training camp at Maroochydore</title>
  <content>
CRICKET: The representative schedule of South Australian Travis Head has certainly intensified in the past year, with a raft of new national commitments mixing in with his already burgeoning state career.
But, the 23-year-old is taking it in his stride and is relishing a week-long pre-season camp in the sun with the Redbacks on the Sunshine Coast.
Head made his coveted debut for the Australian Twenty20 side last year and soon after played his first game for the Australian one day side.
The left-handed batsman also juggled commitments with the Big Bash League's Adelaide Strikers, who he has played for since 2013.
"It was a busy summer last year," he said.
"I didn't miss a lot of cricket for South Australia, but I missed a little bit."
It's set to be another busy summer for Head but the Redbacks captain is locked into a domestic league mindset for now, as he joined his state team-mates for their first day of training on the Coast on Saturday.
"I guess with no Australian A tour it was a nice time just to be back with the boys," he said.
"I haven't had a pre-season for a few seasons (with Redbacks), so having a month is really good with the boys and I'm feeling good."
Head wasn't part of the team's pre-season visit to the Sunshine Coast last year but said it was nice "to get out in the sun and have a hit" in the region's warmer climate.
"We've been indoors for the whole pre-season so there's a few itching for a bit of outdoor training," he said.
The team hit the nets and field for a range of training and fitness exercises.
"The bowlers get to bowl off a long run and batters get a hit outdoors and as the week progresses we'll ramp it up and start doing a couple of match scenario-style stuff and a bit more specific things with the white ball with Matador Cup in mind," Head said.
Just missing out on Sheffield Shield glory against Victoria in the 2016-17 grand final, he was hopeful to go one better this year.
"That's always the aim when you go into it, you want to win silverware," he said.
"The last two seasons have been really good so we'll just keep on improving on that.
"The boys are fitter again this year and stronger and more experienced so I think we tick most boxes to hopefully keep that consistent standard going."
The Redbacks will remain on the Sunshine Coast until the end of the week.
The Maroochydore Cricket Club will play host to a number of other state squads in the coming weeks and will also be home to Matador Cup practice matches in September.
Nearly 4000 people attend concert at stadium
Rescue helicopter, SES, firies on scene at Mt Beerwah for rescue
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Netflix health doco slammed for scaremongering, 'cherrypicking' data
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Travis Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheffield Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matador Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Twenty20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Cricket Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League's Adelaide Strikers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
