<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438255741032693</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/tony-abbott-a-sook--and-a-sulking-kid-say-disillusioned-swing-voters-20170806-gxqb4m</url>
  <title>Tony Abbott a 'sook'  and a 'sulking kid', say disillusioned swing voters</title>
  <content>
Tony Abbott may see his role as the upholder of conservative values in a Malcolm Turnbull-led Liberal party, but swing voters are not buying it.
In extensive focus group polling conducted last week by Ipsos Australia for Fairfax Media, the dominant reaction to Mr Abbott was that he was "a sook" who voters wished would go away.
Focus group polling tests attitudes and opinions, rather than actual voting intention, and the reaction to Mr Abbott's name was near unanimous.
"Forget about Abbott, I wish we could," said one woman. Others remarked that "he's a sook", "like a sulking kid", "spoilt kid" and spoiler.

AAP

"I think he's just starting trouble. Sulking. He didn't get his way. They kicked him out and now it's pouting and he's just causing trouble," said one man who voted Liberal last year and still likes Mr Abbott personally.

"He should be working with them, not against them."
Wasting our time

The reaction to Mr Abbott, who is destabilising Mr Turnbull after losing the prime ministership in a coup in 2015, dovetails with a broader discontent from the swing voters over what they see to be constant infighting while nothing gets done.
"They all just fight. The minute someone gets in, someone's trying to topple him and they haven't even got the seat warm," was one typical comment.

Another was: "I've become very disillusioned with the whole way the fighting is going between Tony Abbott and Malcolm Turnbull. Instead of governing the country with concrete policies ... they're wasting their time and our time."
Ipsos conducted four focus groups last week. On Monday night, two groups of undecided voters in western Sydney were tested, One group comprised votes aged 45 and over who voted Liberal in 2016 and a group aged between 18 and 45 which voted Labor last year. On Tuesday night in Melbourne, a group of 45s and over who voted Labor in 2016 were tested, followed by a group of 18-to-45s, who voted Liberal.
All voters from all four groups are undecided voters.
﻿

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipsos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull-led Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipsos Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
