<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438831266655557</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/investment-banking/sims-metal-wants-growth-ceo-and-not-a-change-agent-20170806-gxq8jj</url>
  <title>Can a turnaround CEO also be a growth expert? Not at $2.7b scrap metal firm Sims</title>
  <content>
The chairman of $2.7 billion metal recycling company Sims Metal says he is in the company's share price on Friday, but says the board has made the right "tough" decision in forcing leadership change at the top.
Geoff Brunsdon, a former investment banker , said on Sunday the board was prepared to wear some short-term pain as it opted to install a "growth" chief executive at the helm. It has dispensed with a turnaround and cost-cutting specialist in Galdino Claro, who had been chief executive at Sims for four years. It also triggered the abrupt exit of chief financial officer Fred Knechtel, who worked closely with Mr Claro.
"It's the job of the board to look to the future," Mr Brunsdon told The Australian Financial Review.
"It's clearly a tough decision. Sometimes you've got to take a bit of short-term pain," he said.

Sims appointed Alistair Field as chief executive. Mr Field had been managing director of the Australia and New Zealand business at Sims for two years and has a long track record as a senior executive at logistics firm Asciano and at mining giant Rio Tinto.

Mr Claro was aggrieved at the decision to remove him and felt he had more to give after leading a solid turnaround. But the board was steadfast that Sims had entered a new phase and needed a different type of leader built around strong growth plans.
"Galdino was a great change agent," Mr Brunsdon said on Sunday.
He said events had happened fast, but that was because the board didn't want to sit around once it became clear that change at the top was coming.
"Once you make the decision, you can't just leave it on the shelf," Mr Brunsdon said. 

Mr Brunsdon was surprised at the extent of the 12.5 per cent share price fall on Friday, particularly given Sims had been clear to investors that there was no "black hole" in the books.
"Yes I was. I think it sort of highlights the differences there are with an internal view, balanced against the external view," he said.
Sims said on Friday it expected underlying earnings before interest and tax to be in the range of $180 million to $185 million. This compared with consensus estimates of $178 million.
Mr Brunsdon said the fact that two internal executives were able to step up as replacements was a good sign. Amit Patel, who has been the chief accounting officer at Sims since 2008, has been made acting group chief financial officer.

Citi analyst Simon Thackray said on Friday the "timing and lack of clarity" around the reasons for the executive departures were of concern.
Sims, which operates 200 metal recycling facilities in 20 different countries, has suffered a 17 per cent drop in its share price overall since July 11, when the stock was trading at $16.12.
Mr Brunsdon was confident that Sims had the right foundation now to build back up.
"It's not a board's job to say what the share price should be," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amit Patel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Claro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galdino Claro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asciano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Brunsdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred Knechtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galdino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIM</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sims Metal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brunsdon</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALISTAIR FIELD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Thackray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
