<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437955093319129</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/06/17/50/would-be-parents-urged-to-undergo-genetic-screening</url>
  <title>The warning every couple needs to hear before starting a family</title>
  <content>
A Sydney children's doctor who delivers heartbreaking diagnoses to first-time parents is calling for more couples to undergo genetic screening before starting a family.
Paediatric Neurologist Dr Michelle Farrar specialises in Spinal Muscular Atrophy (SMA) Type 1, which is the biggest genetic killer of babies under two years old.
"This is where I feel very sad about potential missed opportunities," Dr Farrar, who works at Sydney Children's Hospital, told 9NEWS.
"There is preconception screening and allows couples to know if they're carriers for severe, rare genetic disorders before they plan to have a baby," she said.
"There needs to be education and resources to enhance the awareness and I think potentially with those, this could be a preventable disease."
First-time parents Rachael and Jonathan were heart broken when their baby daughter, Mackenzie, was diagnosed with SMA this year.
"One in 35 people carry it (the gene) and we found out that it was preventable," she said.

Related Articles

"There was a blood test that we could've taken to find out that we were carriers before... we (wondered) why were we not offered it."
Rachael said not knowing about the disease or the test made her angry after doing everything to prepare herself before falling pregnant.
"We think there needs to be a bigger focus on genetic testing for would-be parents," Jonathan, Mackenzie's father, said.
"There are tests out there that test for 175 different recessive disorders and it can be stopped in its tracks," he said.
Mackenzie's parents have decided on palliative care for their daughter.
Another couple, left devastated by the same disease, are trying a novel, but expensive, treatment for their daughter Aviana.
The drug is called Nusinersen, and while 13-month-old Aviana has become stronger and more mobile on the treatment, it is not a cure.
"We're uncertain of the future. We know the future is probably not great still," Aviana's father, Johnny McElwee, said.
"What it does give us is the chance to have quality time, the chance to enjoy this moment," he said.
Dr Farrar said there are more promising treatments in the pipeline.
"We are starting to see the first ever novel therapies reaching patients and getting motor outcomes."
But she said the high cost of orphan drugs could limit access.
Aviana's mother, Bethan, said she believes that one day there will be a cure, but until that day comes, genetic testing is vital.
"When we were told she had SMA, we'd never heard of it and then we were told it's the biggest genetic killer," she said.
"Why were we not told?"
For more information about Prepair and Counsyl screening, click  and .
What is Spinal muscular atrophy (SMA)
*SMA is a genetic condition which causes muscle weakness and wasting
*A child with SMA type 1 rarely lives beyond two years.
*About 1 in 6,000 babies born have Spinal Muscular Atrophy
*One in 35 people carry the SMA gene
*Both parents must carry the mutated gene to pass on the disease
*If both parents are carriers - there is a one in four chance their child will inherit the disease
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackenzie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nusinersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Farrar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachael</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Type 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counsyl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spinal Muscular Atrophy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aviana</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bethan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neurologist Dr Michelle Farrar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny McElwee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prepair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
