<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439033130120257</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/crunch-time-for-malcolm-turnbull-in-samesex-marriage-showdown-20170806-gxq8xv</url>
  <title>Crunch time for Malcolm Turnbull in same-sex marriage showdown </title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull and his senior ministers are banking on a strong majority of the Liberal party room opposing an immediate free vote on same-sex marriage in Monday's emergency meeting to convince backbench rebels to back off and avoid splitting the government.
But in an attempt to find a compromise that gives all sides something they can seize on, one possibility being canvassed is setting a specific date for a parliamentary free vote later this year or early next year in conjunction with the announcement of a .
Ministers believe a postal plebiscite could be conducted by Christmas if it survives a threatened High Court challenge that gay marriage activists have vowed to immediately launch.
Liberal MPs will meet in Canberra at 4pm for a  to discuss the future of the party's election commitment to a plebiscite before allowing a parliamentary vote.

Sources said that based on a straw poll of the 83 Liberal MPs and senators, about 58-60 would hold firm on wanting a plebiscite while around 23-25 would prefer the party move straight to a free vote in Parliament.

Little appetite for change

"He can't ignore the majority of the room," said an ally of Mr Turnbull. "The numbers for this [change] are simply not in the room."
Should this scenario unfold, it is likely the first response will be to try again and put the legislation for a plebiscite to the Senate.
Given this is likely to be rejected again, the next plan would be for the postal plebiscite, which the government believes can be established without legislation.

Such a course of action would allow Mr Turnbull to claim no election promise had been broken, address conservatives' demands for "the people to have their say", and give cover to Liberals to support legalising gay marriage as a reflection of the public's will.
To try to appease the five Liberal dissidents pushing for an immediate free vote, a date would be locked in for when Parliament would vote to legalise same-sex marriage, although the flaw with this strategy is what happens if the pro-change camp fails to gain majority support.
The rebels - Senator Dean Smith and lower house MPs Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Warren Entsch and Trevor Evans - will wait until after Nationals MPs give their input at Tuesday's joint party room meeting before deciding whether  in the House of Representatives.
Sources believe Mr Entsch will push ahead for a free vote regardless of the party room's decision but a strong showing of support for the status quo from their colleagues may induce the others to retreat.

Appeal to conservatives

The gang of five released on Sunday their private members' bill, attempting to comfort conservatives by stressing protections for religious freedom in the bill.
Clergy and civil celebrants would be protected from legal action under anti-discrimination laws if they refused to solemnise same-sex marriages because it clashed with their beliefs.
The protections do not extend to businesses servicing the wedding industry, such as bakers, florists and venue operators, unless they belong to a body established for "religious purposes".

"People cannot be guaranteed that if a future Labor government is elected, these religious freedoms will be there," Senator Smith said.
The pro-gay marriage agitators received a further boost when Labor's chief parliamentary tactician Tony Burke gave assurances on Sunday the Opposition would not attempt to turn any parliamentary debate on the issue into a broader no confidence vote in the government.
Opponents argued that any move by the rebels to cross the floor to vote with Labor to suspend standing orders to debate on a gay marriage bill would be a de facto loss of confidence in Mr Turnbull.
"We want to be able to give an absolute guarantee to those members of the Liberal Party who are pursuing this that if anyone puts to them this would amount to a vote of no confidence in the government, it would not," Mr Burke said.

Activists marshal their troops

Hundreds of gay-marriage supporters rallied in Sydney to show their support ahead of the party room meeting.
Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays has obtained legal advice from Ron Merkel QC claiming the government needs to pass a new law to allow a postal plebiscite and allocate specific funds to conduct the vote.
"Some in the government are so intent on continuing the discrimination of LGBTI people they are now stooping to unconstitutional practice," national spokeswoman Shelley Argent said.
"As a mother of a gay son and as a representative of parents in this country with LGBTI children I will not hesitate to take the government to the High Court to stop a postal vote."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friends of Lesbians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelley Argent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron Merkel QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
