<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438818381753523</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/we-made-mistakes-says-cba-boss-ian-narev-20170806-gxqerj</url>
  <title>'We made mistakes', says CBA boss Ian Narev  </title>
  <content>
Commonwealth Bank of Australia chief executive Ian Narev has admitted the bank "made mistakes" in failing to report money laundering but defended his leadership, saying he is "motivated" to help restore trust and that problems identified by Australia's financial transactions regulator don't reflect cultural shortcomings under his watch.
In an interview with The Australian Financial Review on Sunday morning at the bank's Sydney headquarters, Mr Narev said CBA is taking the case  "extremely seriously". He vowed "unequivocally" that senior executives would be held accountable although punishments could only be determined once the legal process had run its course.
He said reduced pay packets for senior management and staff was a matter for the board of directors, which will meet on Monday to approve CBA's full-year results to be released on Wednesday.
Mr Narev had no criticism of the Australian Transactions Reports and Analysis Centre (AUSTRAC ) for bringing the court action against CBA. But he warned other banks against throwing stones, declaring it would be "bold" for any bank CEO to declare their compliance systems were perfect.

While AUSTRAC claimed CBA violated the law more than 53,500 times when it failed to file "threshold transaction reports" on time for deposits of more than $10,000, CBA argues this was caused by the same error in computer code being run on its "intelligent deposit machines". This prevented reports from being generated automatically. "That's the nub of it ...This is the coding problem. They are all related to that single change of coding in 2012 which delinked them."

As a result, the bank believes it only violated the law once, and that any fine - which will be determined by the Federal Court - ought to reflect this. Unlike cases brought by the Australian Securities and Investments Commission, the only way AUSTRAC can extract a penalty is to issue civil proceedings. The claim had not been filed as a result of negotiations collapsing, Mr Narev said, maintaining the bank has had "a very constructive dialogue with AUSTRAC".
CBA self-reported the extent of the reporting failure to AUSTRAC after it had identified two reports were missing. "When you're a big institution, mistakes can have a big impact," he said.
The latest failures follow scandals in CBA's financial planning and insurance divisions, which Mr Narev also had to mop up. He said these cases had been "very difficult and hard and upsetting things to work through" but had "solidified" the resolve of his team to focus and improve. He said he remained committed to leading the bank through its latest travails.
"I've made my share of mistakes, and maybe even more, during that time, and if ever it was in the best interests of the bank for me not to be the chief executive, I would hopefully realise that, and if others had to tell me I totally respect that," Mr Narev said.

"I feel a very strong sense of energy and motivation working on both the opportunities and also these very difficult matters. And everything beyond that, as you would expect, is for the board to work out."
Although the allegations are before the court, Mr Narev pledged transparency. "We can't just say wait till our defence, so we're departing from the normal to be as open as we possibly can because we recognise the public interest," he said.
"Clearly when we have developments like we've had here, we will absorb everything that we have learnt that we didn't know from what we've heard from AUSTRAC, and feed that into a process which says, are we doing enough?"
While the broken code resulted in the "mistake" of not filing the thousands of "threshold transaction reports", Mr Narev said it would be for the Federal Court to determine whether CBA met its obligations by generating enough "suspicious matter reports".

AUSTRAC alleged CBA failed to report suspicious matters either on time or at all, and failed to monitor various customers even after it became aware of suspected money laundering or "structuring" of deposits, which refers to making numerous deposits under reporting thresholds. Algorithms in the surveillance systems would never to be perfect, Mr Narev said. "The question is are they good enough. And that will obviously be a topic of discussion in the proceedings."
AUSTRAC's claim also revealed CBA appeared to be slow in dealing with various requests from its own staff and internal teams which identified suspicious activity. For example, an alert by a concerned branch manager in Leichhardt, in Sydney, on May 28 2015 - that a series of large deposits had been made on one of the accounts the subject of criminal proceedings - were not reviewed by the bank's Anti Money Laundering team until June 29 and 30. In the interview, Mr Narev sought assure staff their reports of suspicious activity "are listened to", but said the bank's response to allegations of delay would be made in the legal defence.
Shadow Minister for Financial Services Katy Gallagher said on Sunday the allegations against CBA  "to restore faith in our banking and financial system", although Mr Narev said AUSTRAC's case showed it is a diligent regulator, making a Royal Commission unnecessary.
After ANZ Banking Group CEO  against CBA, Mr Narev warned that "any CEO of a major bank anywhere in the world who says they definitely don't have any problems with financial claims compliance would be a very bold CEO, because...you've always got to improve your controls."

Despite its extensive allegations, AUSTRAC's case does not reflect a poor culture at CBA, Mr Narev argued. "I do not believe that what we're seeing here, is the result of any cultural aspects in the organisation...People can make their own views from the outside, but sitting here as the CEO, I can say for the mistakes that we've made here, we need to acknowledge them, we need to fix them [and] we are fixing them. But I feel confident in saying that the culture is strong. And I think if you look at the sort of feedback I've had from our people on this, you'd probably form a similar view."
With technology becoming a much bigger part of how banks will do business, Mr Narev said it not only creates opportunities for banks but "it obviously creates different risks". Many CBA customers complain that it was too difficult to open accounts, he said, but "the priority for us is to find the appropriate balance between rigorous compliance and safety and customer experience."
"The more you innovate and try and do things for people you've got to realise, just as a fact of life, that there are going to be people who are going to try and exploit it.... We will always engage with AUSTRAC and other regulators on how we can work together to keep things safe."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Services Katy Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 28 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Transaction Reports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Banking Group CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Analysis Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leichhardt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
