<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438985885479624</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-opinion/fairfaxipsos-focus-groups-major-parties-doing-nothing-to-prevent-populist-anger-infiltrating-australia-20170806-gxqea5.html</url>
  <title>Major parties doing nothing to prevent populist anger infiltrating Australia</title>
  <content>
When a focus group of undecided voters in a marginal seat was asked to discuss politics, two politicians' names were conspicuously absent.
The voters, mostly in their 20s, spent an hour on the topic without once mentioning the names of the prime minister or the opposition leader. 

Up Next

Search called off for US Marines

01:09

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Push for four year terms

Bill Shorten has reignited debate over fixed four year terms of government and Malcolm Turnbull is interested.

"[It is] interesting to see leaders were completely irrelevant, not even a mention of Turnbull or Shorten an hour into the conversation," remarked the moderator of the group, Ipsos research director Laura Demasi.
The main parties and the political class have taken themselves to the brink of oblivion in these voters' lives, opening the way for populist insurgents and minor parties.Photo: Andrew Meares
The Coalition government and the Labor opposition are preoccupied with machinations and performances that hold absolutely no interest for these voters.
And while the younger voters were deeply uninterested, groups of older voters were just deeply sceptical.

"They just compete with each other for power," said one man. "They want the power and the money and the big pensions - they don't give a shit about us." And voters know that handouts are not solutions: "Stop bribing us," said a woman.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Yet voters, sometimes spontaneously, brought up the names of some of the fringe figures - Pauline Hanson and Derryn Hinch won plaudits for speaking their minds. Nick Xenophon won tributes as an effective negotiator and a sensible man.
"Hanson," said one woman, "blurts out what everyone else is thinking."
Malcolm Turnbull has failed utterly to persuade these undecided voters that he has accomplished anything whatsoever.
After nearly two years in power, this is a signal failure. Voters saw that he was a powerless captive of his party's conservative wing. They've given up on him.
And Bill Shorten has failed to persuade them that he would be any better, although one older voter said that Shorten had his attention on the issue of inequality. No one could name the Greens leader. 
Unless the main leaders can stop indulging their own political self-absorption and speak powerfully and consistently about voters' problems, the voters will turn to the fringe politicians who can.
And the most effective kind of speech is action. As Prime Minister, this is Turnbull's advantage. Seen as ineffectual, he is frittering it away.
A woman's comment went to the heart of the voter disenfranchisement: "Deep down," she said, "which ever one you vote for, you just know they're not going to fix anything."
The populist anger that has gripped the US and UK and much of Europe has largely been absent in Australia. But unless the main parties change dramatically, it's probably just a matter of time.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Demasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipsos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
