<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438839856590271</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:15</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/markets/reserve-bank-has-good-news-and-bad-for-the-big-four-20170804-gxpdaz</url>
  <title>Reserve Bank has good news and bad for the big four</title>
  <content>
At a time when the prospect of a royal commission is striking ever greater dread into the hearts of the chiefs of the big four banks -  - they might like to reflect on the glimmer of good tidings provided by the Reserve Bank of Australia.
In its latest Statement on Monetary Policy, the Reserve Bank points out that the big banks' interest rate margins - the gap between what they pay for deposits and what they charge for loans and which is a key driver of bank profitability - are continuing to widen. That's because banks have responded to tighter prudential guidelines by increasing the interest rates they charge for investor and interest-only home loans at a time when their funding costs are edging lower.
According to the statement, "the implied spread between lending rates and debt funding costs for the major banks is estimated to have increased over the past year".
But before the big bank chiefs start popping the champagne corks, the statement also has some less welcome news: their share of housing loan approvals "remains around its lowest level since 2012".

Their smaller, local rivals appear to have taken up some of this slack. According to the statement, "slower growth in the major banks' housing lending over the past six months was partly offset by stronger growth by other authorised deposit-taking institutions".

Rapid growth

Non-bank lenders also continued to grow their home loan books at a rapid clip, although the statement notes that "these institutions account for less than 5 per cent of the stock of housing credit".
Still, the future isn't all that bleak for the big four. They continue to dominate the home loan market - accounting for more than 75 per cent of all home loan approvals. What's more, their market share is likely to pick up as their rivals struggle to cope with the flood of new home loan requests.
As the statement noted, "in general, non-major lenders are running up against constraints in their capacity to process the increased volume of applications in a timely manner".

But how much are the banks raking in from hiking interest rates?
According to the statement, since May most lenders have increased the reference rates they charge for interest-only loans by around 30 basis points, while cutting the rates for principal-and-interest loans for owner occupiers by around 5 basis points.
The statement says that in combination with the rate hikes announced since last November, "this implies a rise in the average outstanding variable interest rate of 15 to 20 basis points".
Banks get less

But, it adds, the banks are likely to receive less than this. That's because some existing borrowers are likely to switch out of interest-only loans and to start paying back principal in order to avoid higher interest rates.
In addition, the lowest interest rates being advertised by the the banks haven't risen to the same extent as their reference rates. And interest rates on new fixed-rate loans remain well below those on maturing loans, which means that when their loans mature, home loan borrowers can roll them over at lower interest rates.
Meanwhile, the big banks look set to enjoy even lower funding costs.
According to the statement, "the cost of the major banks' outstanding deposit and wholesale debt funding is estimated to have declined a little this year".

Interest rates on domestic deposits - which now account for around 60 per cent of banks' overall funding - have declined, while the cost of issuing new long-term wholesale debt is at historically low levels.
What's more, banks should be able to reduce their funding costs even further as term deposits that were entered into at higher interest rates mature, and as more expensive short-term wholesale debt is replaced by new lower-cost borrowings.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
