<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439076079793684</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/cowboys-question-notry-call/news-story/25cdb564fe66a1a1229a0523f7e8bd3c</url>
  <title>Cowboys question no-try call</title>
  <content>
COWBOYS coach Paul Green could be fined for his post-match referee blow-up, but Lachlan Coote and Michael Morgan both insist they were unlucky not to be awarded what they believe was a fair try in Friday's loss to Melbourne.
In the first half when the game was still on the line, Coote leapt for a bomb and was adamant he had knocked the ball backward to Morgan, who scored under the posts.
But referee Ashley Klein ruled Coote had knocked on and didn't send the decision upstairs to the NRL Bunker.
Green could become the second coach in as many weeks to be fined $10,000 by the NRL for referee criticism after unloading on the officials after the game.
"That was the worst refereeing display I have ever seen," he said.
"There were some calls where they lacked consistency.
"I'm not one to shift the blame away from our performance, but the fans deserved more than that.
"There were two quality teams out there and I was left scratching my head at some of the calls."
Asked about the no-try call and that it hadn't been sent upstairs to be looked at, Morgan said: "That's what's disappointing I guess at times, you work hard to get opportunities like that. "Cootey's pretty adamant he knocked it back and we were able to get a try off it. A lot of the time it does get looked at, it didn't that time and they obviously saw it that way which is what they're out there to do, to call the game.
"I'm not one to bag refs or anything like that because they have a very tough job, I don't envy them, and I saw last week playing the Roosters when we walked off the field (at halftime) the amount of stuff they copped from the crowd down there.
"It is a tough job."
Coote added: "I went up for the ball and personally I thought it went back, but I guess the ref was in a better position.
"It was disappointing to not get that because I think Morgo was under the sticks. We'll move on from that."
After beating the Tigers on Sunday the eighth-placed Penrith are now just two points behind the sixth-placed Cowboys, who must win at least one more match to cement a spot in the finals.
It makes Saturday's road assignment against the Panthers a mini final as they look to arrest a two-game losing streak, albeit against the top two teams in the competition.
"I'm not sure where Panthers are sitting but it's a game we must win," Coote said.
"It'll be good for me and 'T' (fellow former Panther Te Maire Martin). I always look forward to going back there, not just playing the old club but catching up with family.
"If we maintain our standards with the effort we put in (against Storm) with the injuries we had going into the finals, I'm sure we'll be there."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cootey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther Te Maire Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coote</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL Bunker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Klein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Coote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
