<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438049582600608</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/instagram-star-pia-muehlenbeck-finds-the-glamour-blogging-life-a-lot-of-hard-work/news-story/33476a941c40fced9911e0b5a510d64a</url>
  <title>Glamorous life is just hard work</title>
  <content>
SHE makes an enviable living posting glamorous photos from some of the world's most exotic locations to her two million Instagram followers, but it's not easy.
Pia Muehlenbeck, a Gold Coast lawyer turned travel blogger, insists her beach-hopping life is hard work.
"I work more hours now than I did as a lawyer," she says in the September issue of Cosmopolitan, which comes out today.
"When it's your own business, it's really hard to figure out when to switch off."
Muehlenbeck, 26, is leading the pack of millennials turning social media into a business empire as she travels the world with her partner Kane Vato, regularly attracting more than three million views on her YouTube travel videos.
She has also turned her hand to design, launching the luxury sportswear brand SLINKII last year.
"We don't take any of this for granted," Muehlenbeck told the magazine.
"I'm lucky we are such a social media-obsessed world right now. Being in the right place at the right time is a big part of it. But also, Kane and I are both very business-minded.
"While our friends were out on a Sunday having cocktails, we would be out creating content," she said.
Muehlenbeck appears on the cover of Cosmopolitan with Instagram stars Lauren Curtis and Kayla Itsines, who made a total of $46 million last year, according to the 2016 BRW Young Rich List.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pia Muehlenbeck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayla Itsines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muehlenbeck</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Curtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muehlenbeck, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SLINKII</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRW Young Rich List</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Vato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
