<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439071784826369</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/bridgewater-resident-angela-knight-now-has-to-deal-with-a-stolen-motor-vehicle-as-she-battles-cancer/news-story/9d2c29418a16b3a7857583791fb2cdde</url>
  <title>Car theft hits community stalwart</title>
  <content>
A BRIDGEWATER resident battling breast cancer has had her precious ride stolen and torched.
Angela Knight, a full time disability carer who took out this year's Citizen of the Year award at Brighton Council, woke up Saturday to find her beloved Toyota missing from the driveway.
It was found a burnt-out wreck, completely destroyed, on Cove Hill Road.
The Tasmania Fire Service had been called out earlier that morning when the thief, not content with just having stolen the car, decided to light it up as well.
It appeared to have rolled before it was set on fire.
Ms Knight, who co-founded the Bridgewater-Gagebrook Clean Up organisation, said it would have been a "major upheaval" if she hadn't got hold of a loaner until she find a replacement.
Thankfully she had just finished a course of daily radiation treatment for her cancer, she said.
"I really miss my little Toyota but I know how lucky I am to have had insurance, so many cars are being stolen and burnt out and for a lot of people they never recover from it and end up having to rely on public transportation or friend," Ms Knight said.
She said the perpetrators needed to not only be held accountable but be introduced to a program where they could repair cheap cars and return them to victims.
" I would say to the people who destroyed my car that it may just be a means of fun for them, it causes major hardship for their victims, it is a struggle to find other means of transportation not to mention the stress it puts on finances," she said.
Ms Knight said car theft was a daily problem in the area.
"We know it is a problem for many areas of Tasmania and we are racking our brains to find some sort of solution," she said.
Not one to take things lying down Ms Knight said she would raise the issue at community forum on August 31 at Brighton Civic Centre at 6pm.
The forum was to tack issues like " vandalism and car theft and any other topics" that the community feels need addressing.
Ms Knight was awarded the Citizen of the Year on Australia Day for her work in cleaning up Brighton Municipality.
Along with Mark Bartlett she formed the Bridgewater/Gagebrook Clean Up Group that has been dedicated to cleaning up rubbish in the area.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Knight</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridgewater-Gagebrook Clean Up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citizen of the Year</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton Civic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridgewater/Gagebrook Clean Up Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cove Hill Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRIDGEWATER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Bartlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton Municipality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania Fire Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
