<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439080374761085</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-east/bowling-ladies-famous-for-their-beyonce-moves-say-they-wont-move-for-stonnington-council/news-story/741176d608fb4f8c00cf17d941f003bb</url>
  <title>Who run the world? These bowling girls</title>
  <content>
THE sassy lawn bowlers from Chadstone have confirmed that while they've got the moves like Beyonce, they won't be moving for the council any time soon.
Terry Foster, Janine Halls and Wyn Hewett shot to international stardom last week when their video adaptation of pop icon Beyonce's hit song All the Single Ladies attracted more than one million views on social media.
The two minute clip, which sees the leading ladies aged from their 60s to 82 shake their hips and sing about their club's stoush with Stonnington Council over its bid to build a $25 million sport stadium at their home site, was viewed in countries as far away as Kenya.

But Chadstone Bowls Club's Ms Hewett said there was a serious side to their video, All the Bowling Ladies, and she wanted the council to reconsider its proposal to move the club to make way for a new sport stadium.
Bowls club president Nigel Maxwell said the support from viewers had been wonderful, and the club had received coverage from media outlets in the United States and the United Kingdom.
"The actual video has been viewed over one million times. Lots of the comments online are saying 'wishing you all the best'," Mr Maxwell said.
Hundreds of thousands of people watched the video posted to Facebook on July 29 and news outlets across the world picked up the story.
But Stonnington Mayor Jami Klisaris said last week a decision had yet to be made regarding the club's future and the location of the new stadium.
"In December 2016, (the) council passed a motion confirming the Chadstone Bowls Club site at Percy Treyvaud Memorial Park as the preferred location for a new stadium," Cr Klisaris said.
"A feasibility study is underway to provide council with expert opinion, independent data and community feedback."

The council has said it would find an alternative place for the bowlers to play if the club had to be moved, and a report looking into three alternatives to the Percy Treyvaud Memorial Park will be discussed at a council meeting held at Malvern Town Hall on August 21.
Stonnington Council's stadium plan follows a 30-year campaign by the Prahran Netball Association for new courts to be built in the municipality.
There are currently just two courts in the area to cater for more than 4000 basketball players and netball players living in Stonnington.
The association's Linda Rowland said there should be a way to accommodate everyone on the site.
"The Chaddy bowling ladies' video is a great video, but there is room for everyone at Percy Treyvaud Reserve," Ms Rowland said.
The three alternative sites the council is considering and which will be discussed at the council meeting on August 21 are the Malvern Valley Golf Course, the Orrong-Romanis Reserve, and the carpark opposite the East Malvern RSL.
The council's feasibility study considering Percy Treyvaud Memorial Park will be completed in November.
Details:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyn Hewett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington Mayor Jami Klisaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malvern Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Rowland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowling Ladies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prahran Netball Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Percy Treyvaud Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Single Ladies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Klisaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chaddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orrong-Romanis Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malvern Valley Golf Course</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janine Halls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Percy Treyvaud Memorial Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Rowland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadstone Bowls Club's Ms Hewett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Malvern RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadstone Bowls Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
