<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438637993125700</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/opinion/liberal-party-to-consider-private-members-bill-on-samesex-marriage/news-story/d533f508f8a1ccb17d72dd92bb2f22a0</url>
  <title>Same-sex marriage derails LNP agenda</title>
  <content>
PRIME Minister Malcolm Turnbull is again likely to be pondering "how did we get ourselves here?" when he enters the federal parliamentary sitting week.
The six-week winter recess, traditionally a time for governments to regroup while away from the day-to-day attrition of parliament, has afforded the federal Coalition little respite.
Rather, the recess has ended with another damaging demonstration of the administration's internal fissions, played out before a public that grows weary of the Liberal Party's preoccupation with internal issues.
The latest sortie comes not from the conservative members of Mr Turnbull's party room, but from his supporters over the issue of same-sex marriage. West Australian Senator Dean Smith will take a private member's Bill to today's Liberal party room meeting, seeking to extend the definition of marriage to allow two people to wed regardless of gender.
Senator Smith is supported by Queenslanders Warren Entsch and Trevor Evans, who have both backed releasing MPs from the bonds of party solidarity and giving a free vote on the legislation.
Conservative forces are livid that the issue of same-sex marriage has been revisited and at the attempt to overturn the Coalition joint party room's decision for a plebiscite on the issue. Between the two forces, Mr Turnbull is attempting to walk a tightrope with the expectation being he will push for a non-binding postal vote on the issue as well as a deadline for Parliament to decide on the reform.
Today's party room meeting shapes as a pitched battle between the two sides amid veiled threats to preselection and speculation that a Victorian Nationals MP could cost the Turnbull Government its one-seat majority by shifting to the crossbench. This has become a test for Mr Turnbull's leadership.
However, it comes on what is a fringe issue to many Australians and one that a mature and cohesive government could have dealt with quickly and without all the teeth gnashing. Even the champions of the change to a free vote have acknowledged the tumult they have triggered is a low-order issue, compared with problems such as energy affordability, house prices, regional unemployment and counter terrorism.
Today's Galaxy Poll, however, should demonstrate to forlorn members of the Coalition that they should not be sizing up seats on the Opposition side of the Parliament just yet. And neither should Opposition Leader Bill Shorten pre-order removalists for a shift to The Lodge.
The poll shows a gradual improvement in the LNP vote at the expense of Labor and Pauline Hanson's One Nation party, which has declined from 18 per cent of the Queensland vote to 12 per cent in just six months.
The Coalition has edged ahead on a two-party preferred basis. This is still a swing against the Government of about 3 per cent, enough to imperil the Queensland seats of Capricornia, Forde, Flynn, Dickson and Petrie. But it also indicates that Federal Labor's ascendancy in Queensland has, for now, been arrested.
Mr Shorten has proved to be a far more formidable opponent than many, even his own party, imagined. Today's figures could be coming from the hubris that has crept into the Labor camp as the Liberal Party has indulged in internal warfare.
Mr Shorten has flipped from four-year terms to a push for a Republic, and has fuelled class envy with an attack on Australians who order their financial affairs legitimately through trusts. The Labor Leader doesn't remain focused on an issue long enough to provide substance, before he flits off to the next.
Perhaps, in the fog billowing from the Coalition, Queenslanders have turned their attention towards the alternative of Labor and are unimpressed that it does not seem focused on substantive issues.
Mr Turnbull needs to push past the latest same-sex marriage debate and wrestle his Government's agenda back to the things that matter to voters.
This is the only way to reclaim the significant support the Coalition
has lost in Queensland since the 2016 election.
TRAGEDY REOPENS OLD WOUNDS
GIVEN time, official investigations will hopefully ascertain why an MV-22 Osprey conducting what has been described as "regular operations" off the USS Bonhomme Richard, ditched in water off central Queensland.
Now, though, thoughts and prayers belong with the families of the three US marines who lost their lives in this tragic accident. The marines had only recently completed Talisman Sabre, a biennial training exercise with members of the Australian military.
The accident will revive memories of the 1996 Black Hawk tragedy near Townsville, in which 18 servicemen were killed. Fifteen Special Air Service (SAS) soldiers and three army aviators were carrying out a night counter-terrorism training operation ahead of the Sydney Olympics when their helicopters collided. An inquiry found organisational, training and command deficiencies and made 79 recommendations to ensure such a tragedy would never happen again.
Such events demonstrate the huge risks that our servicemen and women take - both in war and in peacetime training - to keep our countries safe.
******
Responsibility for election comment is taken by Lachlan Heywood, corner of Mayne Rd & Campbell St, Bowen Hills, Qld 4006. Printed and published by NEWSQUEENSLAND (ACN 009 661 778). Contact details are available at
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capricornia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy Poll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Bonhomme Richard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifteen Special Air Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWSQUEENSLAND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talisman Saber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REOPENS OLD WOUNDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Nationals MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Heywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson's One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayne Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV-22 Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACN 009 661 778</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld 4006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
