<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439080374761045</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/foodbank-victoria-and-eat-up-charities-filling-gaps-for-greater-dandenong-schoolchildren/news-story/660df31b34b244cda2f88b0a3c49f50e</url>
  <title>Charities left to feed hungry schoolkids</title>
  <content>
HUNDREDS of Greater Dandenong children are being sent to school without breakfast or lunch each week, according to food charities.
Foodbank Victoria supplies more than 1700 breakfasts to hungry students in 15 local schools every week while Eat Up dishes out 320 lunches a fortnight.
Eat Up's Lyndon Galea said the charity was working with four schools but had identified another 11 where children missed out on lunch.
Dandenong Primary School accepts food from both charities and principal Daniel Riley said teachers were always alert to hungry students and helped out.
"If a child's saying they don't have lunch, there's not a teacher on the face of the earth who wouldn't want to help," Mr Riley said.
Now, with Eat Up providing lunches for the school, students who say they have no lunch or who are noticed by a teacher, are given a voucher to collect a sandwich, muesli bar and fruit from the school kitchen.
Mr Galea said it was not known exactly how many students were going hungry.
"We do know that about one in seven students in Australia doesn't come to school with a packed lunch," Mr Galea said.
Foodbank Victoria runs a breakfast club with each club averaging 32 students per school.
"You cannot expect a child to concentrate, to participate, to socialise, to grow and develop, when they are under a cloud of hunger," Foodbank Victoria chief executive Dave McNamara said.
Dandenong Plaza holds sessions where volunteers make sandwiches by the hundreds for Eat Up.
Dandenong Plaza Centre manager Mark Tannahill said: "We all agreed this was a great cause to get behind as it would make a positive impact within the community."

Madeline Haseltine of Wetherill Park is living off $2 worth of food a day to raise awareness of world poverty by participating in the five-day Live Below the Line challenge.

LIVE BELOW THE LINE
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave McNamara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eat Up</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeline Haseltine of Wetherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyndon Galea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Plaza Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Galea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Tannahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Live Below</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
