<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651437826244299197</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/rugby/shute-shield-finals-manly-v-eastwood-souths-v-norths-warringah-v-randwick/news-story/1458dbc7c8fdf40554c735efc689cf2d</url>
  <title>Rebels raring to go in finals</title>
  <content>
​A call to "start again" after a Thursday training in May was the genesis of an nine-game unbeaten run by Southern Districts that has the Rebels positioned as the danger side of the Shute Shield finals.
In an eventful final round at the weekend, Souths knocked over Randwick to finish second and secure a home qualifying final this weekend against Norths.
Manly were crowned minor premiers despite falling to Wests, and they'll host Eastwood while Warringah booked a home playoff against the Wicks by beating Norths.
Sydney Uni will miss the Shute Shield post-season for the first time since 1997 after finishing equal with Eastwood but below on for-and-against. On a positive note for the Students, they won their 14th straight club championship.
Souths undoubtedly enter the finals as the form team.
After the first nine games they were mid-table with just four wins, but coach Matt Barr said the team had got on a roll after drawing a line under their start.
"We weren't playing with any consistency in he first half of the year and we got to 4-5 I think," Barr said.
"We just sort of got together, had a talk and said "right, we start fresh from here and this is what we will focus on". From that point things we'd been working on in the first part of the year started to click and we started winning games, and with each wins you build more and more confidence."
Led by Waratahs no.8 Jed Holloway, the Rebels have also benefited from the likes of Brumbies no.9 DeWet Roos, Aussie sevens speedster Alex Gibbon and the return of tough forward Marcus Carbone, Barr said.
Known as a team who can always score points, Souths' much-improved defence has been noted by rivals.
No-one is popping Champagne corks in the Shire yet, however. The Rebels have been close a number of times in recent years, losing Grand Finals in 2012 and 2014; the former by just a single point.
Barr said lessons from those defeats - and a handful of players still in the side - gave the club confidence they could the club's first ever Shute Shield premiership if they play well enough.
Norths' surging run home last year - they won 14 on the trot to claim their first title in 41 years - was a pointer to the value of entering the finals in form, said Barr.
Simon Cron's team head to Forshaw Park with a last-start loss but Barr said Will Miller's influence made them a very dangerous rival.
"It's a really open final series, it'll be a great couple of weeks," Barr said.
"Manly have been the most consistent side for sure and only dropped a couple but the rest of the top six have shown they can beat each other on any given day so we know we need to keep improving."
​SHUTE SHIELD QUALIFYING FINALS
Manly v Eastwood - Manly Oval
Souths v Norths - Forshaw Park
Warringah v Randwick - Pittwater Park
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Cron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHUTE SHIELD QUALIFYING FINALS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forshaw Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Carbone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Barr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pittwater Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warringah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jed Holloway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastwood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barr</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Gibbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Uni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DeWet Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shute Shield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
