<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439200633846801</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836529/states-waste-more-than-a-load-of-rubbish/?cs=305</url>
  <title>State's waste more than a load of rubbish</title>
  <content>
THERE is a lot we don't know about how an approval for an 80,000 cubic metre landfill site at a Mangrove Mountain golf course in 1998, associated with a redesign of its steep site, turned into 800,000 cubic metres of landfill by 2012 and plans for a regional landfill facility.
We know that by 2005 Gosford City Council officers were complaining to the Environment Protection Authority's Newcastle office about the volume of waste at the site, and the way the landfill area was being operated.
We know that the EPA was monitoring activities, because the state's environmental watchdog released photographs of waste over a number of years to a Mangrove Mountain community group in response to a freedom of information application.
We know that the EPA continued to issue annual licences as the mountains of waste piled up, and changed the licence at some point to allow waste more likely to leach into groundwater.

We know that former Maitland MP and Environment Minister Robyn Parker was advised in 2013 of Gosford Council's anger about the EPA's role in allowing the landfill operator to take in waste more than 10 times the amount originally approved by the council, at a site above an aquifer and feeding into the region's water catchment.

What we don't know is why?
Why would the state's environmental watchdog allow this to happen, or accept that an environmental review in 2017, however independent and scrupulously thorough, would take the place of a proper planning process that would start from scratch, and include a rigorous environmental process and public involvement?
No doubt one answer is that such a process would rule the Mangrove Mountain landfill proposal out on the first day. The SLR Consulting independent review, commissioned by the EPA, says as much. The Mangrove Mountain site "would be deemed inappropriate for a landfill" if appropriately assessed based on 2017 environmental requirements, the review found.
Rubbish is big business. Every year millions of tonnes of household and commercial waste is generated in NSW. The proposal for the Mangrove Mountain landfill facility is to allow 1.3 million cubic metres of waste over 10 years, or 55 truckloads each day. It might solve one problem - a necessary landfill site close to the M1 - but the environmental risks are a serious concern.

Issue: 38,564.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SLR Consulting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Protection Authority's Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Minister Robyn Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mangrove Mountain</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
