<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439157684173429</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/di-pillas-aurrum-grows-into-greenfield-development-20170804-gxp6bm</url>
  <title>Aurrum grows into greenfield development</title>
  <content>
Former star banker David Di Pilla and his fellow investors, such as UBS' Matthew Grounds, have stepped up a gear with their start-up aged-care business, Aurrum, by ploughing money into greenfield developments.
In all, Aurrum has 1100 beds existing or allocated in its pipeline and is eyeing a 1500-bed portfolio in the near future. It's a portfolio worth $300 million or more.
"It's the next phase of our growth," Mr Di Pilla told The Australian Financial Review. "You need to establish an operating business and we've now got a very strong one, so the next logical step is to develop your own facilities in an area where you see a need."
Aurrum opened a 71-bed Terrigal Drive facility at Erina on the NSW Central Coast last week. Next to open will be a 120-bed facility at Plenty in Melbourne's north in October.

Scott Riley

Aurrum also plans to begin work on a 120-bed facility at Rowville in Melbourne's south-east later in the year.

Further north, a 57-bed expansion of its Norah Head facility on the NSW Central Coast is also in the pipeline.
An expansion into Brisbane is not far away, following the purchase of a site at Jephson Road, Toowong.
Building the platform

It's an impressive workbook, and growth into development has accelerated just four years after Mr Di Pilla started the business,  in Victoria and NSW to build the platform.

"We acquired and upgraded them and now we're very much in a greenfield development mode," he said.
The A-League banker is married to one of the granddaughters of the late Carlo Salteri, who co-founded -Transfield, then created Tenix.
Also backing the Aurrum venture are UBS heavy hitters Mr Grounds and Robbie Vanderzeil, Sydney investor Greg Hayes and Mr Di Pilla's parents-in-law Mary and Alex Shaw.
The same crowd came in with Mr Di Pilla last year as he to buy out the former Masters portfolio 
Mr Di Pilla and his co-investors saw the opportunity in aged care emerging after the federal government's first moves to deregulate it through the Living Better, Living Longer reforms in 2012.

Daily payment system

"That was a greater opportunity that we believed, in terms of the Living better, Living Longer funding changes, for us to get into the sector," he said.
About 70 per cent of Aurrum residents opt for paying a lump sum accommodation deposit, known as refundable accommodation deposits or RADs, while  the remainder elect a daily payment system.
Listed aged-care operators, including Estia Health, Japara Healthcare and Regis Healthcare, have been under pressure over the past 18 months asand to funding and service fees regimes. 

Occupancy at Aurrum facilities is strong, more than 95 per cent, and the business runs without the extra services that some operators may rely on to top up revenue.
The accommodation deposits Aurrum collects are a key part of the capital structure Mr Di Pilla uses to drive development.
Aurrum is focused wholly on aged care. And that's the way Mr Di Pilla wants it. It is a sector more akin to healthcare than the property plays seen in the broader retirement living sector, in his view.
Roll out into Asia

There may be more upside to come in the medium term. By then the Aurrum model, bolstered by the strength of Australian standards, will be ripe to roll out into the Asian region, as the demand for aged care emerges there.
"Definitely there is scope for that," he said.
So, the inevitable question, will Mr Di Pilla and his co-investors contemplate a public float of Aurrum to fund further growth?
"At the right time it's something you can look at and should be considered but it's not something that we're considering at the moment," he said. 
"I first want to build a really strong organisation, then we'll look at what's next.
"We've got a great pipeline of growth and we want to execute on that in the near future."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tenix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regis Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Vanderzeil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlo Salteri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japara Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Di Pilla</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW's Central Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Grounds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norah Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS' Matthew Grounds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrigal Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estia Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jephson Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Living Better</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALEX SHAW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurrum</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Di Pilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
