<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439501281560332</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/1230191/demolition-drawcard-at-albion-park-show/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Demolition drawcard at Albion Park show</title>
  <content>
Demolition drawcard at Albion Park show

Luca, 6, Chloe, 4, Ricky, 7, and Miley, 3, inspect the Albion Park Show goodie bags. Picture: GREG TOTMAN

Vehicles from three states will take part in the seventh annual Albion Park Ute Show on tomorrow.

exit

More than 10,000 people are expected at the 126th Albion Park Agricultural Show this weekend.
This year's show will include several drawcard events from interstate but it is the demolition derby that will be responsible for many ticket sales.
Albion Park Show Society president Glenn McParland said tonight's derby, which starts at 8.30pm, would involve up to 30 cars.
Much of the fun lay in sizing up the vehicles and picking which one would still be standing at the end, he said.
"People dress up cars and they take them out into the middle of the ring and they bash them up and the last one standing wins," he said.
"It's usually the little cars that surprise people."
This year's show will include performances by Queensland freestyle motocross team FMX Kaos and the Australian Horse Academy, which features horses dancing, moving and jumping through fiery hoops.
Australian vintage speedway cars will do a parade lap at 4.30pm.
Tomorrow, hundreds of utes will roar into the showground for the seventh annual Albion Park Ute Show, the biggest on the South Coast according to event co-ordinator Heidi Caldwell.
The 2013 show is expecting more than 150 utes from across NSW, Victoria and Queensland.
The utes will compete in 12 categories, ranging from classic utes, street utes and girls' utes. Winners from each category will then be judged for the prestigious Ute of Show title.
The Albion Park Show is at Albion Park Showground today and tomorrow, with the ute show tomorrow from 10.30am.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park Showground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidi Caldwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miley, 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park Agricultural Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luca, 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Horse Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREG TOTMAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe, 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FMX Kaos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park Ute Show</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park Show Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park Show</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn McParland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky, 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ute of Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
