<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438985885479609</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-06/mandogalup-gets-epas-all-clear-for-development/8779142</url>
  <title>Mandogalup gets EPA's all clear for air quality, putting Kwinana industry heavyweights offside</title>
  <content>
Kwinana industry heavyweights are trying to ensure residential development in Mandogalup is kept to a minimum after the Environmental Protection Authority (EPA) gave much of the contested area a potential 'all clear' for new housing.
The director of the Kwinana Industries Council, Chris Oughton, did not mince words.
"We're appalled at the EPA's report, we think it's deeply flawed and it's too narrow in its findings," he said.
The EPA was tasked by the Barnett Government after its proposal to push out the buffer zone last year met with strong resistance from residents and developers.
The EPA considered dust from Alcoa's bauxite residue disposal facility, and its potential impacts on health and amenity.

It said that while the north required further investigation, as the air quality did not meet national air quality goals, there were "negligible" and "unlikely" impacts in the east.
Mr Oughton said the EPA should have investigated more factors, and may not have considered all of the wind strengths and directions.
"There's more to amenity than just dust. There's noise, odour, light, risk and so forth," he said.
"The Health Department itself has conditioned - if there's an approval to go through - has conditioned the titles of those lots to say that there will be health and amenity impacts."
He said the industries council had an application for a special control area ready.
"The special control area is the strongest planning tool in existence that can be used to protect an industrial area, that's what we're going for now and I hope we can get the support of the Government in that because it will resolve all of these ongoing issues and threats," Mr Oughton said.
The Kwinana Industries Council represents Alcoa, BHP Nickel West, Cockburn Cement, Synergy, BP, Coogee Chemicals, CSBP, Tronix and Fremantle Ports, and has more than two dozen associate members.
It was to have a special board meeting on Thursday night, and was seeking urgent meetings with the Environment Minister and the Planning Minister.
Developer planning 950 lots welcomes 'sensible' report

Developer Nigel Satterley welcomed the EPA's report.
"We think it's a very sensible, very thorough report, took a lot longer to do than we thought, lots of test have been done, independent tests and there is no health risks," he said.
"We are now going to ask the Department of Planning to lift the urban deferment and then we'll be lodging a subdivision for the balance of our landholding, so we've got about 950 lots to develop there.
"Qube, who are going to move first, tell us they'll be selling land towards the end of this year, then we'll start. This area will start to be developed, I would think, towards the end of this year."

He said he believed his campaign against then-premier Colin Barnett and his ministers had an impact on the issue, but not the state election.
"We had to bring it to attention, not only our own landholdings, but there were 55 decent families there that couldn't get anywhere, so the local member Roger Cook, Fran Logan, Mr McGowan himself and us, we worked with the residents," Mr Satterley said.
"I only have one vote. Mr McGowan ran a very, very good campaign."
Report comes as relief for local residents

Mandogalup resident Reid Donald had been living in the area for decades and never really worried about Alcoa's bauxite residue disposal facility.

Like many local residents, he welcomed the EPA report, which he said relieved the pressure of concern about what he could do with his property.
"I look at it as very positive, it's taken a big weight off my mind. I wasn't sleeping at night, worrying about the buffer. The first good night of sleep I've had was when we got the report," Mr Donald said.
"There's no health problem, there's supposed to be an amenity problem now, and we just don't get amenity problems.
"There's a real mixture in the street, there's people with young grandchildren, there's people with teenagers, and we're all healthy!"
Planning Minister Rita Saffioti said there was still much work to do before final decisions were made.
She said further monitoring was needed north of the Alcoa site.
"I've had some preliminary discussions with my agency and have asked for very detailed advice," she said.
"I want to sit down, get very detailed advice from my agency and also work with other ministers and the Premier in his capacity as State Development Minister so we get a good outcome that supports industry but doesn't sterilise land that doesn't need to be sterilised."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnett Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSBP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alcoa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwinana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environmental Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Planning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coogee Chemicals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Nickel West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cockburn Cement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle Port</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Satterley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Rita Saffioti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Oughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Oughton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Development Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Satterley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwinana Industries Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid Donald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPA</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fran Logan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tronix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Barnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandogalup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
