<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439037425087563</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/chanticleer/cba-chief-executive-ian-narevs-survival-is-an-open-question-20170806-gxq8po</url>
  <title>CBA's Ian Narev explains why the bank is fighting AUSTRAC in court</title>
  <content>
It is an open question as to whether or not Commonwealth Bank of Australia chief executive Ian Narev can survive the third in a series of major reputational incidents to have hit the bank during his six-year tenure.
between 2012 and 2015 follows the reputational damage caused by incidents at and arms.
Narev admitted during an hour-long interview with The Australian Financial Review on Sunday that the bank's management would have to be held accountable for the  last week by AUSTRAC.
"In the case of the accountability for the more senior executives there is a need to be pretty clear about that, which I think you'll see we will be," he said.

Cole Bennetts

It is almost certain that  to show accountability for the anti-money laundering incident.

Narev said on Sunday it would not be fair to name individuals responsible for the software coding mistakes that led to CBA not reporting 53,000 breaches of anti-money laundering to AUSTRAC.
The law leaves it open for CBA to argue that because these breaches relate to one software glitch that any fine imposed by the court could be for only one single breach, which would mean a fine of only $18 million.
Buck stops here

During his interview with the AFR, Narev accepted that ultimately the responsibility for protecting the good name of the bank landed on his desk.

Alex Ellinghausen

"I'm the head of the bank and when anything happens to the Commonwealth Bank it reflects on me," Narev said.
"I understand why people would then question what my role and accountability would be.
"What I can say to you is you know I've been doing the job for six years, and been at the bank for 10 years, I can put my hand on my heart and say every day that I've come to work I've come to work for the best interests of the stakeholders of the bank.
"I've made my share of mistakes and maybe even more during that time and if ever it was in the best interests of the bank for me not to be the chief executive I would hopefully realise that, and if others had to tell me I totally respect that."

Daniel Pockett

No culture fail

But Narev is not showing any signs of being willing to leave his position as CEO.
"I feel a very strong sense of energy and motivation working on both the opportunities and also of these very difficult matters and everything beyond that as you would expect as is for the board to work out."
Rather than harming the morale of the bank, Narev believes the scandals that have overshadowed his time as CEO have helped to strengthen the leadership team.

Christopher Pearce

"What I can say is our team is extremely well aligned and has a really sense of common values and purpose and, if anything, having worked through some difficulties, has really solidified the sense of that among our executives," he said.
Above all, Narev does not believe the anti-money laundering case has exposed a failure of culture at CBA.
"People can make their own views from the outside but sitting here as the CEO of the organisation, I can say for the mistakes that we've made here we need to acknowledge them, we need to fix them and we are fixing them.
"We've obviously got to do our job with these proceedings but I feel confident in saying that the culture here is strong."

Narev was smart to interrupt his weekend preparations for Wednesday's release of full-year financial results to answer questions about the AUSTRAC case.
It was sensible to abandon the usual corporate cover-all excuse for not talking, which usually takes the form of "it's before the courts so I cannot discuss it".
Unanswered questions

Narev provided fresh insights into why AUSTRAC took civil action against CBA. But his explanation did leave questions unanswered about the relationship between the bank and AUSTRAC.
"One important thing for you to be aware of is our understanding of the act is that the only way AUSTRAC can extract financial penalties is serve civil proceedings," Narev said.
"It's not like there were a whole lot of discussions or negotiations which then collapsed leading them to serve civil proceedings."
Narev refused to accept the proposition that CBA had been ambushed by the regulator in the same way that Tabcorp was ambushed when AUSTRAC sued that company in 2015.
"What you are not going to hear from me is any complaint about the way this was run by AUSTRAC - right," Narev said.

"AUSTRAC are doing the job. That's different from saying we agree with everything, and we will file a statement of defence.
"But we're taking the legal proceedings very seriously and we're doing it against a backdrop of respect for them and nowhere in what you hear from us is going to be any complaint about why didn't they do X or why didn't they do Y. That's not part of our view on this."
But the fact is Narev only found out about the federal court action on Thursday morning. Within 10 minutes he had rung the bank's chairman Catherine Livingstone to tell her that the matter had gone to court.
Shock move

Livingstone and her fellow board members have been kept informed about the AUSTRAC case by management, but the directors must have been shocked by the regulator's move.
In his interview with the AFR, Narev gave a detailed explanation of the software coding errors that he claims were responsible for the 53,000 breaches of anti-money laundering reporting obligations between 2012 and 2015.
It is significant that at no stage did Narev attempt to downplay the broader failings in the bank's processes raised by AUSTRAC case.
"When I make the point about the software I'm making it very specifically relating to the 53,000 reports," he said.

"I'm not saying the only weakness we have in the whole world of this area is the one coding error."
It is these weaknesses which will have to be the subject of hard discussions with Livingstone and the board.
When reminded that AUSTRAC had accused CBA of not carrying out anti-money laundering risk assessments before the coding error or in response to notifications from the Australian Federal Police, Narev said the bank's response to these claims would have to await the court case.
The AUSTRAC case highlights the ease with which criminals can obtain bank accounts in fake names and how simple it is to transfer money from an Australian bank to a Hong Kong bank account owned by a criminal syndicate.
Convenience v. security

These specific issues are being investigated by CBA as part of a review of its entire transaction monitoring and compliance processes.
Narev agrees the issues of client identification and the need for co-ordination between police, banks and regulators are worthy of increased public debate.
He says there needs to be a balance between "everyday people doing everyday stuff simply and cheaply" and the need to curb crime. Secondly, technological developments inevitably opened the way for criminals to do things more easily.

"Every time you keep innovating people who want to do bad (things) are going to try and find new ways to circumvent your new aspect," he said. "So the only way we can think about this stuff is continuous improvement and really strong cooperation between banks and policymakers and law enforcement and regulators.
"That's why I keep saying we're really committed to our partner even when we've got a serious court proceeding on with the regulator."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y. That</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Livingstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA's Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narev</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cole Bennetts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
