<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439123324434654</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/federal-government-finds-serious-concerns-at-adria-village-care-home-20170804-gxpayx.html</url>
  <title>A Canberra care home is on notice for 'serious concerns' related to residents' health</title>
  <content>
Fresh allegations of aged care abuse in the ACT can be revealed as separate concerns about another Canberra nursing home also emerge.
The Canberra Times has obtained reports authored by the federal Aged Care Complaints Commissioner, describing recent allegations within the ACT's aged care sector, including claims of physical and sexual abuse.
In one report, government inspectors were told that a resident was fearful to leave their room after another resident allegedly grabbed their groin.
"This started as a random mention, and continued for some time with [the resident] repeatedly taking family members aside to reassert something had happened," the report read.

The same report dealt with further allegations of physical abuse between residents and under-reporting of incidents inside the facility.
"[One respondent] stated that two staff had informed [them] on separate occasions that another resident was being violent ... that there was a culture of under-reporting at the service."

However, the government's investigation found that all allegations had been appropriately responded to, with both the Department of Health and police notified of concerns as needed.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"We are satisfied that any systemic risks to other residents identified in the information available will be escalated to the appropriate authority," the complaints officer wrote.
In another report a care home resident alleged they had been restrained while a nurse "vigorously" smeared their face with stinging ointment.
"During the incident [the resident] did not give staff permission to apply the ointment as [they] knew it was the wrong one," it was alleged.
"The RN ignored this and told the other staff member, 'Hold [the resident]'.
"The RN then applied the ointment vigorously... The ointment caused a burning sensation."
Inspectors found the care home had dealt with the incident promptly and correctly, and could not substantiate the allegation of assault as described.
In a separate development, The Canberra Times has obtained a letter from the federal Department of Health revealing "serious concerns" with the Adria Village care home in the suburb of Stirling.
It is not suggested that these concerns were in any way linked to the abuse allegations detailed above.
"Between the 3rd and 7th July 2017, while visiting Adria Village to review the standards of care and services at the home, an assessment team from the Quality Agency identified some serious concerns regarding the safety, health and wellbeing of residents," officials wrote on July 18.
"As a result of these findings the secretary of this department has imposed sanctions on the approved provider of Adria Village under section 65-1 of the Aged Care Act 1997."
The sanctions included a three-month freeze on funding for new residents, and a threat to revoke Adria's licence unless staff responsible for residents' care received additional training.
The online Aged Care Guide describes Adria Village as a 40-bed facility with 12 permanent places for residents with dementia.
A spokeswoman for Adria Village said the home was working with the government to address the matters raised, and would not be commenting further.
In July The Canberra Times revealed the case of Peter Tunnecliffe, a 77-year-old resident at the Southern Cross care facility in Garran who was sent to Canberra Hospital with maggot-infested facial wounds.
Senior hospital staff were so disturbed by Mr Tunnecliffe's case, they took it upon themselves to lay a complaint with the federal government's aged care watchdog.
Southern Cross conceded there were "major failings" in Mr Tunnecliffe's care, and outlined subsequent measures they had undertaken to meet government aged care standards.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quality Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aged Care Act 1997</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Tunnecliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Cross</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tunnecliffe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aged Care Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adria Village</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Times</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Health</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aged Care Complaints Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
