<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439200633846827</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/princess-scrumpy-looking-to-shake-up-darwin-council-elections/news-story/d8f05404921dddd611547ca98bdb9be9</url>
  <title>Pooch's paw-licies not barking mad</title>
  <content>
THE youngest candidate to put her paw up for Darwin Lord Mayor will be ineligible for the role because of her age and canine lineage.
Despite the clear setback, the political pooch is keen to share her vision for Darwin's future.
Princess Scrumpy of Scrumpyton, 15, first entered the political arena for last year's Territory elections.
The Jack Russell's campaign manager Deb Taipale said the idea to enter Princess Scrumpy in the 2016 election arose because of the uninspiring -nature of the other candidates and -because she thought her dog could do a better job.
"So we organised a few signs and set off at 5am, putting the posters up at the dead of night like ninjas."
Princess Scrumpy said, through her interpreter Ms Taipale, if NT law permitted a canine to nominate, she would have beaten Chief Minister -Michael Gunner at the polls.
The dog has a vision of a green, clean and cool Darwin.
Princess Scrumpy wants more shade and green spaces in Darwin's CBD, citywide free parking, more dog-friendly parks and cafes and free microchipping and desexing.
The dog's policies also included putting more money towards animal welfare organisations, and introducing a 10¢ return on wine bottles.
"This will mean no more broken glass everywhere, and Mummy has heaps of empties," Princess Scrumpy said. "I also want all cats to p-ss off down south."
Scrumpy wants a ban on personal fireworks, because they are scary.
There are 15 candidates running for the role of Darwin Mayor in the August 26 local government elections.
Current alderman Rebecca Want de Rowe said it was lucky she wasn't vying for the top spot, given the pooch's popularity.
"I'm also voting for Scrumpy," she said.
NT electoral commissioner Iain Loganathan said despite Princess Scrumpy's enthusiasm, the dog would be ineligible for mayor.
"She never nominated and nominations have closed," he said.
"Unfortunately for Scrumpy, you have to be on the electoral role and you have to be an Australian citizen and you have to be over 18 years."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Scrumpy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gunner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scrumpy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Taipale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deb Taipale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iain Loganathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Scrumpy of Scrumpyton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Want</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
