<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439123324434680</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/the-economy/our-it-systems-arent-bound-by-commercial-service-standards-says-ato-20170803-gxorv1.html</url>
  <title>Our IT systems aren't bound by commercial service standards, says ATO</title>
  <content>
The Australian Taxation Office said in its own report into the IT outage debacle that it is not bound by the same service standards as commercial organisations are when it comes to assessing its liability for repeated system crashes.
The ATO's services have been continually taken offline for hours, proving especially frustrating for Australians looking to lodge their returns in the lead-up to tax time, and creating tension between the agency and tax professionals.

Up Next

Wall Street rallies on jobs report

01:19

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

A 'complex web of tax evasion': Commissioner

Tax Commissioner Chris Jordan has provided an update on the $165 million tax fraud syndicate involving the son of a deputy Commissioner.

The ATO conducted its own review into the IT outages in which it blamed major pre-Christmas outages . PwC is now doing another review, which sources suggest is not likely to be publicly released until December.
The agency's June report noted "some stakeholders raised the option of the ATO providing IT systems with more precise service standards". And that "improved or tighter service standards are increasingly common in digital commercial transactions".Photo: Andrew Quilty
But the ATO said, in its view, "against this option" was "recognition that our systems are generally provided to stakeholders free of charge and therefore in distinction to commercial IT provision".
"As far as excuses go, this makes 'the dog ate my homework' look pretty damn good," said senator Nick Xenophon, who added he would be speaking toRevenue and Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer about the lack of service standards.

"I will, in the next fortnight, move a resolution in the Senate to call on ATO to be subject to service standards," he said.
"Whatever happened to high standards being required of the public sector?"Photo: Andrew Meares
Senator Xenophon said the ATO's portals are designed to help the government get more revenue and and supposedly make it easier for accountants to do their jobs. "This is a lame excuse and the Assistant Treasurer should issue a directive to the Tax Office to meet these [service] standards," he said.
The Institute of Public Accountants (IPA), which has about 15,000 members made up mainly of small-firm accountants, has long argued that their members should be compensated to deal with productivity losses caused by constant outages or loss of functionality.Photo: Peter Braig
The IPA's Tony Greco said: "We are concerned on behalf of all the stakeholders who are users of the IT system that the ATO will not adhere to commercial standards as implied in the above statement."
"The expectations of the tax practitioner community would be that the ATO is in fact operating to a best-practice standard especially as more digital interactions are on the horizon such as single touch payroll.
As far as excuses go, this makes 'the dog ate my homework' look pretty damn good.
Senator Nick Xenophon

"There is a huge opportunity cost on all users when systems do not perform as expected."
A recent review by the Inspector-General of Taxation Ali Noroozi suggested the ATO set and tax practitioners who faced losses, including non-economic ones, due to mistakes or prolonged IT outages. Photo: Josh Robenstone
Mr Greco said a financial penalty may also improve the ATO's culture. "The ATO do a lot of good things, but IT is not one of them. If you can't get on the system to lodge in the first place, there is no standard," he said.
The federal government has been into repeated failures of online Tax Office services. Ms O'Dwyer has largely kept quiet on the issue.Photo: Louise Kennerley
After a series of IT outages last year, 2017 has been a continuing saga. Information provided to a Senate committee by ATO officials details repeated critical incidents that have been identified as an IT outage between February 1 and June 30 this year.
ATO systems have continued to crash. An outage occurred last month, just a few hours after Chris Jordan presented to the National Press Club. Mr Jordan conceded that the outages and the  for alleged abuse of his position, which has led to a into the agency, had destroyed the ATO's credibility with taxpayers.Photo: Rob Homer
Labor's shadow assistant treasurer Andrew Leigh said the ATO had been left struggling because of public service cuts by the Coalition.
Follow Nassim Khadem on  and .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Institute of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>toRevenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Chris Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Press Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Noroozi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PwC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Robenstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tax Office</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Taxation Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Greco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nassim Khadem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Braig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Kennerley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector-General of Taxation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Homer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPA's Tony Greco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
