<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439076079793693</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/the-heat-is-on-api-joins-laser-clinics-australia-bidding-fray-20170804-gxpu63</url>
  <title>The heat is on: API joins Laser Clinics Australia bidding fray </title>
  <content>
Listed health and beauty retailer Australian Pharmaceutical Industries has emerged in the hotly contested battle for Laser Clinics Australia.
Street Talk can reveal API is working with Morgan Stanley as it seeks to lob a final bid for the botox and hair removal business by an August 24 deadline.  
The timing of a tilt at Laser Clinics is interesting, however, given API's shock downgrade of its earnings guidance last week which saw investors pummel the stock by 13 per cent on Thursday. API downgraded its full-year profit guidance to 5 per cent growth for the year ended August 31, citing poor consumer sentiment. 
Sources said API was running hard at Laser Clinics as a synergy play given the companies have similar target markets, largely females. 

API is considered a strong contender given it knows the franchising and clinics industry well and would be seeking to add another growth avenue to its Priceline Pharmacy network. API is expected to be debt free by the end of the calendar year and the company's chief executive Richard Vincent was keen to point out last week that the balance sheet remained healthy. 

Laser Clinics has earnings before interest, tax, depreciation and amortisation in the high $30 millions this year, spiking to the low $50 millions next year, which suggests a sale price in the order of $500 million. 
API is the parent company of Priceline Pharmacy, Soul Pattinson Chemist and Pharmacist Advice.
Sources said Bain Capital was also fighting hard for Laser Clinics and was taking advice from Goldman Sachs and Citigroup. European buyout firm Permira is also in the final round of bidding, taking counsel from Credit Suisse, and  is working with 
The other trade buyer in the Laser Clinics contest is US-based spa services provider Steiner Leisure, which is owned by consumer-focused buyout fund L Catterton. The firm also has an investment in Melbourne-based compression active wear company 2XU. 

Boutique advisory firm Luminis Partners is managing the auction.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laser Clinics</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citigroup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luminis Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bain Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharmacist Advice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Permira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steiner Leisure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priceline Pharmacy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Vincent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pattinson Chemist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laser Clinics Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L Catterton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>API</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Pharmaceutical Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
