<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439200633846799</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/fbi-investigating-minnesota-mosque-bombing/8779676</url>
  <title>FBI investigating explosion described as 'fire-bombing' at Minnesota mosque</title>
  <content>
FBI investigators are seeking suspects after an explosive device tore through part of a suburban Minneapolis mosque as people were preparing for morning prayers.
The blast happened at around 5:00am on Saturday (local time) at the Dar al-Farooq Islamic Centre in the town of Bloomington, according to the Bloomington Police Department.
Windows of the imam's office were shattered but there were no injuries, authorities and witnesses said.
The centre's executive director, Mohamed Omar, said one worshipper saw a pick-up truck speeding away shortly after the explosion and the mosque, which primarily serves people from the area's large Somali community, occasionally receives threatening calls and emails.
"We came to this country for the same reason everyone else came here - freedom to worship - and that freedom is under threat," Yasir Abdalrahman, a worshipper at the mosque, told the Minneapolis Star Tribune.
"Every other American should be insulted by this."
Asad Zaman, director of the Muslim American Society of Minnesota, described the attack as a fire-bombing.
Investigators will try to determine whether the incident was a hate crime and who may have been behind it, according to Richard Thornton, special agent in charge of the FBI's Minneapolis division.

Thornton said during an afternoon news conference the explosion was caused by an "improvised explosive device", and investigators had recovered components of the device to figure out how it was put together.
The mosque serves as a religious centre and community organising platform for Muslim activists and leaders in the area the Muslim American Society of Minnesota is offering a $10,000 reward for information that leads to an arrest or conviction.
The same reward is also being offered by the Minnesota chapter of the Council on American-Islamic Relations. The group said its national office was urging Islamic centres and mosques to step up security.
"If a biased motive is proven, this attack would represent another in a long list of hate incidents targeting Islamic institutions nationwide in recent months," said Amir Malik, the local chapter's civil rights director.
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BLOOMINGTON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomington Police Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yasir Abdalrahman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thornton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somalis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minneapolis Star Tribune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Omar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI's Minneapolis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINNEAPOLIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asad Zaman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Islamic Relations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amir Malik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minnesota</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Thornton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim American Society of Minnesota</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farooq Islamic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
