<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439119029467300</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836853/government-could-end-hiv-in-australia-with-just-32m/?cs=4219</url>
  <title>Government could end HIV in Australia with just $32m</title>
  <content>
Government could end HIV in Australia with just $32m

NEWS: Canberra??????s International AIDS Candlelight Memorial held at the Great Hall at University House in Acton.  17th May 2015. Photo by Melissa Adams of The Canberra Times.

exit

Australia could become the first nation in the world to effectively end HIV transmission with extra government funding of just $32.5 million a year.
A new plan developed by the Australian Federation of AIDS Organisations says the investment would not only prevent thousands of people contracting the virus but would also eventually deliver $2 billion of savings to the federal government's budget.
The HIV Blueprint - to be presented to federal MPs this week - is designed to avert more than 2000 transmissions over the next three years through better prevention, testing and treatment programs.
The 15-point plan calls for investment in new national education programs, a renewed push behind the once-a-day HIV prevention pill PrEP, the promotion of rapid testing and self-testing, and a new media campaign to promote safe sex among Australians travelling overseas.
The plan also calls for a sustained HIV response among Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people, the improvement of the expertise and knowledge of the HIV workforce and better use of data from the Pharmaceutical Benefits Scheme and Medicare Benefits Schedule.
The driving force behind the blueprint, AFAO chief executive Darryl O'Donnell, says Australia is at an "inflection point".
"HIV transmission has plateaued at approximately 1000 notifications per year for the past five years. Yet the capacity to end HIV transmission is within reach. Just as we led the world in containing HIV in the 1980s, we can now lead the world in ending transmission," he said.
The blueprint has been endorsed by 29 community, clinical and research organisations, reflecting an overwhelming expert consensus.
It is underpinned by modelling from researchers at the Burnet Institute, which says the savings on treatment and care would begin to exceed the cost of the strategy by 2020. The financial benefit would continue to compound thereafter, with lifetime savings from the first 2025 averted infections exceeding $2 billion.
"It makes extraordinary financial sense," Mr O'Donnell said.
The main method of HIV transmission in Australia continues to be sexual contact between men, which accounts for 68 per cent of notifications.
A further 20 per cent of cases were attributed to heterosexual sex, 5 per cent to sexual contact between men and injecting drug use and 3 per cent to injecting drug use only.
Over a quarter of the new HIV notifications in 2015 were late, meaning people were likely to have been living with HIV for at least four years without being tested. Over the past five years the proportion with late diagnoses was highest in people born in south-east Asia and sub???Saharan Africa.
The rate of HIV notification in 2015 among Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander peoples was more than double the rate in the Australian???born non???Indigenous population.
At the end of 2015, an estimated 25,313 people were living with HIV in Australia - with an estimated 2619 unaware of their HIV-positive status. There were 36,171 cases of HIV diagnosed in Australia between the first diagnoses in 1982 and December 21, 2015.
Since the 1990s, treatment that stops HIV from progressing to AIDS - which damages the immune system to the extent that it can no longer fight off infection - has become more effective.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darryl O'Donnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharmaceutical Benefits Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Adams of The Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnet Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 21, 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV Blueprint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International AIDS Candlelight Memorial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare Benefits Schedule</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federation of AIDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saharan Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFAO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Donnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV-positive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
