<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439161979140729</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/investment-banking/tale-of-two-halves-for-capital-markets-teams-20170731-gxlzwk</url>
  <title>Tale of two halves for capital markets teams</title>
  <content>
It's the best of times and worst of times for Australian capital markets bankers. 
Fixed income deal volumes are at near record highs, while equity raisings for the year-to-date are at their lowest levels in the past decade.
So when Morgan Stanley's recently appointed heads of fixed income and equity capital markets pitch for work together, as they often do as part of the bank's global capital markets unit, it's easy to imagine which way the conversations head. 
Bob Herbert is in the hot seat, as head of fixed income capital markets. He's been busy taking the major banks and other big Australian corporates including Fortescue Metals Group and Scentre Group to raise offshore in the past year, tapping into global investor demand for yield. 

Paul Rovere

"There are a lot of bread and butter raisings in our business, but we also spend plenty of time talking to clients about bringing innovation to their deals," Herbert says. 

"That innovation does not always come to market but I think it is important to think about it, particularly for the big issuers, including the banks. Regular issuers have to keep themselves current, fresh and every now and again, try something different." 
So between the usual five and seven year US144A bond market deals, Herbert's team has helped each of the big four banks with something a little different. 
For Commonwealth Bank of Australia, it was the first Australian issuer to raise 30-year money in a $US1.5 billion deal in June, while National Australia Bank twice tapped Taiwan's "Formosa" bond market for a combined $US1 billion earlier this year. 
Westpac Banking Corp's innovation was the first 15-year raising not callable for the first 10-years worth $US1.5 billion, while ANZ Banking Corp was the major bank to issue a Basel 3 compliant tier one deal mid last year. 

Anthony Macdonald (AFR)

The question now is which of the new structures will catch on. 
Melbourne-based Herbert says that while there is plenty of offshore investor demand for fixed income product, it comes down to the cost for the issuer. So while it may be the cheapest time ever to raise 30-year money, it is still not as cheap as a five- or 10-year deal.  
"A lot of people are thinking about it, but they're still cost conscious," Herbert says. 
"Even though it is cheap for the tenor, you still have to pay something for it. And the banks in particular are under cost pressure. The balance for them is probably in favour of reporting the best cost numbers and ROEs at the moment. They have to weigh it all up." 

Louie Douvis

What has not changed is Australia's big debt issuers - be it the banks or corporates like Transurban Group or Ausgrid - heading offshore to raise funds. 
Herbert says the Australian dollar corporate bond market is "fickle", with local investors mostly looking for a particular type of deal. 
"A good deal will get done, and the next one will be a struggle," Herbert says, adding the successful deals tend to be vanilla. 
"Australian fund managers like simple deals. They prefer A to BBB and prefer five- or seven-year tenor rather than longer. If you were a BBB-rated Aussie corporate, and you want 10-year funding, you can still do an $A deal but it is a harder deal to do.

Anthony Macdonald (AFR)

"But quality Australian banks and corporates seeking larger or longer deals are not running up and down George Street asking bond funds to invest in them. They just go offshore instead."
Equity capital markets more challenging

It's not boom times for his equity capital markets colleagues. Skittish investors and a relatively expensive equity market mean initial public offerings have all-but dried up, while few companies have asked shareholders to fund growth or help restore their balance sheet. 
There has been only $US7.6 billion raised in Australian ECM this year, which is the quietest start to the year in the past 10, according to Dealogic. 

Anthony Macdonald (AFR)

Another way to look at it that there was only $1 billion in net Australian equity issuance in the financial year to June 30, down from $15 billion in fiscal 2016 and $52 billion one year earlier, according to Credit Suisse. The long-term average is $40 billion. 
Morgan Stanley's ECM head, Bryce Thompson, says the IPO market is cyclical and, while not shut, will take some time to recover to levels seen during the past four years. 
What about listing companies earlier? 

In the meantime, he would like to see private equity vendors and listed equity investors think about IPO structures and when companies are brought to market. 
"Is there merit to listing a little earlier, have a smaller listing and sitting there as a partner to the public markets for the medium term?" he says.  
"It is the way things are done in other parts of the world and the Australian market has got itself into a situation where vendors haven't exited and tend to lock up to a forecast period.
"Some innovative thinking and structuring around those issues is what we would like to see. 
"Those are the conversations we are having with clients. There is a lot of proof that it works in international markets. You will not find an incidence of a US IPO, for instance, that is followed by one large block trade after for the vendor to sell out." 

He says equity investors - both institutional and retail investors through the firm's Morgan Stanley Wealth Management arm - are generally more supportive of secondary market raisings. 
"Whenever anyone comes to market we are seeing really high quality and high levels of demand," Thompson says. "It is a good market for secondary raisings. Our clients - both on the institutional and retail side - are supportive of good deals." 
. Both report to global capital markets boss Mark Burmeister, who has had more than 25 years' working in Australia's capital markets. 
"[The change] is thinking about the future of our business," Burmeister says. 
"And it releases me to be a broader coverage banker at a very senior level and have an impact at that level." 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Macdonald</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Banking Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US7.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US144A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burmeister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US IPO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Metals Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herbert</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBB-rated Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Formosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRANSURBAN GROUP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley Wealth Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian ECM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based Herbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac Banking Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Herbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basel 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Burmeister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rovere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scentre Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dealogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ausgrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley's ECM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
