<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439200633846806</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/racing/jason-mannings-evergreen-battler-saturday-sorcerer-a-darwin-cup-chance/news-story/e2f73930f54ea737972313ece60d17ce</url>
  <title>Magic in the air for Saturday Sorcerer</title>
  <content>
SATURDAY Sorcerer is the battler of today's star-studded $200,000 Darwin Cup field.
But jockey Vanessa Arnott believes the evergreen eight-year-old could surprise many punters among the bumper crowd at Fannie Bay.
And you don't need to only take her word for it.
"The vet comes and looks at all the horses running in the Cup, and he said how good his legs were for his age," Arnott said of the gelding with 47 previous runs.
Arnott was highly impressed with the stayer's second place in the $45,000 Million Dollar Fish Buntine Handicap (1900m) on July 22.
"He was super in the Buntine. He ran second in the Buntine last year," she said.
"He's just fit and well, and ready to go."
Arnott has developed a strong rapport with the unflappable Saturday Sorcerer.
"The owners said they wanted me this year because I've had four rides on him for three seconds," she said.
Saturday Sorcerer's trainer and Arnott's fiance Jason Manning believes that run of second placings could end in the best possible fashion on the biggest day of the Top End racing calendar.
"Hopefully 'grand final day' is the monkey off the back, as they say," he said.
"He's in there with a shot.
"I was rapt with his Buntine run the other day.
"His whole campaign's been for (today).
"He's an honest campaigner who rolls forward and puts himself up there."
Saturday Sorcerer has shown steady improvement since his last place in last year's Cup.
"He left here after last year's disappointing run in the Cup, went down and won the Dunkeld Cup for us," Manning said.
"That was a big weekend in country Victoria at the base of the Grampians.
"He picked up some money and we came up.
"He appreciates the 2000 metres. Anything beyond a mile is his go.
"This is his fourth Darwin Cup campaign. He's been up and down that highway a few times."
Manning was delighted after Saturday Sorcerer drew barrier 15 at the draw on Thursday.
"Perfect. It was quite funny at the barrier draw - we wanted to draw an outside gate," he said.
"As it worked out we were the last ones drawn and that was the last gate.
"We weren't disappointed when all the inside gates were getting drawn because we wanted to be out wide."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday Sorcerer</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Manning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Million Dollar Fish Buntine Handicap (1900</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnott</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grampian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanessa Arnott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunkeld Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fannie Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buntine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
