<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439071784826337</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/confidential-reports-on-reality-tv-celebrity-gossip-and-chris-lilley-in-brisbane/news-story/30d76d53b41fc5746cde66b68c20ca1f</url>
  <title>The one product Survivors can have</title>
  <content>
SURVIVE THE SUNBURN
CONTESTANTS on Australian Survivor know to expect to rough it in remote Samoa, but it seems there is one commodity they can have in abundance.
A Channel 10 insider has revealed contestants are offered sunscreen so they don't suffer extreme sunburn or risk skin health during filming.
Of course it is up to the contestants to use that sunscreen - and not everyone managed to avoid a "warm red" welcome.
While contestants have to go without basics, including toothpaste, the insider reports they are given charcoal to clean their teeth and maintain oral health.
We are sure the families of those who can last the 55 days will be extremely grateful.
BACHELOR STARS NOT CHEAP
RUMOUR has it that ex-Bachelor stars won't get involved with the show again without money.
A number of sources have told Confidential that former contestants from the Channel 10 reality dating series were turning down media opportunities through companies not linked to the network when they discovered they wouldn't be paid or believed they weren't being paid enough.
While the sources wouldn't name names, they said a number of those who had appeared on past seasons of The Bachelor and The Bachelorette had been offered opportunities across both print and radio that involved ideas such as providing reviews or opinions for current episodes.
Apparently, in some cases it came down to not being able to agree on a figure, with the reality TV personalities asking for sums outlets deemed not to be in line with their appearances or what they were providing.
NEW MANTRA FOR CHRIS LILLEY
COMEDIAN Chris Lilley was spotted in Brisbane as he came under fire for posting a blackface video.
Lilley last month faced huge social media backlash after he re-posted a video clip from 2014 called "Squashed N***a" less than a week after the man who ran over and killed indigenous teenager Elijah Doughty, 14, was acquitted of manslaughter.
He issued a public apology soon after.
The Aussie star was spotted at a Brisbane hare krishna restaurant picking up takeaway at about the same time.
Spies said a young girl working at the store recognised him and told her boss about the famous guest. The store manager ducked out and gave Lilley a mantra CD.
While it is unknown what he was referencing, spies say Lilley responded: "Thanks, I probably need it right now."
RULES BEATS THE BLOCK
WITH The Block in full swing, Confidential can reveal which high-profile renovator missed out on being cast in the series.
House Rules winner Aaron Winter had previously applied for the Channel 9 renovation series with a male friend.
After missing out on the casting, the Gold Coast carpenter switched tactics and convinced his renovation-rookie wife Daniella to team up with him for the House Rules auditions.
Following a gruelling casting process, in which camera crews came to their Gold Coast home for screen testing, the couple were selected.
It was a smart choice as they banked $200,000 for winning the Channel 7 show in May. They also filmed an episode for the network's The Great Day Out.
CODY RIDES ALONE
CODY Simpson has revealed he is single.
Asked if there was "anyone special" on the scene at the moment, the LA-based Gold Coast singer said: "No there isn't, there's no one."
The 20-year-old, who is one of the faces of the new Bonds Homegrown Tees campaign, has new music due out next month and has just shot his first feature film. He has been snapped with a mystery blonde or two over recent months but said he didn't have a girlfriend.
"I wish I had a more interesting answer," he said.
Simpson has previously dated Victoria's Secret model Gigi Hadid and has been linked to models Sierra Swartz and Sahara Ray.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sahara Ray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Winter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Secret</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CODY RIDES ALONE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Lilley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lilley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sierra Swartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cody Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Rules</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA-based Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonds Homegrown Tees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gigi Hadid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEW MANTRA FOR CHRIS LILLEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Day Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BACHELOR STARS NOT CHEAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elijah Doughty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
