<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439286533193524</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/107551/she-says-he-says-peugeot-4008/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>She says, he says: Peugeot 4008</title>
  <content>
He: French car maker Peugeot is known for its small hatches and delivery vans but lacks in-house expertise in the booming SUV sector. It has hit up Mitsubishi for some help - first it turned the Outlander into a 4007, and now the smaller ASX has been restyled into the 4008. First impressions?

She: With tall, boxy styling and a grinning grille, it certainly looks the part - and that is probably key to attracting attention in a  segment where buyers are  spoilt for choice.
He: It's $1000 more expensive than the ASX it's based on when you equip both with a continuously variable transmission (CVT) auto, which adds an extra $2500 to the five-speed manual model we're testing. But it also  adds auto headlights and wipers, daytime running lights, tweaked styling and a European badge on the nose. Still, I can't help thinking the Mitsubishi-sourced interior feels a bit dowdy for a Pug. 
She: Couldn't agree more, Steve. The front pews are comfortable and look smart, but overall the dark cabin feels altogether more basic than I'd expected. What did you make of the room in the back?
He: Adjustable seat-backs in the rear  help with passenger comfort although the seats themselves are very firm, the uneven floor is disconcerting and headroom becomes an issue for anyone taller than 180 centimetres. I was surprised to find two pockets in the back of each front seat. The loading area is well short of being family-size, unless you drop the rear seats. 
She: Rear passengers (think: kids) get no air vents and only wallet-sized stowage space in the doors. But there's ample storage up front. The five-speed manual gearbox is slick but what's with the long gear stick that seems more at home in a Mitsubishi Triton?
He: That lever does look a bit truck-like. The engine isn't exactly urgent but it has enough go for cruising around the suburbs. Overtaking on a country road is another matter, though. And at 8.9 litres per 100 kilometres on my highway-dominated drive I thought it was a bit off the pace for fuel economy. I'm guessing your city sojourn wouldn't have fared better?
She: No, 13.1L/100km around town fails to impress, but I was  surprised by its turning circle in the car park. Engine noise is a bit intrusive for my liking, and I found the ride to be a tad harsh. Vision out the back and over the shoulder isn't the best, but how do you like the reversing camera in the mirror? 
He: Although it's a small image, I think it's a better solution than a camera in the centre stack because you're more likely to be looking at your mirrors while reversing. I prefer reversing sensors, though, which this car also has. 
She: So what's your verdict overall? There are some sharp rivals - the Volkswagen Tiguan, Mazda CX-5 and Subaru's XV - among the compact SUVs.  Where does the Pug sit in the mix?
He: I  like its sharp, new face but that downmarket interior is very un-Peugeot, and its ride and handling aren't class-leading. There's no shortage of competition at this price  but I'd find it hard to go past the CX-5 for value, competence, and practicality. The Skoda Yeti might score a test drive, too. You?
She: In this company, the Peugeot 4008 doesn't quite stack up. I've got a soft spot for the Tiguan, but the   Mazda may be the one to beat.
Peugoet 4008 Active AWD
The price: From $30,990 plus on-road and dealer costs
Vital statistics:  2.0-litre 4-cyl petrol; 110kW/197Nm; 5-sp manual; 7.9L/100km and 186Nm; AWD

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi-sourced</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skoda Yeti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen Tiguan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peugeot</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L/100</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiguan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peugeot 4008</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CX-5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outlander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi Triton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru XV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peugoet 4008 Active AWD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda CX-5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CVT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
