<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438814086786212</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/1751589/haynes-leads-magic-to-final/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Haynes leads Magic to final</title>
  <content>
Haynes leads Magic to final

CENTRE OF ATTENTION: Broadmeadow Magic striker Peter Haynes, No.9, celebrates scoring with his teammates.  Picture: Jonathan Carroll

exit
BROADMEADOW striker Peter Haynes received a message at the end of last season from Lambton Jaffas coach David Tanchevski, asking him what were the chances.

The Jaffas were planning a maiden assault on the Northern NSW State League with the immediate purpose of avoiding relegation.
Haynes, a Jaffas junior and the 2011 state league player of the year, would have been an ideal man to lead the charge.
Twelve months on, Haynes is preparing to lead Broadmeadow Magic against the Jaffas in the grand final.
It is a strange but satisfying scenario for Haynes on two fronts.
''I got a text from Dave Tanch last year, I think a day after they won their grand final, saying, 'What are your chances,''' Haynes said. 
''But I think we both knew it wasn't going to happen. I'm a Magic guy now.
''But I'm really happy they are there. They've done so well and are a great club.''
Haynes played his junior football at the Jaffas until age 11 and said the connection to his grand final rivals had already put him in the firing line.
''My uncle Scott [Haynes] was quite a good player and played at KB United,'' he said. 
''He played at the Jaffas and still supports them, so he's been into me this week as well. 
''We had a Father's Day dinner the other night and he was poking me, trying to give me a bit of stick.''
Defending major premiers Magic will go in as clear favourites after beating the Jaffas 4-0 in the major semi-final two weeks ago.
The Jaffas hit back on Saturday with their second penalty shoot-out win over Hamilton in two weeks to set-up a dream first-season, grand final appearance. It is remarkable effort, given the Jaffas' immediate goal this year was avoiding relegation.
Haynes, though, said his side would not take the Jaffas lightly.
''I don't know if I buy into the fairytale any more. It's hard to be a fairytale when you come second in the league,'' Haynes said.
''They've overachieved in terms of what people thought they'd do, but they've finished second and won two semi-finals, so you can't buy into the underdog tag too much anymore.''
He also believed their recent win had  painted the wrong picture. 
''I think we got a bit lucky there,'' he said. 
''It's not too often you win 4-0 and your goalkeeper gets man of the match. That must tell you something about the game.''
Haynes expected the return of Jobe Wheelhouse from suspension to boost the Jaffas, who have come through a gruelling finals campaign and will be without Abe Wheelhouse due to an ankle injury. Micheal Sessions (back) and Paul Devine (knee) are also in doubt. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haynes</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern NSW State League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Haynes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadow Magic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaffa</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Tanchevski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Micheal Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KB United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CENTRE OF ATTENTION</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAMBTON Jaffas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Wheelhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father's Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Devine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abe Wheelhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Tanch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
