<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438985885479629</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/2560301/keep-yourself-together-at-the-races/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Keep yourself together at the races</title>
  <content>
A big day at the races can be an endurance test for even the most resilient two-legged filly and her outfit. Our guide can increase your staying handicap and ensure you are still fresh for the after races party.

Ladies pose as they arrive to attend the 2009 Melbourne Cup Day meeting at Flemington Racecourse. Getty Images.
Fashion preparations need to start early cup day to get you looking your best and track side before the first horses thunder down the straight so make sure you get a good night's sleep. The best race days need good planning. Make sure you know what you are taking with you and plan your preparation for the next morning as time will be limited.

Discarded shoes at the 2013 Melbourne Cup. PHOTO: Fairfax Digital Collection.
Of course they must be lovely and compliment your outfit but consider some practicalities also. Don those fabulous shoes, but keep in mind you are on your feet for most of the day so comfort should also be a priority. Even if you are buying new shoes for the event make sure you have worn them at least once before race day. This is the only way to to break shoes in and discover potential problem spots before they ruin your day. Take note of any irritations and plan accordingly.

Ensure you have gel pads to cushion the balls of your feet as nothing ruins a great day more than burning soles. There is a great range of insoles, heel liners, anti-slip heel inserts and heel cushions on the market so stock up and take a couple extra in your bag as well as a good supply of band-aids. Better to be safe than sorry.
Heels with a platform are usually more comfortable than those without. The platform provides height while putting less strain on the arch and ball of the foot. If this look is not for you there are many styles that have a hidden platform which will give you a more streamlined look.
A rub relief stick may be worth investing in. It coats your feet in a waxy, clear finish that acts as a protective layer against friction.
Another tip which sounds a little odd, but may save your feet, is toe tapping. There is a nerve that splits between your third and fourth toe which causes pain in the balls of your feet. By taping toe three and four together with surgical tape, less strain is put on the nerve which helps prevent and alleviate pain.
If all else fails some ladies bring fold-up ballet flats or thongs, room permitting, in the handbag for real pain emergencies.

These girls managed to keep their headgear in place despite the wind at Oaks Day 2005.  PHOTO: Fairfax Digital Collection.
Keeping your hat or headpiece in place all day and having the hair beneath dressed to complement it can be harder than picking the trifecta in the third.
As this is the spring carnival and and the weather may be windy you need to ensure your head wear will stay where it is put. Crown Oaks Day at Flemington in 2005 was very windy and changeable making it difficult for the ladies to keep both head-wear and hems in place.

There is nothing more annoying than having a headpiece that you need to hold on to on a windy day so plan for this in advance.

Usually head-wear designed by a milliner will come with a comb, elastic or both to help it stay in place. Hat elastic is a fantastic way to keep a hat or fascinator in place. The elastic should go to the back of the head, behind the ears and in or under the hairline. If your hair is very fine or straight elastic will be a big help in keeping your head-wear in place.
With hats also comes the dreaded hat hair. Whether its too much frizz or loss of volume, your hair is bound to look a little, or a lot, worse for wear once you take your hat off.

Wear your hat on dry hair by blow drying the hair completely dry and sealing the cuticles shut with a blast of cold air. This also seals in the style, making your hair less prone to taking on the shape of your hat.
Volume boosting spray will give your hair that instant uplift after wearing a hat. Flat, lifeless hair is a problem when you wear certain types of hats but a small spritz of this spray will give your hair that oomph that it needs to look fabulous in a matter of seconds. Apply the spray on the roots for that instant lift. Dry shampoo or hair spray will also do the job well. Flip your hair over and spray on the roots while running the fingers through the hair.

When choosing a dress for race day make sure it ticks all the boxes. PHOTO: Getty Images
When choosing your perfect race day outfit consider first if you would wear it to a nightclub. If you would chances are it is not suitable for the racecourse. Think well-cut dresses that fall to the knee or just below, along with contemporary takes in the classic suit.
The most important rule of thumb for the dress is the silhouette must be suited to your shape and it must be something you can comfortably wear all day. Dresses that are too tight, have no give, are uncomfortably short or rub around the armholes or anywhere else should be discarded. Nothing says fashion victim quite like a lady wearing something trendy that isn't quite right for her figure.
When choosing an outfit for the races do consider the weather and keep in mind you may be out in the elements for much of the day. Many a spring carnival event, including the Melbourne Cup,  has been held in the wind and rain so check the forecast. If wind, rain and cold is on the radar you'll need to be prepared as shivering under a sheer silk frock is not a great look or feel. Bring a stylish jacket and an umbrella if you think you'll need it.

Melbourne Cup 2010 Erin Borrows shelters from the rain. Make sure you plan for any weather. PHOTO: Fairfax Digital Collection.
Before leaving the house make sure you check your chosen dress for any potential problems such as a hem that is about to give or a seam that is about to burst. Again this kind of issue could mess with your whole cup day feel.
A great tip is to take some Magic tape with you. This product doesn't just prevent "nip slips," (think Janet Jackson) but can also be used to keep up the fallen hem on a dress, to fix a fascinator clip or elastic band which has become detached or used to hold pesky shoulder straps in place.

To enjoy your day to the maximum make sure your bag will carry everything you need. PHOTO: Getty Images.
Clutches look lovely but carry very little. If you plan to survive well at the races you are better off bringing a shoulder bag so you can fit in all the essentials.
Depending on the size of your bag, it is possible to ensure you are well covered for any contingency.
Walking bare-foot out of the races, shoes in hand, is not a good look not to mention bad for your feet. The advantage of taking a bigger bag is fold up ballet flats will fit in, saving your feet and your dignity.
Travel sized deodorant is a great idea as is a compact mirror for when the public toilet is so packed you can't get any mirror space. Hand sanitiser or a small packet of hand and body wet ones are also a race day must if you can fit them in.  
Wallet, phone, sunglasses, camera, sunscreen, blister band-aids, essential make-up, are all non-negotiable items. A small sewing kit, safety pins, and pens don't take-up much room while, depending on the forecast, an umbrella may need to be included. Any extra room will happily be taken up with your form guide.

By following these tips you should have no trouble keeping both yourself and outfit together for the entire day. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oaks Day 2005</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Oaks Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington Racecourse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janet Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Digital Collection</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup 2010 Erin Borrows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
