<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439033130120241</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/tensions-at-mca-over-finkel-strategy-20170806-gxq7xn</url>
  <title>Tensions at MCA over coal-focused Finkel strategy </title>
  <content>
The Minerals Council of Australia's determined defence of Australia's domestic coal market and it has triggered tremors of boardroom dissent within industry lobby.
The MCA's, in particular, has proven a flashpoint for fractures between the mining lobby and a powerful cohort of its membership.
It is understood that a recent council board meeting heard pointed criticism of the organisations response to Finkel's slate of recommendations with BHP Billiton's head of Australian operations, Mike Henry, reportedly taking the lead in delivering rebuke.
It is said that Henry and several other council directors upbraided the council for the comparatively singular focus of its response to a set of recommendations that a weight of the membership recognised as a very reasonable pathway to the solution to an energy problem that is undermining competitiveness of both existing businesses and future investment options.

BHP's position on the Finkel Review is publicly clear. It is genuinely supportive, impatient for action and fearful that its opportunity will be squandered for lack of consensus.

Australia's biggest miner maintains that Finkel's recommendations represent the only answer on offer to an energy emergency that, left unaddressed immediately, will only become more expensive and difficult to resolve and will cause permanent harm to industry generally and the mining sector particularly. 
One of the MCA's dilemma's in responding to the Australia's energy trilemma is that it needs to represents all of its membership and, since it took over the Australian Coal Association back in 2013, that base has included everyone who is anyone in coal.
Conversations with base metals producers evince support for the MCA's broader position on coal, which is that it is a regional poverty buster and will likely be an ever bigger part of the emerging world's energy mix for the foreseeable future.But there is growing frustration that this  faceted advocacy has contained the MCA's thinking on Finkel is, though, deeply frustrating.
More tactics than strategy

The idea, for example, that the MCA is urging a government fund on its proposed solution to our base load electricity conundrum sits obviously jarring with the organisation's free marketeering membership. And, as we have noted here in the recent past, Australia's domestic coal consumption sits essentially a blip on the radar of the export industry, so it is hard to understand why the anxiety levels are so high. 
Sure, I acknowledge that there is potentially dangerous public affairs paradox in the idea that we will be sending more coal to the world while using less of it ourselves. But that is where we are headed unless those who direct capital allocation in the Australian power sector change their minds on coal's place in their diets. Far better then to promote coal for what it is, a regional poverty buster that can be used every more efficiently to provide power to the 1.7 billion people of the world who do not have access to electricity.  
The Finkel Review was established to design a new path to Australia's suddenly vulnerable energy security. And the MCA Council has patently failed to see the mountain for the trees in its responding to Finkel's recommendations. Instead of being seen to help in the manufacture of the broad political consensus needed to translate Finkel's recommendations into a realistic national energy policy, it has driven itself to the fringes of a debate. And, frankly, there is a great weight of its constituents who simply cannot afford for Finkel to become a dusty debating point.
From the get-go, the MCA's response to Finkel has appeared more tactical than strategic. The Finkel Review has been used as just another platform for advancing the case for coal and the need for public subsidy to extend coal's future in the domestic power business. 

While that might be reasonable for, say, a coal association, the fact is that the Minerals Council represents a far broader church of miners, many of whom require reliable, price-predictable sources of electricity to run minerals processing operations or downstream processing plants. 
To some degree, Rio Tinto and Glencore sit evidence of the delicacies the MCA has to weigh in assessing the ambitions of its advocacy. Both are diversified miners who run fleets of metals processing operations that have been pushed to capacity shut-ins in the wake of surging power prices. Both recognise that coal mining faces very particularly challenges in a world determined to take control of carbon emissions. But each is pursuing quite different portfolio strategies in response to Australia's unique energy crisis and its equally unique place in the carbon trading game.
From what we understand, Rio is another concerned about the direction the MCA has taken on Finkel specifically and coal particularly while Glencore's recent public utterances would indicate that is sits more aligned with the direction the Council has pursued.
Rio is, of course, deep into the process of selling its coal business and reassessing the future of the energy business generally while Glencore has recently been a desperate buyer of those very same assets that the Australian dual listing is surrendering.

'A serious situation'

In announcing Rio's shareholder-enriching results last Wednesday, chief executive Jean Sebastien Jacques was blunt in his appraisal of Australia's challenge.
"I know there is a serious situation in relation to energy in Australia. It is not only about Rio Tinto. It's across the patch, all right. What we want as a company is a source [of] affordable and reliable of power in Australia. And today, that is not the case. And it's not because of a lack of capacity. It's about the regulatory framework and how it's working at the state level.
"So, the only thing I can say is, please fix the problem because otherwise when I look at the plan, either at the state level or the federal level in Australia where people want to develop more manufacturing activities, if the industry can't have access to reliable and affordable source of power that will not work.

"The model is broken today. Everybody is in agreement with that. It has to be fixed. I mean, three weeks ago, I was with the PM and we made the point again and again, and will continue to fight for this one because we want Australia to be competitive in that space. And they need to fix the problem and the government needs to step in on this one."
Just hours before the commentary from Jacques, Glencore's Australian based global coal business, Peter Freyberg, delivered a now familiar assessment of where we are and how far we are from fixing our problems.
Freyberg indicated that Glencore sees rather less potential in the Finkel Review than some of his contemporaries on the MCA. He said Finkel had described "one possible pathway" the report had done "very little to provide investors with any confidence for future investments".
"There are a number of unanswered questions in terms of the modelling and analysis in the Finkel Review," he continued. "Such as what is the assumed make-up and nature of Australia's industrial base and, just as importantly, what are the policy recommendations around future energy affordability?"
Freyberg ran through a long list of priorities for future Australian energy markets that ran from widely agreed basics to somewhat more contentious detail. Freyberg's call for a single national policy that replaces a complex of conflicting commonwealth and state programs and the need to replace base load generation sits thoroughly uncontroversial. The push to replace the market distorting renewable energy target is, too, a position widely shared and is proposed by Finkel.
But the idea that Australia might need to "consider a possible delay in meeting its emission reduction targets under the Paris Agreement" is a little more contentious even within the mining sector.
As one Glencore competitor said to me last week: "We keep telling people that our industry relies on national sovereignty and on government's delivering on legislated commitments. 'Don't change the rules on which investments are made', that's what we keep telling governments."
No, Australia can't simply walk away from Paris and not just because there would be dangerously limited tolerance among the voting public for such a retreat. What Australia needs to do is develop a national energy policy that recovers security of supply through reforms that recovery a level of agnosticism to the economic incentives within the market. Those far better informed than me maintain that Finkel has provided an extremely workable framework for a more secure energy future.

Sure there are flaws but the MCA should be working to illuminate and fill in whatever detail is missing. Instead it risks being isolated from the future policy evolution because even people inside the council have decided it is an evangelist for the past. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCA</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freyberg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean-Sebastien Jacques</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minerals Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel Review</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Freyberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Coal Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCA Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Billiton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minerals Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacques</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
