<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439114734499973</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4797673/forget-politicians-the-people-should-decide/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Forget politicians, the people should decide</title>
  <content>
OPPORTUNISM: One contributor is questioning why some politicians won't support a popular vote on the issue of changing the Marriage Act.

SO now Bill Shorten supports a plebiscite, his previous concerns about a people's vote being divisive, expensive and non-binding magically disappears. He's not letting us have a say about marriage of course, but about Australia becoming a republic.
Why a people's vote on a republic but not on marriage?
At least the government can claim a mandate for a marriage plebiscite, but Labor has no mandate for a republic, which could need two plebiscites plus a referendum.
Bill Shorten even acknowledges no public groundswell for a republic, while ignoring polling confirming that most voters want same-sex 'marriage' decided by a popular vote. It's all about political opportunism, not principle. In 2013 Bill was 'completely relaxed' about preferring a national vote on marriage. Some Liberal MPs also seem keen to backflip on their party's election promise of a plebiscite on marriage.
We can't trust the politicians with this, so let the people decide.
Peter Dolan, Lambton

Turning history to rubble

WHAT a fabulous icon The Store has been to our city and beyond.
Early history: My grandparents immigrated to Australia in the early 1900s from the other side of the world. And it must have been like that because my grandfather was a miner and they settled in West Wallsend. In Scotland he had 'gone down the mines at 12 years of age'.

It was the period of miners demanding better conditions and pays leading to strikes and no pay. The Store was born, and supported these families during these times and debts were paid off by installment.
The Store expanded and built the remarkable and outstanding Co-op in Hunter Street, selling everything, delivering groceries to homes free of charge and employing a very large number of people.
Australians travel overseas and marvel at the historical protection of their past. The Store's future - our city's shame - a heap of bull-dozed rubble taken to a dump site.
Mary Gayner, Lambton

Coincident timing

IN response to Jeremy Bath (Letters, 2/8): Nice try Jeremy, you really don't believe that the people of Newcastle are so gullible as to believe your spin concerning money being spent on the east end was not for the Supercars event?

The Supercars event just happened to come at exactly the same time as all these renewal works were being started. Were the S bends also in the renewal plans? Please explain.

Watt Street, as you said, is Newcastle's oldest street that was in desperate need of repair long before the Supercars was even considered. Why did it take the Supercars event to have the facelift and repairs done?

This work should have been done years ago. I would like to know who these ratepayers from western suburbs are. It's alright for them, they won't have to put up with the noise and fumes or the unsociable behaviour long after racing is over for the day.

I notice you didn't mention any comments from the residents from the East End.

Is the council or the race organisers going to compensate all the businesses that are losing their income? I doubt it.

Unfortunately there will be some residents of Newcastle who believe the spin.
Melville Brauer, Gateshead

Vote yes for Wests

IN reply to Dale Allen (Letters, 1/8) and supporters of other clubs, their dollars will be minor compared to the large income that will come to Wests from increased bar sales, meals, etc when Knights fans head to their club after a home game, especially a win.
It is imperative they have the backing of a leagues club otherwise they are doomed. It is well known the NRL have spoken about moving the Knights to another area.
How unpalatable it would be to hear of the Brisbane Knights or some other area?
As the greatest breeding ground of rugby league champions, it is unthinkable to not have our own team.

Robert Martin, Warners Bay

It's happening, accept it

IN reply to Shane Brassington (Letters, 4/8): I would like to take issue with your reference to the abuse traffic controllers are getting working in the East End.

First up, they are doing their job and are not representatives of the council and shows a complete disrespect, people know the construction is happening.

This goes on top of a story that was told recently about a unit resident throwing hot water from their balcony over workers below. Secondly, as for Jeremy Bath's column being full of blah, blah, blah, may I say, the majority of Newcastle are sick of the same old blah, blah, blah and fact twisting coming out of anti-race supporters.

It's time to accept the event and the construction works happening, or start planning a weekend escape in late November.
Tony Mansfield, Lambton

Not all so lucky

FRANK Ward expresses his thanks and gratitude for himself and siblings for their commitment to community over their lifetime  (Letters, 1/8).

He fleetingly mentioned the sexual abuse that has recently been revealed within the Catholic Church. He embraces the good works of the Newcastle Citizen of the Year Sister Diana Santleben.

Frank recounts his memories under the care of nuns at St Patrick's Armidale in 1931. He also reports the family's distinguished careers and excellent community service because of the care they received.

If Frank had followed the trail of destruction to thousands of people I can introduce him to, because of dealings with the Catholic community, he would realise he and his siblings were simply very, very lucky.

There are equally many people in society who demonstrate the same spirit, care and example that has been shown to Frank and his siblings. The most prominent is a policeman who was the whistle blower of the sexual abuse tragedy in the Newcastle-Maitland diocese.

Not everybody had the example of Sister Santleman and I can assure Frank that the current victims and survivors of sexual abuse in Armidale won't hear or recognise "a bar" of his account within the Catholic institutions of Armidale.

Had they had your experience Frank, we wouldn't now be contending with the crimes from which children "lost the essence of their being".

Pat Garnet, Newcastle East

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle-Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Garnet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East End</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armidale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateshead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Brassington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wallsend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watt Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Patrick's Armidale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Citizen of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Mansfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-op</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Bath</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Gayner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sister Santleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melville Brauer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Knights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sister Diana Santleben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
