<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439458331886948</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/1585573/gallery-mel-doyle-quits-sunrise/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>GALLERY: Mel Doyle quits Sunrise</title>
  <content>
GALLERY: Mel Doyle quits Sunrise

Mel Doyle in a publicity shot for Channel 7's Sunrise morning show.

Melissa Doyle, David Koch and Natalie Barr on the Sunrise set. Picture: Supplied

Melissa Doyle meets her World Vision sponsor child Elyas and other local children when visiting his village of Chencha in Southern Ethiopia in August 2011.

Sunrise hosts Natalie Barr, Mel Doyle and David Koch have their make-up attended to on set at the Channel 7 studios in Docklands, Melbourne in May, 2013. Picture:Paul Jeffers

Sunrise presenters David Koch and Mel Doyle talk to the audience at the Channel 7 studios in Docklands, Melbourne in May, 2013. Picture: Paul Jeffers

Sunrise presenter Mel Doyle has her hair and make-up attended to mid-way through the show at the Channel 7 studios in Docklands, Melbourne in May, 2013. Picture: Paul Jeffers

Sunrise presenter Mel Doyle on set in Melbourne in May, 2013. Picture: Paul Jeffers

Sunrise presenters David Koch and Mel Doyle pose for a photograph with a member of the studio audience at the Channel 7 studios in Docklands, Melbourne in May, 2013. Picture: Paul Jeffers

Sunrise presenter Mel Doyle on set in May, 2013. Picture: Paul Jeffers

exit

Melissa Doyle will today leave breakfast show Sunrise, seven weeks after she announced she would be leaving the program after nearly 12 years.
A tearful Doyle told viewers in June  that she would be leaving breakfast television to take on a new challenge in a prime time "network news" initiative with Channel Seven.
"I can honestly say that the team I've worked with at Sunrise over the last 12 years in particular have been like a second family," Doyle wrote in a message posted on Facebook.
"You cannot spend your working hours with people you don't like or respect and you cannot fake the camaraderie, respect and empathy we all have for each other. And that includes all the on-air and off air team that work to put this show together each day."
In particular, she thanked her Sunrise co-host David Koch.
"He's been my partner, supporter, confidante, and friend. I'll miss working alongside him each day," Doyle wrote.
Doyle will take on two new roles with Seven, including a 4PM national news bulletin with former Today Tonight host Matt White from August 19 and a national 7PM news bulletin on 7Two from next Monday.
''I decided it was time to take on a new challenge and so it is with great sadness that I announce I will be leaving Sunrise.
''When Sunrise started again in 2002, not many people were watching. We were the upstart and not taken seriously by anyone - and certainly not our rivals.
''I am proud to say that over the ensuing years, we collectively built the show to be a fun, entertaining and informative way for so many households in Australia to start their day. It's been a privilege to have hosted it and be invited into your homes.
''Thank you to each and every viewer who tuned in each morning - for laughing with us, laughing at us and turning to us for your morning news fix,'' Doyle wrote.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel Doyle</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Today Tonight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chencha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Ethiopia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Doyle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elyas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Barr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2013</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Vision</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doyle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Koch</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
