<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439084669728433</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/orca-researchers-further-buoyed-by-significant-findings-on-killer-whales/news-story/a6b218d4529030aca278bd81a4e9eee0</url>
  <title>Killer whale research revelations</title>
  <content>
RESEARCHERS are another step closer to understanding the little-known behaviour of killer whales following a pair of significant findings this month.
Killer Whales Australia manager David Donnelly has confirmed two of the three orcas spotted off the Tasman Peninsula last week were the same animals photographed off Phillip Island, Victoria in December 2013.
The remaining juvenile is also likely to be a match with the 2013 sighting.
Mr Donnelly said the whales would be added to KWA's catalogue later this year to help further understand the population.
"It will help to understand the life history of each animal in terms of its habitat use and its abundance in certain areas," he said.
"We have no idea how many are living on the coast of Australia. They range between Sydney and the Tasman Peninsula but they are probably going down further [south], we just don't know."
Mr Donnelly said the discovery would also tie in with University of Tasmania PhD candidate Ben Sellers' research into killer whale diets, hunting preferences and foraging range.
It comes after Wild Ocean Tasmania used an underwater camera to film whales off the peninsula earlier this month, with a microphone picking up vocalisations.
Curtin University PhD candidate Bec Wellard, who has been researching killer whale acoustics off Western Australia for five years, said it was the first time in Tasmania that an orca vocalisation had been recorded concurrently with visual footage.
Ms Wellard said orcas used three types of vocalisations: echolocation clicks for hunting as well as burst pulses and whistles for social interaction. The whales in the video were using the latter two.
"I compare acoustics from populations all around Australia and see if there are differences in dialects between populations and family groups," she said.
Ms Wellard said she could not use the file for accurate analysis, but that she was now considering coming to Tasmania to use an underwater microphone known as a hydrophone.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donnelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtin University PhD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wild Ocean Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Sellers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bec Wellard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wellard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PhD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whales Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Donnelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
