<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439157684173409</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/john-nolan-is-not-interested-in-making-you-comfortable-20170803-gxoxxj</url>
  <title>John Nolan is not interested in making you comfortable</title>
  <content>
The thought of buying  at current levels makes John Nolan want to BARF.
The legendary Australian asset consultant and founder of JANA believes popular US tech stocks Facebook, Apple, Netflix and Google (FANG) are wildly overvalued. Especially when compared to out-of-favour miners like BHP, Anglo American, Rio Tinto and Freeport McMoRan (BARF).
"Booms always end in tears," he says, comparing their respective revenues, price-to-earnings ratios and market capitalisations.
Nolan says sections of the equity market are at "very stretched valuations", and given the long bull run in US equities he would be inclined to allocate less to equities overall. Developed market equities, especially.

Having seen a few booms and busts in a 40-year plus career as a professional investor and adviser to superannuation funds, it might pay to heed his warning.

, the 68-year-old veteran investor is kept busy as a member of investment committees at the $40 billion REST super fund and Warakirri Asset Management.
Taken on trust

The various investment options at both show significant outperformance over the long term thanks to his guidance. He admits, however, that it hasn't always been smooth sailing, and at times stakeholders have had to take him on trust.
Nolan founded the asset consultants John A Nolan & Associates, or JANA, in 1987 after working for both National Mutual and Victoria's State Electricity Commission.

He was the finance director of the SEC and oversaw a pension fund with 22,000 employees and $1.5 billion in assets. It was a responsibility hindered by a lack of independent research and the opaque nature of asset management firms.
When his contract came up for renewal, the then premier of Victoria, John Cain, declined to extend his tenure.
Having run a large pension fund, Nolan was acutely aware of the lack of independent research available on asset classes, asset allocation and fund managers. So he decided to set up his own shop. Mercer took a small equity stake in exchange for office space.
The Wesfarmers staff super fund was among the first to benefit from Nolan's experience in dealing with institutional fund managers.

"You could replicate a balanced account buying the bits individually. Someone like National Mutual would have a bonds pool and an equities pool, and you could actually construct a balanced fund more cheaply than buying one from them," he says.
Wesfarmers ' no-brainer'

Wesfarmers had a defined benefit scheme, a challenging prospect at the best of times. One of Nolan's first big calls was to recommend Wesfarmers load up on bonds to inflation and backed by the Victorian government.
The bonds would deliver CPI plus 5 per cent. Wesfarmers put about 20 per cent of its fund into the bonds. It was a no-brainer - right up until Victoria plunged into recession.

Nolan remembers the events clearly, getting a nervous phone call from Wesfarmerss young chief financial officer Michael Chaney, who wanted to know if Victoria was going broke. Nolan replied that Victoria was never going to go broke, it was too important to the Commonwealth. The economy recovered, and it turned out to be a great investment for Wesfarmers.
"I wasn't interested in running a business that sold comfort. We tried to add value, and that was through asset allocation and manager selection," he says.
Nolan doesn't exactly dismiss passive investing, but he doesn't condone it either; REST has had zero passive equity market exposure since he joined the investment committee.
"I believe in active management, and if you don't do any research I can understand why you would want to do passive management. But if you do the research, then I believe in active management."

Picking managers

Nolan says that when it comes to picking managers, his approach is to look carefully at the managers, the ownership structure and the methodology. If he doesn't gel with the manager or understand their strategy, he won't invest.
It seems to have worked.
The decision to back , for instance, played out well.
"REST had the courage to give David Paradice his first mandate, $30 million or $40 million. It has been very rewarding for both parties."
Paradice, or the small caps king, has grown his funds under management to more than $10 billion and earned himself a place in the Financial Review Rich List.
There have been misses alongside the hits. Greg Perry, who had one of the all-time great records as a fund manager at Colonial First State, was one Nolan passed on.
"You are not going to get everyone right," Nolan says.

Then there was the Collins Street outfit that was guided by the stars. It's unclear whether astronomy or astrology was the key input.
There were two portfolio managers, as Nolan tells it, and one of them had previously made a living selling white goods in Narrandera. He passed on that one too, but was curious to see what they had to say.
Nolan says that picking managers is like picking stocks - if you get six or seven out of 10 right then you are in a happy place. His approach to finding quality stockpickers appears to be driven by some degree of gut feel, even if they are intrinsically numbers driven.
Fundies are human

At JANA he introduced a policy where they would visit fund managers every six weeks. Monthly results were important, and he wanted to see the whites of the fundies' eyes.
Fund managers are human after all, and their performance can be affected by personal issues. Marriage breakdowns. Health problems. He remembers a portfolio manager who went to pieces after his daughter was diagnosed with diabetes.
The human condition accounts for the tendency of investors to get sucked into booms.
Which brings us back to the . In 2000, the four most popular tech stocks were Microsoft, Cisco, Intel and Dell.

By 2007, that list had changed to Apple, Google, Amazon, and Blackberry manufacturer Research in Motion. Today the list is Facebook, Apple, Netflix and Google, and their price-to-earnings ratios are similar to the four horsemen of 2000.
Back in the 1990s, Nolan was growing increasingly concerned about the valuations of another set of tech companies. They were typically in telecommunications, media and technology (TMT).
Dangerous words

Nolan says that after the Japanese boom and bust of the 1980s he thought he'd never see a price-to-earnings ratio of 17 again, and yet at one point the US market was trading on 19 times. He advised the super funds that he was consulting with to position themselves for a crash.
The boom went longer than he expected, and he lost big clients like Kodak as he waited for the correction to come. It eventually did, and Nolan was vindicated.
But don't tell Nolan that "this time it's different".
They are the four most dangerous words in the English language, he says. And if Nolan is right, the next four most dangerous might be Facebook, Apple, Netflix and Google.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Chaney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warakirri Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Nolan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narrandera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paradice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review Rich List</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TMT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglo-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesfarmerss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Mutual</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nolan</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Paradice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesfarmers</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jana</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BARF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlackBerry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John A Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Cain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's State Electricity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freeport McMoRan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kodak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FANG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonial First State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
