<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438552093778835</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/national/us-osprey-may-have-smashed-into-ship-during-landing-off-central-queensland/news-story/781e5e903dfe9bb16531d83b5e800bea</url>
  <title>How the Osprey crash unfolded</title>
  <content>
A US Marine Osprey aircraft is believed to have struck trouble while attempting to land on a transport ship, smashing into its deck and sliding into the ocean off the coast of central Queensland.
Australian Defence Minister Marise Payne confirmed last night that HMAS Melville, a specialist sonar ship, and a crew of Australian Navy divers had been dispatched to assist US salvage operations and to search for the bodies of three passengers missing and presumed dead.
Family members believed one of the missing men was Osprey crew chief Corporal Nathan Ordway, from Wichita, Kansas.
Cpl Ordway's sister Taylor asked people to "please pray for my brother" in a post on the 31st Marine Expeditionary Unit's Facebook page.
A family friend, Heidi Peltzer, said Cpl Ordway was one of the missing men and asked friends to "please pray for his life, his safety, and comfort for the family".
The crash occurred at 4.07pm on Saturday.
The Marine unit, usually based in Okinawa, Japan, had lingered off the coast of the Shoalwater Bay to continue training drills for almost two weeks since the official end of the high-profile Exercise -Talisman Sabre.

Talisman Sabre: USS Bonhomme Richard visit and capability demonstration in Townsville. Footage by Rachel Riley

Talisman Sabre: USS Bonhomme Richard visit and capability demonstration
It's understood the controversial V-22 Osprey, , was flying from the amphibious assault ship the USS Bonhomme Richard to the transport dock ship the USS Green Bay.
On approach to the Green Bay, the Osprey slammed into the flight deck and then slid into the water.
It is not believed weather contributed to the accident.
Most of the 26 people on board were rescued and -uninjured. One Marine was taken to Rockhampton with a broken leg.
"The circumstances of the mishap are currently under investigation," a statement by the Marine Corps Camp Butler in Okinawa said.
By noon yesterday, US search-and-rescue efforts were suspended and operations shifted to "a recovery" effort focused on an area about 25 nautical miles (33km) off the coast, between Cape Manifold and Cape Clinton, north of Yeppoon. Water depth in the area is about 50m.
"The transition comes after teams led continuous sustained search efforts supported by aircraft and ships," the statement said.
US President Donald Trump and Australian Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull were yesterday briefed about the incident.
Defence Minister Marise Payne last night confirmed the Australian Defence Force would support the recovery efforts, which could continue for several months.
"A number of (ADF) assets are involved in supporting the US-led recovery operation," Ms Payne said.
"One of the Royal Australian Navy's survey ships, HMAS Melville, is currently en route to the search area from the ship's home port of Cairns.

Minister for Urban Infrastructure Paul Fletcher on June 29 welcomed US troops to Australia for the two allies' biggest joint military exercise, Talisman Saber. Speaking onboard the USS Bonhomme Richard amphibious assault ship docked in Sydney, Fletcher said the biennial exercise was important for the two militaries to test their systems and demonstrate to the world the resources they have committed to self-defence. "This tradition of our two militaries working together is long established, we have fought together in many wars, our alliance is very deep and based on shared values," Fletcher said. About 30,000 American and Australian service members were to part in the months-long exercise, mostly in the Shoalwater Bay Training Area, near Rockhampton in central Queensland, according to the Australian Department of Defence. There will also be activity in the Mount Bundy Training Area south of Darwin, and military bases in the US. Twenty-one ships and 200 aircraft were to take part in the warfighting scenario, according to a US Army press release. Credit: YouTube/Paul Fletcher MP via Storyful

Joint US-Australia Military Exercise Talisman Saber Kicks Off in Sydney. Credit - YouTube/Paul Fletcher MP via Storyful
A Navy Clearance Diving team is also preparing to move via a Royal Australian Air Force C130J Hercules aircraft to the Shoalwater Bay Training Area.
"Australian Army aviation assets are at short notice readiness to support any further requirements."
Ms Payne warned the recovery would be complex.
"The incident is currently being investigated by US authorities and Australia will assist in these investigations where appropriate."
CRASH MAKES HEADLINES AROUND THE WORLD
THE crash has made headlines around the world, not only in the United States but Japan as well.
Japanese Defence Minister -Itsunori Onodera yesterday reportedly said his country would ask the United States Government about the cause of the accident and the reliability of the notorious Osprey.
According to Japanese media outlet NHK, he also -reportedly encouraged the US to consider not flying the Ospreys in Japan, following Saturday's crash, until a satisfactory explanation came to light.
Japan had previously made calls for the aircraft to be grounded after a crash off the coast of Okinawa in December last year.
Five crew members were caught up in that incident, with two reportedly injured.
- Additional reporting by Michael Wray and Peter Michael
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Infrastructure Paul Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V-22 Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube/Paul Fletcher MP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Expeditionary Unit's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NHK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Bonhomme Richard</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wichita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Bundy Training Area</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talisman Saber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marines Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Department of Defence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalwater Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Australia Military Exercise Talisman Saber Kicks Off</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Corps Camp Butler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Air Force C-130J Hercules</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporal Nathan Ordway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cpl Ordway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-one</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Itsunori Onodera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Payne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Minister Marise Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Wray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Green Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defense Minister Marise Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalwater Bay Training Area</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Melville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Manifold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeppoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okinawa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sabre</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kansas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAKES HEADLINES AROUND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidi Peltzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese Defense Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navy Clearance Diving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
