<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439037425087573</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/how-cba-recruited-austrac-executives-20170806-gxqdxj</url>
  <title>How CBA recruited AUSTRAC executives </title>
  <content>
The Australian Prudential Regulation Authority gave a presentation to the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision in October 2001 titled Money laundering, a risk management issue. It said supervisors globally were increasingly recognising the importance of banks putting in place controls and procedures to ensure they knew their customers.
It went on to say "sound KYC [know your customers] procedures must be seen as a critical element in the effective management of banking risks". Without proper due diligence, it warned that banks could become subject to reputational, operational, legal and concentration risks, which could result in significant financial cost.
Almost 16 years later, by financial intelligence agency AUSTRAC that alleges CBA's controls and procedures were not effective. In some cases it enabled customers to be anonymous and create fake names, which enabled drug dealers, organised crime syndicates and terrorists to launder and transfer money overseas.
by failing to report more than 50,000 deposits over a certain size in its network of more than 500 Intelligent Deposit Machines (IDMs), which it rolled out in 2012. It also alleges it failed in its obligations to monitor hundreds of thousands of accounts between 2012 and 2016.

Given the seriousness of the allegations, including "serious and systemic non-compliance" at a time when terrorist threats are a reality, it is not hard to imagine APRA and ASIC crawling all over the bank to ensure this doesn't happen again. Neither regulator would comment, nor would CBA.

Root cause analysis

As AUSTRAC's acting chief executive Peter Clark said: "The effect of CommBank's conduct in this matter has exposed the Australian community to serious and ongoing financial crime."
The Australian Financial Review can reveal that, in 2015, about the time CBA took steps to assess money laundering or terrorism finance risks posed by its IDMs, it went on a recruitment drive, hiring people from AUSTRAC into roles that directly related to money laundering and terrorism finance.
It is understood that in April 2015, AUSTRAC made inquiries about some suspicious accounts and, during that discussion, CBA realised there might be a problem with its suspicious matter reporting and decided to launch a root cause analysis.

It was then it realised there was a failure in the IDM system relating to Threshold Transaction Reports (when someone deposits $10,000, a report should automatically be generated and sent to AUSTRAC) due to a coding error, which it immediately fixed. That coding error dates back to late 2012.
It immediately told AUSTRAC of the problem. About that time it was also getting queries from the AFP about some suspicious transactions relating to criminals.
It was then CBA decided to beef up its capabilities in the area and went on a hiring spree, poaching at least four staff from AUSTRAC.
Cluster of departures

Some of the appointments include the general manager of compliance who worked at AUSTRAC from 2007 until April 2015. In April, she moved to another big four bank.
CBA poached an AUSTRAC director in August 2015 who had worked at AUSTRAC for five years as a front-line director regulating anti-money laundering and counter-terrorism financing across a number of entities, including the banks. He left CBA in April this year.
The bank also hired AUSTRAC's anti-money laundering/counter-terrorism finance senior manager, enforcement, as head of financial crime policy and regulatory engagement, as well as the regulator's anti-money laundering/counter-terrorism finance manager, compliance.
AUSTRAC refused to comment on the cluster of departures to CBA at a critical time in its investigation. Each of the four individuals were contacted for comment but either failed to respond or passed the query onto CBA.

Banks hiring regulators isn't unusual. There is a revolving door of gamekeepers turned poachers who have left ASIC and APRA for the higher paying jobs in the banking sector. Sometimes it goes the other way. Indeed, in April this year AUSTRAC boss Paul Jevtovic announced his resignation to join HSBC as head of financial crime threat mitigation, Asia Pacific region.
Revolving door

Some believe the revolving door strengthens the industry, while others believe it can create conflicts of interest or regulatory capture. Andy Schmulow, a senior law lecturer at the University of Western Australia, who had a short stint working at APRA in 2013, says his sense is the revolving door with ASIC and the banks has facilitated regulatory capture. "Whether this was the intention with recruiting staff from AUSTRAC I don't know. But if it was, it has failed spectacularly."
In 2015, the Swiss watchdog Finma introduced rules preventing senior staff working for a company they were responsible for overseeing within 12 months of leaving the regulator.

Whatever the case, the knowledge of how AUSTRAC works, the relationships, contacts and expertise in the area is undoubtedly an attractive skill set for the private sector. How effective that may be depends on the systems it has in place, as was so presciently outlined to the industry by APRA in 2001.
But it also helps to know what was going on inside CBA at the time. In 2013 and 2014, one division of the bank, its financial planning arm, was in crisis mode as a powerful Senate inquiry investigated rampant and systemic misconduct. In June 2014 it recommended CBA face a royal commission to investigate fraud, forgery and allegations of a management cover-up inside its financial planning arm.
Unethical tactics

About the same period, its life insurance division was dealing with its own issues after its chief medical officer Benjamin Koh informed independent CommInsure directors of an "improper state of affairs" going on inside the insurer in November 2014, including sick and dying people deprived of their entitlements by scandalous and unethical tactics.
Against this backdrop, AUSTRAC's statement of claim alleges that, between October 2012 and September 2016, CBA didn't comply with the provisions of its transaction monitoring program in respect to 778,370 accounts, known as "affected accounts". It says: "None of those accounts were subject to transaction monitoring at the account level at various times, and some were not subject to customer level transaction monitoring."
At the micro level, the impact of failing to monitor accounts was profound. One of the more shocking allegations relates to a notice issued by the AFP on May 18, 2015, requesting information in respect to an account in order to proceed with an investigation relating to 16 suspicious accounts. "No customer due diligence was carried out in response to this request," the statement says.
CBA said in a statement that, "while we may have a different view to AUSTRAC on some elements of the case, our responses should be considered with respect for AUSTRAC's role while balancing the desire for greater information by our people, shareholders, customers and the community".
Time for a change at the top

A growing number of investors, bankers and former bankers are saying it is time for a change at the top of the bank.
There is even speculation the board has already begun canvassing names. CBA declined to respond.
The seriousness of the allegations raises questions of whether CBA should have informed the ASX under listing rules obligations when it became aware of the AUSTRAC legal proceedings.
It prompted one litigation funder to suggest a class action wouldn't be out of the question if the share price continued to fall. On Friday, CBA's share price fell 3.8 per cent, equivalent to $5 billion of its market value.
CBA says, in an organisation as large as the bank, mistakes can be made and "we recognise that our scale means these can have a big impact".
"We have increased investment in people and processes as well as embarked on a program to lift our capability to meet the growing complexity in this area," it says.
It is right. AUSTRAC's allegations paint a disturbing picture of not just a systems issue that was allowed to continue for a number of years but also a failure to act quickly even when alerts were provided by the police. Whether this was laziness, process, cultural or something else will become clearer when the defence is filed and the case plays out. But for now the statement of claim suggests wide-scale, systemic, cultural and operational dysfunction.
It begs the question: when is enough, enough?

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basel Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IDM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KYC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Koh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Threshold Transaction Reports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>20</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2001</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Schmulow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APRA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jevtovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prudential Regulation Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Western</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDMS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banking Supervision</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2015</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommInsure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommBank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
