<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439119029467312</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/small-business/smallbiz-marketing/free-postcards-sold-pat-mackle-finds-buyer-for-avant-card-in-sam-dellaglio-20170803-gxomlf.html</url>
  <title>Postcard queen Pat Mackle finds buyers for Avant Card</title>
  <content>
Free postcard business Avant Card has been rescued by a Melbourne businessman.
Media company founder Sam Dell'Aglio has swooped in and purchased Avant Card collateral, client lists and distribution rights in three states, announcing plans to resurrect the free postcard business under a new name.Photo: Justin McManus
Last month, Avant Card founder Pat Mackle  which provides free postcards in cafes, bars, cinemas, theatres, libraries, universities and galleries around Australia.
But Dell'Aglio has confirmed he will bring Avant Card into his stable of out-of-home media options, known as Mr Moto. He has operated in the out-of-home space for 32 years.Photo: Supplied
From Avant Card to Drawcard

The Avant Card purchase includes about 1000 display stands, client lists and distribution rights in Sydney, Melbourne and Brisbane. Dell'Aglio has renamed the postcard business Drawcard, and is confident he can breathe new life into the once iconic national out-of-home business.
The sale comes despite the founder of the national postcard design, printing and distribution firm describing the postcard business as running its course. Avant Card founder Pat Mackle blamed falling sales and rising print costs for forcing the closure of the business, saying the explosion in digital offerings have also stolen market share from its biggest customer base - art and culture, festivals, events and exhibitions - in the last two years.

"The business in its current format wasn't sustainable, but we had always hoped to be able to sell the displays and local client lists to buyers in each state. Being able to achieve this has taken some of the pressure off as we wind up the business.
"I'm offering my full support in the handover and transition phase. It's a very exciting outcome for Avant Card, and one that I'm wholeheartedly behind."Photo: Barry Newberry
Drawing on economies of scale

Dell'Aglio has no qualms about purchasing a business the founder struggled to keep afloat financially, saying economies of scale will make Drawcard financially viable. He confirmed that campaign prices will be 25 per cent less than when the business was under Mackle's reign.
"I can run the same postcard offering for less because I've already got the warehousing, distribution infrastructure and staff, which will dramatically reduce overheads."Photo: Justin McManus
Postcards have always been a big part of Mr Moto's offering, though it also prints cafe posters, other larger format collateral and has a large digital screen network available to roll-out.
"This purchase means we can offer greater campaign coverage, providing better integrated options for clients to boost their out-of-home campaigns. We're really looking forward to carrying on the postcard culture in Australia."
There's been such an outcry from the public about the closure of Avant. We're still receiving letters from the public every day who don't want to see us go.
Pat Mackle

The sale price is undisclosed with Avant Card founder Pat Mackle breaking the business down into state-based display networks and client lists.
Mackle says displays and local state-specific client lists were purchased by Spy in Canberra, The Poster Girls in Perth and Passing Out Distribution in Adelaide. Mr Moto purchased Brisbane, Melbourne and Sydney displays. Hobart was the only state not to produce a buyer.
"Given that I've broke the company down into pieces, I decided that the business name should end with me. And each purchaser in each state has plans to name the business something different anyway."
Mackle says Avant Card could have limped on a bit longer, a look at broader industry trends and the company's financial forecasting was the nail in the coffin. Staff received all redundancy entitlements, totalling nearly $300,000. The Sydney office is currently being wound down.
Never-ending costs

Mackle says Avant Card's Sydney offices have been sold for $2.7 million, but admits the costs involved in winding up the business are never-ending.
"We've got a lease over our Brisbane office until early next year and contracted internet and phone costs we're unable to get out of, which all adds up."
She launched Avant Card in 1992 after noticing free postcards being used as promotional material in cafes during a trip to Europe. Revenues grew to $3.2 million last financial year, though attempts to diversify into mini-magazines and street magazines weren't working, she says.
"There's been such an outcry from the public about the closure of Avant. We're still receiving letters from the public every day who don't want to see us go."
Mackle plans to take a break for a couple of months before investigating growth opportunities in her husband's Victorian eco-store. "I'm confident that I can sell anything that I'm passionate about. It's in my blood."
Follow MySmallBusiness on ,  and .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avant</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aglio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poster Girls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin McManus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avant Card's Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Passing Out Distribution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Newberry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MySmallBusiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Moto</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avant Card</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Mackle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
