<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438560683713488</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/tarzans-selfless-act-doesnt-pay/3209418/</url>
  <title>Selfless act doesn't pay off for Toowoomba's Tarzan</title>
  <content>
MARK 'Tarzan' Herlaar gave away the hidden immunity idol that he found in Samoa, and in the end that choice cost him his place in the game.

However Herlaar said he doesn't regret giving the idol to his closet ally in Samoa - Victorian doctor Tessa O'Halloran - but he does regret letting player AK Knight know about it.

"If I have one regret, it was telling bloody AK,' he said.

"In hindsight, which is easy to say, myself and Tess could have kept that to ourselves.

"I guess it's just one of those things."

Herlaar had hoped to get Knight to switch and blindside his alliance on the Samatau tribe, but in the end the most talked about player on Australian Survivor, decided not to switch.

In Herlaar's selfless move in giving O'Halloran the idol saved her - she received give votes, Herlaar received three, and Lockie, one vote.

When O'Halloran played the immunity idol, that Herlaar gave her, he ran out of luck and he was sent packing.

In an unusual move, Herlaar also voted for O'Halloran, but he said he knew he was going home anyway, and he looked at his vote in a different way.

"I did vote for her, but I only vote for her as a vote of confidence," he said.

"I know that she couldn't go home, and I knew I was destined to go home, unless everybody voted for Lockie, and that wasn't going to happen.

"It didn't matter."

Despite getting voted off Australian Survivor before the merge, the Gehan lime farmer described his Australian Survivor experience as "incredible."

He said he didn't mind getting voted out, and was very happy how he handled himself.

"Jonathan said to me at the end, that I looked like I was at peace, and I was," he said.

"I'm always a peace, I let the circumstances determine by identity.

"I had a ball."

He hopes his friend O'Halloran will win Australian Survivor, and he also praised his nemesis, South Australian

"When he got rid of Adam (poker player Adam Parkin), I congratulated him on that.

"I said to him, well played, I never saw that coming.

"He really knows the game, he is a master of the game.

"The man is very clever, and I take my hat of to him.

"I love him, but he is forever stabbing people in the back."

Australian Survivor is on air again tomorrow on Channel 10 from 7.30pm.
Nearly 4000 people attend concert at stadium
Rescue helicopter, SES, firies on scene at Mt Beerwah for rescue
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
Netflix health doco slammed for scaremongering, 'cherrypicking' data
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Do you own a discontinued iPod Nano or iPod Shuffle?
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herlaar</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gehan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba's Tarzan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarzan' Herlaar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Nano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tessa O'Halloran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod Shuffle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Halloran</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AK Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samatau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Parkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TESS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
