<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438835561622931</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:14</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/fix-it-and-hurry-japan-posts-orders-for-new-toll-ceo-michael-byrne-20170802-gxnti1</url>
  <title>'Fix it and hurry': Japan Post's orders for new Toll CEO Michael Byrne</title>
  <content>
New Toll Group chief executive Michael Byrne is confident he can return the trucking company to profitability after being instructed by owners Japan Post to "fix it and hurry".
The $6.5 billion acquisition of Toll by Japan Post in 2015 has been a financial disaster for the Japanese group, which  on its Australian investment in fiscal 2017, forcing it into a $477 million net loss. 
Japan Post executive Taneki Ono flew to Melbourne in July to explain the importance of turning around Toll to 150 senior executives from around the world at a leadership conference, including Japan's need to find homes for more than 100,000 people who remain displaced six years after the 2011 earthquake and tsunami, which triggered a meltdown of the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant.
"We have a great moral obligation to help relieve those people of their suffering," Mr Byrne told The Australian Financial Review in his first interview since starting as CEO on January 1, when he turned up to the office while the rest of Australia celebrated New Year's Day. "That has now been explained deeply to the Toll management."

The Japanese government sold 20 per cent of its stake in Japan Post to the public in late 2015 after the Toll takeover, partially to raise money to rebuild cities and towns devastated by the tsunami. But plans to sell more shares to the public  by the poor performance of Japan Post's stock, which is stuck at its float price of ¥1400.

Mr Byrne won't disclose how much money Toll lost in 2017, say only that it was "a lot". Toll posted an operating profit of $69 million in the 12 months to March but recorded an overall loss due to impairments and adjustments to its balance sheet.
The 52-year old Mr Byrne was tapped by new Toll chairman John Mullen in mid-December after former chairman Ray Horsburgh and former CEO Brian Kruger were sent packing.
"I was in Europe in holidays and got asked to go to Japan for the day," Mr Byrne recalled. By the end of the day, after being interviewed by five of Japan Post's most senior people, he had the job. "They didn't muck around."
Mr Byrne and Mr Mullen already knew each other well. Mr Byrne, who ran family-owned trucking group Linfox between 2005 and 2014, was a client of ports and rail group Asciano, which Mr Mullen ran between 2011 and 2016.

"John's a lovely man, very charismatic, very statesmanlike," said Mr Byrne. "They call us yin and yang - I'm the operator and the blunt edge."
Mr Byrne said that even though the Japanese are  and are now more engaged in developing its strategy, they remain "extremely supportive" of the Australian group, approving capital investments into the business. 
"If you boil down probably 1000 pages of strategy, it's fix it and hurry and get back to what we're supposed to be doing - which is growing a world-class business."
Mr Byrne hasn't wasted time. Some 2000 jobs - about half of them overseas - including 1000 management jobs are going, with the cuts expected to be completed at the end of August. The top management team is being restructured, with a new global chief financial officer, to be based in Melbourne, and a new global head of forwarding, to be based in Singapore, due to be announced this month.

Toll's Hong Kong office is being closed, with people moved to Singapore, where Toll has 2500 employees. Businesses than generate more than half of Toll's $8 billion in annual revenues will be run out of Singapore, where it is building
Mr Byrne wants to focus Toll's operations on Asia, Oceania and North America, and in Africa for the long term. But he plans to withdraw from countries in war zones as well as parts of Europe, and will avoid Central and South America. 
Focus on human capital

Mr Byrne believes Toll's business "lost its way" by expanding into too many countries, noting that the 113 acquisitions made under former management over a dozen years were , leading to complaints from customers. Instead of five divisions and 24 business units, Toll now has three divisions and 11 units. 

And instead of a "world domination strategy", Mr Byrne plans to run the core business hard, focusing on improving IT systems and strengthening Toll's "human capital" with a graduate trainee program to make its 44,000-strong workforce more diverse. About half of this year's 15 graduates are women, and half have English as a second language. The program is expected to double in size next year and be more international, and Toll is also training 18 young people that Japan Post have sent to Australia.
The changes are already paying off - Toll had three months of consecutive year-on-year revenue growth for the first time in three years, in April, May and June.
Mr Byrne has met with 45 of Toll's top 50 customers, who have demanded better technology, including better data security. In March, Toll's board approved six new technology programs, with the company spending an additional $420 million during the next 2 1/2 years on top of the $336 million it already spends annually on IT.
It plans to upgrade about 11,000 hand-held electronic PDAs (personal digital assistants), which use a variety of hardware and software, and create one global "MyToll" website where people can track the location of their goods and parcels.

Toll's chief information officer, Francoise Russo, goes to Japan every two months to swap technology ideas with Japan Post. "We need to learn from each other, we have particular skills in certain things - fleet and equipment and heavy assets - they have other skills, particularly in last-mile delivery and customer B2C." Mr Byrne makes about 10 trips annually to Japan, including attending four two-day board meetings every year.
Toll's 37,000 customers, which include big retailers like Woolworths and Coles as well the Australian and Singaporean governments, have higher expectations than they did in the past, Mr Byrne says. "The days are long gone where supply chain was seen as a back door to the escape hatch where someone went if they weren't really good doing something else." 
The imminent arrival of US retail giant Amazon in Australia is "a good thing", Mr Byrne added. "It's changed the conversation and it's made people aware that they need to adapt.
"We're in a semi-unique position - I have to help all my customers adapt and be agile to compete with a new competitor because we have such a big retail business ... and Amazon are in different parts of the world are our customer, so I also have to help them."
Toll, like other logistics operators, is in talks with Amazon about providing services to the retail group in Australia but "no decisions have been made", Mr Byrne said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toll's $8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Horsburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MyToll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francoise Russo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singaporeans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan Post</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oceania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Brian Kruger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mullen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asciano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Byrne</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Mullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toll CEO Michael Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linfox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Year's Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Toll Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fukushima Daiichi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B2C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PDAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taneki Ono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
