<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438822676720861</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/reliance-rail-asks-court-to-get-2b-restructure-back-on-track-20170804-gxpu3x</url>
  <title>Reliance Rail asks court to get $2b restructure back on track </title>
  <content>
Reliance Rail's $2 billion rebirth has hit a snag.
Three months after AMP Capital and Downer EDI-owned Reliance Rail took a recapitalisation and refinancing proposal to the NSW government, the deal is no closer to being done.
The latest problem is two existing lenders - European financial institutions Dexia and FMS Wertmanagement - who are senior bondholders and do not want to be repaid early.
They argue that early repayment would see them suffer a material loss, which is believed to relate to upstream hedges which were taken out to cover the bonds and would incur a break fee should they be closed out early.

Reliance Rail, advised by Gilbert + Tobin and RBC Capital Markets, is set to take matters into its own hands this week.

It is seeking a ruling from the NSW Supreme Court to allow it to push ahead with the deal, without the approval of existing lenders such as Dexia, FMS or anyone else in the syndicate. The hearing starts on Monday. 
Dexia and FMS are working together and have also tapped Herbert Smith Freehills for advice. There have already been numerous legal letters between the sides, according to documents before the court.
Should Reliance Rail be successful, it would be expected to pull the trigger on its long-awaited proposal, pending support from the NSW government.
NSW is a key counterparty to the contract and has a right to purchase the project for $175 million in 2018, should Reliance Rail be refinanced successfully.

which landed in the government's office on May 5 this year.
The most likely deal is where at least one of Reliance Rail's existing investors, such as AMP Capital, buys the government's option for $175 million or more, increases its own stake in the trains project and secures a new debt package.
Reliance Rail's owners and credit wrappers have been keen to push ahead with a deal for much of the past year, seeking to have the situation sorted well ahead of the debt maturity date.
The first tranche of debt is due in September 2018, with the rest due one year later. Reliance Rail itself is said to be performing well, and is likely to attract interest from new equity and debt investors should it go to market as expected.

Most parties involved in the situation realise that given the complicated capital structure, involving senior and junior bonds and two credit wrappers, it will take considerable time to get all the necessary approvals and paperwork done. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herbert Smith Freehills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reliance Rail</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downer EDI-owned Reliance Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP Capital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dexia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rail's $2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FMS Wertmanagement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FMS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBC Capital Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
