<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438814086786209</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/gambling/tabcorp-could-sell-luxbet-20170805-gxq6xe</url>
  <title>Tabcorp could sell Luxbet</title>
  <content>
Tabcorp could look to sell or even close its Luxbet wagering business as its  looms.
Luxbet, which made an earnings before interest and tax loss of $13 million, is under review by Tabcorp management who have previously restricted it from taking market share from its existing TAB brand.
But it could be attractive to an overseas corporate bookmaker given Luxbet has a group of high-yielding customers connected to the horse racing industry and may fetch Tabcorp $50-100 should it be sold.
Tabcorp chief executive David Attenborough said Luxbet was a good business but it was effectively on "starvation rations" given it does not compete against TAB.

"We've got the strategic review and we will see what we do after that. But it has been partially handcuffed and going into the Tatts combination it could be handcuffed some more."

Mr Attenborough would not be drawn on whether Tabcorp would sell the business.
​Tabcorp established Luxbet in late 2008 as a Northern Territory-licensed venture to compete with other corporate bookmakers also operating from Darwin and allow punters to bet on non-racing and sport competitions such as entertainment events and elections.
The business grew steadily, taking bets on sports and racing and at one stage having an estimated 10 per cent market share of the corporate bookmaker market.
Advertising restrictions

But more recently it has been restricted from advertising widely in NSW and Victoria, where Tabcorp's existing TAB wagering arm had exclusive retail betting licences and a strong market positing for its digital website and app services.
That restriction would presumably be widened to the Tatts states such as Queensland and South Australia, where the TAB brand will be rolled out to replace Tatts' Ubet should the mooted merger between Tabcorp and Tatts be finally ratified later this year.
The deal is subject to an appeal by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission and rival corporate bookmaker CrownBet, 
A full bench of the Federal Court will hear both the ACCC's and CrownBet's applications on August 28 and 29.

Mr Attenborough said when releasing Tabcorp's full-year financial results that the main priority for the remainder of the year would be the Tatts merger, a scheme of arrangement for which would be voted on by Tatts shareholders in October should the Federal Court not block the deal.
Tabcorp will also be buoyed by pending changes to the Interactive Gambling Act that will make it tougher for the mostly foreign-owned and NT-registered corporate bookmakers to compete with it.
The corporate bookmakers say several measures will hit their profits hard and make their business less viable, including a mooted ban on television advertising during live sport, a point of consumption tax on betting in South Australia and an end to credit betting.
William Hill, headed in Australia by Tom Waterhouse, has said about 30 per cent of its business is reliant on credit betting while CrownBet and SportsBet have already moved to lessen the promotion of South Australian racing after the introduction of the tax on July 1.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Waterhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Attenborough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sportsbet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrownBet</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT-registered</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luxbet</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatts' Ubet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory-licensed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Interactive Gambling Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Attenborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
