<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438814086786197</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836837/brown-calls-for-nrl-to-enforce-salary-cap/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Brown calls for NRL to enforce salary cap</title>
  <content>
Outspoken Newcastle coach Nathan Brown has dared the NRL to "do the right thing" and force clubs who have overspent the yet-to-be-confirmed salary cap to shed players.

Brown suggests teams who have overspent as a result of uncertainty over the exact cap for next year are just using it as an excuse for their recklessness.

PLEA: Knights coach Nathan Brown.
"Everyone got the email saying you have to work off $9.1 million and if you don't it's your responsibility," Brown told Triple M on Sunday.

"Some went over it and took a chance ... some like us stayed under it in the hope that players would come along.

"Let's hope our friends at the NRL hold their nerve and make them go under it and don't allow something like a grandfather rule.

"Those that put the market into a spin have to pay the price."
He confirmed the Knights were "certainly looking at clubs who are rumoured to be over the cap" in their recruitment plans.

"We had some interest in James Graham some time ago but he wanted to stay at Canterbury and they didn't want to let him go," Brown said.

"If the NRL do the right thing and make them go under the cap, then they might have to let a player go."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
