<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439071784826304</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/this-would-be-a-boost-to-employment/news-story/42842e8d5ad1e454df60a4630511edea</url>
  <title>Local scrap metal on track for Adani mine</title>
  <content>
SCRAP steel from a Townsville business may be used in construction of Adani's planned Galilee Basin rail line, after a Queensland company signed a Letter of Award with the Indian conglomerate.
OneSteel Recycling, which has recently expanded its Townsville branch, is part of the Arrium group which has signed on to supply 53,000 tonnes of steel for the line.
Scrap steel collected by OneSteel Recycling across Australia, including at Townsville, may be used by Arrium in its steel making process.
Glenn Scoble of OneSteel Recycling Townsville said the company was well placed to capitalise on the potential benefits for the community and the company.
"We now have about 50 per cent more room and capacity to expand the business," he said.
"This would be a boost to employment for OneSteel Recycling as well as local contractors and suppliers."
Mr Scoble said the proposed Carmichael coal mine would be a big boost to the local steel recycling industry. OneSteel Recycling Townsville would also be well placed to receive and recycle scrap steel from Adani during the construction stage.
Arrium is in the process of being sold to London-based GFG Alliance. The sale contract is scheduled to be signed at the end of August after a 17-month administration.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galilee Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Letter of Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmichael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Scoble of OneSteel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OneSteel Recycling Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arrium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scoble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OneSteel Recycling</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London-based GFG Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recycling Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
