<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438552093778816</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/horseracing/sheikh-could-rattle-australian-sprinters--if-he-rolls-the-everest-dice-20170805-gxq6gp.html</url>
  <title>Sheikh could rattle Australian sprinters - if he rolls the Everest dice</title>
  <content>
His English trainer, Charlie Hills, describes him as "a speedball".
His jockey, British champion rider Jim Crowley, says he is "a motorbike" - a horse with serious pace and all the gears.Photo: bradleyphotos.com.au
And, if Sheikh Hamdan Al Maktoum is up for the challenge, he just might be a wildcard chance of upsetting the applecart in Australia's richest race, the $10 million Everest at Randwick in three months.
The horse in question is Battaash, who simply galloped his rivals into submission in a group 2 sprint over 1000 metres at Glorious Goodwood over the weekend.

It was a performance that had pundits asking whether the gelded son of Dark Ange was the quickest 1000-metre horse in Europe.
Not yet, said Hills, as he still has to prove himself at the highest level, in group 1 company.

But Battaash's profile suggests he could be the one to watch in the championship sprints in the second half of the European season - and further afield if the Shadwell Stud boss Sheikh Hamdan wants to seek a slot in the Everest.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Asked moments after Battaash had seen off group 1 winners Profitable (Kings Stand Stakes in 2016) and Marsha (Prix de l'Abbeye de Longchamp last year) if he knew about the riches on offer at Randwick, Hills' eyes lit up.Photo: bradleyphotos.com.au
"I am very well aware of it," he said.
"I have to speak to Sheikh Hamdan. But certainly we would ... I mean he's a gelding, so I wouldn't be afraid to travel, but it's all up to Sheikh Hamdan."
The Australian sprinters are renowned for being the fastest in the world. Would Hills have reservations about even thinking of a tilt against the likes of Chautauqua in his own backyard?
"He's got plenty of speed, I wouldn't worry about that," the young trainer shot back.
Just how much speed Battaash has was evident from the race time for the King George V Stakes. 
The track had been subjected to a deluge earlier in the week and was still riding good to soft when Battaash ran. Nevertheless he still managed to post a time of 58.51 seconds, which was some 1.5 seconds quicker than the median time for all races run over the 1000 metres at Goodwood. 
On his previous start at Sandown Battaash had also returned impressive figures, setting a new course record for the 1000 metres at the London track.
While the Everest is on the radar there are other more immediate priorities. And Hills, son of legendary English trainer Barry Hills, stressed that his owner would have the ultimate say on the horse's future.
"Maybe [Australia could be considered]. I mean the plan at the moment would be to go to the Nunthorpe (a group 1 sprint at York later in August where he would be up against American trainer Wesley Ward's flying filly Lady Aurelia, owned by Coolmore).
"He will have an entry in the Breeders Cup [in the US] as well and there is the Abbaye [at Longchamp on Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe day[. But it's all to do with Sheikh Hamdan. It will be his decision."
His jockey won the UK riders Premiership on the flat last year and was blown away by the three-year-old's performance.
"I don't think I've ridden a better sprinter. It's like riding a motorbike up the gallops. There's still plenty left in the tank," Crowley said after his partner eased down for a two-and-a-quarter length victory.
"He is very fast, and although you have to keep an eye on him in the race, he does everything and takes you into it lovely. I could not believe how well I was going ... he just has so much natural speed."
Whether he comes this year or perhaps next, Battaash is likely to set the standard for European sprinters for seasons to come.
He is unusual for a European group 1 horse because he is a gelding, so can race for years, providing a benchmark against which succeeding generations can be judged.
Hills certainly should know where he stands with Battaash, having trained the champion sprinter of 2015, Muharrar, who won, among other races, the group 1 Commonwealth Cup at Royal Ascot, the July Cup and the British Champions Series Sprint final.
Could he compare the two? Does Battaash match his older former stable companion for talent?
"It looks that way for sure now. This horse is a serious speedball."
The key to Battaash's transformation this season has been a gelding operation.
He was strongly fancied for a two-year-old race at Royal Ascot last year but misbehaved in the barriers and ran disappointingly. He then failed to win in three subsequent starts so the ultimate gear change took place - with devastating results.
"He seemed to lose it that day and he was very unruly in the stalls so we got together and decided to have him gelded during the winter. Since then he has improved so much," Hills declared. 
That's an understatement.
If plans were changed and Australia, rather than America, became a target, then Battaash would certainly look to be a player.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hills</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dark Ange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Longchamp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nunthorpe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glorious Goodwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheikh Hamdan Al Maktoum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does Battaash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chautauqua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Champions Series Sprint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muharrar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandown Battaash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Crowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George V Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Ascot</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbaye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battaash</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheikh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Stand Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Aurelia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbeye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triomphe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breeders' Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marsha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheikh Hamdan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesley Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shadwell Stud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
