<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438723892472356</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/ghost-stories-from-residents-of-brisbanes-cemeteries-rise-from-the-dead-20170730-gxls8u.html</url>
  <title>Brisbane's ghosts: Was this conman Jack The Ripper?</title>
  <content>
The ghosts of Brisbane's past have been brought back to life in a new book, which looks into the stories of those buried under the tombstones in cemeteries across the region.
Among the ghost stories in the Brisbane edition of Grave Tales is English conman Walter Thomas Porriott, who is accused of being Jack the Ripper - the man responsible for a series of gruesome murders in Whitechapel, London.Photo: Supplied
The horrific killings took place between August and November in 1888 in east London. While the murders of 11 women over several decades have been attributed to the serial killer, London police believe only five of the deaths during the three-month period were in fact connected to Jack the Ripper.
The five victims were all prostitutes and mutilated to different extents, with the most brutal killing involving a woman's body parts being severed and rearranged.Photo: Supplied
Mr Porriot, who was , was suggested to be the man behind Jack the Ripper by his great-grandson, Steven Wilson, in 1997.
Mr Wilson believed his great-grandfather was the infamous murderer because he lived in Limestone, which was near Whitechapel in Eastern London, during the killings.

He also said that his great-grandfather had written about having a hatred of prostitutes and Mr Wilson thought he could see handwriting similarities between his great-grandfather and a letter allegedly sent by Jack the Ripper to a London newspaper during the killing spree.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The full story of Mr Porriot has been documented in the Brisbane edition of Grave Tales, which explores his fraudulent activities, including stealing money from women and working as a doctor despite having barely any medical knowledge.Photo: National Library of Australia
The book is written by Helen Goltz and Chris Adams, both professional journalists, and explores plenty of other interesting historical figures who were buried across Brisbane.
Case studies include the , Australia's greatest World War I sniper, the only woman to be hanged in the state, as well as two people who perished on the Pearl ferry during the worst disaster on the Brisbane River. Photo: Supplied
Adams said the book took six months to research and produce and used history to tell interesting stories.
"Half of the book features the stories of people who didn't want to come to Brisbane, and the other half documents everyday people involved in non-everyday events which happened in Brisbane," he said.
Adams said he personally was sceptical of Mr Porriot being Jack the Ripper, but it was possible.
"I think it's probably unlikely, but it's been nearly 130 years and so many people have been linked that it's definitely a possibility," he said.
"He was there at the right time and expressed his pathological hatred for prostitutes."
The Jack the Ripper investigation saw more than 2000 people interviewed, 300 investigated and 80 detained, yet to this day the identity of the serial killer remains a mystery.
.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Porriot</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitechapel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ripper</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Goltz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Library of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Thomas Porriott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grave Tales</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
