<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439076079793676</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-union/brumbies/canberra-star-louise-burrows-gets-dream-womens-world-cup-call-up-for-wallaroos-20170805-gxq3wa.html</url>
  <title>'Is this a dream?' Burrows gets lifeline for fourth World Cup after SOS from Wallaroos</title>
  <content>
Canberra rugby star Louise Burrows thought she was dreaming when she woke up to an SOS from the Wallaroos and a chance to revive her World Cup fairytale.
But the 39-year-old will fly to Ireland on Monday morning to play at her fourth women's World Cup after the Wallaroos were hit by injuries just days before the tournament.Photo: Jay Cronan
Mother-of-two Burrows hastily organised time away from her job as a teacher at Canberra Girls Grammar after getting the call she thought may never come.
The veteran is regarded as the best set-piece hooker in Australian women's rugby but was a controversial omission from the initial Wallaroos squad in June.

, but those painful tears fuelled her mission to keep training in the hope of being recalled.
That call came at 7.30am on Saturday and Burrows packed her bags for a remarkable fourth World Cup 16 years after starting her international career.

"I saw two missed calls on my phone when I woke up and I didn't know what was going on. I called back and I had to say to [Wallaroos coach Scott Allen], 'I've just woken up, is this a dream?'," Burrows said with a grin.
"You never wish injuries on anyone and I feel for the girls who have been injured. I wanted to be ready if they needed me and I'm confident going over there.
"I'm pinching myself a little bit. I've had my heart set on this for the past four years, I've made so many sacrifices and so many people have been on this journey with me.
"To get this opportunity, it's something I'm very thankful for."
Burrows was on standby for any front-row injuries and continued a training program at Brumbies headquarters.
The Wallaroos will start their campaign against hosts Ireland Thursday, meaning Burrows could walk off the plane and into the game-day squad for the World Cup opener.
The Wallaroos will also play France and Japan in the pool stages as they set their sights on a top-four finish.
Burrows is keen to play beyond the World Cup and even started setting her sights on the next tournament in 2021 after missing Wallaroos selection.
But strong results in Ireland would be a perfect way to cap her international career, which started when she made her debut against England in 2001.
But the Canberra Royals star believes she still has plenty to offer the Wallaroos as a late call up and is determined to make an impact.
"I'm really thankful I had been keeping positive and that has helped me to maintain that motivation," Burrows said.
"There have been days where it's been difficult. When the team flew out to Ireland and landed, it hit home that I wasn't with them.
"I've had moments when I've been quite upset because I wanted to be there so badly.
"To have the chance to wear the gold jersey again and maybe get another cap for the Wallaroos ... it's the pinnacle.
"This was the goal I've worked hard for. Even up until the other day I really started to think about playing until I was 43 and get to the next World Cup.
"But this could be my last. You never say never, I love it and as long as my body holds together, I'll keep playing."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Royals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Burrows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Cronan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SOS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Girls Grammar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
