<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439076079793728</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/smh-editorial/samesex-marriage-if-not-now-then-when-20170804-gxpxi0.html</url>
  <title>Same-sex marriage: if not now, then when? </title>
  <content>
By now it's widely accepted we will have marriage equality in Australia. That loving gay couples should be able to declare a lifetime commitment to each other before the law with the same rights and responsibilities as heterosexual couples do is mainstream thinking. So when will it happen, and why not now? 
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull and his Liberal Party colleagues are going to have to come up with a credible, workable answer in their party room today. On when, progressives say sooner, conservatives say later. On why not now, the straight answer is that any quick resolution risks not only  Turnbull's leadership but his government. But that's a purely political answer to a largely moral question, so fails to satisfy.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
Easier, then, to put morality aside for the moment and focus on the politics. Are the Liberal MPs agitating for gay marriage now, rather than in two years' time, willing to sacrifice their leader, and probably their chances of winning another term in government, by forcing a vote on the floor of the parliament?
Option A is to stick with the plan to put the issue to voters at a plebiscite. This was the bargain that Turnbull made with the conservatives when he won the leadership from Tony Abbott. The Herald supported a traditional plebiscite in conjunction with the last election, because we preferred the $44 million cost estimate to the $158 million bill for a standalone plebiscite. We also argued the risk of inflaming anti-gay sentiment would be reduced because the issue would not dominate public discourse during an election campaign as it would in the run-up to a standalone plebiscite.
Option B, the postal plebiscite, is again being championed by Peter Dutton, the immigration minister and soon-to-be Home Affairs minister. Mr Dutton is a conservative, and that should be a clue. A postal plebiscite would be cheaper, and might look simpler, but could prove as effective a delay tactic as the conservatives' previous preferred option of a plebiscite. First, because it will be subject to a High Court challenge. If the challenge succeeds, we are back where we started; if the challenge fails, and the postal plebiscite goes ahead, the legitimacy of its outcome will be in doubt. Did all the ballots make it to and from all the voters in time? Was voter turnout high enough? 
Option C is a free vote on the floor of the parliament. Mr Turnbull cannot be seen to condone it because it would break his pledge to the party and so doom his leadership. If the five Liberal MPs identified as most in favour cross the floor to get a same-sex marriage bill passed, that would mean the Prime Minister had lost control of the house, also dooming his leadership.
Another idea doing the rounds: stick with Option A, the plebiscite, until closer to the election, then switch to Option C with an election promise to match Labor's of a parliamentary conscience vote after the election. It's hard to see how such a nudge, wink solution - we say we're doing this, but we're really doing that - could last the distance. It depends on everybody keeping their word. 
Either way same-sex marriage has emerged as the battlefield on which the Prime Minister's leadership stands or falls. He can fight to the death now or call an uneasy truce to fight another day. Two things are certain: no one is about to leave the field, and we will have same-sex marriage, come what may.
'A note from the editor' - to have Sydney Morning Herald editor Lisa Davies' exclusive weekly newsletter delivered to your inbox sign up here: 
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Option A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Option C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Morning Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Affairs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
