<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438642288093013</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/dylan-shiel-says-gws-giants-must-back-up-epic-tackling-effort-against-western-bulldogs/news-story/b5611a5cbee58c3cfe24a3e5d5463c3b</url>
  <title>Giants must bring pressure for Dogs</title>
  <content>
MIDFIELD gun Dylan Shiel says the GWS Giants' massive 119 tackle count means nothing if they can't reproduce the same level of effort on Friday night against the Western Bulldogs at Etihad Stadium.
The defensive effort was the second biggest total by any club this season and a staggering 50 more than their average this season of 69.
"People might highlight what we did on the weekend but what's more important for us is how we back it up again," Shiel said.
BANNED GIANT:
GRAND FINAL:
"The Bulldogs are the reigning premiers and play the inside handballing game better than anyone. The question for us is, can we back up again? We don't want to be a team which does it one week and then drops away the next."
If the team's last two matches are anything to go by the clash in Melbourne will be a classic.
Toby Greene and Jonathon Patton combined to get the Giants home by two points in Canberra in Round 6 and their previous match up was the 2016 preliminary final.

Both Greene and Patton are expected to be back for the match in four days time.
Shiel says it won't be a case of seeking revenge for the finals loss but the experience was enormous for the young team.
"What I do remember of the prelim was I learned what finals footy was about," Shiel said.
"It's about the added expectation and pressure out there. There's so much more on the line and it goes up another gear in intensity. We didn't get the job done but it was one of the best games of footy I've played in, it's what footy is about.
"It was fast and exciting and two young teams as well. The atmosphere at Spotless Stadium was electric. Hopefully we can find ourselves in a similar position again this year and this time learn from our mistakes and go a bit further."
The clash with the Bulldogs midfield guns, Marcus Bontempelli, Tom Liberatore, Luke Dahlhaus, Lachie Hunter, Toby McLean and Jack Macrae, will be worth the price of admission.
Shiel, Josh Kelly and Callan Ward have been doing the heavy lifting for most of this season and now have the reinforcements arriving with Stephen Coniglio and Jacob Hopper.
"We all bring our different strengths to the table," Shiel said.
"It's great to have Steve in the team against he's in great shape and it's great to run out alongside him. Jacob is a really tough inside midfielder along with Matt Kennedy and they're both very important at the pointy end of the season."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callan Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shiel</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Shiel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Dahlhaus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Liberatore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Macrae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
