<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439080374761064</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/small-business/growing/risky-business-how-the-black-hawk-tragedy-led-to-kimberley-turners-10m-company-20170803-gxoach.html</url>
  <title>Risky business: How the Black Hawk tragedy led to Kimberley Turner's $10 million business</title>
  <content>
Kimberley Turner was 18 years old in 1996 when a , killing 15 SAS soldiers and three army aviators. 
She was just a university student, but one of Australia's worst peace-time military disasters galvanised the army reservist into action.Photo: Supplied
As part of her army reserve role Turner worked with two senior officers to design a risk management program.
​"It was really the opportunity to work with that organisation and develop this new emerging field that nobody had heard of, but it was in a really difficult situation," she says.Photo: Supplied
Qantas comes calling

Then an invitation came from the Qantas Flight safety department to talk about what she was doing.
"The weekend before I went to that meeting with Qantas, I was sitting around the table with my family and I said, 'Wow, I've got this opportunity,' so I registered a business name and a domain name and I went and briefed Qantas in a different capacity," Turner says.

Aerosafe Risk Management was born, offering strategic risk pictures at different points in time.
Within six months of starting the business, Turner employed her first full-time staff member.
"I started doing consulting, but being young and junior I didn't have much to sell, so it was really about building the intellectual property and know-how," Turner says. 
Winning an airforce tender

A turning point came when Turner was offered the opportunity to work with the Australian air force to design a risk management strategy.
"I designed the strategy and said what it would take to implement it," Turner says. "They decided to go out to a full tender and put an ad in the paper. I pulled together the best team I could with pilots, psychologists and a professor from university who was one of my lecturers," Turner says. "We won the tender."
That tender turned into an ongoing source of work for Aerosafe, thanks to Turner's negotiating nous. 
If you want to work at the top end of town you need to build a solid business, which is comparable not in size but in professionalism.

"One of my best business decisions was it was a multi-year, multimillion-dollar contract and to pull down the price I negotiated a retention of intellectual property rights," Turner says. "Under the defence policy of building Australian businesses and know-how, I was able to retain all that work and accelerate our growth."
While many small businesses struggle to win government contracts, Turner attributes her success to her approach.
"If you want to work at the top end of town you need to build a solid business, which is comparable not in size but in professionalism," she says. "Everything has to be documented and accounted for. You have to be prepared to put in the hard work." 
Turner says the secret to growing Aerosafe over two decades has been her responsiveness to change.  
"You have to be prepared to be adaptable and let product lines and service lines that aren't needed by the market go, in order to be cutting edge," Turner says. "It's hard to cut it away to start afresh with things, but you need to if you want to be a thought leader and at the top of your game." 
​International impact

Aerosafe has clients around the world, including the US Department of Defence, Lockheed Martin, Boeing, Textron, Qantas, Air New Zealand, China Airlines, Singapore Airlines and Sydney Airport Corporation.
Turner says she decided in 2004 that Aerosafe was going to be the premier provider of airline risk management globally. 
"It meant getting on a plane, it meant living overseas," she says.
Turner is now back in Australia and based in Canberra, but says last year she made 45 international trips, which involves a significant family commitment, leaving behind her partner and seven-year-old step-son. 
"Saturday morning every week without fail at 6.30am we have our weekly management meeting with the United States," Turner says. "They are the small but big sacrifices, it's the commitment you make to maintain a global business."
Looking forward

Aerosafe's global success has enabled it to reach turnover of more than $10 million a year, but Turner has further growth plans. 
"Our funding has really come out of retained earnings and we have had a number of research and developments grants," she says. "We are now seeking investment funds to really grow and scale."
Turner is looking to raise $7 million to accelerate the development of Aerosafe's technology program and invest in patents and a global sales team.
Aerosafe will look for private equity investment or strategic partnerships.
"My preference is to access Australian funds, but it depends how accessible they are," she says. 
Creating something out of nothing

Aviation expert Keith Tonkin runs one of Aerosafe's competitors in aviation risk management, Aviation Projects, but says he's impressed by Turner's business. 
"She created something literally out of nothing and for her to do that is quite admirable," he says.
Tonkin says there is growing opportunity in aviation risk management.
"We are increasingly becoming involved in more and more complex situations," he says. "There has been a concerted effort over the last 12 years to put into place more robust aircraft safety management and risk management." 
But rising professional indemnity insurance costs and cost-cutting by clients pose a challenge for the sector. 
"I characterise what we do as the neck that other people stick out," he says. "The cost of [insurance] is not prohibitive but quite expensive because we are dealing with safety. People like the idea of risk management; they don't necessarily like paying a lot for advice on how to do it and it's hard to put it into practice." 
Turner is ready for the challenges and advises other entrepreneurs to get involved. 
"Don't be afraid to take risks," she says. "I know that's a little bit bizarre coming from someone who runs a risk management company, but step out and the worst thing that happens is that it doesn't work and you have to try again."
Follow MySmallBusiness on ,  and .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aerosafe Risk Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Textron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley Turner's $10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Tonkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas Flight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aviation Projects</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Department of Defense</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MySmallBusiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockheed Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aerosafe</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
