<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438814086786201</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/entertain-guests-in-high-style-at-this-brighton-east-beauty/news-story/e42a1f19a34ec61988940a6ceff929c5</url>
  <title>Entertain guests in high style at this Brighton East beauty - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, has now sold.

A basement theatre room is one of the star attractions of this , offering the ultimate home-entertainment hub with a large living area and built-in wet bar.
But, that's not all - another indulgent entertainment hub can be found on the ground floor, where the open-plan living and dining area leads to a covered entertainment zone with a solar-heated pool.
A 3m-high ceiling, together with floor-to-ceiling windows and an expansive sliding glass door, accentuate the spacious feel and light-filled living experienced in this part of the home. French oak engineered flooring downstairs also complements the bright and airy setting.
SUBURB PROFILE:

The open-plan zone flows out to an entertainment area with inviting solar-heated pool.

There are two more living areas, including a large formal sitting room that greets you on entry, and a combined rumpus and study upstairs. They provide plenty of options for the whole family.
The kitchen is top-class, with every stylish fitting and finish imaginable, from imported Italian marble benchtops and splashbacks, to European tapware, a fully integrated Fisher & Paykel fridge and dishwasher, plus stainless steel Miele appliances and Italian-designed Snaidero cabinetry.
The home has two main-bedroom suites - downstairs features a 3m-high ceiling and a private sunlit terrace; a walk-in wardrobe with designer timber fitout, including LED-lit drawers, and an ensuite with twin vanity and wet room. The latter has a freestanding bath and separate shower are contained in a fully tiled area behind a glass screen.

The sleek kitchen showcases marble benchtops and Miele appliances.

The ensuite also has fully automated external louvres.
The second main-bedroom suite, or guest bedroom, is upstairs and has two built-in wardrobes, an ensuite, and automated external louvres.
Two secondary bedrooms with built-in wardrobes, are also upstairs within easy reach of the main bathroom. Each upper-level bedroom, plus the retreat and study, has its own split system for year-round heating and cooling comfort.

The rumpus room upstairs could be configured as a study area.

Other features include limestone floors in the bathrooms and laundry, a basement-level bathroom, ducted heating and cooling downstairs, as well as double-glazed windows.
The home is also smart-wired with data points in each room; a video intercom; alarm; plus, there's a lift!
AGENT SAYS:
"Immaculate, luxurious and spacious living is exemplified in this brand-new, light-filled, modern family home."
- Justin Follett, Follett & Co
DETAILS:
SOLD
Price guide: $2.4 million - $2.64 million
Agent: Follett & Co Brighton
Contact: Justin Follett, 9598 9111 or 0405 996 822; Marcus Heron, 0424 696 822
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Follett, 9598 9111</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miele</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Follett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LED-lit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Follett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAYKEL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian-designed Snaidero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Heron, 0424 696 822</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
