<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439462626854295</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/europe/a-british-model-says-she-had-her-wrists-and-ankles-handcuffed-before-being-stuffed-in-bag-by-kidnappers/news-story/60b6561811c60170cec60edd29c6215d</url>
  <title>A British model says she had her wrists and ankles handcuffed before being stuffed in bag by kidnappers</title>
  <content>
British model Chloe Ayling has revealed she thought she was going to die at the hands of kidnappers who kept her captive for a week. Picture: Instagram

The SunNews Corp Australia Network

Share

A BRITISH glamour model drugged and taken captive by dark web kidnappers has revealed she thought she was going to die at the hands of her abductors.
Glamour model Chloe Ayling, 20, before being auctioned on the dark web for A$445,000.

on

Speaking from her home in London, Ms Ayling told  "I've been through a terrifying experience. I've feared for my life, second by second, minute by minute, hour by hour.
"I'm incredibly grateful to the Italian and UK authorities for all they have done to secure my safe release.

Lukasz Pawel Herba has been arrested over Chloe Ayling's abduction. Picture: Italian PoliceSource:Supplied
"I have just arrived home after four weeks and haven't had time to collect my thoughts. I am not at liberty to say anything further until I have been debriefed by the UK police."
Now her account of her ordeal, as told to Italian investigators, has revealed she was informed several potential buyers had been lined up.

Chloe Ayling was stuffed in a bag and put in the boot of this car after she was kidnapped. Picture: AFP/Italian PoliceSource:AFP
Il Giornale reported that Ms Ayling was informed by the Black Death kidnappers she would be sold to someone in the Arab world, who would feed her to tigers when he became bored.

A post shared by Chloe Ayling (@chloeayling) on

She said: "He told me ... that he alone had earned more than 15 million euros (A$22 million) in the last five years and explained to me that all the girls are destined for the Arab countries.
"When the buyer gets tired of the girl bought by auction (they) can give them to other people, and when it is no longer of interest they are to become a 'tiger meal'."

The house in Turin where she the young woman was thought to have been held captive. Picture: Italian Police via APSource:AP
and is reprinted with permission
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Death</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ayling</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Ayling</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arab</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP/Italian PoliceSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian PoliceSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lukasz Pawel Herba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Il Giornale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Ayling, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
