<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439338072801545</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/atomic-bomb-dropped-on-hiroshima-2017-8</url>
  <title>Hiroshima: The moment the US deployed the most powerful weapon known to man</title>
  <content>
On August 6, 1945, at 8:15 a.m local time, the world entered the atomic age.

The Enola Gay, a B-29 Superfortress bomber, deployed the most powerful weapon then known to man over Hiroshima.

The southern Japanese city  "an important army depot and port of embarkation," but its location and population also appealed to US officials who  their new weapon's destructive power.

Sunday marks the 72nd anniversary of the bombing of Hiroshima, ordered by President Harry Truman in the final days of the war.

In 2016, just a few months before the 71st anniversary, then-President Barack Obama became the first sitting president  the city - a trip to, , "ponder a terrible force unleashed in a not-so-distant past."

President Donald Trump, then a candidate for the presidency,  of Obama's remarks.

The 5-ton nuclear bomb, named "Little Boy," emerged from the  Manhattan Project. The Enola Gay released it  above the city, and the bomb fell for 44.4 seconds before detonating in a blast that would ultimately kill 140,000 people and destroy 90% of the city.

Three days later, the US dropped another bomb farther south, on the Japanese city of Nagasaki. That blast killed about 40,000 people instantly - thousands more would die of radiation poisoning.

Japan announced its surrender to Allied forces on August 15. On September 2, Japanese leaders signed the formal instrument of surrender aboard the USS Missouri, anchored in Tokyo Bay, formally ending World War II.

composed an earlier version of this post

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enola Gay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nagasaki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-29 Superfortress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Missouri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Harry Truman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6, 1945</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Boy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hiroshima</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
