<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438685237766273</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/dean-cox-says-matildas-star-sam-kerr-would-be-the-top-target-for-a-west-coast-aflw-team/news-story/78421ec986fea9a05e9b2cb3245a93ec</url>
  <title>'She'd be the number one target'</title>
  <content>
WEST Coast assistant coach Dean Cox says Matildas star Samantha Kerr would be the "number one target" if the Eagles attained an AFLW licence.
Kerr has been the talk of the sporting world after scoring four goals in three games at the Tournament of Nations, cementing her reputation as one of the world's best footballers.
But Cox said the Eagles would love to lure Kerr - whose older brother is Eagles premiership player Daniel Kerr - across to the AFLW.
"She'd be the number one target you would have thought," Cox said on Fox Sports News' Gameday Live.
"Hopefully that can happen and we can attract people like that to the footy club."

AFLW: West Coast legend Dean Cox says the Eagles would target Sam Kerr if they get an AFLW licence.

AFLW to target Kerr
However, that dream outcome for the Eagles looks set to be quite a few years off - if it ever eventuates.
Despite being a massive AFL fan as a youngster, Kerr said the round ball game was her life now.
"I grew up on AFL so AFL to me was everything," Kerr said on Fox Sports News' Gameday Live.
"I used to be Ashley Sampi in the backyard for hours after school and take hangers on the fitness ball.
"But I love soccer now - it's given me everything and it's my life now. So I did love AFL but the tables have turned a little bit."
When asked whether she would consider playing for the Eagles in the AFLW, Kerr said there was "no comparison" to the opportunities soccer provided.
"Maybe at the end of my career but at the moment there's really no comparison for me," Kerr said.
"Playing in Olympic Games, playing at a World Cup. I think women's football is growing and it's great but yeah I think I'll stay with soccer for the moment."
As for playing both sports - like Adelaide Crows premiership player and Canberra United footballer Jenna McCormick - Kerr said both her body and her commitments to football would prevent a dual-code career.
"I don't think FFA would allow that - and I don't think, honestly, my body would hold up. I've had a fair few injuries over the time."
A former teammate of Daniel Kerr, Cox praised the younger Kerr for her remarkable achievements with the Matildas.
"It's an amazing feat ... Daniel now, he's probably the third-best Kerr after (their father) Roger," Cox said on Fox Sports News' Game Day Live
"With Sam, Sam's probably a better footballer than Daniel was as well.
"But it's unbelievable, what she's done and how hard she worked to get to where she has.
"But that family is talented, that is one thing they are and for her to show it on the international stage has been unbelievable."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenna McCormick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Cox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Kerr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News' Game Day Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFLW</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Sampi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News' Gameday Live</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
