<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439333777834220</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/life/how-to-win-any-argument-boosting-your-powers-of-persuasian/news-story/6981f4d672dc0a2212e0c43f4c9e2b98</url>
  <title>How to win any argument</title>
  <content>
Jay Heinrichs knows a thing or two about arguing. He is the American author of Thank You For Arguing, a book first published in the US 10 years ago that became a bestseller taught in colleges. He now uses the principles of the -ancient art of rhetoric to advise -organisations ranging from NASA to Wal-Mart.
There is one man, though, who he concedes may be tricky to outwit. President Donald Trump's tendency to deny reality, present his own "alternative facts", or -baldly state the opposite of what appears to be the truth, makes him an extremely challenging -opponent in a verbal joust.
But if you thought Donald Trump was just displaying astonishing chutzpah when he claimed that his inauguration crowd was huge when photographic evidence suggested it wasn't, he should not be dismissed as a one-trick arguer.
According to Heinrichs, Trump's confrontations with the media (or the "fake news media") are part of a long tradition of disagreement. "It's a clash between two kinds of rhetoric."
When a US newspaper writes an editorial full of carefully researched arguments against a Trump policy it is practising deliberative argument, one of the three types of rhetorical persuasion (the other two are demonstrative and forensic rhetoric). "What Trump practises is demonstrative rhetoric - a way of defining who is good and who is bad. I call that tribal rhetoric."
He's not the only one who does this. "Look at the mayor of London (Sadiq Khan) after the recent attacks. He said, 'This is what we are; who we are' - defining ourselves as a people. Trump talks about 'we are good, the people south of the border are bad'. Tribal rhetoric."
All too often we use the word argument almost as a synonym for "fight". "An argument, done skilfully, gets people to want to do what you want," Heinrichs writes. "You fight to win; you argue to achieve agreement."
Issues you may argue about boil down to three core categories: blame, values or choice. "Who moved my cheese?" is a blame issue. "Should abortion be legal?" is a values issue. "Should we build a new car factory in Britain?" is an issue of choice.
Blame focuses on the past, -values are discussed in the present tense and choice questions are about the future. If you want to succeed in arguments, you do best to cast them in the future.
Heinrichs has two grown-up children. When they were younger he was always explaining rhetoric to them. One day he found the toothpaste tube empty and yelled at his son, George: "Who used all the toothpaste?" Back came the sarcastic answer: "That's not the point, is it? The point is how we're going to keep this from happening again." George had been listening to his dad about looking to the future to resolve arguments.
Aristotle's most powerful tools for persuasion are: logos, argument by logic; pathos, argument by emotion; and ethos, argument by character.
The most powerful tool in the logos box is concession, in which you cannily use your opponent's argument to your own advantage. If a colleague says your work is -unoriginal, you agree: "Sure, in the sense that it's already been used successfully."
The key pathos tactic is sympathy, registering your concern for your audience's emotions and then changing the mood.
Three essential qualities of a persuasive ethos are seeming to care about your audience's interests; an appearance of knowing the right thing to do; and virtue, which here means sharing your audience's values.
Heinrichs contends that Trump has impeccable virtue. "I am not sure that anybody likes Trump, but most of his followers trust him. They feel like he's the leader for them."
Jeremy Corbyn also is a man of ethos. Just look at the young people cheering him at Glastonbury. "They are cheering Jeremy Corbyn representing their values," Heinrichs says. "He is fighting the good fight for them. Whatever that fight is they don't seem all that well-informed about. But that doesn't matter."
When it comes to speeches, President Obama performed as if he had been to rhetoric school. He followed Cicero in the way he organised his speeches. While he may lack Obama's craft, however, Trump does one thing very well. He fills his speeches with impromptu bursts of sound bites that are repetitive and build to punch-lines.
Heinrichs found these bursts were about 12 seconds, the same as the climax of speeches in films such as Braveheart. Ancient rhetoricians believed that an audience could easily absorb a thought in such a stretch of time. "There's -ancient method to this seeming madness," he writes of Trump's oratory of nonsequiturs.
Heinrichs, 61, a former journalist who turned his fascination with ancient rhetoric into a book and then a consulting business, worked with NASA to reframe its arguments for a budget increase "really, space is a rapidly -developing economy" - and with a healthcare company to encourage parents to vaccinate their children (the word "protection" was substituted for "vaccination").
He is full of crafty tricks. When his wife didn't like the name -George for their son, he proposed names he knew she really wouldn't like until she decided -George wasn't so bad after all.
What advice might he have for Theresa May to help her to win the arguments with the EU over Brexit? "One of the biggest mistakes that people make in the beginning of any argument is that they haven't set real goals, so square one is setting a goal that she and her party can agree on. Is it hard or soft Brexit?
"How to then negotiate? The only strategy she has is to ask: what is advantageous to the audience? She has to go to the EU and say, 'I understand what you want, here is how we will deliver for you'. If she goes in saying, 'I'm going to be a bulldog', then the EU will say, 'What on earth do we want with a bulldog?' "
That sounds fairly unpromising, but perhaps Heinrichs can help with my concerns, namely how to persuade my 13-year-old son to detach himself from his screens and go to bed. I explain I have already tried all logical arguments about the need for sleep.
"Those arguments are never -effective," Heinrichs says. "It has to speak to his identity. So if there is a choice it could be: what's more important, the screen or staying up? Say he can stay up and read a book."
If that doesn't work, he suggests the high-risk option. I can tell my son: "Make your schedule, but it has to be a schedule that ends up with you going to a fine university after school."
I can see the logic, but also the very large pitfalls. So that evening I offer him the choice. He takes the third way, and goes straight to bed, telling me on the way: "You're- -ridiculous."
Remembering my training in rhetoric I immediately offer a concession. "I know, I am ridiculous!" He looks at me as if I am also mad.
Thank You for Arguing: What Cicero, Shakespeare and the Simpsons Can Teach Us about the Art of Persuasion
The Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heinrichs, 61</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thank You For Arguing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cicero</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Heinrichs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wal-Mart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sadiq Khan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glastonbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art of Persuasion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons Can Teach Us</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braveheart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Corbyn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aristotle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heinrich</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theresa May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
