<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438826971688201</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/personal-finance/superannuation-and-smsfs/unisupers-internallymanaged-portfolios-set-to-grow-20170803-gxodc8</url>
  <title>UniSuper's internally-managed portfolios set to grow</title>
  <content>
Up to 80 per cent of UniSuper's assets could be managed internally in five years' time as contributions flow into the superannuation scheme's key portfolios.
Melbourne-based UniSuper is already managing 60 per cent of its $60 billion of assets in-house, putting the fund at the forefront of a trend among large retirement schemes to manage member savings internally rather than outsourcing the function to external fund managers. 
Other super funds managing sizeable portions of member savings in-house include . The trend is also pronounced among large offshore pension funds.
UniSuper chief investment officer John Pearce said the fund had no target for its internally-managed portfolios, but noted that the bulk of contributions were flowing into the scheme's default and defined benefit divisions, where more of the assets tended to be managed by the 44-strong internal team.

"If, in five years' time, we had 80 per cent being managed internally, it wouldn't surprise me," Mr Pearce told The Australian Financial Review.

Seven years ago UniSuper's assets were all managed by external specialists.
Today 55 per cent of the Australian equities portfolio is managed internally, 40 per cent of international equities and 70 per cent of cash, bonds and hybrids. By contrast, highly-specialised asset classes, such as credit or corporate bonds, tend to be managed by third-party providers.
Internalising asset management has helped to drive total fees at the fund, which caters to employees in the tertiary education sector, to 0.5 per cent, including a 0.2 per cent investment management fee. Mr Pearce said the investment fee takes into account the salaries of the in-house teams.
Analysis by research firm Chant West shows that UniSuper posted a 9.6 per cent return for the year to June 30, before administration fees,  However, over the past five years and 10 years UniSuper outperformed the industry average, with annual gains of 11.2 per cent and 5.8 per cent respectively.

In sharp contrast to other large industry funds, UniSuper has a low exposure to unlisted assets. Just 9 per cent of the balanced fund is invested in unlisted property and infrastructure assets, which posted strong gains in 2016-17. 
"We are very concerned about liquidity," Mr Pearce said.
UniSuper has an older membership base, in addition to which the fund wants to prevent members switching between investment options based on old or stale prices. 
"It's about member equity," Mr Pearce said.

He added that the internal teams for the most part had outperformed their relevant benchmarks. Over the past year 78 per cent had outperformed their benchmarks, while 94 per cent had outperformed their benchmarks over three years.
Mr Pearce said that employing highly-paid fund managers had not created any cultural problems. He said base salaries offered by UniSuper to fund managers were "quite competitive" with the market, but bonuses were lower, at less than 100 per cent of base salary. 
"There is a clear understanding [at the fund] we had to attract certain types of individuals [to the investment team]," Mr Pearce said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UniSuper</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chant West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based UniSuper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearce</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
