<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438732482406968</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/queensland-rookie-renovators-left-in-tears-after-main-bathroom-not-ready-for-the-block-judges/news-story/b75e50cf00a7ba1a3dc13e0726cfb6d8</url>
  <title>Block couple's epic bathroom fail</title>
  <content>
HANNAH and Clint Amos have described failing to finish their main bathroom for reveal on last night's episode of The Block as "heartbreaking and soul destroying".
The Queensland renovation rookies, who broke down in tears on camera after coming last in the judging for their unfinished room, told Confidential they didn't want to let down the Sunshine State or their family.
"Hannah and I are very proud coming from Queensland and we felt like we had a lot to prove," Clint said.
"At tools down, I just remember Hannah walking away in tears and that cut me up a bit. We are capable of doing it and we didn't want to embarrass anyone."
While the feeling on set was that they were largely let down by their tradies, Hannah and Clint said they weren't keen to point fingers.
"I didn't understand how labour intensive the tiles were so that didn't do them any favours," Hannah said.
"(The tradies) all have lives after The Block and (their trades) are their livelihood so we don't want to go there pointing fingers because that's just not us."
The pair scored just 16 out of a possible 30 from judges Neale Whitaker, Shaynna Blaze and Darren Palmer with Elyse and Josh winning on 27.
Sticks and Wombat came in second by half a point on 26.5, Ronnie and Georgia third on 25.5 and Jason and Sarah fourth with 24.
"Once we got a three (from Blaze), that was as bad as it was going to get so it just made us want to work our backsides off the next week," Hannah said.
"Once you've fallen so low you can only dust yourself off and move forward from there - it was a steep learning curve."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neale Whitaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaynna Blaze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronnie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint Amos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elyse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
