<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439333777834225</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/more-sports/australian-400m-runner-morgan-mitchell-says-she-has-been-suffering-from-depression/news-story/63f64726cd881d28d3a3211c9e2a4f97</url>
  <title>Mitchell opens up on depression battle</title>
  <content>
AN emotional Morgan Mitchell has revealed she's been battling depression in the lead-up to the world championships.
After just missing a place in the 400m semi-finals, Mitchell admitted that off-field issues had plagued her preparation to the point where at times she didn't want to get out of bed.
The Australian champion, who blew up in the Olympic semi-finals in Rio last year, said she was "cooked" after a tough 12 months.
"It's the hardest sport," Mitchell said.
"I don't think people understand how hard you work, for it to all fall to pieces in 52 seconds is just crap, it feels like last year all over again but I am a different person, a different athlete.
"I just don't know what's going on, we just have to sit down, re-evaluate and fix what went wrong.
"It's just hard separating yourself from athlete to person, particularly when you're suffering on the sidelines and people don't get that.
"If people understood how hard it is to mentally bring yourself to these Games and perform well . . . I just couldn't do it this year.
"I felt cooked. It just sucks because that is not who I am."
Mitchell, 22, is still haunted about what happened in Rio where she went out too hard in the semi-final and faltered badly over the final stages to finish fifth, missing a place in the Olympic final.
"That definitely haunted me, it wasn't supposed to go that way last year," she said.
"I think to be honest, I didn't want to care anymore. I fell into a heap of sad emotions, depression, I didn't want to get out of bed, I was crying at training.
"I'm not an excuse person, I told Fitz (coach Peter Fitzgerald) that I might be sad but that doesn't mean I am going to bring that to the track.
"So it's a sh.t feeling like I have brought it all back to the track, I just don't know. I'm so f..king lost at the moment.
"I just don't get it, I really don't get it."
Mitchell thought she'd got things under control in the lead-up to London, running personal bests at training but she faded late in the heat, finishing fifth in 52.22sec - almost a second outside her personal best.
"I thought I was doing alright. I was running PBs in training five days ago. I just can't seem to put it together on the day of competition," she said.
"To be honest, this year, mentally more than anything, I've struggled with a lot of issues.
''I ran a second PB over 250 and then I come out and run the exact same race I have been doing all season.
"It's been a long season. Nitro was awesome but when you do this, that and otherwise, you try to attend to everyone else's needs and forget about your own.
"With the Comm Games around the corner, I've got to switch on. I want to make that semi, I want to grow, I want to make a final."
Mitchell will return later in the championships in the 4x400m relay, the team which made the Olympic final last year.
In better news for Australia, 20-year-old pole vaulter Kurtis Marschall has qualified for the world championships final.
There were plenty of anxious moments but the South Australian scrapped into the field tied for 11th with a best leap of 5.60m.
After entering qualifying with an easy first-up clearance at 5.30m, Marshall struck trouble missing two attempts at 5.45m.
But showing coolness beyond his years Marschall delivered on his third leap and then went over 5.60m at his first attempt.
He then missed his three attempts at 5.70m but still made the field on a countback.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comm Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
