<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439415382213648</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/aaron-carter-comes-out-as-bisexual-in-twitter-post/news-story/4117c35029503f085f955544c3becb68</url>
  <title>Aaron Carter comes out as bisexual</title>
  <content>
FORMER teen pop star Aaron Carter has come out as bisexual in a revealing Twitter note to fans.
"I grew up in this entertainment industry at a very young age and when I was around 13-year-old I started to find boys and girls attractive," he tweeted on Saturday night.
that Carter, 29, started off by saying he needed to get something off his chest that was both weighing him down and of importance "for myself and my identity."
"There were years that went by that I thought about it, but wasn't until I was 17-year old, after a few relationships with girls, I had an experience with a male that I had an attraction to who I also worked with and grew up with," Carter said not mentioning names.
The I Want Candy singer adds his experience and feelings for the same sex doesn't "bring me shame, just a weight and a burden I have held onto for a long time."
The estranged younger brother of Nick Carter of the Backstreet Boys ended his message with a quote from Boy George that reads, "I've never felt as though I didn't belong, I just acted as though I did."
Aaron Carter - I'm All About You

It's been a troubling several months for the young singer. In July, Carter revealed he's suffering from an eating disorder and was as well.
Carter's father, Robert, died in May and he confessed to battling alcoholism in October 2016.
This story was first published in  and is reproduced here with their permission
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Carter of the Backstreet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Carter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carters</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carter, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALL ABOUT YOU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Want Candy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
