<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440325915289319</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/private-sector-to-turn-nambour-into-cultural-hub/3209283/</url>
  <title>Private sector to turn Nambour into cultural hub</title>
  <content>
THE private sector looms as key to creating certainty for Nambour's future when some of the 350-odd Sunshine Coast Council staff relocate to the .

Sunshine Coast Mayor Mark Jamieson said the private sector would ultimately be responsible for driving the town's economy, and it was the council's job to ensure the right planning was in place to allow that to happen.

His comments came after LNP candidate for Nicklin Marty Hunt, a police PCYC Sergeant and local resident of the past 17 years, expressed concern about the town's future once the workers vacate.

"It's the uncertainty that's the issue," Mr Hunt said.

"It's going to be less of a presence and we know that.

"We've got to prepare as a town."

Mr Hunt said he was eager to hear what the council's plans were to soften yet another economic blow to the town following the closure of the Moreton Sugar Mill and downsizing of Nambour Hospital.

"We don't want another kick in the guts," he said, adding he'd spoken with many businesses who were concerned about the future.

He said ideas circulating to reinvent the town included a university arts campus in the vacated council office space, as well as student accommodation in the town with "trendy bars and live music".

"We need to map some plans out with the council leading the way as they're the ones... taking away the economic certainty," Mr Hunt said.

Cr Jamieson said the plans to relocate to Maroochydore had been public knowledge for a decade.

"In a lot of ways it's up to the private sector to see the opportunity," he said.

He thought an active entertainment precinct in Nambour would be an "outstanding" outcome, and hoped the arts would play a key role in the town's future.

A technology hub, museum or office space were some of the ideas he threw up as possibilities for vacant space within the Nambour council building.

Cr Jamieson said entitlements had been included in the previous plan to try and encourage higher-density living in the CBD with greater street-level activation.

He believed the State Government's failure to deliver rail line duplication had also held Nambour back significantly.

"That's been one of the great challenges for Nambour," Cr Jamieson said.

He said the council would be working "as hard as we can" with Nambour and Caloundra to manage the transition of council staff.

Nambour Alliance president Tony Vella said the council building drew in thousands of people to Nambour for business and he was looking forward to working collaboratively with the council to offset the impact of the shift.

He thought higher education services, like a university campus for performing and visual arts, would be a great fit for Nambour.

"All I see is a bright future as long as the right steps are taken," Mr Vella said.

Rescue helicopter, SES, firies on scene at Mt Beerwah for rescue
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Intense patches to touch down on Coast
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
A BIG bathtub and a golden speaker were the major talking points.
Netflix health doco slammed for scaremongering, 'cherrypicking' data
Meghan Markle will never carry the title princess
RICHARD Roxburgh returns as Roger Rogerson in a new mini-series.
Voices and bodies entwine in complicated yet seamless arrangements.
Hamish and Andy's series set to hit small screen again
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Vella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicklin Marty Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Mayor Mark Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Roxburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Sugar Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Vella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Rogerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jamieson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCYC Sergeant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hunt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
