<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439982317902136</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/03/31/vic-priest-to-be-sentenced-for-sex-abuse</url>
  <title>Vic priest to be sentenced for sex abuse</title>
  <content>
A Victorian priest is due to find out how long he will spend in jail after pleading guilty to molesting boys at Victoria's notorious Rupertswood boarding school.
Frank Peter De Dood, 64, is scheduled to face the Victorian County Court for sentencing on Monday after pleading guilty in July to six counts of indecently assaulting five boys.
De Dood's victims were aged 11 to 16 when they were abused between 1978 and 1983 at Rupertswood and at a theological residence at suburban Oakleigh.
One remembers wearing his altar boy robe when molested, while another woke to find the priest assaulting him.
De Dood told another boy no one would believe him if he told anyone about the abuse, and if he did, he would be expelled.
De Dood has been in custody since July 27 after Judge Susan Cohen, the prosecution and defence agreed he faced an immediate jail term.
The priest sat with his hand covering his face for most of a plea hearing as prosecutor Matthew Fisher recounted the details of his crimes.

Related Articles

"He was a man who was entrusted to look after and care for the children," Mr Fisher told the court.
"These acts were, and are, reprehensible. They are disgusting."
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian County Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Peter De Dood, 64</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Susan Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupertswood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
