<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440188476334632</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/2059404/roxby-enjoying-return-to-form/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Roxby enjoying return to form</title>
  <content>
Roxby enjoying return to form

CONTRIBUTING: Wallsend's Cameron Roxby has rediscovered his love for cricket. Picture: Max Mason-Hubers

CONTRIBUTING: Wallsend's Cameron Roxby has rediscovered his love for cricket. Picture: Max Mason-Hubers

exit

WALLSEND all-rounder Cameron Roxby has credited the enjoyment factor with his return to form.
Like the Tigers, the 19-year-old appears to be on the rise in Newcastle district cricket.
Going into last season, the former Cricket Australia Centre of Excellence student was being touted as one of the competition's brightest talents, given his heroics in Wallsend's grand-final loss against Merewether in 2011-12.
But injuries and poor form left him with just 64 first-grade runs last season at 10.67 and 12 wickets at 20.50.
The knee injury is behind Roxby and he has played every game this season for 267 runs at 33.38 and 20 wickets at 22.20.
"I was only talking to a couple of boys at Wallsend training this week that I haven't missed a game this year, which is a first in a long time," Roxby said.
"I'm really just enjoying this season running around with my mates playing cricket.
"While I'd like to get back into the representative stuff, it hasn't happened this year. I'm in a much better place today than I was 12 or 18 months ago, and it probably comes down to having fun and enjoying my cricket a lot more."
There was plenty of expectation on Roxby's shoulders and he admitted it was difficult to handle last season.
"All that talk that was going on was all right, but personally the injuries played a big part on how I was feeling. And when you can't contribute 100 per cent to the team, it feels like you're letting them down," he said.
"But I'm slowly getting back to where I was."
Today there will be expectation again as Roxby and his new-ball partner, Matthew Wicks, look to bowl Wallsend to a vital victory over Charlestown at Kahibah Oval.
The Magpies will resume at 3-7 in reply to Wallsend's 9-223 last week, with the winner to take ownership of fourth spot.
Wicks and Roxby put Wallsend on top with their lively spell in the final five overs last week, and they will need to continue that today with Charlestown's English import Callum Jackson at the crease.
"Cal has had an outstanding season and the plans we've been putting together obviously revolve around him, but other batsmen too," Roxby said.
Jackson is at the crease with his housemate and Roxby's fellow Newcastle Colts rep teammate Daniel Arms. There is plenty of batting to follow in Chris Connors and Charlestown captain Steve Mace.
"We're three down at the moment, but if we have a good session first up we're back even or on top," Mace said.
"The outfield will be a lot quicker this week obviously with no rain and the wicket, you would think, would be slightly harder given the weather conditions.
"So it's all there for us to get them and get them well. We just need to apply ourselves."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Arms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxby</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallsend's Cameron Roxby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown's English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Colts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Wicks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kahibah Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia Centre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallsend</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Mace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Roxby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
