<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439587180906904</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/1316124/generous-memories-with-a-song-in-the-heart/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Generous memories with a song in the heart</title>
  <content>
Generous memories with a song in the heart

Grace Leonard will audition for a $60,000 scholarship, thanks to a bequest by music lover Norman Bushman (inset). Picture: Marina Neil

exit
AUDITIONS will be held at the University of Newcastle's Conservatorium of Music today for students hoping to receive scholarships funded by sentimental Hunter man Norman Bushman.

Mr Bushman, a Singleton-raised music lover, died in 2010 and bequeathed $2.8million to the university to fund two $60,000 scholarships for music students each year.
Lambton's Grace Leonard 19, who is entering her second year of a Bachelor of Music in Classical Voice degree, said she was nervous about performing three pieces at her audition but excited about the possible opportunity to receive a scholarship.
''It would help me with uni fees, singing tuition and equipment, as well as other pre-professional study and workshops that will help me with my goal of becoming a professional classic vocalist,'' she said.
Mr Bushman was living in Sydney when he met talented pianist and vocalist Joy Ingall and her husband at a soiree.
Mrs Ingall had studied at the Sydney Conservatorium of Music but had not pursued a professional career, choosing instead to focus solely on her marriage and five children.
She performed occasionally at parties, but her new friend Mr Bushman encouraged her to return to her studies and give music lessons.
''He gave her moral and financial support, she was his protege,'' University of Newcastle Foundation executive officer Bernie Curran said.
Mr Bushman continued to support Mrs Ingall's family after her death from pancreatic cancer at age 48 and was committed to ensuring the memory of his 
friend and her love of music lived on.
His bequest supplements two annual scholarships named the Norman Bushman Scholarship for Undergraduate Studies Relating to Voice and the Joy Ingall Scholarship for Studies in 
Music.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grace Leonard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joy Ingall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton's Grace Leonard 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Curran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor of Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Classical Voice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joy Ingall Scholarship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservatorium of Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman Bushman Scholarship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bushman</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Undergraduate Studies Relating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Conservatorium of Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Ingall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman Bushman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singleton-raised</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
