<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440373159930008</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/thousands-turn-out-to-celebrate-the-coasts-50th-bi/3209337/</url>
  <title>Thousands turn out to celebrate the Coast's 50th birthday</title>
  <content>
THE WEATHER threatened, but held off, and the crowds came out in droves to ring in the 50th anniversary of the naming of the Sunshine Coast.

Just less than 4000 people flocked to the Sunshine Coast Stadium to join the festivities, the new hills awash with families and picnic blankets.

Our Sunshine Coast Concert proved a raging success, with the best of the community, through local groups and artists, creating a memorable afternoon for those who gathered.

MC and special performer Darren Percival was among the talent on display and a Sunshine Coast Council spokeswoman said the final pieces by the choirs and the Sunshine Coast Youth Orchestra had been the hands-down highlights of the afternoon.

"We were really lucky the weather held off until the very, very end," the spokeswoman said.

Massive Woodford creatures kept the kids entertained throughout the afternoon.

Sunshine Coast Mayor Mark Jamieson said the pinnacle of the anniversary celebrations were yet to come, with the end of year fireworks spectacular ahead.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Youth Orchestra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Mayor Mark Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Concert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Percival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
