<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440617973068052</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/these-middle-ring-units-come-in-cheaper-than-blocks-of-land/news-story/2bf87307adf53204bce3d138bca3e710</url>
  <title>Middle ring units cheaper than land</title>
  <content>
TWO bed unit prices in middle ring suburbs have emerged as some of the cheapest on the market, with some costing less than a block of land.
The lowest two bed unit on the market in Greater Brisbane right now is  in Zillmere priced at offers over $249,000.
Agents Colin and Jenny Street of @Realty were marketing the solid brick property as one that would "stand the test of time".
"Rental expectation around $280/wk is expected. This is way cheaper than the price of a block of land, and offers the new owner a rental income to cover the utility bills."
Among improvements made by the current owner were fresh carpets and a new kitchen.
Another two bed unit in Zillmere at was priced at $259,900. Agent Matt Phillips of Image Property Aspley did not expect it to remain on market for too long at that price.
He was marketing it as having a large balcony as well as extra storage space and a large lock up garage - "a must see".
Two other middle ring two-bed units on the market in the late 200s were in highly popular Chermside (offers over $280,000) and e which was at least $5,000 less at $275,000.
The Chermside unit is on the top floor of a six-unit block, with new carpet, paint, curtains and fixtures, a large balcony, lock up garage and secure intercom access.
Agents Ryan Hoelzl and Luke Burton of Burton & Ryan Property were marketing it as being "only 13kms from the CBD" and close to Westfield Chermside, Prince Charles Hospital, transport, parks and schools. https://www.realestate.com.au/property-unit-qld-chermside-126092806
The Forest Lake unit was the only one of the four to have two bathrooms, and has long term tenants in place until March 2018.
It is currently rented at $340/week, a rental yield of around 7 per cent. The complex has an inground pool and was security gated with basement parking and storage, with body corporate fees of about $51 a week.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chermside</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forest Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Phillips of Image</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Hoelzl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Aspley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield Chermside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zillmere</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Street of @Realty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Burton of Burton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
