<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651438552093778811</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/liberal-mps-expected-to-reject-immediate-conscience-vote-on-samesex-marriage/news-story/e7e3b06aae7a3f7d20329e8d1b6ea514</url>
  <title>Rebel Libs will be left at the altar</title>
  <content>
A REBEL group of Liberal MPs will on Monday ask the party room to endorse a free vote for its MPs on a marriage equality Bill that contains exemptions for celebrants who don't believe in gay marriage.
But the bid by the small group of marriage equality supporters to secure a conscience vote before the Federal Election is expected to be futile.
An overwhelming majority of Liberal MPs are expected to reject an immediate conscience vote and recommend that the Cabinet instead try for a second time to persuade the Senate to allow a public vote via a plebiscite to proceed.
The Government could also try to hold a national postal vote without parliamentary approval, but that would be challenged in the High Court as unconstitutional.
The rebels were yesterday tight-lipped about whether they would be willing to introduce the same-sex marriage bill without party room approval.
West Australian Liberal senator and marriage equality supporter Dean Smith said a free vote should be allowed in Parliament.
Senator Smith said the Bill he had circulated ensured that celebrants and church-owned organisations could opt out of involvement in same-sex weddings.

A postal plebiscite on same-sex marriage could be ruled invalid by the High Court, reports say.

Postal plebiscite could be ruled invalid
"If the Government should change at the next election, people cannot be confident that those same protections will be in a Labor Bill,'' he said.
"The argument that I will be putting as strongly as I can tomorrow is that a parliamentary free vote earlier rather than later is the best way to proceed, not least because it allows the Government to move on to other issues.''
In addition to Senator Smith, Liberal MPs Dean Smith, Tim Wilson, Warren Entsch, Trevor Evans and Trent Zimmerman are all pushing for a conscience vote.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull called the party room meeting after conservative Liberals reacted angrily to their pro-gay marriage colleagues revealing they had drafted the Bill.
Senator Smith, who is gay, opposed same-sex marriage when he first entered Parliament in 2012.
He said he had changed his mind after reading an article about Tori Johnson, the Lindt Cafe manager who was murdered by Man Haron Monis during the 2014 Martin Place Siege in Sydney. Mr Johnson had a same-sex partner.
South Australian Senator Nick Xenophon said if Senator Smith introduced the same-sex marriage Bill into the Senate, he would vote for it.
Senator Xenophon said it was embarrassing that Parliament had been unable to settle the national debate over same-sex marriage.
"This is not a just a national embarrassment, it's an international embarrassment,'' he said.
Australian Christian Lobby managing director Lyle Shelton said the marriage Bill circulated by the rebel Liberals lacked protections for business owners who had moral objections to supplying goods or services for same-sex weddings.
"There is no protection for a business owner who does not wish to violate his or her conscience about what marriage is,'' Mr Shelton said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Elections</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place Siege</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Bill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man Haron Monis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyle Shelton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shelton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindt Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tori Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Christian Lobby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
