<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440377454897337</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/flying-fijian-unleashes-as-bombers-retain-top-spot/3209369/</url>
  <title>Flying Fijian unleashes as Bombers retain top spot</title>
  <content>
GIANT centre Marika Kuriyalavou scored his second hat-trick in consecutive weeks as the Fassifern Bombers continued their march towards the minor premiership.
The flying Fijian was credited with one try last week on the RLI statistics list online but the QT was there and he definitely scored three against Swifts that day, as the scoresheet testified.
It is not hard to get him mixed up with the other centre Leveni Kurimalawai in one respect.
They are both Fijian and they both cross the white stripe on a regular basis.
Fassifern coach Daniel Roos said Kuriyalavou was outstanding at Harrisville on Sunday and had developed as the season progressed.
"Marika is a union player and he understands a lot more about where to run and what to do," Roos said.
"He has taken full advantage of that. He's really strong, and quick as well."
In yesterday's 52-30 win over the Eastern Cobras, Ratu Tabaiwalu scored a double and had a big game in the second-row and prop.
Former Kiwi international and NRL star David Fa'alogo returned from a hamstring injury and was a key man in the big moments.
"David adds that experience and knows what to say to the guys in the important times," Roos said.
"He does a lot of the talking when we get scored against and when we are walking to the scrum. He is a leader."
Eastern Cobras took the game up to the Bombers and never took a backward step.
"They turned up to play and we were a little bit lethargic and took a while to get into it," Roos said.
"Then we lifted the intensity and kicked up a gear.
"In this competition some of the scorelines have been a bit of a blowout but it really comes down to how the other side turns up on the day."
Roos said Cobras prop Samisani Latu had a big game and was hard to stop. Latu scored two tries in a powerhouse display.
The Bombers travel to West End on Saturday night for their next clash. Two rounds remain before the finals with Fassifern needing just one win to wrap up a top two position.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrisville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leveni Kurimalawai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cobra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fassifern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Cobras</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samisani Latu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RLI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fijian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swift</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marika Kuriyalavou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Fa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fassifern Bombers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ratu Tabaiwalu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuriyalavou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
