<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440373159929969</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/appeal-for-help-after-knife-point-car-jacking/3209370/</url>
  <title>Knife-point car-jacking sparks appeal for help</title>
  <content>
A MAN had his car stolen from him at knife-point while stopped at an intersection at Maroochydore, police have said.

The 39-year-old man was stopped at the intersection of Maroochy Boulevard and Plaza Parade about 8.35pm on Saturday when a man armed with a knife approached him and opened car door, demanding he get out.

Once the man was out of the car, a 2011 white Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution sedan with Queensland registration EVO-123, the bandit got in and took off north along Evans Street, then onto Fisherman's Road, heading towards Bli Bli.

Police are appealing for help tracking down the car and the thief, who was described as Caucasian, aged about 25 with scruffy hair. At the time of the incident, he was wearing a dark-hooded jumper and a backpack.

This is the second such incident on the Sunshine Coast in recent weeks, although there is no suggestion of a connection between them.

In late June, police alleged a man armed with a handgun tried to steal a car at Brightwater. In that incident, the driver manoeuvred away from the man.

Police arrested a man over that incident, charging him with one count of attempted armed robbery as well as with assaulting police and resisting police.

That matter remains before the courts.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plaza Parade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EVO-123</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisherman's Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Boulevard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brightwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caucasians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
