<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440411814636005</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/get-me-out-of-the-cleaning-kfc-workers-heartfelt-p/3209251/</url>
  <title>'Get me out of the cleaning': KFC worker's heartfelt plea</title>
  <content>
ONE of the Coast's favourite ladies has made a heartfelt plea to her loyal legion of KFC-loving fans.

Legendary KFC Maroochydore drive-thru operator Barb Ehrlich has taken to social media to get out of the cleaning, reminding people the popular fast-food restaurant is open for business.

She posted on a local community Facebook page in a bid to clear up any confusion, with a series of roadworks around the restaurant leaving some thinking the outlet was closed.

"This is to let you (know) that our store is open and ready to take your orders," Barb's post reads.

"A lot of people think we are closed because there are roadworks going on around our store.

"When we are not busy I have to clean (and you know how much I enjoy doing that...not, hahaha). Please come in and see us."

HAPPY FACE: Barb Ehrlich is celebrating 30 years with KFC, she's a local legend and great customer service person. Her sunny disposition has helped many a hungry traveller.Patrick Woods

The popular customer service expert holds a special place in many local hearts.

She took out an online poll a few years back asking people to nominate the best customer service provider on the Coast and there was even a crowd-funding campaign to send her on an overseas holiday.

After more than 30 years at the Maroochydore store, it's clear she still has a passion for hooking people up with a serve of Colonel Sanders' best.

CLASSIC: Barb Ehrlich's hilarious Facebook post.Facebook
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonel Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barb Ehrlich</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC-loving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
