<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440669512676116</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/specials/curious-canberra/2017-08-07/how-long-did-lake-burley-griffin-take-to-fill/8756482</url>
  <title>How long did Lake Burley Griffin take to fill?</title>
  <content>
Lake Burley Griffin is the centrepiece of Canberra - named in honour of the man who designed it.
These days it's a place where people gather for sport, recreation or just to soak up the sights.
But for half of Canberra's history, the grand lake was nowhere to be seen, and Canberra was a city divided by the Molonglo River.
Scott Mollan is this week's questioner. He grew up in Canberra but now calls the Illawarra home.
Scott can't remember the city without Lake Burley Griffin, and he wanted to know where the water for the man-made lake came from, as well as how long it took to fill.
The first attempts to fill the lake occurred during a severe drought, and it wasn't the first time the development had been challenged.
Financial hardship, along with a strategically located sporting field, almost stopped the lake from being built.
'Water all the great cities of the world'

Dianne Firth wrote her PhD on the lake and is also the deputy chair of the ACT Heritage Council.

Dianne Firth wrote her PhD on the lake and is also the deputy chair of the ACT Heritage Council.

ABC News: Elise Pianegonda

Dr Dianne Firth is an adjunct associate professor at the University of Canberra, and deputy chair of the ACT Heritage Council.
She also completed her PhD on the history of Lake Burley Griffin, which detailed how the political landscape of the time shaped its design and construction.
She explained that even before architect Walter Burley Griffin submitted his design for Canberra, it was required that some body of water be included.
"From the time of Federation, 1901, it was written into the Constitution that the new Commonwealth would have a new city that would be the seat of government ... and this was to be a beautiful city and all beautiful cities had ornamental water bodies," she said.

Regatta Point on October 17, 1964 at the official inauguration of Lake Burley Griffin versus how it looks now.

Regatta Point on October 17, 1964 at the official inauguration of Lake Burley Griffin versus how it looks now.

ABC News: Elise Pianegonda / Richard Clough, National Library of Australia

In fact, at the official inauguration of Lake Burley Griffin in 1964, then prime minister Sir Robert Menzies echoed that sentiment.
In an  Sir Robert told the crowd: "Wonder to yourselves what London would be like without the Thames or what Paris would be like without the Seine."

"Indeed I've always thought that part of the dullness of Berlin, if I may so speak, was due to the fact it had nothing but a miserable trickle of water running through it.

"Water, water all the great cities of the world."
Harold Holt tried to axe the project

Construction of the lake was delayed due to both World Wars as well as the Great Depression.

Construction of the lake was delayed due to both World Wars as well as the Great Depression.

Supplied: ACT Heritage Library

When the construction of Canberra began in 1913, Australia was still recovering from World War I. While some development went ahead, the capital in its early days looked more like a collection of sheep paddocks.
When the Great Depression hit, followed by World War II, Canberra's development slowed again, and questions were raised about whether the young capital should have - or could afford - a grand lake.
Dr Firth said Sir Robert Menzies remained a steadfast supporter of Lake Burley Griffin, and in 1959, formal permission was granted for construction to begin.
But not all members of the government were happy with the decision - a few departmental heads were annoyed that their golf club, located on what is now the bed of the West Basin, would disappear under water.
Sir Robert even referred to the golf course in his speech at the lake's official opening.
"There were powerful forces against me because there was a golf course [on the now lake bed] and all the heads of all the departments belonged to it," he told the laughing crowd.

Sir Robert Menzies was so integral in bringing the lake to fruition that many suggested naming it after him.

Sir Robert Menzies was so integral in bringing the lake to fruition that many suggested naming it after him.

ABC News: Elise Pianegonda

Even Harold Holt, the treasurer at the time, had reservations about the lake.
According to Dr Firth, Holt struck the funds for the initial lake works from the budget in a bid to save money - while Sir Robert was on a trip to England.
Dr Firth said if Sir Robert had not returned when he did to challenge the decision, Canberra's central lake may have never been built.
A lake without water

It took months for Lake Burley Griffin to grow from the steady stream of the Molonglo River to a full lake.

It took months for Lake Burley Griffin to grow from the steady stream of the Molonglo River to a full lake.

Richard Clough, National Library of Australia.

Once construction of the lake began, it moved quickly.
Scrivener Dam - named after surveyor Charles Scrivener who chose the site for the capital - was designed to stop the flow of the Molonglo River that was currently running through the middle of Canberra, trapping water in Lake Burley Griffin.
Dr Firth said the skills developed from the recent Snowy Hydro Scheme meant Scrivener Dam was constructed with the latest technology.
And, despite a few instances where sections of the lake retaining wall fell in, the project was completed on time and on budget.

Lake Burley Griffin is fed by the Molonglo River and stopped by Scrivener Dam.

Lake Burley Griffin is fed by the Molonglo River and stopped by Scrivener Dam.

ABC News: Ryan Kerlin

The Scrivener Dam was complete in 1963, when Canberra was in the midst of a crippling drought.
So, while Canberrans waited for the new lake to be unveiled, they made the most of the vast expanse of the lake bed.
, including eating lunch by the lake bed while waiting for it to fill, driving over the newly constructed bridge looking down onto a mere trickle of water and even going for a spin in the car on the lake floor under the already-constructed jetties.
Canberra's 'quietly beating heart'

Sir Robert Menzies said the lake united the city and gave Canberra a heart.

Sir Robert Menzies said the lake united the city and gave Canberra a heart.

ABC Radio Canberra: Hannah Walmsley

Finally, in April 1964, the drought broke and in just six days Lake Burley Griffin was filled.
It was good timing, Dr Firth pointed out that an international regatta had been organised for the very next day.
"They decided that they'd hold it but there was so much wash and turbulence in the water that one of the visiting rowers crashed into the pylon of Kings Avenue bridge, so that was the end of it," she said.
While regattas are no longer held on the lake, it remains a recreational space for many water sports.
Currently, Lake Burley Griffin has no problems when it comes to water supply. Today it's more common to see the gates of Scrivener Dam open to allow excess water to flow downstream and join the Murrumbidgee River.

Commonwealth Bridge slider

Commonwealth Avenue Bridge in the 1960s.

Commonwealth Avenue Bridge in the 1960s.

Richard Clough, National Library of Australia

Commonwealth Avenue Bridge today.

Commonwealth Avenue Bridge today.

ABC News: Elise Pianegonda

Almost seven months after Scrivener Dam's gates were shut. and about 50 years after the lake was designed, Sir Robert Menzies officially opened Lake Burley Griffin.
At the time he noted the capital's long journey to receive its lake but also noted its importance, not just for Canberrans, but also for Australians visiting their capital city.
"It unites this city," he said.

"Some people thought it would divide the city. On the contrary, it has united the city because it has given a centre and a heart to the city.

"I hope it will be a heart that will be quietly beating ... for the rest of our lives."

More about our questioner:

Curious Canberran Scott Mollan.

Curious Canberran Scott Mollan.

Scott Mollan grew up in Canberra but now calls the Illawarra home, though he travels a lot for his work in advertising.

At the moment he mostly jets between his home, Sydney, Los Angeles and China.

He wondered how long Lake Burley Griffin took to fill because his mum always told him that "Canberra was a dust bowl until that point".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snowy Hydro Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Dianne Firth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Burley Griffin</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>-1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Firth</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Kerlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harold Holt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dianne Firth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Heritage Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War I. While</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberrans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Robert</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Mollan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PhD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Library of Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regatta Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberran Scott Mollan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elise Pianegonda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Clough</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thames</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Walmsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Burley Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 17</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Avenue Bridge</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molonglo River</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Robert Menzies</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Depression</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Scrivener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murrumbidgee River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Heritage Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 1964</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scrivener Dam</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
