<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440665217708782</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/melbourne-express-monday-august-7-2017-20170806-gxqjjj.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Express: Monday, August 7, 2017</title>
  <content>
Some pretty extraordinary conditions in the alps on the weekend. Weatherzone says the winds and heavy snow-fall were bad enough to create "virtual white-out conditions".

Mount Hotham's Buff Farnell said the snow had not let up since dawn.
"It's been dumping hard all day ... it's as hard as I've seen it snow, flakes the size of 20-cent pieces and just hammering down all day," he said.
"I went into some spots that hadn't been skied and it was well above my boots, so that's like 40 centimetres deep, but might include a bit of overnight accumulation."
 
Two 16-year-olds have been arrested after leading police on a high-speed chase in Taylors Hill early this morning.

Police on patrol spotted a white Toyota Camry sedan racing through Calder Park Drive about 1.30 this morning. They tracked the car to Mimosa Way, Burnside Heights where it was dumped and four men tried to flee on foot. Police nabbed two of them, and they are now helping police with their inquiries.

Weatherzone says the cause of today's wild weather is a deep low that's sitting across much of south-eastern Australia - check it out in the synoptic. You can also see the cold-front pushing east across Melbourne today.

Looking like it's going to be very wet and wild today, folks - bring a brolly.

The Bureau of Meteorology is tipping a top of 12 with possible hail and thunder.

The Bureau says there's an 80 per cent chance of rainfall. I can inform you that number is now comfortably closer to 100 per cent.
In overnight police news, a 45-year-old Sunshine West man has been charged with murder after the body of a 44-year-old Sunshine West man was found at a house on McGregor Court just after 8.30pm on Saturday August 5.

The man will appear at the Melbourne Magistrates Court today.
Good morning and welcome to Melbourne Express - it's set to be a wet one today folks. Liam Mannix behind the wheel today. Let me know what your run into work is like by emailing liam.mannix@fairfaxmedia.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Mannix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weatherzone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Express</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnside Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Camry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calder Park Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Hotham's Buff Farnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mimosa Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
