<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440789771761591</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/ohio-state-fair-ride-malfuncion-caused-by-excessive-corrosion/8780044</url>
  <title>Ohio fair ride malfunction caused by excessive corrosion on support beam, company says</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

The Dutch manufacturer of a thrill ride that broke apart and killed an 18-year-old man at the Ohio State Fair says excessive corrosion on a support beam led to the "catastrophic failure".
A statement on KMG's website said the company officials visited the accident site and conducted metallurgical tests.
It said the corrosion "dangerously reduced" the thickness on the wall of the beam holding a passenger gondola on the swinging and spinning ride.
The company said the ride was 18 years old.
Tyler Jarrell died from blunt force trauma injuries after being .
Four people remained hospitalised last week, including one woman in a coma.

Video footage captured by a bystander showed the ride swinging back and forth like a pendulum before a part falls off, throwing riders through the air and to the ground as it continued swinging.
"The entire seat came off the ride and went flying," an Ohio witness wrote on Facebook after the incident.
The company that provided the ride to the Ohio State Fair, Amusements of America, described the Fire Ball as an "aggressive thrill" ride.
The ride swung riders 12 metres into the air while rotating at 13 revolutions per minute, the website said.

AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OHIO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ohio State Fair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler Jarrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
