<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440755412022900</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/meghan-markle-says-she-feels-ethnically-ambiguous-as-she-holidays-with-prince-harry/news-story/e58e3f7e5b627174a916e0f0feb8a6fa</url>
  <title>Meghan's admission as rumours swirl</title>
  <content>
MEGHAN Markle has revealed more about her bi-racial upbringing as she continues to enjoy a romantic holiday with Prince Harry in Africa.
In an interview with Pride Magazine in the UK, Ms Markle has told her fans that her life hasn't always been easy.
The Suits actress says she grew up "ethnically ambiguous" with a black parent - referring to her mother Doria.
She told of how they were confronted by racist jokes from people who had no idea her mother was African-American.
Ms Markle, who also said her mother was dubbed the N-word, said she felt an 'obligation' to speak about being half-black.
"I don't care if I'm fair-skinned and I don't care what it is, that's who I am and that's my family," she said.
"My hope is for the world to get to a place where it's colour blind."
After wrapping filming for Suits, she flew to London to meet Prince Harry and the loved-up couple are in Botswana enjoying a secluded, romantic holiday together.
Prince Harry has returned to Botswana for work on local wildlife conservation projects as patron of the Rhino Conservation Botswana charity.
Royal watchers are keeping a close eye on any news about his latest jaunt their with Ms Markle, after Harry has previously taken his former girlfriends Natalie Pinkham, Chelsy Davy and Cressida Bonas to the same location.
It is being seen as an indication that Harry may be closer to proposing to her.
According to the Sunday Express, Ladbrokes have cut the odds to 6/4 that Harry will propose to her.
A spokesman said: "It's a case of when and not if Harry pops the question and royal punters are convinced it will be while the happy couple are on holiday."
Ms Markle will also celebrate her 36th birthday while on the trip with Harry, who turns 33 on September 15.
Some believe he may pop the quesiton before his birthday.
Prince William popped the question to Kate Middleton while on a 2010 holiday to Kenya.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhino Conservation Botswana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Markle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsy Davy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cressida Bonas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladbrokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N-words</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Pinkham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Middleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Express</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meghan Markle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botswana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pride Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
