<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440493419015357</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4835199/cycling-gives-variety-to-training-program/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Cycling gives variety to training program</title>
  <content>
TEAM EFFORT: Peter Haynes from Northern NSW Football with colleagues Jackie Murnain and Nyssa Suchanow took part in the six-hour Variety Spin 4 Kids challenge at Honeysuckle on Friday. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

I had the privilege of taking part in the first ever Variety Spin 4 Kids last Friday and there was a few things that struck me about the outdoor event.
It was a six-hour team challenge on a spin bike, set at Harbour Square, Honeysuckle in fairly blustery conditions, to raise funds for disadvantaged children in the Hunter region.

In all, 36 teams signed up for the inaugural event, which Variety regional director Jason Bourke told me he planned to make an annual fixture on their calendar.

In those 36 teams, which included Newcastle businesses, sporting organisations and local identities, there were 300 people in total taking part.
One guy, Benn Coubrough of Stroke No Limits, took on the challenge solo.
As I pedalled through my half-hour stint with Ladies in Lycra, I started thinking how great it would be to be able to do this every week.
The event was held first and foremost to help kids in need. Money raised funds Variety Heart scholarships for talented Hunter children living with a disadvantage to reach their full potential.
Jason told me they had raised $35,000.
But that was just one positive aspect of the day. 
It was a wonderful community event to be part of.
The atmosphere was electric with music blaring and teammates supporting and encouraging their riders throughout the day.

We are living in a time where obesity has become an epidemic and we need to be promoting physical activity to more people as often as we can.
This was certainly a good advertisement for that and I spoke to a few participants on the day who agreed doing something like it on a regular basis would be a wonderful initiative for the city.
Obviously it wouldn't be for six hours but a Friday lunchtime or afternoon outdoor spin session with the harbour as a backdrop would be fantastic.
A lot of businesses already have quite good health and well-being programs but a lot don't and it was just such a good feeling seeing so many people being active.
Cycle classes have a lot of benefits for a range of people.

Not everyone can run.

But cycling is low impact and can be helpful when recovering from an injury or regaining fitness because you can work at your own pace.

Even sitting there spinning in a low gear is doing something.

According to , the benefits of regular cycling include: "Increased cardiovascular fitness, increased muscle strength and flexibility, improved joint mobility, decreased stress levels, improved posture and coordination, strengthened bones, decreased body fat levels, prevention or management of disease and reduced anxiety and depression."
No one at Harbour Square looked stressed last Friday.
If you are looking for a more adventurous cycle event, the Wollombi Wild Ride is coming up on September 2. It is a mountain bike event for riders of all abilities with 13.5km, 30km and 58km options.

GOING SOLO: Merewether's Benn Coubrough took on the whole six-hour challenge by himself last week. Picture: Jonathan Carroll
Winter Warmer Workout

There are 25 days until spring. Last week I put out the challenge to try 30 minutes of physical activity for the month of August. That might be a combination of strength sessions and cardio workouts.
Interval sessions are a great way to get a solid workout in limited time. Interval training means to work at a different pace (harder then easier) for alternating periods.
Here is a 30-minute interval session you could do on the bike, in the pool, walking or running. 
Hard 2min: easier 2min; 90sec: 90sec; 60sec: 60sec; 30sec: 30sec. Go back to the start. Continue for 30 minutes.
Upcoming Fitness Events

Lake Macquarie Running Festival, August 27, Warners Bay: Sign up for a 21.1km or 10.5km challenge. There is also a 4km kids event. .
Wollombi Wild Ride, September 2, Wollombi: A recreational mountain bike event for riders of varying abilities. There is a mostly flat 13.5km for novices or a 30km or 58km hilly course for the more adventurous and experienced. .
Fernleigh 15, October 22, Fernleigh track: Runners and walkers can complete the full length of the Fernleigh Track traffic-free. There is also a five-person relay option. .

Renee Valentine is a writer, qualified personal trainer and mother of three. r.valentine@fairfaxmedia.com.au.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benn Coubrough of Stroke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harbour Square</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether's Benn Coubrough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Haynes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollombi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fernleigh 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Variety Heart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fernleigh Track</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie Running Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollombi Wild Ride</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Bourke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Valentine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nyssa Suchanow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Variety Spin 4 Kids</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warmer Workout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitness Events</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern NSW Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honeysuckle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie Murnain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fernleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
