<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440802656663601</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/no-splendour-amber-heard-and-elon-musk-break-/3209446/</url>
  <title>No Splendour: Amber Heard and Elon Musk in break-up</title>
  <content>
HOLLYWOOD star Amber Heard has endured her second breakup while visiting Australia.

Currently Down Under filming Aquaman, sources close to Heard have revealed she has split from billionaire boyfriend Elon Musk.

A friend of the pair has told British press that the couple ended their year-long romance last week.

"It's all over between Amber and Elon and she's devastated. It was his decision," the insider told The Mail on Sunday in the UK.

"He ended it a week ago. He'd heard certain things about her behaviour that didn't sit well with him.

"Amber can be very manipulative and selfish. Elon's back in LA while she's licking her wounds in Australia."

It is understood Musk ended the relationship with Heard. Picture: NIGEL HALLETT

The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass music festival in Byron Bay two weeks ago.

The pair have been spotted around the Gold Coast and northern NSW during their time in Australia for filming.

Yesterday, there was radio silence from both camps.

The actor was first linked to the boss of US electric car giant Tesla last summer when they were spotted together in London.

Musk made his first millions as co-founder of online payment service PayPal and currently plans to build the world's largest lithium ion battery in Adelaide.

Last month Heard's father David spoke openly about their relationship which he called serious.

"Amber and Elon are both very serious about each other. She would love to get married," he told Grazia magazine.

"One of the things they want to do is settle down and have a family. They are making plans for that."

Amber Heard with then partner Johnny Depp.

The breakup follows Heard's dramatic divorce from Johnny Depp.

Their relationship broke-down when the couple were living in Australia while Depp filmed Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Men Tell No Tales.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIGEL HALLETT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aquaman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Depp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amber</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Men Tell No Tales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Depp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paypal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grazia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pirates of the Caribbean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amber Heard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
