<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440102576987744</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/technology/boy-9-writes-to-nasa-asking-if-he-can-be-a-guardian-of-the-galaxy/news-story/ca65cb4362943d6c7f11b57b9f9372ea</url>
  <title>Boy's letter to NASA is everything</title>
  <content>
WHEN NASA announced that they would be hiring a planetary protection officer - they would have expected applications from the world's top scientists.
But one nine-year-old boy, a self-proclaimed "guardian of the galaxy", threw his hat into the ring for the job with an adorable application letter,
The young boy, named Jack Davis sent the US space agency a handwritten letter applying for the role, which is set to involve preventing "biological contamination in human and robotic space exploration."
He told NASA that he would be perfect for the job because his sister always tells him he is like an alien and that he is obsessed with sci-fi movies.
Jack, who is in grade four at primary school, wrote: "I may be nine but I would be fit for the job.
"One of the reasons is my sister says I'm an alien. Also I have seen almost all of the space and alien movies I can see.
"I have also seen the show Marvel Agents of Shield and hope to see the movie Men In Black.
"I am great at video games. I am young, so I can learn to think like an alien."
And Jack's letter obviously melted the hearts of those working at NASA as Dr James L. Green, director of the planetary science division, sent him a heartwarming response.
He wrote telling Jack that he was delighted to hear he was a "guardian of the galaxy" and gave him some advice on joining NASA in the future.
Dr Green added: "We are always looking for bright future scientists and engineers to help us, so I hope you will study hard and do well in school.
"We hope to see you here at NASA one of these days!"
But it wasn't just the letter that NASA sent, he also received a phone call from the agency's planetary research director Jonathan Rall, where he congratulated Jack on his interest in space.
The new role at NASA comes as the space agency has been testing its "doomsday defence system" on a 30-metre asteroid that is said to be heading our way in October.
NASA is also giving space fans an insight into what it's like on the International Space Station by taking a Google Street View tour, which will make you feel like you're floating in space.
and is republished with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Space Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Rall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Street View</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Agents of Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. James L. Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man In Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
