<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440751117055565</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/david-riccio-looks-at-20-reasons-why-usain-bolt-will-always-be-the-greatest/news-story/ed74f8d3fb63d415016532565844cb90</url>
  <title>Riccio: 20 reasons Bolt is the greatest</title>
  <content>
CALL him Lightning Bolt. Call him U-Bolt. Call him this generation's Michael Jordan or Muhammad Ali.
As Chief Sports Writer David Riccio explains, here's 20 reasons why Usain Bolt will always be the GREATEST.
1. Veteran US sports broadcaster Bob Costas suggested what few would dare; Bolt is a more popular Jamaican than Bob Marley. Cool man.
2. The fastest man in the world suffers from scoliosis (an abnormal curve in the spine). He took up athletics to keep his back strong.
BOLT HOLE:
UPSTAGED:
REPORT:
3. He's the only sports star in the world who would find being run over by a Segway scooter funny.
4. He'll party with you. Bolt landed at 10pm in Melbourne last year and by midnight had taken over as DJ of an exclusive nightclub, Alumbra.
5. Bolt once adopted the world's fastest cat; a cheetah.
6. He has commenced a war against drug cheats by declaring dopers will kill athletics.
7. Everyone from Obama to Prince Harry have struck the famous "Lightning Bolt" pose.
8. At the 2008 Beijing Games, U-Bolt ate 1,000 Chicken McNuggets in 10-days and still won three gold medals.
9. His appreciation from fans is legendary. On a trip to Sydney, Bolt told his own security guards to step aside so he could take 'selfies' with every person inside an auditorium.
10. Midway through a post-race interview with a reporter, Bolt stopped answering questions so he could respect the US national anthem being played in the background.
11. In a 2010 charity match, 'Lightning' clean-bowled sexist West Indian cricketer Chris Gayle.
12. Bolt invited Padstow's 400m sprinter James Kermond to personally train with him in Jamaica earlier this year. "Experience of a lifetime,'' Kermond called it.
13. His first coach in high school, Pablo McNeil, felt frustrated by a young Usain's lack of dedication to his training and his obsession for practical jokes.
14. He chose to race over 100m and 200m because he says he's too lazy to run 400m.
15. His $32.5m in earning over the last 12 months is 10 times what other track and field stars like Mo Farah and Ashton Eaton bank.
16. He donated $1.3m to his financially-strapped former school. Included in the donation were 50 pairs of football boots, shin guards and 50 Usain Bolt branded footballs.
17. He's the first man to win the 100 and the 200 in three consecutive Olympics.
18. The only time Bolt did not win an Olympic gold medal between 2008 and 2016 was when he was disqualified by a false start in the 100m final of the 2011 world champions.
19. He won 20 Olympic and world championship medals - the most in the sport's history.
20. He's famously declared that he wants people to add 'Usain Bolt' to the list when sport's greatest including Muhammad Ali, Michael Jordan and Pele' are being discussed. Done.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beijing Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Costas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Gayle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pablo McNeil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kermond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Kermond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Segway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jordan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mo Farah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicken McNuggets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Sports Writer David Riccio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Padstow's 400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muhammad Ali</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Marley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashton Eaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U-Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alumbra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOLT HOLE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riccio: 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
