<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440411814635973</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/live-enhancing-devices-give-back-independence/3209360/</url>
  <title>Live-enhancing devices give back independence</title>
  <content>
THEIR brief was to create a life-enhancing device for someone with a disability and that's certainly what they did.

Animatronics Anonymous, a group of engineering students from the Queensland University of Technology, designed a glove for a man with upper limb hemiplegia, which in its most severe form causes complete paralysis of half of the body.

Chelsea Kramer said the glove was designed to "give back independence and take back the livelihood".

Animatronics Anonymous was one of the seven teams that participated in the second Queensland Assistive Devices Hackathon at TAFE Queensland South West at the weekend.

The Queensland Government-funded quest was developed to coincide with the rollout of the National Disability Insurance Scheme.

Teams were given a challenge from a person with a disability and had to work around the criteria of innovation, scalability and affordability.

The hackathon's project manager, Karli Austin, said judges praised Animatronics Anonymous for their "innovation but also the applicability to a wider range of markets".

She said all the teams had formed bonds with their challengers.

Other life-enhancing devices designed over the weekend included a story clock and a cooking device, Maid to Measure.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Disability Insurance Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Kramer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Assistive Devices Hackathon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government-funded</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland University of Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Animatronics Anonymous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karli Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE Queensland South West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
