<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439801929274029</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/3201470/illawarra-day-care-centres-get-lowest-rating/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Illawarra child care centres get lowest rating</title>
  <content>
Two Illawarra day care centres are being closely monitored by the nation's childcare watchdog, after being slapped with the lowest possible quality rating, potentially putting children's safety at risk.

Four Seasons Family Day Care in Cringila and Wollongong's Up and Ready Family Day Care failed to meet six of the seven quality areas set by the Australian Children's Education & Care Quality Authority (ACECQA).
Both providers were rated "significant improvement required".
An ACECQA spokeswoman said she could not discuss individual cases but the rating was only given to a service that did not meet the quality areas "to an extent that it is considered to be a risk to the safety of children".
The two Illawarra operators rated poorly in educational program and practice, children's health and safety, physical environment, staffing arrangements, collaborative partnerships with families and communities and leadership and service management.
They each rated slightly higher as "working towards" in the final quality area of relationships with children.
Across the seven quality areas, ACECQA assesses 18 standards, including 58 specific elements.
If a provider is given a "significant improvement required" rating for just one standard, they will receive that rating for the entire quality area.
"The [NSW Department of Education] will tell the service where it needs to improve and will work with the service until that occurs," the ACECQA spokeswoman said.

"There are penalties for services that don't improve and if needed, their operating licence can be cancelled which means they would be shut down."
Four Seasons general manager Mohamed Issak said the centre was "working hard on a lot of things at the moment" and referred the Illawarra Mercury to the centre's director, who did not provide comment by deadline. Up and Ready spokeswoman Joseline Manamfasha said her educators were also "working hard" to improve, and hoped it would be reflected in the future.
Across the Illawarra there are 182 childcare centres ranging from preschools to after-school care, long day care and family day care, with 39 per cent of those assessed as "exceeding" national quality standards.
Only one facility was deemed "Excellent" - the highest rating an education and care service can achieve - St Luke's Pre-School in Dapto.
Director Julie Irving applied for the special rating because she wanted the school "to be acknowledged for the good that we already do" for three to five-year-olds.

"We wanted to show that we can produce that quality regardless of funding and parliamentary support," she said. "We embrace the differences in children's learning styles ... so each child has an individual program in our service," Ms Irving said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Luke's Pre-School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Irving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Mercury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Children's Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care Quality Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ready Family Day Care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACECQA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Irving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Issak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cringila</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong's Up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seasons Family Day Care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseline Manamfasha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
