<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440617973068040</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/05/58/children-sexual-behaviour-teachers-research</url>
  <title>Teachers need more training to identify worrying sexual behaviour in children, research suggests</title>
  <content>
Children as young as five are displaying concerning sexual behaviour at school, promoting concerns teachers are ill-equipped to differentiate between potential victims of sexual abuse or if they are imitating what they see in music videos and ads, new research has revealed.
the research shows teachers feel they are not educated enough about problematic sexual behaviours to confidently manage increasing incidences in Australian schools.
In in the journal Sex Education, Dr Lesley-anne Ey asked more than 100 teachers from government, independent and Catholic primary schools across Australia about their experiences with children's problematic sexual behaviours, and their management strategies in schools.
Dr Ey told Fairfax Media she was surprised to discover 40 percent of teachers involved in the the research reported witnessing problematic sexual behaviour in schools, including simulated intercourse, attempts to coerce other students into sexual conduct, and in one case, a year 4 child who threatened to rape other students.
While teachers said they were confident about mandatory reporting requirements, they were less confident about how to deal with children displaying concerning behaviour.
Dr Ey said access to smartphones and devices were connecting children as young as eight to a range of online content, including pornography.
"If kids are acting out inappropriately, whatever the reason, it's a problem. But the issue for many teachers is knowing how to respond to what they see," Dr Ey said.

Related Articles

"We don't want kids being treated or labelled as deviants because they are copying behaviour they understand to be normal because they see it at home or on television."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lesley-anne Ey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Ey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
