<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440665217708765</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-07/venezuela-crushes-antimaduro-uprising-at-military-base-authorities-slam-terrorist-attack/1691674</url>
  <title>Venezuela crushes anti-Maduro uprising at military base; authorities slam 'terrorist attack'</title>
  <content>
Venezuelan authorities have suppressed a rebellion at a military base near the city of Valencia, arresting seven men who they say participated in a "terrorist attack" against the Government of unpopular leftist President Nicolas Maduro.
On Sunday, a video circulated on social media showing a group of men in military uniform announcing an uprising in the wake of the creation of a pro-government legislative superbody on Friday, .
"This is not a coup d'etat," said a man who identified himself as Juan Carlos Caguaripano, a former National Guard captain.
"This is a civic and military action to re-establish constitutional order. But more than that, it is to save the country from total destruction."
Hundreds took to the streets in Valencia to support the uprising, resident Carolina Herrera said, who like other witnesses reported shots through the night.
But hooded protesters had been largely dispelled with tear gas by midday (local time) on Sunday, and the rest of the South American country of 30 million appeared to be calm.
Still, the episode highlights how  over what foes call a lurch into dictatorship in the middle of a bruising economic crisis.
Venezuela's armed forces issued a statement calling the rebellion an ill-fated "propaganda show" aimed at destabilising the country and reaffirmed their allegiance to Mr Maduro.
Authorities said the men were mercenaries working for a US-backed opposition to bring down nearly two decades of Socialism in oil-rich Venezuela, raising the spectre of a further Government crackdown on dissent in coming days.
"These attacks, planned by delirious minds in Miami, only strengthen the morale of our armed forces and the Bolivarian people," Socialist Party official Elias Jaua said.
The latest apparent bid to spur a national uprising comes  in Caracas by helicopter, but also failed to spark a larger movement.
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juan Carlos Caguaripano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socialist Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIAMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolina Herrera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Guard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valencia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elias Jaua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
