<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440532073721335</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/before-the-bell/asx-to-open-higher-after-dow-extends-winning-streak-20170804-gxpx9g</url>
  <title>ASX to open higher after Dow extends winning streak</title>
  <content>
by
Timothy Moore

The Dow powered higher for an eighth consecutive day over the weekend as more positive economic news strengthened  and the Trump administration revived chatter about tax reform.
The benchmark 30-member index rose 0.3 per cent, extending its record setting streak and its advance above the 22,000-point mark. Goldman Sachs and JPMorgan were among the top three advancers.
The S&P 500 and the Nasdaq each added 0.2 per cent. For the week, the Dow gained 1.2 per cent, helped by Apple's post-results surge; the S&P 500 rose 0.2 per cent and the Nasdaq slid 0.4 per cent.
Over the weekend the better-than-expected July jobs report temporarily edged corporate results aside.

Total nonfarm payroll employment increased by 209,000 in July, and the unemployment rate was little changed at 4.3 per cent, the US Bureau of Labor Statistics reported late on Friday. Employment growth has averaged 184,000 per month thus far this year, in line with the average monthly gain of 187,000 in 2016.

"US growth is just fast enough to support profits and keep workers fully employed (and spending), but not fast enough to jolt wages, inflation or interest rates," said Bank of Montreal senior economist Sal Guatieri.
"A patient Fed means a slow grind higher for Treasury yields," said Mr Guatieri. "The Dow may take longer to reach its next milestone, but the macro climate remains supportive of further moves in that direction."
The first expected step by the Fed is to proceed, as it has signalled, with the start of a very gradual paring down its massive balance sheet. That decision is expected at the Fed's September policy meeting.
Second, the jobs data has firmed ever so slightly bets that US interest rates could rise for a third time before the year is out even though inflation remains reluctant to rise.

The latest wage growth data showed a modest improvement. In July, average hourly earnings for all employees on private nonfarm payrolls rose by 9 cents to $US26.36. Over the year, average hourly earnings have risen by 65 cents, or 2.5 per cent; unchanged from June's pace.
For the Dow, as well as the Standard & Poor's 500 and the Nasdaq, steady upward economic momentum and solid corporate results are the key.
Analysts, on average, expect S&P 500 earnings to have grown 12 per cent in the second quarter and they project earnings up 9.3 per cent for the September quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S.
Among the US companies poised to report this week: CBS, Marriott, CVS Health, Walt Disney, Ralph Lauren, Twenty-First Century Fox, Office Depot, Agrium, Nvidia and Snap as well as retailers Macy's, Nordstrom, Kohl's and JC Penney.

Today's Agenda

Local data: AiG performance of construction July, ANZ job ads July
Overseas data: China second quarter current account; German industrial production June; US consumer credit June; Fed speaker: Kashkari
Market Highlights

SPI futures up 22 points or 0.4% to 5682
AUD -0.3% to 79.29 US cents (Session range: 0.7891 - 0.7980)
On Wall St, Dow +0.3%, S&P 500 +0.2%, Nasdaq +0.2%
In New York, BHP +1%, Rio +1.4%

In Europe, Stoxx 50 +1.2%, FTSE +0.5%, CAC +1.4%, DAX +1.2%
Spot gold -0.7% to $US1259.20 an ounce
Brent crude +0.7% to $US52.37 a barrel
US oil +1% to $US49.53 a barrel
Iron ore +1.6% to $US74.12 a tonne
Dalian iron ore +2.7% to 563 yuan
LME aluminium -0.3% to $US1910.50 a tonne
LME copper +0.3% to $US6372 a tonne

10-year bond yield: US 2.26%, Germany 0.46%, Australia 2.62%
From Today's
Financial Review

United States

The Dow Jones Industrial Average ended at its eighth straight record high on Friday, with gains in JPMorgan Chase and other banks after data showed US employers hired more workers than expected in July.
"We would expect next week to see market highs again just based on the positive tone created by strong second-quarter earnings and favourable outlooks," said Tim Ghriskey, chief investment officer of Solaris Group. "We're really in a sweet spot here."

For the week, the Dow climbed 1.2 per cent, the S&P 500 rose 0.2 per cent and the Nasdaq shed 0.4 per cent.
: US employers hired more workers than expected in July and raised their wages, signs of labour market tightness.
Perceived chances of an interest rate hike by the US central bank by the end of the year increased to 50 percent from 46 percent after the release of the data, according to CME Group's FedWatch tool.
White House economic adviser Gary Cohn suggested that the US must cut its corporate tax rate by at least a third to compete with other developed countries. Cohn highlighted the importance of getting the current 35 per cent US corporate rate more in line with the average rate among countries in the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development, which is about 23 per cent. A White House tax outline released in April had set the 15 per cent goal for corporations and pass-through businesses.
Martin Shkreli was convicted of fraud by jurors in a US court in Brooklyn on Friday, in a blow for the controversial former drug company and hedge fund executive, who had forcefully and repeatedly proclaimed his innocence. Shkreli showed little emotion as the verdict was read, but outside the courthouse portrayed it as a victory, though he could face up to 20 years in prison for securities fraud.
Europe

European shares ended the week on a strong note as a drop in the euro helped shares in exporters, while investors also focused on a raft of company results with insurance firm Swiss Re hit after missing profit estimates.
The regional STOXX 600 index was ended with a gain of 1 per cent, rallying into the close with all sectors in positive territory as the euro - a source of pain for the index over the past months - eased and the dollar gained following the strong US jobs report. Euro zone blue chips rose 1.2 per cent.

While both Germany's DAX and Britain's FTSE 100 also gained, the STOXX also posted its first weekly gain after two weeks of losses.
"The decline in the pound and the euro accelerated the move higher in the FTSE 100, DAX and CAC 40," David Madden, market analyst at CMC Markets UK, said.
Nearly two thirds of the companies listed on the MSCI Europe index have already released results. Of them, 61 per cent have either beaten or matched expectations with second-quarter earnings growth expected at more than 22 per cent, according to Thomson Reuters data.
Swiss Re was the biggest single drag on the STOXX, down around 3 per cent after the world's second-largest reinsurer reported a bigger than expected 35 percent drop in first-half net profit as claims from natural disasters weighed.
Volkswagen executive Oliver Schmidt pleaded guilty on Friday in US District Court in Detroit in connection with a massive diesel emissions scandal that has cost the German auto maker as much as $US25 billion. Under a plea agreement, Schmidt will face up to seven years in prison and a fine of between $US40,000 and $US400,000 after admitting to conspiring to mislead US regulators and violating clean air laws.
Asia

Shanghai stocks fell on Friday, but managed to notch their seventh straight week of gains, bolstered by the continued robust performance of resources firms. The blue-chip CSI300 index fell 0.5 per cent, to 3707.58 points, while the Shanghai Composite Index lost 0.3 per cent to 3262.08 points.
Baoshan Iron & Steel, the country's largest steelmaker, advanced 4.1 per cent to a more than 2-year high. The stock has gained 27.6 per cent this year.

"The strong rally in cyclicals, including steelmakers and non-ferrous metals producers, is not over yet, as valuations for those firms remain low," Changjiang Securities said in a report.
For the week, the CSI300 was down 0.4 per cent, while the SSEC gained 0.3 per cent.
Hong Kong stocks inched up on Friday to post their fourth consecutive week of gains, helped by a robust rally in resources and financial firms. The Hang Seng index rose 0.1 per cent, to 27,562.68 points, while the China Enterprises Index was unchanged at 11,003.08 points. For the week, HSI gained 2.2 per cent, while HSCE added 2.3 per cent, largely led by strong gains in material and financial firms.
Japan's Nikkei share average slipped on Friday as the yen's rise to seven-week highs overshadowed optimism on corporate earnings, while Mazda Motor rose ahead of an expected announcement of a capital alliance with Toyota Motor. The Nikkei shed 0.4 per cent to 19,952.33, but stayed flat on the week. The trading range in which it has remained since mid-June has narrowed.
The broader Topix fell 0.2 per cent to 1631.45, maintaining its outperformance versus the Nikkei since June thanks to strength in small-cap shares.
The so-called NT ratio, which measures the Nikkei's value relative to the Topix, fell to 12.23, its lowest level since February 2016.
Japanese companies that have reported quarterly earnings so far saw a 12.9 per cent rise in operating profit, with 60 percent of them beating market expectations, according to Okasan Securities. Market players also noted, however, that many shares tended to fall, or quickly lose gains, even if their earnings were in line with expectations.
Currencies

Bloomberg's US dollar index surged as much as 0.8 per cent Friday on a government report showing that the US added 209,000 jobs in July. The data highlighted the strength of the world's biggest economy and sparked a surprising reversal for the greenback.
"It is more of a story of providing underlying dollar support at key levels rather than a full-on reversal," said Alan Ruskin, global co-head of foreign-exchange research at Deutsche Bank. "Unfortunately for the dollar, the ideal dollar scenario needs a significant change in Fed expectations."
Europe's shared currency bottomed out on Friday just above the $US1.1714 level it exceeded last week for the first time in almost two years. A lower level, at $US1.1616, will also provide support, Ruskin said.
Technical indicators had suggested the greenback was due for a reversal. As of the end of trading on Thursday, the dollar index's relative strength index showed the greenback was oversold on a daily and weekly basis, with the latter's reading the lowest since 2007. It remains stretched on a weekly perspective.
Euro three-month risk reversals, a barometer of medium-term directional bias, remain bullish on the shared currency, with calls at premium levels last seen in 2009.
Commodities

Brazilian iron ore export volumes to China increased by 17.5 per cent year-on-year in July, according to figures released by the country's foreign trade ministry, MDIC. Shipments came to 18.17 million tonnes, against 15.46 million tonnes a year before.
China's benchmark rebar and hot rolled coil futures contracts surged 2.3-2.9 per cent per tonne during the day on Friday, with the former hitting a four-year high, according to Metal Bulletin. The September and January iron ore contracts also both saw their values increase by 1%. The weathervane billet price in Tangshan rose by another 50 yuan ($US7.40) per tonne to a multi-year high as well. Amid such strong steel prices and profit margins, mills continued to seek out high-grade iron ore, especially Carajas fines. At least four shipments of the top-grade product have changed hands in the past three days, at prices about $US17 per tonne higher than the 62 per cent Fe index.

Zinc prices clawed higher on Friday, getting a boost from another surge in Chinese steel prices and from investors who are still bullish about shortages of the metal developing.
Some investors have become wary about zinc's bull story after Chinese output unexpectedly rose 17 per cent month-on-month in June despite last year's closures and suspensions in zinc mines, said analyst Vivienne Lloyd at Macquarie.
"That's made people wonder whether the expectation of zinc cuts has been too optimistic and in fact the Chinese smelters are able to continue to produce at stronger levels than expected," she said. "We tend to think that one month's print isn't enough to ruin the bull story, but it has caught our attention ... I think people today are looking at whether it has been carried down too far and are thinking about entry points."
Benchmark zinc on the London Metal Exchange closed 0.7 per cent higher at $US2812 a tonne after slipping 0.3 per cent in the previous session.
LME aluminium finished down 0.3 per cent at $US1910.50 a tonne.
"While governmental interference poses the biggest upside risk given the world's reliance on Chinese exports, we believe this is to a large extent already reflected in today's (aluminium) prices," Carsten Menke at Julius Baer said in a note. "We remain of the opinion that oversupply should persist, pushing prices towards our 3- and 12-month targets of $US1750 per tonne."
Three-month LME copper ended 0.3 per cent firmer at $US6372 a tonne, lead shed 0.3 per cent to $US2361, nickel lost 1.3 per cent to $US10,250 and tin ended 0.7 per cent weaker at $US20,510.
Working rigs targeting crude fell by 1, bringing the total to 765, according to Baker Hughes data reported over the weekend. Producers ended 23 straight weeks of additions with a pullback at the end of June, breaking the longest stretch of continuous growth in three decades. Even so, more than twice as many rigs are drilling for oil now than in May 2016, when the count hit a low point of 316.
Australian Sharemarket

A large slump in Commonwealth Bank held the sharemarket back on Friday, but the ASX still managed to end the first week of earnings season slightly higher.
Investors on Friday moved more aggressively to sell CBA shares as further details emerged of the scope of the civil case being brought against the bank by the anti-money laundering regulator. CBA shares dropped a sharp 3.9 per cent to drag the benchmark S&P/ASX 200 index down 0.25 per cent to 5720.6 points.
The index still ended the week 0.3 per cent higher despite a mixed batch of earnings reports.
Street Talk

with Reuters, Bloomberg, AAP
Comments? Questions? Let us know what you think of Before the Bell. You can reach Timothy Moore at timothy.moore@fairfaxmedia.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Enterprises Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kohl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.1616</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1750</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Metal Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nordstrom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CME Group's FedWatch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSI300</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LME</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC +1.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okasan Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$40,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baker Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walt Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Changjiang Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of Montreal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CMC Markets UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hang Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solaris Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US52.37</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julius Baer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2812</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MDIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed's September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany's DAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Nikkei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX +1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metal Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CVS Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STOXX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US20,510</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baoshan Iron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSCI Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sharemarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nvidia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shkreli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office Depot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow +0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiss RE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2361</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1910.50</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio +1.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Guatieri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.62</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US26.36</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Motors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detroit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD -0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SSEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Ruskin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tangshan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Madden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JC Penney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikkei</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones Industrial Average</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 400,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's FTSE 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Cohn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10,250</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda Motor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 (  ): +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ralph Lauren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US49.53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carajas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 2.26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kashkari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Composite Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6372</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Shkreli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 +1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74.12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruskin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poor's 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Ghriskey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE +0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carsten Menke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sal Guatieri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vivienne Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg's US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Economic Co-operation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Bureau of Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP +1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan Chase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agrium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1259.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US7.40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.1714</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty First Century Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
