<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440789771761616</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-now-news-in-90-seconds-for-august-7-2017-20170806-gxqge0.html</url>
  <title>Canberra Now: Aged care abuse claims and a boxer fighting stereotypes</title>
  <content>
Good morning Canberra,
Last night's rain is set to hang around today, with cloudy skies and showers forecast to start the week, with the chance of a thunderstorm and possibly hail. However, it's set to clear in the late afternoon or evening . Today's minimum temperature of 4 degrees is set to rise to a top of 9 degrees. 
Here's what's making news this morning.
Fresh aged care abuse claims

The Health Department has imposed sanctions on Adria Village aged care home in Canberra's south due to "serious concerns" about residents' health, safety and wellbeing.
In a separate development, alleged physical and sexual abuse within the ACT's aged care sector has been detailed in federal Aged Care Complaints Commissioner reports.

Government inspectors were told a resident was afraid to leave their room after another resident allegedly grabbed their groin, one report said.
Steven Trask .
Nail salon probe

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

At least a quarter of Canberra nail salons have been investigated in the past two years and several hit with health and safety sanctions linked to vermin infestations, unsafe chemical practices, poor infection control and cleanliness.
Advocacy groups have also questioned working conditions, with one migrant women's network describing long hours, underpayment and an expectation that employees perform household jobs for bosses.
An appetite for fast and cheap beauty treatments has seen a 13-fold increase in the number of nail salons in Canberra in almost as many years. Emily Baker . 
Light rail casts doubt over cemetery expansion

Woden Valley Community Council president Fiona Carrick is worried about Woden Cemetery's plan to expand into public parks.  Photo: Karleen Minney

The ACT government has been urged to find alternatives to the , after City Services Minister Meegan Fitzharris said it was being reconsidered because of light rail.
Ms Fitzharris told a budget estimates committee the government was having "another think" about expanding the cemetery, which will run out of space next year. She flagged a Gungahlin expansion as a possible alternative.
Woden Valley Community Council president Fiona Carrick said .
Katie Burgess has more .
Hackett blaze destroys unit

Fire destroyed a unit at Haddon Court apartment block in Hackett.  Photo: Jamila Toderas​

Police are expected to investigate the cause of a on Sunday evening.
While no one was at home at the unit at the time of the fire, the residents of two of three adjoining Haddon Court units were forced to leave their homes.
Neighbours huddled outside in heavy rain and hail as firefighters retrieved some of their belongings from their units.
Fighting stereotypes

Bianca Elmir at Stockade Training Centre in Dickson. Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong

Fitting in has never been part of Canberra boxer Bianca Elmir's DNA. The self-described outsider has made fighting a way of life, something she has had to do both in the ring and outside it.
As a young Muslim woman who doesn't fit a stereotype, she has been abused by co-workers because of her faith but also rejected by sponsors for not being Muslim enough and refusing to wear a headscarf.
Sitthixay Ditthavong's  show Elmir is using her own journey to educate and inspire other young Muslim women.
Today's cartoon

Pat Campbell

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bianca Elmir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Trask</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adria Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woden Cemetery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karleen Minney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockade Training Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bianca Elmir's DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haddon Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Carrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fitzharris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Services Minister Meegan Fitzharris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elmir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sitthixay Ditthavong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woden Valley Community Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aged Care Complaints Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
