<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440446174374661</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/world/historian-mary-beard-abused-on-social-media-over-her-comments-on-roman-britains-ethnic-diversity/news-story/4eb71a116e6567062ffe28a4f0898fa0</url>
  <title>Historian trolled for diversity claim</title>
  <content>
FAMED British historian Mary Beard, who has long been on the receiving end of online trolling, has said she has faced a "torrent of aggressive insults" on social media after posting messages about the ethnic diversity of Roman Britain.
The popular claccissist used the online social media site to voice her support for a BBC educational cartoon depicting a black Roman soldier and his family.
But she became the target for misogynistic abuse from members of the public, some of whom admitted having never read a single book on ancient history.

this is the kind of stuff that goes on...'everything you write is BS..' Sorry I dont think it is! And the omnium gatherum of'black.. etc ' !

Oh dear. Prof Taleb still talks re my BS. Another says 'one swift meme jihad would be enough to force Mary Beard into retirement' (reported)

She was referred to as a "batty old broad pretending Romans were black", "shrill", "a pretentious know-nothing", "f****** retarded", and "a bum".
One person said Beard was "literally rewriting history".
Professor Beard hit back at the trolls, tweeting: "I fear I'm about to lose my usual courteous patience with those who sound off on Roman Britain without any info at all. so will shut up."
Last week she used a post on the Times Literary Supplement to clarify her position, and explained: "I have been in something of a Twitter storm over the past few days, all because of an argument about the ethnic diversity of Roman Britain (sounds harmless enough you think, well ... just see).
"I think, for example, that the BBC character was loosely based (with a bit of a chronological shift) on Quintus Lollius Urbicus, a man from what is now Algeria, who became governor of Britain
"One thing is for sure, the Roman empire - Britain included - was cultural and ethnically diverse, from the Syrians in Bath, to Quintus Lollius Urbicus, the Ethiopian who met Septimius Severus on Hadrian's Wall and the wonderful couple from South Shields, Barates and Queenie ('Regina'), he from Palmyra, she an Essex girl."

ffs. I don't want to restrict history to historians for moment.But spent 2 days debating Roman Britain with those who had read nothing on it

Professor Beard said the trolling got worse when Nassim Nicholas Taleb, a professor of risk analysis in the US and author of the best-selling book The Black Swan, criticised her.
Beard told Taleb on Twitter that this kind of family in Roman Britain was unsurprising. He questioned her scholarship and accused her of "talking bulls**t".
Writing in her blog, Beard said: "I think I was courteous throughout, though I guess that is for others to judge. I think Professor Taleb did get annoyed when I said that I had read his 'pop risk' book, not the others. But I was actually trying to make clear that I had some knowledge of his work, though not a lot."
She also said that some of her critics, who acknowledged Taleb's professorship, dismissed hers by calling her "Ms Beard". "I don't actually give a stuff about academic titles, but you see what's going on here," she wrote.

Wusses in UK intelligentsia who hate the Pol.Cor.Gestapo yet are afraid to speak.
They study in detail Ceasar, Hanbl, but they are wusses.

Support for the respected Cambridge University scholar came from the author J K Rowling, politician Jess Phillips, singer Billy Bragg and fellow academics.
Rowling tweeted: "A historian gave her expert opinion on ethnic diversity in Roman Britain. What Happened Next Will Not Amaze You", while Phillips added: "Man alive @wmarybeard takes some c*** on here.

I got >1000 insults hurled at me by the Brit IYI mob, posts on hist newsletters, etc.
I am still around (haha)
What wd break me? 10^5? 10^6?

Professor Beard said she would not block her opponents because "it feels to me like leaving the bullies in charge of the playground. And it's rather too much like what women have been advised to do for centuries. Don't answer back and just turn away".
She has previously spoke about confronting one of her online abusers and then taking him out to lunch. She said the man broke down and apologised for his behaviour.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Algeria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit IYI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Bragg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Beard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Taleb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hadrian's Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Times Literary Supplement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Britain</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pol.Cor.Gestapo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Beard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmyra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Swan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Septimius Severus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nassim Nicholas Taleb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FAMED British</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanbl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Happened Next Will Not Amaze You</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ethiopians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quintus Lollius Urbicus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taleb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Taleb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Shields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Beard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J.K. Rowling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ceasar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
