<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440802656663645</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/crows-embrace-being-the-hunted-kelly</url>
  <title>Crows embrace being 'the hunted': Kelly</title>
  <content>
Crows defender Jake Kelly is embracing Adelaide's status

ADELAIDE defender Jake Kelly wants the Crows to embrace the expectation of being the premiership favourites.

The top of the table Crows shook off last week's disappointing draw with Collingwood in the best way possible, belting fifth-placed Port Adelaide by 84 points at Adelaide Oval on Sunday night.

The Crows have now cemented a place in the top four with three home and away games remaining.

"I love it knowing we're the hunted rather than hunting," Kelly told AFL.com.au.

"I love it personally, knowing that teams feel like they are up against it with us each week.

"We've guaranteed top-four now, which is great, but now it's about cementing that top two or ideally top spot going into finals.

"We've just got to bring that consistency though, because last week wasn't good enough."

The Crows have prided themselves on winning the contested possession battle all season, but were smashed in that area against the Magpies.

They turned things around dramatically in the space of a week, with the Crows dominating the Power whenever the ball was in dispute.

"Against Collingwood we were disappointing in contested ball, that starts our whole game," Kelly said.

"It looks great when we move the ball so quickly, but all that has started from the contest, so that's what we've got to make sure we can do consistently.

"We were at the level tonight, and it's about doing it next week and coming with the same attitude and effort."

Kelly has become an important part of the Crows backline, building on his 10 games from 2015 after not being able to force his way into the side last year.

The 22-year-old is off-contract at the end of the season, but has started negotiations on a new deal.

He doesn't believe the speculation around the futures of teammates Jake Lever and Mitch McGovern has put his own talks on the backburner.

"I thought potentially it could have been, but it's been a normal process for me," Kelly said.

"I've spoken to them recently in the last week or so, so hopefully that progresses in the next few weeks.

"It's going well."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
