<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440802656663613</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/injury-wrap-premiers-sweating-on-scans</url>
  <title>Injury wrap: Premiers sweating on scans</title>
  <content>
WESTERN Bulldogs vice-captain Easton Wood could be out for the rest of the season after badly injuring his left hamstring against the Brisbane Lions, joining fellow defenders Dale Morris (broken arm) and Marcus Adams (foot) on the sidelines. 

The 27-year-old reached high up on his hamstring as he was wrapped up in a Jarrod Berry tackle midway through the first term and hopped off the ground in the hands of trainers.

Wood, who suffered separate hamstring setbacks last year that forced him to miss a total of six matches, was ruled out of the game. 

"It's probably more likely it's a bad one than just a two or three-weeker," Bulldogs coach Luke Beveridge said post-match.

"They always scan it and we'll give more during the week, but it appears as though he's hurt pretty badly." 

Meanwhile, Bulldogs rebounding defender Jason Johannisen was a late out against the Lions with a hamstring complaint. 

Brisbane Lions draftee Cedric Cox had ice applied to his right ankle during the second quarter against the Bulldogs and sat out the rest of the contest.

Fellow draftee Alex Witherden had his right hamstring assessed at the interchange area late in the final quarter against the Bulldogs. 

The pair will have scans to determine the severity of their respective setbacks. 

Geelong captain Joel Selwood will have surgery on his left ankle after scans confirmed he suffered a syndesmosis injury against Sydney. 

The 29-year-old will miss the Cats' last three rounds of the season, but the club expects him to be available in time for the finals in just over a month. 

Selwood, who hurt his left ankle in two separate incidents, first rolled the outside of his ankle when he stood on teammate Zac Smith's foot in a marking contest late in the second quarter.

He had his ankle strapped and performed a fitness test in the rooms during the main break, before starting the third quarter on the ground. 

Selwood then suffered the more severe injury to the same ankle late in the third term as his leg got caught under a Lance Franklin tackle - this time twisting inwards.

The tough skipper began the last term on the ground but was wrapped in cotton wool a few minutes later.

, saying surgery was deemed the best option after "consulting with specialists in the field". 

Joel Selwood has come off after this incident.

Essendon small forward Orazio Fantasia picked up an untimely right hamstring injury in the first quarter against Carlton.

The 21-year-old, who has played every game this season and kicked 38 goals, burst through the middle of the ground at full speed when he pulled up short and handballed. 

Fantasia immediately limped off and had ice applied to his leg shortly after, playing no further part in the match. 

Orazio Fantasia's day is over after injuring his hamstring.

Collingwood midfielder Levi Greenwood looks set for a spell on the sidelines after hyperextending his left knee before half-time against North Melbourne.

The 28-year-old ran into Todd Goldstein as the Kangaroos' ruckman was swung off-balance in a tackle. 

Greenwood was helped off the ground and was on crutches in the rooms.

Magpies coach Nathan Buckley said Greenwood had suffered a suspected medial ligament injury, with more to be known following scans. 

Levi Greenwood collided with Todd Goldstein at the end of the first half and was helped from the ground.

Fellow Collingwood onballer Daniel Wells entered the game against North "clean and clear" after battling a corked thigh last week, according to Buckley. 

However, the 32-year-old aggravated the injury after overstretching for an aerial ball in a marking contest during the second quarter. 

He had his left thigh heavily strapped at the start of the third term and battled through the game despite being restricted in his movement. 

Wells was rested in the closing minutes of the game. 

North Melbourne key forward Ben Brown spent Saturday night in hospital after being knocked out in a tackle from Collingwood ruckman Brodie Grundy during the second quarter. 

Brown was tackled from behind and hit his head on the turf while his arms were pinned.

The star Kangaroo briefly laid motionless before slowly rolling onto his back while the club's medical team went to his aid.

Play was halted for several minutes as Brown was fitted with a neck brace and taken from the ground on a motorised stretcher.

Brown, who gave the thumbs up to the crowd as he left the field, was taken to hospital as a precaution and was resting at home on Sunday. 

Ben Brown is being taken off on the stretcher following this tackle from Brodie Grundy.

In other injury concerns in round 20:

- Adelaide midfielder David Mackay was hampered by a corked thigh against Port Adelaide. "Generally, you can come up with those, but it was a fairly solid one that happened early," Crows coach Don Pyke said post-match. 

- Adelaide defender Daniel Talia was rested late in the game as a precaution after experiencing an apparent groin complaint against Port Adelaide. 

- Fremantle small forward Brady Grey suffered a right hamstring injury in the second term against Gold Coast and did not feature after half-time. 

- Gold Coast midfielder Aaron Hall picked up a right hamstring injury in the second quarter against Fremantle and sat out the rest of the game with ice strapped around his leg. 

- Gold Coast midfielder David Swallow was a late out against Fremantle with a tight groin. 

- Melbourne youngster Christian Salem looked in serious trouble after his lower right leg became trapped under a tackle from Giants defender Nick Haynes late in the third quarter. Salem needed assistance to come from the ground, but returned in the final term.               

Christian Salem left the field after injuring his leg in this tangle.

- St Kilda midfielder Jack Steven spent over five minutes in the rooms during the second quarter against West Coast after receiving a knock to his right hip. He returned before half-time and got through the second half. 

- Retiring St Kilda forward Nick Riewoldt was concussed and did not return after clashing heads with West Coast onballer Dom Sheed midway through the final term. Riewoldt was left bleeding from the mouth following the incident. 

Nick Riewoldt was left dazed after this collision in the last quarter.

- St Kilda wingman Jack Newnes needed treatment in the third term for a cut below his right eye he picked up in a tackle on West Coast forward Malcolm Karpany.

- Essendon forward Joe Daniher jarred his already-taped left knee as he was chased down by Carlton defender Liam Jones. In a good sign, Daniher contested the next centre bounce and played out the game.

- Carlton forward Jack Silvagni hurt his right shoulder in the second term when he tackled Essendon defender Michael Hurley. The 19-year-old consulted the medicos a couple of times on the bench, but played out the second half.

- Collingwood defender Tyson Goldsack collided heavily with North Melbourne midfielder Ben Cunnington in the third term. Goldsack passed the routine concussion test and returned just before three-quarter time. 

- North Melbourne captain Jack Ziebell was left worse for wear after colliding into a mark from Collingwood's Matt Scharenberg before half-time. Ziebell went to the rooms for assessment and was cleared, playing the second half as a deep forward.

- Brisbane Lions defender Darcy Gardiner was left dazed in the first term after he leapt to spoil a mark and received an accidental head knock from Western Bulldogs defender Easton Wood. Gardiner passed a concussion test and returned. 

Darcy Gardiner came off the field after this contest.

- Sydney forward Gary Rohan experienced muscle cramps in the final term against Geelong and was rested for the latter part of the game.

- Geelong midfielder Cam Guthrie played out the match against Sydney with an apparent adductor strain. 

- Sydney ruckman Kurt Tippett picked up a corked right quad from a Wylie Buzza knee at a centre bounce, but got through the game.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Salem</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Tippett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Goldstein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ziebell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Swallow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi Greenwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Silvagni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton Wood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brady Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson Goldsack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Newnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Witherden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Gardiner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Talia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Ziebell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Steven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam Guthrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hurley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cedric Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wylie Buzza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orazio Fantasia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gardiner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood's Matt Scharenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Karpany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fantasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Haynes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Pyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldsack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Cunnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
