<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440875671108343</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/health/health-problems/bloodied-melbourne-teen-eaten-by-mystery-sea-creatures/news-story/f8491eb771b0db371d4980a9bd4e29d0</url>
  <title>Bloodied Melbourne teen 'eaten' by mystery sea creatures</title>
  <content>
Melbourne teen left bleeding after mystery sea creature attack
0:32

Melbourne teen Sam Kanizay stood in the water for 30 minutes at a Brighton beach before emerging with blood all over his feet from an unknown sea creature. Courtesy: Sunrise/Channel 7

August 7th 2017
4 minutes ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Sam Kanizay, 16, in a Melbourne Hospital after sustaining suspected bites from 'tiny marine creatures' at Brighton Beach. Picture: Jarrod Kanizay/AAP

AAP

Share

WARNING: GRAPHIC IMAGES
A MELBOURNE teenager has gone for a dip at the beach and come out covered in blood and looking like a horror movie extra.
When Sam Kanizay, 16, felt sore after football on Saturday, he decided to soak his legs at Dendy Street Beach in Brighton.
Half an hour later, he walked out covered in what his family said were tiny marine creatures eating his legs.
"When he got out, he described having sand on his legs, so he went back in the water," his dad Jarrod Kanizay told AAP.
"He went back to his shoes and what he found was blood on his legs. "They ate through Sam's skin and made it bleed profusely," he said.
Mr Kanizay couldn't stop his son's legs bleeding and they went to hospital, where staff were at a loss to explain what had happened.
"As soon as we wiped them (his legs) down, they kept bleeding," he said.
"There was a massive pool of blood on the floor (at the hospital).

"No one knows what the creatures are. They've called a number of people, whether it's toxicity experts or marine exerts and other medics around Melbourne at least ... (and) yep, no one (knows)."

Sam Kanizay's legs were covered with blood when he emerged from the water. Picture: Jarrod Kanizay/AAPSource:AAP

Sam Kanizay in a Melbourne Hospital after sustaining suspected bites from 'tiny marine creatures' at a local bay. Picture: Jarrod Kanizay/AAPSource:AAP
The next night, Mr Kanizay went back to the beach with a pool net full of meat and captured the creatures he said were responsible.
"What is really clear is these little things really love meat," he said of a video, shared with AAP, showing the bugs in a tray of water devouring chunks of meat.

The teen had been 'eaten' by the mystery sea creatures. Picture: Jarrod Kanizay/AAPSource:AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dendy Street Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GRAPHIC IMAGES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Kanizay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kanizay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Kanizay/AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Kanizay/AAPSource</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kanizay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunrise/Channel 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kanizay, 16</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
