<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440317325354641</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/retail/fmcg/milking-it-the-a2-challenge-to-keep-churning-out-profit-growth-and-share-price-highs-20170802-gxnszl</url>
  <title>Milking it: the A2 challenge to keep churning out profit growth and share price highs </title>
  <content>
More than one seasoned investor has pointed out that infant formula producer The A2 Milk Company's fondness for an ASX announcement looks surprisingly similar to a junior resources company spruiking its numbers in a mining boom.
But unlike spivvy miners, A2 - now worth more than $3 billion based on its market capitalisation, and due to report its annual earnings on August 23 - has some serious runs and valuation metrics on the board.  
Since the start of the year, shares in the infant formula and milk group have risen 114 per cent and it's the fourth best performer in the S&P/ASX 200 over the past 12 months.
The NZ group, founded by scientist Corran McLachlan in 2000 after identifying the fact that cows produce different types of milk proteins, trades on a lofty forward price to earnings multiple of 41.5 times. The index average is around 16 times, and that puts A2 in the same company as market darlings including tollroad operator Transurban, pizza technology company Domino's, hearing aid manufacturer Cochlear and construction software group Aconex.

In the past few weeks, A2 has been the subject of a clutch of broker upgrades including one from Citigroup, after the group raised its revenue by $NZ20 million to $NS545 million for the year.  

And, just in case there was doubt, the company put out a statement on Friday reiterating its confidence in achieving crucial Chinese regulatory approval to export its infant formula from next January, noting it had submitted its application in May and some manufacturer approvals had already been granted. 
Yet, it seems not everyone is convinced that A2 can keep delivering. Ahead of A2's results, noise is rising about whether the company can sustain its spectacular run. The short interest in the stock is also building.
Top 20 most shorted

According to shortman.com.au, A2 is dipping in and out of the market's top 20 most shorted stocks with about 8.8 per cent of its shares being lent out to those betting A2 shares will fall. 

For many that are paring their position, it's simply a valuation proposition: with so much expectation built into the stock, any disappointment will hit the valuation hard. It's an argument that has seen a number of the company's long-term supporters reduce their holdings in the group, which sells infant formula to China though is testing expansion into other global markets.
So far, at least one fund manager noted wryly, that decision has cost them. 
But it's not just institutional investors who are selling shares.
Well-regarded chief executive Geoffrey Babidge has been consistently trimming his holding in the past year, most recently in May, when the director's interest notice said the sale of a parcel of 600,000 shares was "consistent with recent practice as Mr Babidge continues to review his investments to achieve a more balanced portfolio over time".

The statement noted he still owns 5 million partly paid ordinary shares. Still, it's never a great look - whatever the reason - when a chief executive starts selling stock.
The best short trades usually need a catalyst for the stock to re-rate - otherwise the trade can go on too long.
In the case of A2, that's a little hard to spot, though it's clear what the bigger risks to the stock are seen to be.
Firstly, there are concerns that A2's main channel for the sale of its infant formula to the Chinese market is through the daigou personal shopper channel. Deutsche Bank analysts estimate the grey channel accounts for up to 60 per cent of its 2017 volume.

Chinese appeal

A2 has managed the channel well, and the A2 brand is consistently ranked as one of the most sought-after infant formula brands in the China market, where it is thought the group has about 3 per cent market share. 
Infant formula sales account accounted for 61 per cent of group revenue in 2016.
The daigou channel works well because of the arbitrage between the Australian market and China: a daigou that buys a $30 tin of formula in Australia can sell it for up to $100 in China.

A2 has been clever in managing their inventory to control demand. At least one variant of A2 Platinum has remained out of stock at Coles or Woolworths since mid March this year, according to Citigroup, and has also been short in the local pharmacy and daigou channels. While that's usually taken as a means of managing the market, the broker also raises the issue of customers switching brands because of stock shortages.
More broadly, there is a potential problem if the daigou channel is in any way curbed or disrupted - and while there's no suggestion that will occur, it's possible whether led by Chinese or from restrictions being put in place by the Australian government that are feeling pressure from local shoppers frustrated by having no products on the supermarket shelves. 
Blackmores has proven that finding another channel to the Chinse market can prove challenging. When it reduced its reliance on daigou, the impact on sales was swift.   
Ahead of the new Chinese regulations for infant formula products that will be introduced on January 1, there is expected to be some disruption because of the destocking of product given the excess supply held by wholesalers and distributors in the lead-up to China Food and Drug Administration (CFDA) registration.
US expansion

The reliance on China goes hand in hand with another issue - the reliance on infant formula and milk. A2 has flagged an interest in expanding into adjacent categories, although again, as Blackmores proved when it tried to move into infant formula, that can be harder to do than might be expected.
Some of the difference in opinion around the stock lies in the view about expansion into the US. As one investor put it, this is ultimately a brand stock, which means much of the value lies in assessing whether the company will be able to break into new markets. 
The US market is yet to break even, though the company has said its product - including chocolate reduced-fat milk - is now stocked in 1100 stores in Florida, Georgia and the Carolinas. Its higher marketing spend looks to be bearing fruit as well, with one A2 shareholder pointing to an as a sign the company was making inroads in the Florida market.

In the UK, the company also had positive operating earnings for the first time in the first half of 2017.
Perhaps the final point to consider is the fresh milk business. That's regarded as relatively mature in Australia, and with the exception of some product extensions, doesn't attract too much analysis.
One theory doing the rounds is whether a competitor will emerge to challenge A2's milk protein market. There's a few challenges to this, not least being the brand recognition and also the fact the herds which produce the A2 milk are still relatively small. At the moment, Freedom Food's Tony Perich is thought to be one of  the biggest suppliers. 
Despite the risks to the downside, one lesson A2 has probably learnt from its other high-multiple peers is that the market is quick to identify challenges - but isn't always right. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citigroup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffrey Babidge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackmore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corran McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Food</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Babidge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NS545</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aconex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Platinum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedom Food's Tony Perich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drug Administration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milk Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ$20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolinas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
