<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439582885939593</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/house-fire-claims-soar-in-wa/news-story/571020d942d9c2c098788c0b51abff7f</url>
  <title>'One day these may save your life'</title>
  <content>
MORE homes are burning down in WA, prompting calls for people to replace old electric blankets and be vigilant with candles.
An analysis of insurance claims by the RAC found an overall increase in fire claims in the past four years during winter and early spring when the mercury is at its lowest.
RAC Insurance home claims manager Glen Walker said: "Between 2013 and 2016, the months of July, August and September have consistently had a higher percentage of fires when compared to the other months of the year. On average, there is nearly a 20 per cent increase in fire claims over these months."
The cost of rebuilding an average home after a house fire is about $350,000, while the average cost of replacing contents lost in a house fire is $120,000.
Last winter alone the RAC processed 100 house fire claims in WA.
Mr Walker said flammable items being left too close to heaters, open fireplaces, candles, electric blankets and overloaded power boards were common ways a house fire could start.
"Even dust build-up on power boards has sparked house fires here in Western Australia," he said.
"We frequently respond to claims which, with the right preventive action, could have been avoided."
One recent claim was due to a fire sparked by an electric blanket, resulting in a $130,000 damage bill.
"The blanket was very old and should have been replaced years ago," Mr Walker said.
RAC Insurance recommended checking smoke alarms, unplugging appliances when they're not in use, and investing in a fire blanket or extinguisher.
"You'd think that in 2017, people would know to be vigilant when using certain heating items such as electric blankets, heaters and candles, but our data shows the message is not getting through," Mr Walker said.
Department of Fire and Emergency Services data shows there has been one fatality and 24 people injured as a result of 306 house fires across the State from May to July.
But August is the deadliest month for house fires, with 14 deaths in the last month of winter since 2000. Last August, 13 people were injured and two died in house fires.
"Each year people die or are injured under similar circumstances and yet we still don't realise it can happen to us. All too often, the fire could have been prevented," DFES fire investigation and analysis unit District Officer Andy Duckworth said.
Fires were also caused by cooking left on stoves.
"Of the 300-plus house fires that have occurred in the past few months, the instances of unattended heat source fires make up nearly a third of these," he said.
"Learn about the dangers in your home, and put safety measures in place such as working smoke alarms and a home fire escape plan.
"One day these may save your life," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAC Insurance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DFES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Walker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Officer Andy Duckworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
