<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440059627314397</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/world/mike-pence-blasts-report-he-is-planning-2020-presidential-bid/news-story/aa2c772bbe34e063fd062d7f3b38c821</url>
  <title>Pence denies planning presidential run</title>
  <content>
US VICE President Mike Pence has pushed back against a news report suggesting he is laying groundwork for a possible presidential bid in 2020 if President Donald Trump does not run.
In a statement released by the White House, Mr Pence said Sunday's story in The New York Times "is disgraceful and offensive to me, my family, and our entire team."
The report detailed the efforts of several Republicans looking ahead to 2020, calling it a "shadow campaign."
It noted Mr Pence's political schedule and active fundraising, though it also said unnamed advisers have signalled that he would only run if Mr Trump doesn't.
Mr Trump has not suggested he won't seek a second term. But his first six months in office , marked by staff infighting, legislative struggles and a series of investigations.
Mr Pence insisted that "the allegations in this article are categorically false."
He continued, saying his team will "focus all our efforts to advance the president's agenda and see him re-elected in 2020."
White House counsellor Kellyanne Conway dismissed the report that Mr Pence was planning to run in 2020.
"Vice President Pence is a very loyal, very dutiful, but also incredibly effective vice president, and active vice president, with this president," said Ms Conway on US ABC's This Week.

Working in Bedminster, N.J., as long planned construction is being done at the White House. This is not a vacation - meetings and calls!

Meanwhile, Mr Trump hit back at critics of his 17-day holiday at his Bedminster golfing resort in New Jersey, claiming on Twitter that the trip was "not a vacation".
The getaway drew criticism from his political opponents, particularly after Mr Trump had insisted that members of Congress sacrifice their own holidays for the sake of his agenda.
Mr Trump tweeted on Saturday: "Working in Bedminster, N.J., as long planned construction is being done at the White House. This is not a vacation - meetings and calls!"
The claim was mocked by many on social media.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>N.J</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Conway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellyanne Conway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-President Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US ABC's This Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Pence</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
