<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440794066728916</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/06/37/massuer-photos-clients-instagram</url>
  <title>Masseur accused of taking and sharing naked photos of female clients</title>
  <content>
A Newcastle masseur has been accused of taking naked photos of female clients and sharing them among a secret group of male strippers known as "the big fellas".
The Mayfield-based masseur - who is also a topless waiter and male stripper - is accused to taking photos of his clients as they lie undressed and face down on his massage table.
Josh Hewitt - who is not registered under the Australian Health Practitioner Regulation Agency or the Association of Massage Therapists, according to  - then shared the photos with other male strippers in a private Instagram group called "the big fella's" [sic].
Hewitt has reportedly deleted his Newcastle Relaxation Massage Therapy and Newcastle Male Stripper Facebook pages in recent days and has ignored repeated requests for comment from Fairfax Media.
According to screen shots from the Instagram group obtained by the Newcastle Herald, Hewitt not only shared explicit images, but also the contact details of his female clients and encouraged the other men in the group to contact them.
Fairfax Media reports Hewitt sent a photo of a partially undressed woman laying face down from behind with the caption "hard day at the office [at the moment] boys lol".
One woman, reportedly a client, told Fairfax Media she had "caught him with his phone in his hand" during a massage but avoided confronting him.

Related Articles

"I thought at the time he was taking [photos] ... he put it [the phone] down really quickly but I saw the camera on his screen," she said.
"I didn't say anything to him ... I wish I knew at the time what I know now."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Association of Massage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hewitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Relaxation Massage Therapy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Male Stripper Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hewitt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfield-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Health Practitioner Regulation Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
