<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440660922741423</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-07/osprey-mishap-australian-forces-to-join-search-for-missing-marines-after-mv22-training-incident/1691668</url>
  <title>Osprey mishap: Australian forces to join search for missing marines after MV-22 training incident</title>
  <content>
Australian Navy divers and a survey ship are expected to arrive at Shoalwater Bay today to assist with the recovery operation of a US military aircraft.
The  during a training exercise on Saturday afternoon.
Three of the 26 personnel on board remain missing, presumed dead.
One marine was taken to Rockhampton Hospital with a leg injury.

, and moved to a recovery and salvage phase expected to take several months.
Defence Minister Marise Payne said a number of Australian Defence Force (ADF) assets were involved in supporting the US-led recovery operation, including HMAS Melville and a Navy clearance diving team.
"Our thoughts are with all those affected by this tragic event and the Australian Government stands ready to support the US further in any way we can," Senator Payne said.
"Australian Army aviation assets are at short-notice readiness to support any further requirements."
She said the recovery operation was likely to be complex and affected by a range of factors including water depth and conditions, debris and water current.
"The US military is working with the ADF and other Australian agencies to conduct thorough assessments and planning prior to the formal commencement of any salvage or recovery," Senator Payne said.
"The incident is currently being investigated by US authorities and Australia will assist in these investigations where appropriate."
The names of the marines feared dead in the mishap are expected to be made public today.
Next of kin were advised within hours of the crash.
US military training exercises are regularly conducted in the region, and Rockhampton Acting Mayor Cherie Rutherford said the marines were considered part of their community.
"It's devastating news and our prayers and thoughts are with the families and friends of those marines who lost their lives," Councillor Rutherford said.
"It must be extremely difficult for them and of course our community feels that pain with them."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Acting Mayor Cherie Rutherford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Rutherford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalwater Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV-22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Minister Marise Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Melville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Payne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
