<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440665217708805</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/ap-ap-source-jay-cutler-agrees-to-terms-with-dolphins-2017-8</url>
  <title>Jay Cutler will leave job as a TV analyst and sign with Miami Dolphins</title>
  <content>
DAVIE, Fla. (AP) - A person familiar with the situation says free agent quarterback Jay Cutler has agreed to terms on a contract with the Miami Dolphins.

The person confirmed the agreement to The Associated Press on condition of anonymity Sunday because the Dolphins haven't announced the deal.

Cutler is expected to compete with Matt Moore for the Dolphins' starting job while Ryan Tannehill remains out with a left knee injury that could sideline him for the entire season. The deal with Cutler signals the Dolphins anticipate a lengthy recovery for Tannehill.

that he was joining Fox as an NFL analyst, however, he stopped short of calling the decision a "retirement" from playing.

"I don't know if retirement is the right word," Cutler wrote (). "I don't feel that anyone ever really retires from the NFL. You are either forced to leave, or you lose the desire to do what's required to keep going. I'm in between those situations at this point in my life."

Cutler had signed with Fox to work in a three-person booth, as opposed to the more traditional two-person booth. That move suggested that both Cutler and Fox were open to the possibility of Cutler returning to the NFL at some point this season without causing a major shakeup in game assignments for Fox.

Dolphins coach Adam Gase was offensive coordinator for the Chicago Bears when Cutler had a career-best quarterback rating with them in 2015. Gase joined Miami in 2016, and Cutler parted with Chicago in March after eight seasons.

___

For more NFL coverage: http://www.pro32.ap.org and http://www.twitter.com/AP_NFL

___

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIAMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago Bears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miami Dolphins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tannehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Tannehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cutler</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Cutler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP_NFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Gase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
