<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440669512676141</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/murder-suspected-after-womans-body-found-qld-creek/3209427/</url>
  <title>Murder suspected after woman's body found in Qld creek</title>
  <content>
MULTIPLE crime scenes are in place around Cooktown as part of a murder investigation after a woman's wrapped body was found in an isolated creek.

The body is yet to be formally identified, although police believe it likely belongs to local woman Donna Louise Steele, 42, who had been missing since Wednesday.

A major search, involving police and the Rescue 510 helicopter, had been taking place for the mother-of-two over the weekend before police were called to Leggett's Crossing on Endeavour Valley Rd about 5.20am.

It is understood a passer by spotted the wrapped body in water at a site about 20km outside Cooktown.

Far North police Det Insp Geoff Marsh confirmed several crime scenes had been established at the crossing and other sites around the Far North town.

Police also attended a property on Endeavour Valley Rd early yesterday which the Cairns Post understands belongs to a close friend of Ms Steele.

Det Insp Marsh would not confirm if they had any suspects, but said the circumstances were suspicious and they were "following a number of lines of inquiry".

Ms Steele had last been seen at the IGA supermarket on Helen St in Cooktown about 12.15pm on Wednesday.

When police first reported her missing they said they had concerns for her as she suffered a medical condition.

Her friend Kath Pennell spoke out yesterday, saying the incident had left the small township in shock.

"I am so devastated that I can barely speak," she said.

"I will say she was a beautiful mother and friend.

"She loved her children so much. I can't believe someone has done this to her."

Det Insp Marsh said police were offering support to Ms Steele's family including her two young children.

He said specialist homicide and scientific officers from Brisbane were being flown in to assist Cairns and Cooktown investigators.

Police have called on anyone with information to come forward and investigations remain ongoing.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooktown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Louise Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Endeavour Valley Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Steele</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leggett's Crossing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Det Insp Geoff Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rescue 510</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Det Insp Marsh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath Pennell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
