<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440712462349552</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/north-korean-nuclear-threat-overshadows-hiroshima-anniversary-in-japan-20170806-gxqjiq.html</url>
  <title>North Korean nuclear threat overshadows Hiroshima anniversary in Japan</title>
  <content>
Tokyo: Every year in early August, Japanese politicians and peace activists converge on Hiroshima to commemorate the day when the city was devastated by a US atomic bomb. In the famous peace park, the horrors of World War II are vividly recounted. Speakers of all political stripes repeat Japan's postwar mantra: "Never again."
The familiar reaffirmations of peace were there this year, too, on the 72nd anniversary, with Prime Minister Shinzo Abe declaring on Sunday that Japan, "as the only country to be irradiated in war", would "firmly advance the movement toward a world without nuclear weapons."

Up Next

UN bans North Korean exports over missile tests

01:33

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

North Korea concerns heightened

The rogue country is more advanced in its nuclear missile development than previously thought.

But there was no hiding the tensions straining Japan's postwar pacifism, as fears over the fast-advancing nuclear program in neighbouring North Korea - and political disagreements over how to respond - rose to the surface.
At a news conference after the official memorial ceremony, a forum normally dominated by reflections on the past and appeals for a peaceful future, a reporter prodded Abe about the alarmingly here-and-now problem of the nuclear ambitions of the North's leader, Kim Jong Un.

North Korea's repeated defiance of a ban on testing missiles and nuclear bombs prompted the UN Security Council on Saturday to unanimously adopt a resolution imposing the most stringent sanctions yet against the country.
The reporter asked, "Should Japan, whose constitution renounces war, acquire the means to strike North Korean missile sites if an attack on Japan appeared imminent?"

It is a topic that has occupied policymakers and defense experts in recent months as Pyongyang, the North's capital, has stepped up the pace of its missile tests, with pieces of its increasingly sophisticated arsenal splashing down in waters off Japan. But it seemed a remarkable subject for the anniversary in Hiroshima.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Abe's answer was hardly a comfort to Japanese pacifists.Photo: AP
Though he responded that his government was not planning to arm Japan to carry out any pre-emptive strikes, at least for now, he stopped well short of rejecting the idea outright.
"At the present time, we are not planning any specific deliberations about possessing" weapons for a pre-emptive strike, Abe said. He added that Japan needed to strengthen its defenses generally, "given that the security situation surrounding Japan is becoming increasingly severe".Photo: AP
New York Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hiroshima</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Shinzo Abe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
