<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440708167382176</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/technology/innovation/uq-researchers-lead-project-that-could-make-almost-anything-recyclable-20170728-gxkvvw.html</url>
  <title>UQ researchers lead project that could make almost anything recyclable</title>
  <content>
Scientists have created a computer simulation to help scientists modify a bacteria that could lead to almost anything being recyclable.
Researchers at the University of Queensland's Australian Institute for Bio-engineering and Nanotechnology worked in partnership with US company LanzaTech to develop a computer model that will help scientists streamline the fermentation of carbon emissions.Photo: Dr Esteban Marcellin
The project was designed to build upon the natural qualities of the Clostridium autoethanogenum bacteria, which transforms emissions such as carbon monoxide and carbon dioxide into ethanol in a process called syngas fermentation.
The bacteria, originally discovered in rabbit droppings, belonged to one of the oldest living microorganism families on the planet.
AIBN researcher Dr Esteban Marcellin was excited over its possible uses.
"The beauty of it is you can gasify pretty much anything," he said.

​"You could in theory convert municipal solid waste or any waste stream into chemicals.
"That means once you finish eating something you put it in the rubbish bin and instead of going into landfill it could go into a gasifier and then on to the fermenter."

You will now receive updates from

Technology Newsletter

Technology Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

LanzaTech has so far used the bacteria in a process that involved placing fermentors on the end of steel-mill smokestacks to capture their carbon emissions and transform it into biofuel.
By simulating the cellular metabolism of any bacteria-gene pairing, the computer model allows scientists to create bacteria that more efficiently captures carbon emissions and select pairings that allow the emissions to be transformed into other products.
"Instead of modifying the bacteria to see if adding new genes is going to work, we can do it inside the computer," Dr Marcellin said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Esteban Marcellin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bio-engineering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Marcellin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clostridium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LanzaTech</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
