<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651439986612869492</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/03/32/liberals-prepare-for-gay-marriage-stoush</url>
  <title>Liberals prepare for gay marriage stoush</title>
  <content>
Liberal MPs and senators will face off over same-sex marriage in what's expected to be a heated special party room meeting in Canberra on Monday.
But backbencher Dean Smith, who has drafted his own marriage equality bill, says it shouldn't be seen as a vote on Malcolm Turnbull's leadership.
Senator Smith, together with Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans and Warren Entsch, will push for a parliamentary vote on the bill after circulating it to members over the weekend.
The legislation allows for two people to marry regardless of their gender, while enshrining protections and exemptions for religious communities.
That includes religious ministers, civil celebrants, and businesses linked to a religious body who refuse to marry same-sex couples.
Senator Smith believes it's the most comprehensive marriage equality bill to go before parliament.
And it's been given the green light by advocates, who believe it's one of the strongest they've seen.

Related Articles

"It is a bill that is designed to pass the Senate," Australian Marriage Equality co-chair Alex Greenwich said.
It's expected many MPs will continue their push for a plebiscite, which the coalition promised at the last election but has failed to get it through parliament.
Others are tipped to argue for a non-binding postal vote being touted by cabinet minister Peter Dutton.
Legal advice sought by marriage equality advocates suggests, however, that option isn't possible without legislation, which would be unlikely to pass the Senate.
Senator Smith said the issue was bigger than the Liberal Party and did not need to be seen through the prism of leadership.
"This is a test for each and every member of the parliamentary Liberal party," he told ABC TV.
The party room was a respectful place and people showed courtesy to one another, he said.
"There is an expectation people put their best foot forward and make the most convincing argument they can."
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
