<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441176318823094</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-07/skerrett-equine-therapy-counselling-horse/8748936</url>
  <title>Horses bringing people closer to understanding themselves</title>
  <content>
A Sunshine Coast business is swapping the consulting couch for round yards, using horses to help people build self-confidence and awareness.
Skerrett Equine was founded by Ben and Linda Skerrett who have a team of 'horse therapists' including Phoenix - an affectionate Arabian-cross that was terrified of people before the Skerretts took the gelding on as a rescue case.
When it comes to horses, Mr Skerrett has a rich family pedigree.
His grandfather Brian established Australia's first Jackaroo-Jillaroo school in Australia in 1983 and his parents are also in the business, sharing decades of knowledge in horse riding, mustering, whip cracking, lassoing, pasture and livestock management.

"From before I can remember, basically since I was born, I was on the front of a horse in a little pouch. My mum would be riding the horse and leading a packhorse up the creek, leading a trek," Ben Skerrett said.

Phoenix the rescue horse is now helping the Skerretts help others.

Phoenix the rescue horse is now helping the Skerretts help others.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

He began training horses when he finished school, eventually becoming what some would call a 'horse whisperer'.
It was when Mr Skerrett began teaching riders using his methods of natural horsemanship that he made a discovery.
"I really started to notice that it's not about the horse, it's about the person. And the horse will mirror the person," he said.
"I realised that I was trying to train the horse so it can put up with people.

"I thought 'what if I go from the other angle and help people learn about themselves so they can make the change inside themselves?' and then the horse will reflect that change."

Mr Skerrett travelled to America and gained qualifications through the Eponoquest model of equine facilitated personal development.
He also studied equine facilitated experiential learning activities that are done while on the ground with the horse.
"The most common thing I see is that when people open their hearts with a horse, and they become vulnerable, horses honour that," he said.
"They honour people's vulnerability - instead of what happens in the real world [where] when we're vulnerable people will take advantage of it."

Ben Skerrett says horses can help humans build self-confidence and awareness.

Ben Skerrett says horses can help humans build self-confidence and awareness.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Skerrett Equine runs individually tailored sessions and programs at their Kulangoor property.
"Probably one of the most influential first experiences that I had was a lady that went in for a reflective session - which is a session where people go in and they experience their heart's desire with a horse.
"She went into the round pen and the horse didn't want to have anything to do with her. The more she wanted the horse's attention the more it went away and did the opposite of what she wanted it to do.
"This went on for about ten minutes, and when she came out of the round pen she was in tears because she came to the realisation that the horse was reflecting her in her search for love outside of herself.

"She wanted other people to love her for who she was, instead of starting with loving herself and then having other people reflect that. That's what came out of that session for her.

"That was really powerful for her because she'd always been trying to get other people to acknowledge her and to give her that attention and that self love.
"But she had to honour it in herself."

The Skerrett's believe our mood is reflected by the horses' reactions.

The Skerrett's believe our mood is reflected by the horses' reactions.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Another of Skerrett Equine's clients was a Vietnam veteran who suffered from post traumatic stress disorder and found challenges in working with his wife's horse.
"He really struggled to manage his energy and his emotions in his life. He would go in with the horse and if he was fearful and if he was defensive and reactive then the horse would mirror that back to him," Mr Skerrett said.
"At first he really struggled with it but after a while - when we started to talk about 'it's not about what the horse does, it's about your energy that you bring into it' - he realised that he was able to connect with the horse. The horse made a massive change.
"It was an amazing transformation between the two of them. His wife was watching and she said 'I couldn't believe how much of a change it made in him' and it brought tears to her eyes.
"She was so amazed at how he shifted just through his own presence with the horse."

Ben and Linda Skerrett run individual classes and workshops for clients.

Ben and Linda Skerrett run individual classes and workshops for clients.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Ben Skerrett's wife Linda came from Germany to Australia on holiday and never went home.

"I have seen people come that were quite anxious, and the moment they interacted with the horse [they] would calm down and feel a lot more grounded," she said.

"I've seen children that were quite anxious or worried, or even slightly hyperactive, come and relax around the horses, being able to connect and engage and gain confidence from interacting with them."
Theresa Hanich was one of the Skerretts' clients and said she experienced an emotional breakthrough while working with Reijker, a large imposing Friesian horse.
"The activity I was doing was grooming him. I really felt overwhelmed by his power and I really didn't understand why because I'm actually very familiar with horses," she said.
"I used to have my own horse and I thought 'you know, what is this about?'"

"I couldn't believe that I was so frightened of him and that's when I asked Ben to help me work through it. It was just a lot of emotion coming out that I just couldn't stop.

Theresa Hanich says Reijker helped her discover things she never knew about herself.

Theresa Hanich says Reijker helped her discover things she never knew about herself.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

"I had a very domineering, controlling parent and I dared to challenge her rationale over something quite petty one day.
"I was sent to my room and rather than my mother coming in and disciplining me she sent my stepfather in and my stepfather left welt marks on my legs. So I've always had a problem with authority figures because of it.
"It helped me look back at that incident and understand what my fight has been about most of my life.
"That's what I got with Reijker. He showed me exactly who I am and what was going on for me."
Mr Skerrett acknowledged that equine therapy is not mainstream.

"It seems to be a very alternative form of therapy, but it is gaining a lot of merit, I think, for its effectiveness and power," he said.

"You see a lot of news stories about youth having experiences with horses. It's much more experiential-based rather than just sitting down and talking to somebody on a couch.
"Particularly for people who haven't had a lot of experience with horses, it can develop their confidence immensely because they let go of the fear and they start to notice how friendly and how honest and sincere horses can be."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Skerrett</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eponoquest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theresa Hanich</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Skerrett</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skerretts</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Rural</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackaroo-Jillaroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Nichols</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reijker</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kulangoor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skerrett Equine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arabian-cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Skerrett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
