<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441008815096377</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/kayleigh-mcenany-left-cnn-to-host-pro-trump-news-videos-2017-8</url>
  <title>One of Trump's most vocal supporters left CNN to make a pro-Trump news video that's been compared to state TV</title>
  <content>
Former CNN commentator Kayleigh McEnany hosted a pro-Trump news segment on the president's Facebook page on Sunday, one day after she left the cable network.

"Thank you for joining us as we provide the news of the week from Trump Tower here in New York," McEnany said at the top of a roughly minute-and-a-half segment, called "News of the Week," that was posted to Trump's .

It's unclear whether McEnany is being compensated by the Trump campaign, the Trump Organisation, or another source. McEnany did not return a request for comment. 

During the segment, McEnany touted the most recent jobs report and unemployment statistics, adding, "President Trump has clearly steered the economy back in the right direction."

This is the second news-style segment posted to Trump's Facebook page this week  - the first was spearheaded by Trump's daughter-in-law, Lara Trump. She similarly praised the president throughout her segment, and ended by saying she had brought the "real news" to the American people.

Since the series launched, it has been compared to state media outlets in countries such as Russia and Syria, both notorious for their mistreatment of journalists and crackdowns on press freedom. 

"Wow. Feels eerily like so many state-owned channels I've watched in other countries,"  former US ambassador to Russia Michael McFaul.  

In her video, McEnany touched on the Trump administration's newly-unveiled RAISE Act, rolled out on Wednesday. The controversial proposal would slash legal immigration by 50% over the next decade and suggests allowing immigrants into the country based on merit and proficiency in English. 

"For decades, a steady rise in immigration has depressed the wage of American workers," McEnany said. "The RAISE Act will increase wages, decrease poverty, and save the taxpayers billions. Americans deserve a raise, and President Trump is finally putting the American worker first," she added. 

McEnany also mentioned Monday's Medal of Honour ceremony, during which Trump honored Vietnam War hero James McCloughan, and other actions she said Trump has taken to reform the veterans healthcare system. 

"Thank you for joining us, everybody," she concluded. "I'm Kayleigh McEnany, and that is the real news." 

The segment was filmed in front of a backdrop emblazoned with Trump's campaign logo and the name of his website. At the bottom of the screen, a message urges viewers to subscribe to future updates, and a separate bar tells viewers to stay updated via social media and to "Make America great again." 

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Make America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raise Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayleigh McEnany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James McCloughan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday's Medal of Honour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News of the Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McEnany</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia Michael McFaul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.25</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
