<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441227858431004</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/victoria/its-not-a-movie-did-marine-critters-eat-brighton-teenagers-legs-20170806-gxq9db.html</url>
  <title>'Something ate Sam's legs' - teenager's legs bleed after bathing in the bay </title>
  <content>
WARNING: graphic image
It sounds like a scene from a horror movie. You wade to shore after bathing at a Melbourne beach to find your legs are covered in blood.

Up Next

Dumped: Melbourne's waste management scam

01:36

More Environment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

'Something ate Sam's legs'

After a swim at Brighton Beach, Sam's legs were eaten by something in the water. His dad went back down to the beach to find out what bit his son, this is what he found.

You try to  staunch the bleeding but it won't stop.
But that's exactly what happened to Sam Kanizay​, who fears he was attacked by tiny marine creatures at Dendy Street Beach in Brighton.Photo: Scott McNaughton
The 16-year-old, who was sore from playing football, was soaking waist-deep in the bay about 6.20pm on Saturday. 
His legs felt a little numb, with a tingling sensation, but he assumed it was from the soreness and cold. "I wasn't really thinking about being eaten."

Emerging from the water 30 minutes later, he saw under a street light that his legs were covered in blood from the calves down.
"My first instinct was that I must have stepped on a rock," he said. "But I realised that couldn't have been it, because it was evenly distributed over my whole ankle and foot."Photo: Jarrod Kanizay

Sam Kanizay's feet after he emerged from the water at Brighton Beach. Photo: supplied

He walked across the esplanade, "leaving a path of blood", to his home nearby. His father, Jarrod, and sister, Gabby, 14, tried to wash the blood off in the shower.Photo: Scott McNaughton
They couldn't staunch the flow, which seeped from pin prick sized holes, so Jarrod drove Sam to Sandringham Hospital emergency department.
Sam was given painkillers and antibiotics and had blood tests. Photo: Jarrod Kanizay
Jarrod drove him to Dandenong Hospital in the early hours of Sunday for further tests.
On Sunday afternoon, Sam's legs were still seeping blood but doctors had not found a cause.Photo: Jarrod Kanizay
Sam said a nurse had suggested sea lice were to blame, "but it was just a guess". 
In winter of 2015, a suburban newspaper reported that Nick Murray and his son Will, 13, bled from their feet after standing in the bay at Sandringham for 10 minutes.
The pair thought it was sea lice - marine parasites that feed on fish.
University of Melbourne marine biologist Professor Michael Keough said . 'They're scavengers who'll clean up dead fish and feed on living tissue. They're mostly less than a centimetre long, and so the bites they make are pretty small, and so that's more consistent with pinprick size marks." 

Enlarged photo of a sea louse Natatolana woodjonesi, (actual size about 25mm) - one of the species that inhabits Port Phillip Bay.  Photo: Museums Victoria

"It's just food for them. Especially if he's been standing around for a long time, it's the chance for more of them to come in and start biting. Just be attracted to a little bit of blood. And if he's standing in the water and he's cold and may not notice a whole lot of little bites."
Doina​ Canta​, who goes swimming with the Icebergers every morning off the beach where Sam got injured, says it could be a sting ray. She said a man in her group got stung about six months ago on one leg, and had bled extensively.    
Sam Kanizay was still in shock on Sunday but it hadn't put him off swimming in the bay. "It was a bit of a freak thing to happen. I'm not really sure what to think of it."
Sam's father Jarrod Kanizay warned in an email that "something ate Sam's legs. If you are a member of the [Brighton] Ice Bergers [swimming group] or running groups that ice their legs at Brighton, then you may want to repost this to warn them to not stand still in it too long..."
A spokeswoman for Monash Health, which oversees Dandenong Hospital, said the patient was still being assessed and it was too early for a doctor to comment on the case.
Jarrod told The Age that at Sandringham Hospital "We had the emergency room full of everybody that was working there just fascinated, they were all on Google afterwards, hypothesising as to what happened. They pretty much had 10 different hypotheses but nothing yet."
Jarrod said he and his friends often soak their legs after a run, "and I haven't seen this happen before".
He said he was considering putting a bloodied piece of meat in the bay on Sunday night "to see if we can catch these things".  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dendy Street Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabby, 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will, 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Michael Keough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Icebergers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Kanizay</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museums Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natatolana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kanizay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ice Bergers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott McNaughton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
