<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441348117516649</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/boss/why-you-should-visit-london-20170714-gxbjom</url>
  <title>This is why you should make it part of your business to visit London</title>
  <content>
by
Marie-Louise von Haselberg

London's reputation as one of Europe's hippest capitals is well earned - its thriving arts scene, incredible restaurants and bars can tempt even the most jet-lagged traveller.
As the world knows, London was rocked by horrific terrorist attacks at Westminster and  this year.
But, true to form, Brits are rallying and continuing with life as normal - albeit amid heightened security.
Nonetheless, if you're headed to this most cosmopolitan of cities, it's wise to exercise caution.

The Ned

One thing not to miss

For a snapshot of the capital's charm, head to the sixth-floor Kitchen and Bar at the Tate Modern. There's just a wall of glass separating you from the wide vistas blending tradition and modernity with futuristic buildings, the dome of St Paul's and River Thames below. Early morning for coffee and pastries is best. Level 6, Tate Modern, Bankside, SE1. tate.org.uk
Hottest new venue in town

If you want to go to the place for breakfast meetings, visit the recently opened hotel The Ned. Housed in the iconic former Midland Bank building in the City, it was originally designed by Sir Edwin "Ned" Lutyens in 1924 and now plays host to nine restaurants, as well as a Cowshed spa, Cheeky nail bar and Neville salon. 27 Poultry, EC2R. thened.com
Close by, The Curtain Hotel and members' club occupies the site of a former 1970s office block. It boasts 120 rooms and suites, a members' club underground, wellness area and a rooftop pool and restaurant. 45 Curtain Road, EC2A. thecurtain.com

Where the business crowd meets

Impress your colleagues with a reservation at Bentleys Oyster Bar & Grill in Mayfair: it's perfect for hedge fund managers. The quality of ingredients is exemplary and deftly mastered by consummate chef Irishman Richard Corrigan. The best oysters are to be had here, alongside fish soup, pie and, of course, fish and chips. 11-15 Swallow Street, W1. bentleys.org
Heron Tower in Bishopsgate plays host to two restaurants. Take the glass elevator up 38 floors to the effervescent Brazilian-Japanese-Peruvian hybrid Sushi Samba or climb another two floors to Duck & Waffle for inventive food combinations. Prices are as sky-high as the location, but its chic reputation means that bankers, fashion designers and tech start-ups all converge here. 110 Bishopsgate, EC2N, sushisamba.com; duckandwaffle.com
Eat, stay, play

The Wolseley: Ultra-glam Mittel-European brasserie favoured by media types and moguls: breakfast here is superb. 160 Piccadilly, W1. thewolseley.com

The Ledbury: Assuredly modern British cooking, two Michelin stars and a delightful summer terrace. 127 Ledbury Road, W11. theledbury.com

Hotel Cafe Royal: London's palatial grande dame kitted out in sparkling modernity courtesy of architect David Chipperfield. 68 Regent Street, W1. hotelcaferoyal.com

Rosewood London: A neoclassical delight that's a stone's throw from Covent Garden and the Royal Opera House. 252 High Holborn, WC1.

Claridge's Bar: This art-deco watering hole with old-money charm is a luxurious way to spend an evening. 49 Brook Street, W1. claridges.co.uk

The Box:  At this cabaret-inspired decadent club, all the acts are show-stoppers.

11-12  Walker's Court, W1. theboxsoho.com

London resident curator Marie-Louise von Haselberg is a freelance fashion editor and writer who contributes to publications including Vanity Fair and Sunday Times Style magazine.
Like Leadership with the Financial Review on . Follow us on . Join the  conversation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regent Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bankside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanity Fair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker's Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lutyens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Chipperfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultra-glam Mittel-European</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heron Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westminster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosewood London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtain Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SE1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Holborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claridge's Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wc1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piccadilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brook Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W1</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishopsgate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Edwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolseley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sushi Samba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W. 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian-Japanese-Peruvian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irishman Richard Corrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Covent Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtain Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midland Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Thames</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swallow Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie-Louise</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tate Modern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledbury Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haselberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times' Style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleys Oyster Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hotel Cafe Royal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EC2R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EC2A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EC2N</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
