<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441099009410637</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/07/liberal-gay-marriage-supporters-minority-abbott-says-ahead-party-meeting</url>
  <title>Liberal gay marriage supporters in minority, Abbott says ahead of party meeting</title>
  <content>
A crucial Liberal partyroom meeting will be held on Monday afternoon to thrash out the party policy on same-sex marriage.

By

6 MINS AGO  UPDATED 1 MIN AGO

Former prime minister Tony Abbott has warned Liberals not to break election promises in rejecting a plebiscite to resolve the debate on legalising , saying they are honour bound to support a public vote.

"If there is one lesson that MPs and political parties should surely have learnt over the past few years it is that you don't break promises," he said.

Mr Abbott, writing in News Corp papers on Monday ahead of a crucial partyroom meeting in which the issue is set to be thrashed out, says those government MPs who support gay marriage are a minority.

"Of course, some Liberals sincerely support  and want it to be available as soon as possible.

That's a respectable minority view inside the Coalition party room."

Related reading

Mr Abbott said Coalition MPs are honour-bound to oppose  in the absence of a plebiscite.

"Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull never liked the plebiscite policy but fully grasps the importance of keeping commitments and, to his credit, is now resolute that nothing can change without a plebiscite first."

Meanwhile a private members' bill, supported by Dean Smith, Trent Zimmerman, Warren Entsch, Trevor Evans and Tim Wilson, has been circulated ahead of a special party room meeting on the issue in Canberra on Monday afternoon.

The legislation would allow two people to marry regardless of their sex or gender.

It also would protect all religious ministers and civil celebrants from legal action if they refuse to marry same-sex couples, and covers service providers - such as bakers, florists and photographers - if they can prove their business is linked to a religious body.

RELATED READING:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 1 MIN AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
