<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441133369149605</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/queensland/courts-law/teen-charged-over-mason-lees-death-accused-of-bail-breach/news-story/448e67befa2355d13735905e99d11df8</url>
  <title>Teen charged over Mason Lee's death accused of bail breach</title>
  <content>
Ryan Hodson was arrested after allegedly breaching his bail conditions by meeting his witness girlfriend.

Kate McKennaThe Courier-Mail

Share

A POLICEWOMAN jumped on a horse to search for a teenager charged over the death of toddler Mason Lee after he bolted when he was caught at an equestrian centre with his girlfriend, court documents allege.
Ryan Hodson, 18, was granted bail in the Brisbane Supreme Court in June after being charged with manslaughter over Mason's death, only to be hauled back to jail three weeks later for allegedly breaching a condition by having contact with witness Sheila Low. Hodson denies all charges.
Details of Hodson's alleged forbidden equestrian centre rendezvous are contained in documents tendered to the Brisbane Supreme Court, where prosecutors are applying to revoke his bail on the manslaughter charge over the breach.
Witnesses claim a red-haired male - alleged to be Hodson - visited the centre with Ms Low on July 13, signing a disclaimer form under his brother's first name, before riding her horse in a paddock.
"I asked Sheila if the male person was her son as he looked quite young," the centre's owner said in a statement. "Sheila stated that he was not her son but he was her 'boyfriend' and that he was 18 years of age."
When the pair returned the next day, the centre's owner said a different woman told her the teen was in fact Ryan Hodson.
The following day, police became aware of Hodson's alleged meetings at the equestrian centre and, after hearing he had returned, they paid a visit.
As they walked in, the plainclothes officers allegedly noticed Hodson standing next to a horse just 20m to 30m from Ms Low.
"I then said, 'Hey Ryan' ... (and he) started to run," a policeman said in his statement. "I gave chase on foot for approximately 50m before coming to a halt.

"I observed (Hodson) run off into the paddocks towards the forestry."
His colleague said in a separate statement that she contacted police communications to request a dog squad unit and more officers before jumping on a horse "obtained ... from the equestrian centre owner" to search the area.
Hodson, however, was not found.
When questioned, the policewoman said Ms Low denied having contact with Hodson and said they "own a horse together but attend the centre at different times".
Hodson later voluntarily accompanied an officer to a police station, where he was arrested.
He remains in custody and the matter has been adjourned to a date to be fixed.
The body of 21-month-old Mason was found at a Caboolture home in the early hours of June 11, 2016.
Hodson has previously said he would fight the manslaughter charge.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheila Low</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Low</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mason Lee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Hodson, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Hodson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheila</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mason</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate McKennaThe Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodson</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
