<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441008815096381</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/nsw-act/politics/martin-place-tent-city-nsw-premier-gladys-berejiklian-vows-to-end-tent-standoff/news-story/502e31899df455a1781df913e94e0f6c</url>
  <title>Martin Place tent city: NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian vows to end tent stand-off</title>
  <content>
Martin Place Homeless Camp Forced Out of Sydney's Financial Heart
1:19

A homeless camp in the financial heart of Sydney's CBD has been kicked out by authorities who described them as a "public nuisance".

June 24th 2017
a month ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

A stalemate continues over the Martin Place homeless camp, with the NSW government and City of Sydney both refusing to take responsibility. Picture: AAP

Jason Tin

Share

NSW PREMIER Gladys Berejiklian has given the strongest indication- yet that her government is finally preparing to break its stalemate with Lord Mayor Clover Moore over the Martin Place tent city .
As the deadlock continued, the state government said it was preparing to act but only "if forced to do so".
Both the government and City of Sydney have stubbornly refused to take ultimate responsibility for the camp's fate, both pointing the figure at each other.

City of Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore.Source:AAP

NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian. Picture: AAPSource:News Corp Australia
While the state and the police argue that council can confiscate- tents and property, Ms Moore is adamant that she lacks the power to move on the people themselves. Ms Moore said the onus is on the state to act because- Martin Place is subject to the Crown Lands Act.
Progress seemed briefly in reach as the parties met on Friday-. While Social Housing Minister Pru Goward emerged from the meeting saying it was up to council to take action, Ms Moore issued a list of demands she wanted met first. When the government fell short of meeting those demands, which included reopening the Sirius building, Ms Moore said more talk was needed.
Ms Berejiklian said that the government was "exploring all options available to it to resolve this issue".

A stalemate continues over the Martin Place homeless camp, with the NSW government and City of Sydney both refusing to take responsibility. Picture: AAPSource:AAP

Homeless man Peter Watmough in his tent at Martin Place. Picture: Getty ImagesSource:Getty Images
The state has previously said it does not want to use the Crown Lands Act to boot people- out of Martin Place, because it involves a long and complicated court process and issuing warrants. But it is understood the option is still on the table as a last resort.

Ms Berejiklian said that if council continued to refuse to act, her government would "take appropriate action to resolve this issue for the homeless people and the people of Sydney".

The sprawling homeless camp in Martin Place in Sydney's Central Business District. Picture: AAPSource:AAP

The residents of Sydney's tent city
2:08

The Daily Telegraph speaks with some of the residents of the tent city in Sydney's Martin Place

August 4th 2017
3 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

"It has become increasingly clear that Clover Moore has no interest in resolving this issue and serving her ratepayers but would rather play political games," she said. "We call on councillors of the City of Sydney to do their jobs and move against this blatant- act of politicking at their meeting."
In reply, Ms Moore called on "the Premier and Minister to do their job and provide services and supported housing for homeless especially at the start of National Homeless Week".
"I will not support moving on homeless without certainty they have support and permanent homes to go to," she said.
"That isn't politicking, it is doing my job to support society's most vulnerable, as my community expects."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Watmough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place Homeless Camp Forced Out of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Central Business District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Homeless Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Clover Moore.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JASON TIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAPSource</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Lands Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty ImagesSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Housing Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Heart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
