<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441305167843258</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/melbourne-weather-rug-up-for-a-cold-and-wet-start-to-the-week-20170806-gxqjwu.html</url>
  <title>Rug up for a cold and wet start to the week</title>
  <content>
As if Monday mornings weren't difficult enough, Victorians will be buffeted by chilly winds and rain as they head to work.
Spring may be a month away, but the state is still in the grips of wintry conditions, with a forecast top of just 12 degrees.Photo: Daniel Pockett
A cold front is making its way across the state, bringing with it a large amount of rain, strong winds and the chance of hail and thunderstorms.
"Melbourne is in for a cold day today with just 12 degrees," Bureau of Meteorology forecaster Richard Carlyon said on Monday.
"We'll see quite showery conditions, particularly over the eastern suburbs.
"We had a smattering of showers across the weekend but I think we'll see more extensive showers today with two to eight millimetres of rain."

Chilly northwesterly winds of up to 25km/h will also batter the state.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

It was a cold night in Melbourne overnight, with the apparent temperature in the city just 4.9 degrees before 7am. At Melbourne Airport it felt like 2.3 degrees.
Mr Carlyon said Monday's wild weather was associated with the back end of a cold front which sparked a severe weather warning for half of the state on Saturday night and is continuing to cause damage in South Australia.
Conditions will improve in the next couple of days before another cold front blasts Victoria at the end of the week.

"Tomorrow should be mostly fine and 15 degrees and Wednesday mostly fine and 16 degrees but another front is approaching later in the week so it will be fairly short-lived."
The cold weather has resulted in a bumper snowfall for Victoria's slopes, with 80 centimetres of fresh powder falling on Mount Hotham during the weekend.
"Across the region we had 60 to 90 centimetres, which is, for our ski-fields, a large number," Mr Carlyon said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Carlyon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Carlyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Hotham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
