<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441305167843252</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836978/winter-wonderland-as-snow-falls-on-the-central-tablelands/?cs=4219</url>
  <title>Winter wonderland as snow falls on the Central Tablelands</title>
  <content>
Winter wonderland as snow falls on the Central Tablelands

Snow fell in Oberon during cold weather on Monday August 7. It was the first decent snow for the NSW Central Tablelands in 2017.

exit

Sydney is basking in late winter sunshine but low temperatures have brought a dumping of snow to the NSW Alps.
The village of Oberon received a light dusting of white flakes on Monday morning as the NSW Central Tablelands had its first decent snowfall of the season.
At 1100 metres above sea level, Oberon regularly experiences below zero temperatures during winter with daytime temperatures in the single figures.
Snow showers carpeted the town early on Monday but were expected to clear during the day with temperatures forecast to rise to a .
The NSW Alpine region experienced the biggest natural snow dump of the season due to a low pressure system that is moving across the state.
"It is the biggest snow event of the season so far," Weatherzone senior meteorologist Jacobus Cronje said.
"It is the best natural snowfall on the Alps, which is good news for skiers."
As residents of the Snowy Mountains and Central Tablelands shivered, it was a different picture on the coast where Sydney is experiencing a run of mild, sunny days, data from theshows.
The chilly wind forecast to blow across the city on Monday will clear by Tuesday before temperatures rise towards the end of the week.
Sydney residents can expect a top temperature of 23 degrees on Thursday and Friday before the weather cools down to a top of 18 degrees over the weekend.
"We can expect cold nights followed by mild days with the temperature becoming warmer as the week progresses," Mr Cronje said.
"The temperature will be in the low to mid-20s by the end of the week before cooling down a little on the weekend.
is owned by Fairfax Media, publisher of this website.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snowy Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Central Tablelands</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cronje</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weatherzone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Tablelands</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Alpine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oberon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW ALP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacobus Cronje</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
