<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441227858431008</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/malia-obamas-crazy-dance-moves-at-lollapalooza-festival-spark-debate/news-story/ec1c51d1f23c456af039b1c10e2de564</url>
  <title>Malia Obama's crazy dance moves</title>
  <content>
FORMER US President Barack Obama's daughter Malia has sent the internet into a frenzy with her spontaneous dances moves.
Malia, 19, was at the famous Lollapalooza festival in Chicago where she was seen with one of her friends, rocking out to The Killers.
In footage obtained by TMZ, she can be seen rolling on the floor and banging her head after her friend lays down on the ground at the event.
Malia Obama rocks out on the ground

According to TMZ, sources said she was with her friends backstage for most of the set, but came out to the general area to dance later.
Malia sparked controversy when she was last seen at a music festival where she was smoking a cigarette.
Social media users were divided over the footage of her dancing. Many thought she should be left alone to be a teenager.

White people are outraged that  was acting like any other free spirited white kid at a killers concert, lol, boohoo let her live!

y'all need to leave malia obama alone

i want to be bffs with sasha and malia obama, i wouldn't sell them out like their current friends do 👀👀

Recently, she was also a production assistant for actress Halle Berry on a film set.
Berry said she was "amazing" at the job, although it was hard to imagine her a PA given who her parents were.
On an appearance on Watch What Happens Live With Andy Cohen, she also said she is a "smart, beautiful young woman."
When Cohen asked if working with her was "kinda wild," Berry admitted that it was and that she is "such a huge fan of hers."
"Were you like, 'Will you get me a coffee?' " Cohen asked. Berry responded playfully, "Could we call your dad or your mom?"
Malia is expected to go to Harvard University after she finishes a gap year.
The news comes after she also recently celebrated her father's 56th birthday.
Former President Obama is also now being honoured with a new state holiday in his former state of Illinois.
Illinois Gov. Bruce Rauner signed a measure to make August 4 "Barack Obama Day" in the state, according to NBC Chicago. The holiday will be celebrated each year on Obama's birthday beginning in 2018.
The day is "set apart to honour the 44th President of the United States of America who began his career serving the People of Illinois in both the Illinois State Senate and the United States Senate, and dedicated his life to protecting the rights of Americans and building bridges across communities."
The bill was passed by both state houses with no votes against it.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Rauner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illinois</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malia, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People of Illinois</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TMZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illinois State Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halle Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malia Obama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lollapalooza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illinois Gov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watch What Happens Live With Andy Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>States of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
