<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441262218169777</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/seven-mornington-peninsula-cafes-feature-in-the-specialty-coffee-book-victoria/news-story/b8b2ca3787153b38352e75550cc1f1e8</url>
  <title>Specialty coffee scene hot on the peninsula</title>
  <content>
BEAN hunters don't have to travel far to find a good brew on the peninsula with seven of the region's cafes featured in a new book on specialty coffee.
Publisher of The Specialty Coffee Book Victoria, Jonette Wilton George of Smudge Publishing said the Mornington Peninsula was "up there with the best".
"Melbourne is recognised for pouring the best coffee in the world and that standard is definitely reflected on the Mornington Peninsula," Ms Wilton George said.
The Smudge team visited each of the 120 Victorian cafes featured in the second edition of the book, looking at the quality of the beans used and how they were treated by individual baristas.
"It's not just about using specialty coffee beans, it's about training your barista to use their machines properly to ensure the coffee is treated correctly," she said.
Via Battisti, Mt Martha, was one of the peninsula cafes included in the original book and the latest edition, which was released late last month.
Owner Dan Force said the number of peninsula cafes included in the book demonstrated the strength of the region's coffee scene.
"There are some great cafes and coffee roasters on the peninsula," she said.
Ms Force said Via Battisti's inclusion in the book was a testament to the staff and their love of quality coffee.
"We use different methods to get the best out of the beans," she said. "Our baristas can do batch brews, pour overs, filtered, aero press; or bespoke orders for our diehard regulars."
Flock Cafe, Mornington, featured in the book for the second time.
Owner Amy Caulfield said a focus on "always improving" helped the cafe secure its place.
"We have just added a batch brew machine and spend a lot of time developing our own coffee blends with (roaster) Commonfolk," she said.
Ms Caulfield said the book was helping to educate people about the attributes of specialty coffee.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smudge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Caulfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wilton George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Via Battisti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonette Wilton George of Smudge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Specialty Coffee Book Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonfolk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battisti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Caulfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MT MARTHA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
