<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441356707451275</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/two-trapped-in-horror-smash-five-taken-to-hospital/3209473/</url>
  <title>Two trapped in horror smash, five taken to hospital</title>
  <content>
FIVE people have been taken to hospital after crashes on the Sunshine Coast overnight.
At 10.55pm yesterday a car rolled at Hunchy with three people inside.
Paramedics rushed to the scene on Hunchy Rd, and treated the patients for minor injuries.
They took two middle-aged people to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital, while the remaining passenger was taken to Nambour Hospital.
Emergency crews were then called to the intersection of Arcoona Rd and Yandina Coolum Rd at Coolum Beach at 3.49am today after a single-vehicle crash left two people trapped.
Once freed, the pair were taken to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital.
The incidents come after a weekend of heartbreak on Sunshine Coast roads.
A Landsborough motorcyclist died on Saturday after coming off his bike at Palmwoods during a lunchtime cruise.
Later that day a ute rolled after colliding with another vehicle, and police said the ute driver was lucky to escape with non life-threatening injuries.
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
"I then said, 'Hey Ryan' ... (and he) started to run."
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Fiery larrikin Peter FitzSimons had the audience in stitches.
What The Health slammed by experts
Former newsreader Tracey Spicer bares all for autobiography.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunchy Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landsborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arcoona Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina-Coolum Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
