<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440879966075710</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/opinion-how-suncentral-can-learn-from-the-nbns-fai/3209358/</url>
  <title>OPINION: How SunCentral can learn from the NBN's failure</title>
  <content>
IN SOME ways the SunCentral development at Maroochydore is like the Sunshine Coast's version of the NBN - before the NBN went to custard.
It's a project that evokes an exciting vision of the future - a high-tech development in the heart of the Coast that could forge a new era of cultural and economic development.
The dream is of a residential and business hub with exciting work opportunities and funky living for a high-salaried tech class now ensconced in West End in Brisbane, Surry Hills in Sydney, and Carlton in Melbourne
But it's also a project with risk. It's a "build it and they will come" affair, but you can never really know if they will come until they've already arrived.
So the temptation is to look for certainty. You look at things like having the council headquarters there, a university campus, an aged-care facility, even though not all of these necessarily fit the vision.
A university campus would probably work well, and some kind of council office might be a good idea, but how does the full council HQ work into the vision? And is aged care what you want in an area you might hope builds a reputation for its vibrant night life?
We're not saying any of these are necessarily bad, merely that it is critical to hold to the vision for SunCentral.
To return to the analogy, the NBN was an exciting vision that changed track because of fears around cost. That change left us with a dog's breakfast of an internet service that, depending who you ask, has ended up more expensive than it would have anyway.
If the NBN's most useful function now is as a cautionary tale, let's be sure to learn from it. If we want to dream big, then plan properly to start with and follow the dream through.
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
"I then said, 'Hey Ryan' ... (and he) started to run."
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Fiery larrikin Peter FitzSimons had the audience in stitches.
What The Health slammed by experts
Former newsreader Tracey Spicer bares all for autobiography.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunCentral</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
