<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441176318823089</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/homicide-squad-investigate-fatal-melbourne-stabbing/news-story/6adda89c011decb3c0d9decf994fd6a4</url>
  <title>Homicide squad investigate fatal Melbourne stabbing</title>
  <content>
Laura Chan was stabbed during a domestic incident on Saturday night. Picture: Facebook

Share

HOMICIDE squad detectives in Melbourne have charged a man with the murder of his housemate.
The victim, 44, died in the McGregor Court home in the suburb of Sunshine West, about 8.30pm Saturday. It's believed an argument erupted between him and a 45-year-old man over their housemate, 42-year-old Laura Chan.
The Herald Sun reports the deceased man had begun a relationship with Ms Chan while her ex-boyfriend was away.
A 45-year-old man faced an out of session's court hearing on a charge of murder and was remanded to appear at the Melbourne Magistrates' Court later Monday.
Two teenage boys who lived at the address hadn't been seen in a couple of weeks. They are believed to be the children of Ms Chan, who was also stabbed.
Her injuries are not life-threatening and she is recovering in Royal Melbourne Hospital. 7 News reported Ms Chan was in a relationship with one of the men at the home while the other was her ex-partner.

Laura Chan, believed to be in the middle of a fatal love triangle that has left one man dead in Sunshine West.Source:Supplied

Police and forensics at the scene of a suspected homicide in Sunshine West.Source:News Corp Australia
Neighbours told 7 News they felt unsafe after the "shocking' incident.
The house where the man died had seen a number of visitors coming and going, often late at night or early in the morning, and a security camera out the front had been turned around to face a garage wall.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Chan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine West.Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Chan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Melbourne Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
