<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441348117516599</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/cba-blames-austrac-breach-on-coding-issue-fixed-within-a-month-20170806-gxqk6l</url>
  <title>CBA claims it is only liable to one breach of the AUSTRAC laws</title>
  <content>
The Commonwealth Bank will argue that it should only be liable to a single contravention of the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act, reducing its liability to $18 million from as high as $960 billion.
The bank has sheeted the blame for the  scandal back to a single coding error, which was fixed within a month of discovery, in a statement released by the bank early on Monday morning.
"The vast majority of the reporting failures alleged in the statement of claim (approximately 53,000) relate specifically to this coding error," the bank says.
The statement closely followed  as the bank looks to contain the damage from the bombshell development.

In the statement, the bank says that coverage of the allegations that it's  was complex and "some facts are worth clarifying".

The bank said that its failure to generate more than 50,000 threshold transaction reports (TTRs) began after its intelligent deposit machines (IDMs) received a  in late 2012.
"Following the software update, a coding error occurred which meant the IDMs did not create the TTRs needed. This error became apparent in 2015 and within a month of discovering it, we notified AUSTRAC, delivered the missing TTRs and fixed the coding issue."
The statement has the potential to  who say that the bank ignored warnings that theIr network was being used by dozens of criminals and thier syndicates.
The bank acknowledged that there are serious allegations in AUSTRAC's statements of claim separate to the coding error however it does not provide any further details.

The bank also said that it needed to be more vigilant in the area of financial crime and money laundering and was working towards improving its processes.
The bank said that it was preparing its defence to the monster statement of claim that runs for over 500 pages and includes a 70-page document that consists solely of transactions presented on a single line.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TTRs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDMS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counter-Terrorism Financing Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
