<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441442606798493</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/kevin-pietersen-reveals-england-axing-saved-his-marriage/news-story/ef3c3a3a611eebfd03a1d19dd330c34a</url>
  <title>Dumping saved KP's marriage to pop star</title>
  <content>
CRICKET legend Kevin Pietersen has thanked England bosses for sacking him - revealing it rescued his marriage and allowed him to pursue his dream of saving rhinos.
The dad of two, who is married to former Liberty X singer Jessica Taylor, said the endless touring and pressure of captaincy put huge pressure on their family life.
Now, in an extraordinary career change, the 37-year-old is looking forward to a new life as a wildlife conservationist in Africa.
The star said: "England did me a favour in sacking me in 2014 because it has helped me with my relationship with my kids no end. I didn't want to be a lousy dad.
"For the birth of my son Dylan in 2010 I had to fly back from playing in the Caribbean, see him being born then get a helicopter to Gatwick the next day to play in a semi-final for England. I was absent.
"Jess has been a rock to me but we've had tough times.
"People don't understand the pressure that goes on between the four walls of home when it's all going wrong, like it did for me on a daily basis for a year.
"We've put up with a hell of a lot while I was playing for England.
"There are more important things than cricket.
"It sounds crazy but I now want to try to save the 30,000 rhinos that are heading for extinction because of poachers.
"Rhinos are being killed every eight hours in Africa. More than 6000 have been killed by poachers over the past decade. I knew I had to do something.
"I've achieved a lot in cricket but being part of stopping these animals dying out could top it all."
South African-born "KP" also told us says he has started putting rhino stickers on his bat in tribute to his new passion - and accepts he was "silly" to pretend to be English during his glittering career.
The outspoken star exploded on to the scene in England's victorious 2005 Ashes series, watched by peak UK audiences of 11 million.
He scored 13,000 runs for England on his way to becoming a modern great. He was appointed captain in 2008 but quit after five months amid a series of dressing room rows.
While playing international cricket, Kevin found himself away on England duty up to 10 months a year, putting a strain on him and Jessica, 37, who he married in 2007.
The cricketer, who also has 18-month-old Rosie with Jessica, became frustrated with not being able to see Dylan, now seven, when playing for his country.
He said: "I was under strict protocols. They tell you where you have be, you have to ask to do this and that.
"I had the best time playing for England. I wouldn't live here if I didn't love England. There have been hurdles. I was under the microscope. When I was captain, it was the worst year of my life. I took stock and gauged what and who was important.
"That massive fallout I had with England raised my profile and assisted and enabled me to turn a bad thing into a good thing. People think, 'Cricket, cricket, cricket'. Well, stuff cricket. It means that what Jess and the kids have now is so special. I've got such a wonderful life. I wouldn't want to be back on that England treadmill. It becomes monotonous."
Kevin is currently playing in the T20 Blast for Surrey in what will "probably be my last year ever playing in England" but is making up for lost time by throwing himself into fatherhood.
He said: "There is nothing better than being a dad. Your kids growing up is the best National Geographic film you can ever watch. You never get that again. Now I'm at home the whole time. The balance in my world, seeing my kids and going back to my roots has been fantastic.
"That sacking and the hullabaloo it caused for six months has been the best thing for my life.
"Now I wake up with the kids, put them to bed, take them and pick them up from school. I watch most of Dylan's sport. I will hands down see my kids more than a lot of people. I'm now hopefully being the best dad my kids could have. All I care about is my family and my African roots."
He and Jess, who live in Surrey, bought land just outside of South Africa's Kruger National Park last year. They are building a safari lodge that they intend to move into for the summer next year.
Kevin said: "I'm not on a luxury boat in the south of France. I'm not on a private jet heading to a party in Vegas. I'm not showboating.
"I love taking the family to see the animals and my little boy is besotted with them. Our favourite thing is to watch wildlife programs.
"I said to him the other day, 'What do you want to do when you're older?' Thankfully he doesn't want to be a cricketer but he said, 'I want to look after animals.'"
After years of playing for England, memorably getting a Three Lions tattoo on his arm in 2005 to prove his allegiance, Kevin has accepted where his true roots are.
He said: "I tried too hard to be English when I played for England. I always got annoyed when people said I was South African. I concerned myself all the time with what can I say, can I talk differently?
Getting the English tattoo was a silly moment too.
"But you have to accept, you are what you are.
"When I played for England I played to win and I was proud to wear the Three Lions but am I English? No, I'm South African."
This year Kevin is working with wildlife photographer Margot Raggett and the Born Free Foundation on Remembering Rhinos, a book featuring stunning images of the endangered animal, which will raise funds to battle poachers and boost conservation.
On August 13, Surrey's T20 Double Header at The Oval will be in aid of Remembering Rhinos, with £1 from every ticket sold going to the cause. It is one of three matches being played globally to help the species.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caribbean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Three Lions</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Pietersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa's Kruger National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica, 37</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T20 Blast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surrey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surrey's T20 Double Header</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Born Free Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margot Raggett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remembering Rhinos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberty X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
