<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441528506145689</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/severe-turbulence-on-american-airlines-flight-leaves-10-injured/news-story/0d683f3e59d11d6fff06740e0ca06a8b</url>
  <title>'Severe turbulence' on American Airlines flight leaves 10 injured</title>
  <content>
The bumpiest plane landings ever!
0:57

While air travel is, statistically speaking, the safest method of transportation, a bit of turbulence can put even the most seasoned journeyman at the edge of their seat. Hereas a collection of our favorite aviation clips. Credit: Various via Storyful

May 18th 2017
3 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Finance - syndicated/

'Severe turbulence' on American Airlines flight leaves 10 injured. Image: AP Photo/Lynne Sladky

Fox News

Share

TEN people were hospitalised over the weekend after an American Airlines flight heading to Philadelphia experienced "severe turbulence" with nearly 300 people on board.
American Airlines Flight 759 was heading to Philadelphia International Airport after departing from Athens, Greece, when it briefly encountered severe turbulence shortly before landing.
"The seat belt sign was on at the time. Three passengers and seven crew members were transported to a local hospital for evaluation," the airline said in a statement to Fox 29.
"We are taking care of our passengers and our crew members at this time and want to thank our team members for keeping our passengers safe."
Worst turbulence ever!  Athens to Phil. Even the pilot didn't see it coming. Drinks on the ceiling.
There were 287 passengers and 12 crew members on board at the time.
Passenger Ian Smith told WPVI it was 30 minutes before landing when the flight attendants told everyone to get in their seats.
"Thirty minutes out. They were giving us our drinks. The flight attendants were in the last couple rows when they said 'fasten your seat belts,'" Smith recalled to the news station.
"And then they said for the flight attendants to get to their seats, and they didn't even have time.
"It started shaking, then it took a big drop. Babies screaming, people in front of us hitting the ceiling."

Passengers said the turbulence lasted for about 15 seconds. The flight landed safely just after 3pm.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Finance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP Photo/Lynne Sladky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greece</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Airlines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Airlines Flight 759</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WPVI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
