<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441691714904929</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/michael-pell-has-sun-set-on-execs-seven-stint/news-story/8bd03d43d91eea122f64a8b630c7a1fe</url>
  <title>Has sun set for 'boy wonder' boss?</title>
  <content>
SUNRISE boss Michael Pell is at the centre of what could one of the biggest shake-ups in Australian TV.
With his contract asup this year, rival networks and overseas broadcasters are out to poach the 34-year-old, who is known as "boy wonder" in media circles.
Confidential understands Channel 10 have approached Pell to join The Project.
Pell was seen dining with The Project's EP Craig Campbell at Otto on Woolloomoollo Wharf on Saturday where they were deep in conversation. The pair have reportedly been friends for years.
Pell has been running Channel 7's
"Michael has been at Seven and Sunrise for a long time," the source said.
"He has done it all with the show and the fresh challenge is very attractive.
"Michael's passion is live TV, so The Project would be a great option for him so shake things up."
Across Sunrise and Weekend Sunrise, Pell oversees over 24 hours of live television a week.
What specific role Campbell has offered is not known.
If Pell was to take a role at Ten it could mean a move from Sydney to Melbourne where The Project is filmed.
It is understood Pell has also fielded offers from overseas broadcasters. He has previously knocked back offers to work in New York.
Pell has long been a favourite at Seven and is rumoured to be one of the top paid executives at the network.
Channel 7 chairman Kerry Stokes is said to be a big fan of the ambitious producer.
Pell has championed the Channel 7 brekkie show to win five ratings years over Today, and Sunrise looks set to claim the 2017 year after dominating in the ratings last week with more viewers than its rival on every day.
He was instrumental in bring fresh talent to Sunrise including the show's hosts Samantha Armytage, Edwina Bartholemew and Sam Mac. When asked about his contract and a potential move yesterday, Pell did not comment.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwina Bartholemew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Armytage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Pell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Project's EP Craig Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekend Sunrise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Otto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pell</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolloomoollo Wharf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
