<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441657355166115</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/same-sex-marriage/8780460</url>
  <title>Same-sex marriage bill: 'Kamikaze tactics' used to push through private member's bill</title>
  <content>
Federal Liberal MPs pushing for same-sex marriage have been accused of using kamikaze tactics.

Key points:

Liberal MPs have returned to Canberra early for a special meeting on same sex marriage
Ian Goodenough is concerned over gay couples' "impossibility of having children"
MPs are concerned voters will punish the party if it abandons the plebiscite

Liberal MP Ian Goodenough said Cabinet ministers had told him they were concerned at "kamikaze tactics" being used to push a private member's bill through.
Liberal senator Dean Smith prepared the private member's bill that would allow same-sex couples to marry.
Senator Smith and four other Liberals were arguing for MPs to be given a conscience vote in Parliament on the bill.
They had not ruled out a tactical manoeuvre that would force a parliamentary vote on the bill.
Senator Smith and his colleagues said that was the best way to deal with the issue rather than having a plebiscite or a postal ballot.
Another Liberal, John Alexander, today also called for a conscience vote in Parliament.
"I would prefer a free vote in the Parliament and have it done quickly, then everybody is responsible for the way they've voted, and in the future they'll have to face the music," Mr Alexander said.

But Mr Goodenough told the ABC he was worried about Senator Smith's bill because it did not address the issue of children, "more specifically the impossibility of having children without involving a third person, and related issues such as commercial surrogacy, reproductive technologies and the prospect of taxpayer funding of these services".
"As legislators we must consider what happens after the wedding ceremony and the honeymoon is over - what are the public policy implications for our health system, and every other area [in which] the Government provides services?" he said.
Veteran Liberal MP Warren Entsch has long argued for Parliament to allow same-sex marriage.
But Mr Entsch leaves for a stint at the United Nations in September which has added to the pressure to debate the issue within weeks.
Mr Goodenough objected to that saying the bill was "being rushed to meet someone's travel timetable without the detail being properly considered".
Liberal MPs have returned to Canberra early .
Concern over voter backlash

Liberal Craig Kelly warned voters would punish the party if it dumped the policy of having a plebiscite on same-sex marriage.
"We will pay an electoral penalty for that," Mr Kelly told RN.
"Every time you break a commitment to the Australian people there's a transactional cost. Now to go and to break that policy would be a breach of trust to the Australian people."
MPs at this afternoon's meeting are likely to stick to the plebiscite policy.
The Senate refused to agree to a plebiscite last November and is expected to maintain its stance against that position.
The Coalition may decide to have a postal ballot of voters if it cannot get Senate approval for a national plebiscite.
But campaigners for same-sex marriage have already said that might not be constitutional and they would consider challenging it in the High Court.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Craig Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Goodenough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Goodenough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Ian Goodenough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
