<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441519916210977</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/commonwealth-bank-could-face-lost-decade-of-profit-growth/8780132</url>
  <title>Commonwealth Bank could face lost decade of profit growth: analyst</title>
  <content>
Commonwealth Bank shareholders could be facing a lost decade of profit growth, similar to that endured by Westpac shareholders in the late 1980s and early 1990s and NAB shareholders in the early 2000s, cautioned a leading analyst.
The warning from CLSA's Brian Johnson, who has covered the banking sector for about three decades, came after CBA found itself embroiled in yet another high-profile scandal.
that should have been submitted to anti-money laundering regulator AUSTRAC as a result of deposits through its "intelligent deposit machines" (IDMs) that exceeded the $10,000 reporting threshold.
CBA has told the market those violations resulted from a single coding error that disable the automated reporting system for three years before the mistake was uncovered.
"These alleged contraventions could be considered to arise from a single course of conduct to the extent that they emanated from the same systems error," the bank argued in a release to the ASX.
That would be an argument for a single penalty up to a maximum of $18 million to cover all those individual breaches.
However, even if AUSTRAC and/or the court accepts this argument, CBA is alleged to have committed several other serious breaches of the anti-money laundering and terrorism financing laws.
Although the bank played down the likely scale of the penalties.
"Ultimately, a court will seek to ensure that, overall, any civil penalties are just and appropriate and do not exceed what is proper having regard to the totality of established contraventions."
Decade cycles of bank over/underperformance

Regardless of whether the penalties for CBA's money laundering breaches amount to tens of millions, hundreds of millions or potentially more than a billion dollars, Brian Johnson believes the bank's profit heyday is behind it.
"We believe there are [circa] 10-year individual bank stock cycles and success is driven by identifying either that 10-year cycle Australian bank laggard or Australian bank winner," he observed.
In addition to the cost of the penalties and the lawyers to try and reduce it, CBA has sustained further serious reputational damage, which Mr Johnson said local and overseas experience shows costs banks and their shareholders over a long period.
"In the absence of positive earnings surprises CBA's PE [price-to-earnings] premium is stretched and dividend payout ratio is vulnerable," Mr Johnson said.
"To us CBA feels like NAB in 2002 or Wells Fargo in 2016 prior to its 'fake' credit card accounts scandal."
The Commonwealth Bank also garners most of its profits from the home mortgage market, which appears to be at the top of a very large and long growth cycle and is vulnerable to a downturn.
Narev's days could be numbered as CEO

While Ian Narev has told the ABC's AM program that he is still "enjoying" his role as Commonwealth Bank chief executive, the decision may be taken out of his hands.
Already, Mr Narev has hinted that the board, which is meeting over the next two days ahead of CBA's Wednesday profit result, may cut his bonuses.

However, Mr Johnson said that may not go far enough to satisfy some investors, given the strong protest vote against CBA's remuneration report last year.
"With a no vote 'first strike' on the remuneration report at the 2016 AGM CBA look vulnerable to a second strike 'no vote' at this years AGM," he said. A no vote would leave the bank's board vulnerable to a spill motion to sack all the directors.
"While this is likely more a problem for the CBA board the pressure for management change at CBA is growing."
The chief executive of the Australian Bankers' Association Anna Bligh said it will be entirely the board's decision as to whether or not Mr Narev keeps his job.
"Ultimately, this is a question for the board to determine accountability and to determine what, if anything, is an appropriate action to take," she told Radio National Breakfast.
However, the board may also need to take some responsibility for the regulatory compliance failures, according to Susheela Peres da Costa from Regnan, a firm that advises large institutional investors about the corporate governance standards of the companies they invest in.
"What is necessary is that the board is sufficiently equipped to ask the management the right questions and to ask them the hard questions and it's management's job to provide really frank answers," she said.
"On something like regulatory compliance with this particular legislation I would expect that a board would have a very, very low tolerance for any non-compliance."
She said the board needed to have a diversity of professional experience to enable it to interrogate management about all important aspects of the business.
"One of the really important parts of that equation is having the right skills on the board to be able to ask the right questions," she added.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Johnson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLSA's Brian Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGM CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio National Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wells Fargo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susheela Peres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regnan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bankers' Association Anna Bligh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA's Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA's PE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
