<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441562865884467</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/cba-ceo-says-mistakes-were-made,-but-he-wont-be-standing-down/8780270</url>
  <title>Commonwealth Bank boss Ian Narev says he won't be standing down amid money laundering probe</title>
  <content>
The chief executive of the Commonwealth Bank (CBA) Ian Narev is refusing to quit or stand aside  to wash dirty money for criminal gangs, gun runners and potential terrorists.

Key points:

Mr Narev says he is the best person to fix the CBA's problems
CBA accused of breaking anti-money laundering laws on 53,700 occasions
Mr Narev confirmed investigations were under way to get to the bottom of allegations

Mr Narev has admitted "mistakes were made" but maintains he is the best person to fix the problems and the bank's battered reputation, while describing potential fines of almost trillion dollars as "out of the ballpark".
He said he had no plans to resign and that the CBA board had not asked him to go, despite the latest scandal to engulf Australia's biggest bank.
"Right now all of my attention is preparing for the annual results on Wednesday," Mr Narev said.
"But also spending a lot of time going through the proceedings and making sure we understand them. That's where my attention will remain.
"We've got a very big and important job to do and if we haven't done a good enough job we need to put our hands up, say why, and do a better job - we're doing that."
The financial intelligence agency Austrac has alleged the Commonwealth Bank's Intelligent Deposit Machines broke anti-money laundering laws on 53,700 occasions, and that the bank turned a blind eye to suspicious activities.
The potential fines of almost a trillion dollars have already overshadowed a record $9.8 billion full-year dollar profit expected to released by the CBA on Wednesday.
, Mr Narev confirmed that investigations were under way to get to the bottom of the allegations and weaknesses in its compliance system.
"Whenever we get matters that impact the reputation of the bank we make sure we get to the bottom of it," he said.
"And to the extent that there is accountability for individuals or teams, that is a very important part of that work that we do."

External Link:

Peter Ryan's interview with Ian Narev on Soundcloud
Calls for a royal commission rejected

The Commonwealth Bank board will meet today and tomorrow ahead of Wednesday's results, and speculation has grown that bonuses may be withheld, and some senior staff could be hit with pay cuts.
Mr Narev would not speculate, but said he would not be immune from any board decisions on pay and bonuses.
"I would expect that, including with my own remuneration, that they will take very serious account of this and see what consequences are appropriate," Mr Narev said.
While each of the 53,700 alleged breaches carries a potential fine of $18 million, Mr Narev discounted speculation of fines approaching a trillion dollars.
"The speculation on these big numbers is extremely simplistic," he said.
"When people understand the legal principles that are involved, those sort of numbers are completely out of the ballpark."
Mr Narev confirmed that the Prime Minister and Treasurer had been briefed on the latest allegations, and he once again rejected renewed calls for a Royal Commission into unlawful and unethical banking behaviour.
He said the 53,700 alleged breaches were inflated due to a coding error in software used by Intelligent Deposit Machines, which was corrected in 2015.
"This error became apparent in 2015 and within a month of discovering it, we notified AUSTRAC, delivered the missing TTRs and fixed the code issue," the CBA said in a statement.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>8.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SoundCloud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TTRs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>17</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank's Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
