<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441176318823007</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/ephemera-can-stand-alone-as-annual-event/news-story/c8abae0832d004ffa0318db4e77f89f7</url>
  <title>Ephemera can stand alone as annual event</title>
  <content>
TOWNSVILLE'S Strand Ephemera has proven to again be a huge hit, with massive crowds flocking to the city's waterfront to look at the displays of art.
Businesses on The Strand have been cashing in with the extra number of visitors producing a welcome spike in trade.
The public art festival is held every two years but this year's event has been so popular there are now calls for it to be held annually.
A similar although larger-scale event in Sydney, Sculpture by the Sea, has been held annually since 1997 and has become a major tourism attraction.
The Sydney event features more than 100 sculptures compared with the Townsville display which this year featured about 30 artworks.
Despite the difference in scale, there is no reason why Townsville can't use the success of the Sydney event as motivation to make Strand Ephemera an annual attraction.
This would increase the potential to market the event to an even wider audience.
Townsville already has a busy winter calendar of sporting and cultural events, including the Australian Festival of Chamber Music and Townsville Running Festival, both of which overlapped with Strand Ephemera.
Finding a spot on the calendar where Strand Ephemera can stand alone may be difficult but should be explored.
It deserves to have its own slot, free of competition.
Anyone who took the time to visit Strand Epehemera, particularly in the evening, would have come away impressed with the buzz it created.
Townsville needs to ensure that buzz is generated more regularly and holding Strand Ephemera annually is worthy of a trial at least.
Whale collision sends warning
SATURDAY'S frightening collision between a whale and a charter boat in the Whitsundays should be a cause for concern for the North's boaties.
It is a startling reminder of the danger these huge mammals can pose in northern waters at this time of the year.
They are heading north where many of the females will give birth before they return south in late spring.
Saturday's incident had the potential to be much more serious and although it could be considered freakish, it is clear evidence whales are potentially dangerous and boaties need to always be on alert for their presence.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strand Ephemera</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Festival of Chamber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Running Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOWNSVILLE'S Strand Ephemera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strand Epehemera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitsundays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
