<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441434016863761</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/why-is-confidfience-soaring-at-diggers-and-dealers-kalgoorlie/8774510</url>
  <title>Diggers and Dealers: With the WA economy in a slump, why is the mining industry ready to party?</title>
  <content>
It defies all popular logic that miners are getting ready to celebrate at this week's annual Diggers and Dealers Mining Forum when times are so tough.
Western Australia's economy is being described by experts as the nation's , and the mining boom is supposedly over.
Yet this week, more than 2,000 high-flyers from the worlds of mining and finance will descend on Kalgoorlie-Boulder, 600 kilometres east of Perth, for the forum.
It will be the largest turn out at Australia's most colourful mining conference has seen since the height of the boom in 2012.
Exploration drives recovery

While the iron ore price is often used as a barometer for the health of Western Australia's mining industry, gold miners make up the majority of attendees at Diggers.

"I think the industry really hit rock bottom in September-October last year," Northern Star Resources executive chairman Bill Beament said.
"But you've seen it rebound pretty quickly. The iron ore price is going up, lithium is a red-hot commodity."
Born in Esperance but educated at Kalgoorlie's historic Western Australian School of Mines, Mr Beament became a vocal figure in the gold sector as it moved through the recent downturn.
Northern Star's ability to find and extract more gold from mines close to the mining town - and bring more than 1,600 jobs with it - has also turned him into a popular local figure.
The company has spent around $150 million on exploration over the past three years, effectively tripling its known gold reserves as a result.
"You should always look under the headframe for your answers first, then spread out from that. That's always been our philosophy," he said.
"You've got to analyse the geology, prepare to spend the money and take the risk.
"I'm extremely bullish about where the sector is going because people are spending money, finding stuff in the ground, and extending the life of their mines."

Not your ordinary mining conference

Kalgoorlie's century-old Palace Hotel is the spiritual home of Diggers and Dealers, beginning as a gathering of just over 40 miners in the hotel's front bar in 1990.
Palace owner Ashok Parekh is fully booked for the next three nights and has brought on extra staff - including the headline-grabbing skimpy barmaids.

Mr Parekh says business, even if it is being done over a pint glass, remains the name of the game during the forum.
"They're business events with a little bit of social in them," Mr Parekh said.
But he said the unique backdrop brings its own advantages, particularly compared with conferences in major cities.
"You can't rush off anywhere here. You're 600 kilometres from Perth," he said.
"It ultimately means people stay together all the time and more business gets done."
Dual narrative underselling Kalgoorlie's economy

While the past year has highlighted significant social challenges in Kalgoorlie-Boulder, local businesses have faced a different issue.
"There's an anomaly here between what's happening in the Goldfields and what's happening in the Pilbara," Kalgoorlie-Boulder Chamber of Commerce and Industry CEO Hugh Gallagher said.
"Our economy is on the way up, whereas theirs has got to the point where it's stable - but a lot lower than what it was."

While the Pilbara's boom was driven by mine development and construction, the mines never stopped ticking over in the Goldfields, even during the worst of the downturn.
June saw the 60-millionth ounce of gold extracted from Kalgoorlie's golden mile since it was first discovered in 1893, with 20 million of those coming since its mines were amalgamated into the modern-day Super Pit.
Mr Gallagher said the coming boom would fuel demand for higher-skilled workers that the region may struggle to fill without an increase in population.
"We're not just talking about directly-mining related. We're talking about highly-skilled trades, we're talking about professions," he said.
"The majority of the people with the skills that we need are all spoken for."
Proceedings bring political charge

While organisers want the focus on business and investment, the 2017 forum also stands to be one of the more politically-charged in recent memory.
Geopolitical uncertainty - highlighted by  to the Trump presidency - will be the theme of the keynote address from former World Bank president Robert Zoellick on Monday morning.
The organisers' decision ,  a Welcome to Country speech triggered considerable political backlash despite its eleventh-hour resolution.
But the forum is likely to be targeted by two separate protest groups.
Supporters of the Justice for Elijah campaign are expected to continue  against the three-year jail term handed to a 56-year-old man for running down Boulder teenager Elijah Doughty.
Local contract workers who have launched legal action against mining company Eastern Goldfields Limited are also expected to picket the forum when EGL chairman Michael Fotios delivers his address on Tuesday afternoon.
Forum chairman Nick Giorgetta said he expects both demonstrations to be peaceful.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashok Parekh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Giorgetta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie-Boulder Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Parekh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palace Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Pit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Star Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie-Boulder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boulders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Zoellick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dealers Mining Forum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Fotios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Beament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elijah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Goldfields Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EGL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September-october</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Industry CEO Hugh Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian School of Mines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldfields</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elijah Doughty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
