<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441562865884476</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/technology/westpac-zipmoney-in-record-40m-deal/news-story/b1aa7a6350c35d2a7e93016ea2f35e23</url>
  <title>Westpac, Zip in record $40m deal</title>
  <content>
Westpac has poured more than $40 million into listed fintech outfit zipMoney, in what is being hailed as a 'coming-of-age' for Australian fintech.
The investment includes $40 million cash upfront with $8 million in performance options, and Zip boss Larry Diamond said his company would gain access to Westpac's customer network and expertise.
Zip, which closed a $260 million financing deal National Australia Bank in May, has now raised $300 million from two of Australia's big four banks.
"Things are changing so quickly: The rise of millennials, increasing competition and customer demands and the question of what comes after credit cards," Mr Diamond said in a statement.
"Fintech and Zip represent a pathway to the future for the major financial players who are looking to stay ahead. Zip products are a way to access new markets, new sensibilities and new ways of connecting with users. Zip will benefit from Westpac's expertise, its 200-year history and the power of its distribution capability to help fuel our growth."
He said the investment follows record quarterly results for Zip which saw users reach 665,000 and more than $300 million in transaction volume processed on the platform.
The company's core proposition, according to Mr Diamond, is its status as the only fully digital consumer finance option, with a strong focus on interest-free terms. Its proprietary technology also uses big data to facilitate fraud detection and real-time credit decisions.
Zip wants to be ubiquitous at check-outs throughout the country, putting it on a par with MasterCard and Visa.
"Zip's real-time data analytics and proprietary platform offer customers seamless payment solutions," Westpac executive Gary Thursby said. "We look forward to working with Zip to develop these capabilities and offer Westpac customers more choice in the changing payments landscape."
"Banks are coming to understand that partnering with fintechs will be one of the few ways they will be able to reach next generation of consumers and keep pace with disruptive technological and behavioural change," Mr Diamond said.
With Richard Gluyas.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mastercard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Diamond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>zipMoney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RICHARD GLUYAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Diamond</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Thursby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
