<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441610110525249</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/elaine-thompson-beaten-at-world-titles-after-usain-bolt-loss/8780326</url>
  <title>Elaine Thompson beaten by Tori Bowie at world titles after Usain Bolt's defeat to Justin Gatlin</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

First it was Usain Bolt trumped by Justin Gatlin, now Jamaica's sprinting prowess has taken another hit with Olympic champion Elaine Thompson going down in the women's 100 metres final at the world championships in London.
Thompson missed out on adding the world championship to her Olympic 100m gold

Related Story:, with American Tori Bowie snatching victory in dramatic circumstances.
Bowie edged out Marie-Josee Ta Lou on the line to claim victory by just one hundredth of a second, 10.85 to 10.86, ending Thompson's recent domination of the event.
Thompson, the 100 and 200m Olympic champion in Rio last year, finished out of the medals in fifth as Dutchwoman Dafne Schippers took bronze.
Ta Lou started well and looked set to win Ivory Coast's first world title in any event as she pulled away from the field but the big-striding Bowie came out of nowhere to close her down.
Bowie timed her dip perfectly as Ta Lou failed to throw herself at the line, giving the former victory and the US a 100m double after Gatlin's win on Sunday (AEST).
The 26-year-old Bowie, who crashed to the track beyond the finish line, went one better than her silver medal behind Thompson at the Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro last year.
"I never give up until I'm over the line," Bowie said.
"Ta Lou went away fast but she always is. It didn't bother me and I just kept pumping my legs and arms until the finish."
Thompson's shock defeat came after Bolt finished third in the men's 100m and it was the first time since the 2005 World Championships in Helsinki that Jamaica failed to win either 100 metres race.
"I have to give those three girls a lot of credit, so a big congratulations to them," Thompson said.
"I didn't execute my race which is a shame but I'm healthy.
"I don't know what happened. I just wanted to get a good start but they race well. I'll have to watch the video back because I don't know what went wrong."
New Zealand's Walsh takes shot put gold

Tomas Walsh fought off stiff competition in the men's shot put final to win New Zealand's first gold medal of the world championships.
The Olympic bronze medallist threw 22.03m with his final attempt but had already secured the gold with his third effort of 21.75m.
"[It was a] hell of a competition out there. It's awesome. It's something I've always dreamed about, being a world champion," Walsh said.
The win means New Zealand had plenty to celebrate even without four-time world champion Valerie Adams in the women's competition.
The two-time Olympic champion and world record holder missed the championships in London, as she is expecting her first child.
Australia endured a mixed day three, with the highlights being Jess Trengove's ninth place in the women's marathon via a time of 2:28.59, and Kelsey-Lee Roberts (women's javelin) and Kurtis Marschall (men's pole vault) progressing to the finals of their respective events.
Reuters/ABC

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Gatlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand's Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutchwoman Dafne Schippers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janeiro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaica</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivory Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Tori Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ta Lou</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tori Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomas Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elaine Thompson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelsey-Lee Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters/ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helsinki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie Josee Ta Lou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valerie Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
