<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441992362619673</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/construction-speeds-up-july-at-fastest-pace-in-12-years-commercial-work-jumps-20170806-gxqlog</url>
  <title>Construction speeds up July at fastest pace in 12 years: commercial work jumps</title>
  <content>
Construction activity expanded in July as commercial work grew at its fastest pace in 12 years and detached house building also sped up, the latest Performance of Construction Index showed on Monday.
The monthly Ai Group/ Housing Industry Association survey on industry conditions rose 4.5 points to 60.5 points in July, the strongest pace of overall industry growth since the survey's inception in September 2005.
Earlier previous signs of a pickup in commercial construction continued, with that sector jumping 9.8 points from June to 64.3, also the fastest pace of expansion in 12 years.
A reading above 50 indicates expansion and the further above 50, the faster the pace of expansion.

"The long-awaited pick-up in commercial construction seen over the past three months is particularly welcome in light of the anticipated wind-down in apartment building from the very high recent levels and suggests that the national construction industry will continue to play a leading role in the economy for some time to come," said Ai Group Head of Policy, Peter Burn.

Chinese-owned builder John Holland will get a third asset in its growing investment portfolio after agreeing last week to take a stake in .
Last month the  for Melbourne's Metro Rail project. Sydney and Melbourne are both tackling .
The report, which also showed house-building activity rose by 3.4 points to a three-and-a-half-year-high of 62.4, is good news for construction, as it shows that slowing housing construction sector is being offset by other areas of construction, notably commercial and engineering work.
Approvals of new dwellings  from a year earlier, official figures last week showed.

But even though the slowdown in residential approvals is largely apartment-driven, present levels of construction are holding up. Current apartment-building activity levels held up in July, the PCI showed, with that sub-sector returning to positive territory with a 4.3-point increase to 52.6. New orders in apartments have risen for six consecutive months.
Engineering construction sector also rose in July with the sector's sub-index rising by 6.9 points to 57.5, a result of greater government infrastructure spending, particularly transport projects on the eastern seaboard, the report said.
Accelerating activity is putting pressure on prices. The input prices sub-index rose 7.4 points to 73.6 in July, showing cost pressures in the construction of building projects intensified during the month, due to demand for construction materials, rising energy input costs and supplier price hikes. A separate sub-index for selling prices gained 6.7 points to 59.1.
"This growth result suggests that the pressure on input prices from rises in wages and other input costs are being passed on, although not broadly given strong market competition," the report said. "Profit margins remain under pressure for businesses in the construction industry."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ai Group Head of Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Industry Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Burn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ai Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2005</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Performance of Construction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese-owned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Metro Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
