<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441562865884488</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/ama-caught-out-most-studies-warn-of-risks-of-samesex-families/news-story/a7aafee2489ca7b113e133a04842e78b</url>
  <title>AMA CAUGHT OUT: MOST STUDIES WARN OF RISKS OF SAME-SEX FAMILIES</title>
  <content>
Why does the same-sex marriage movement rely on so much bullying, deception and suppression?  

A former senior Australian Medical Association official has lashed out at the peak medical body's campaign for same-sex marriage, accusing it of using false and misleading information in claiming the reform was a public health issue.
Dr Chris Middleton, a former president of the Tasmanian AMA, has joined with five AMA members in penning a 15-page report savaging the credibility of the national body's Position Statement on Marriage Equality.
Dr Middleton, who was inducted in the AMA Roll of Fellows in 2011, renounced his life membership of the body and was critical of its process to adopt a position in favour of gay marriage, saying the membership was not consulted...
"The position statement has very little to say about medicine and was little more than a politically motivated, ideologically-driven opinion piece which is dressed up as evidence-based health policy," Dr Middleton said...
Dr Middleton's report was scathing of the AMA for its "demonstrably false" claim that children raised by gay parents do not suffer poorer psychological health than children who are raised by their biological mother and father...
"Decades of research have confirmed that children do best, on average, when raised by their married biological mother and father," the report said.
"By denying publicly that there is any such evidence of detriment to children, while admitting privately that there is, the AMA has misled the public on a crucial aspect of the marriage debate and must be held to account."...
Dr Middleton said the AMA also provided "feeble" evidence for its assertion that legalising same-sex marriage would improve the health of gay people and give them better access to healthcare...
AMA national president Michael Gannon said that doctors had "overwhelmingly" supported the body's change in policy. He said the AMA had not suppressed any information.
UPDATE
Middleton's critique of the AMA's claims is devastating.
(Thanks to reader Leigh.)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA Roll of Fellows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian AMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA CAUGHT OUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Middleton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Chris Middleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STUDIES WARN OF RISKS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAME-SEX FAMILIES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Position Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
