<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441524211178352</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/markets-live/markets-live-bright-start-ahead-for-asx-20170806-gxqju6.html</url>
  <title>Markets Live: Will CBA bounce back?</title>
  <content>
OK, here we go: Commonwealth Bank says its failure to tell authorities about more than 53,000 large cash deposits was caused by a software update, which triggered an "error" in its reporting system that was not picked up for more than two years.

Will investors be convinced?

The bank this morning will provide a statement setting out further details about one part of the allegations last week made against it: that it failed to tell Austrac about more than 53,000 cash deposits across its ATM network of more than $10,000, as it is required to.

The statement, provided to Fairfax Media, does not directly address other allegations made last week by the government's financial intelligence agency, including that it failed to tell authorities about deposits that were less than $10,000 but suspicious all that same, and that it did not adequately monitor high-risk customers, including when it was warned by the police about suspected criminal activity.

In the statement, CBA says it took more than two years for the bank to detect an error that meant its intelligent deposit machines (IDMs) did not generate threshold transaction reports (TTRs) on transactions of more than $10,000.

"When we first rolled out these machines in May 2012, they were providing all the correct TTR reporting," the statement from a spokeswoman says.

"The issue began after an unrelated software update to the IDMs in late 2012. Following the software update, a coding error occurred which meant the IDMs did not create the TTRs needed. This error became apparent in 2015 and within a month of discovering it, we notified AUSTRAC, delivered the missing TTRs and fixed the code issue."

The comments come as pressure mounts on the bank over the scandal, which has triggered renewed calls for a royal commission into the banking industry. CBA's statement said it was taking the allegations "very seriously," and it reiterated it would file a defence, adding that legal proceedings limited what it could say.

If Friday night's US payrolls report wasn't strong enough to rattle the bond bulls, this week's inflation data may do the trick.

US employers added an above-forecast 209,000 workers in July and the jobless rate matched a 16-year low. Bank of America said the report had "everything you could ask for", and Jefferies dubbed it "rock solid!".

Yet even as 10-year Treasury yields rose Friday, they still ended the week lower, as traders looked to this week's inflation data as a better barometer of whether the Federal Reserve can hike again in 2017.

Right now they're skeptical, with the market-implied odds of more tightening by year-end below 50 per cent, in part because consumer price growth has held stubbornly under the Fed's 2 per cent goal. Given the disappointing inflation readings in recent months, yields may rise if this week's figure merely hits its mark, said Gennadiy Goldberg, an interest-rate strategist at TD Securities.

"The market has paid a lot more attention to inflation than in recent years, simply because that has the potential to be what changes the Fed's mind on further rate hikes," Mr Goldberg said. This week's report "has a pretty substantial amount of power to push rates to annual lows or getting us off those lows and pushing rates higher."

The 10-year yield will start the week at 2.26 per cent, about 16 basis points above its lowest level of 2017.

Both the consumer price index and the core figure that excludes food and energy have tumbled this year after climbing above the Fed's 2 per cent target. They likely remained below that level in July.

The median estimate in a Bloomberg survey calls for a 0.2 per cent month-over-month increase in core CPI, which would be the best since February. Here's the thing: That's been the estimate every month since September 2015, and it's been too high each time since March, according to BMO Capital Markets.

As a result, traders have set the bar low for CPI.
And here are the weekend market highlights:

SPI futures up 22 points or 0.4% to 5682

AUD -0.3% to 79.29 US cents (Session range: 0.7891 - 0.7980)

On Wall St, Dow +0.3%, S&P 500 +0.2%, Nasdaq +0.2%

In New York, BHP +1%, Rio +1.4%

In Europe, Stoxx 50 +1.2%, FTSE +0.5%, CAC +1.4%, DAX +1.2%

Spot gold -0.7% to $US1259.20 an ounce

Brent crude +0.7% to $US52.37 a barrel

US oil +1% to $US49.53 a barrel

Iron ore +1.6% to $US74.12 a tonne

Dalian iron ore +2.7% to 563 yuan

LME aluminium -0.3% to $US1910.50 a tonne

LME copper +0.3% to $US6372 a tonne

10-year bond yields: US 2.26%, Germany 0.46%, Australia 2.62%

On the economic calendar:

AiG construction index at 9:30am AEST, ANZ job ads at 11:30

New Zealand quarterly inflation expectations at 1pm

Stocks to watch:

Bluescope raised to overweight at JPMorgan

​Sims Metal cut to neutral at JPMorgan

Trade Me (raised to hold at Morningstar

More records on Wall St set an upbeat background for investors this week, but the accelerating flow of news from reporting season will ultimately set the tone on the ASX.

The Dow powered higher for an eighth consecutive day on Friday as positive economic news strengthened the US Federal Reserve's bias toward tighter monetary policy and the Trump administration revived chatter about tax reform.

The benchmark 30-member index rose 0.3 per cent, extending its record-setting streak and an advance above the 22,000-point mark.

At home, the August profit reporting season ramps up in the week ahead with around 20 major companies reporting, providing plenty of news for shareholders to chew over. Highlights include hearing implants maker Cochlear on Tuesday, Commonwealth Bank, James Hardie and Carsales on Wednesday, and then on Thursday there are reports from AMP, packaging company Orora and AGL Energy.

"As always, in a low interest rate world dividends will be a key focus," AMP Capital head of investment strategy Shane Oliver said. "But the key to watch will be outlook statements, as the current financial year won't have a repeat of the huge boost in commodity prices to resources profits".

Profits over the 2017 financial year are expected to have jumped by around 18 per cent, driven by a more than doubling in earnings for the listed resources sector as commodity prices rebounded from their 2016 lows. Elsewhere, profit growth remains subdued at around 5.5 per cent, on AMP Capital estimates.

"The challenge is that the good news with regard to strong mining sector profits - owing to last year's iron-ore price surge - appears largely priced in, while non-mining results are likely to be patchy, reflecting subdued growth, a high Australian dollar and intense competition," BetaShares chief economist David Bassanese said.
Good morning and welcome to the Markets Live blog for Monday.

Your editors today are Jens Meyer and Patrick Commins.

This blog is not intended as investment advice.

Fairfax Media with wires.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LME</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC +1.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BetaShares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bassanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morningstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US52.37</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX +1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markets Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TTR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow +0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1910.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jefferies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio +1.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.62</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hardie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Commins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD -0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP Capital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TTRs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDMS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jens Meyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 (  ): +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US49.53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sims Metal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 2.26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CarSales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6372</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluescope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMO Capital Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 +1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74.12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed's 2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TD Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE +0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Goldberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP +1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1259.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gennadiy Goldberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
