<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441481261504825</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/adelaide-crows-ruckman-sam-jacobs-sets-sights-on-toptwo-finish-for-afl-pacesetter/news-story/5ce2f2ed231c9f4a9a3b16b4d90c1b1c</url>
  <title>Crows in rush to lock in home AFL finals</title>
  <content>
CROWS ruckman Sam Jacobs has put the Adelaide Football Club's focus firmly on locking a top-two finish - and unlocking the trophy cabinet at West Lakes.
"We are in a rush to get where to we want to," said Jacobs, the Showdown Medallist as best-afield in the 84-point win against Port Adelaide in Showdown 43 at Adelaide Oval on Sunday.
That record belting of the Power has guaranteed the top-ranked Crows a top-four finish. A top-two placing - with the right to two home finals next month - will be secured with two wins from the remaining three home-and-away matches against Essendon (away), Sydney (home) and West Coast (away).
"We set our goals to qualify for the finals - and then reassess," Jacobs told TripleM on Monday. "Now we are in a position where we have locked away top four. Within the team we are focused on making sure we get the home final now.

AFL: Listen in to the Adelaide Crows post match press conference.

Crows press conference
"We were disappointed with the way we finished last year (missing a top-four berth) and the way we performed in Sydney (with a semi-final loss to the Swans at the SCG).
"We have a group of guys who have played a lot of footy together now - and we are in a rush to get to where we want to. We're trying to set ourselves up as best we can."
Jacobs noted the strong form - and premiership aspirations at West Lakes where the AFL flag last flew in 1998 - could become influential in swaying the decisions of out-of-contract duo Jake Lever and Mitch McGovern who are eagerly being sought by rival AFL clubs to return to their home states of Victoria and WA respectively.
"You can imagine the banter that goes on in the changerooms," Jacobs said. "We let them know what a good spot they are in at the moment."
michelangelo.rucci@news.com.au
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TripleM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown Medallist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacobs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Lakes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
