<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441734664578359</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/food/restaurants-bars/handsome-her-cafe-in-brunswick-melbourne-charges-men-18-gender-gap-surcharge/news-story/81fc5074b7e9be8aa05240f157774e31</url>
  <title>Handsome Her cafe in Brunswick, Melbourne charges men 18% 'gender gap' surcharge</title>
  <content>
Vegan Cafe in Melbourne charges 'man tax'
0:24

A 'feminist' Vegan cafe in Melbourne is charging an optional 'man tax' of 18% to protest against the gender pay gap. Courtesy: Seven News Melbourne

August 7th 2017
3 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Lifestyle - syndicated/Food/

The blackboard outside Handsome Her has caused quite a stir.

Share

A MELBOURNE cafe that caused a social media storm after charging men a tax and seating women first insists it has had a stack of support.
And not just from the girls.
Handsome Her, a vegan cafe in Brunswick, said it was charging men 18 per cent more in a bid to address the gender pay gap.
The cafe, which clearly advertises its rules on a chalk board, explained men will be charged the premium - and the gap donated to women's services.
However co-owner Alex O'Brien told Seven News the surcharge, which is in place one week out of every month, wasn't compulsory.
She also said none had so far refused to pay it and in a Facebook post overnight said the idea has been well supported overall.

Handsome Her say the premium is being used to help support women's services.Source:Supplied
"If people aren't comfortable paying it or if men don't want to pay it, we're not going to kick them out the door," she said.
"It's just a good opportunity to do some good."
Would LOVE everyones thoughts on this. My friends cafe in , Handsom Her - is for women by women AND an has a 18% gender tax!
The idea has caused a mixed reaction on social media, with some supporting the concept.

love it! Spaces for ladies is always great and highlighting the pay gap like this is harder for people to ignore.
I love it. Especially if it creates an environment where women feel safe
Pay gap def worth talking about but reckon much repulsive male vitriol comes from low-paid lads who can't work out why they're being blamed.
Others branded it hypocritical and said it would only further widen the gender divide.
If it was the other way around there would be riots in the streets!!!
I think if you want to fight for equality then surely treating everyone the same is the way to go
Not a fan. Whilst appreciate highlighting the issue of pay, creating an us and them is divisive. Flip this, and Twitter is in flames.
This sums my thoughts up perfectly. I get the idea behind it, but I can't help but feel that it creates a bigger divide.
Discrimination is illegal, regardless of the spurious intent. Do they hire male staff or do they discriminate there too?
Writing on its overnight, the cafe insisted it was jam-packed with customers over the past few days who have shown their support for the cause.
It also insisted it wasn't just women who were backing the idea.
"We've had men travel across town to visit us and pay 'the man tax' and throw some extra in the donation jar - guys, you're pretty neat," the post read.
The cafe also thanked its staff who have taken it all in its stride.
"It's not every day that your boss pulls you into her fire-pit of feminism and you have to quickly become warriors and defend where you work and what you do on a level that others never do," the post continued.
"You have not only been incredibly strong, proud and supportive, but nurturing and protective as well."

Cafe owner Alex O'Brien, left, said she wanted to highlight the issue of unequal pay for men and women.Source:Supplied
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handsome Her</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handsom Her</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex O'Brien</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Lifestyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
