<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440879966075757</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/dream-home-in-millionaires-row-slashed-by-3m-to-go-at-cost-price/news-story/34dd00b552dc3c5b3a10bd7359e7ba3c</url>
  <title>Dream home in Millionaire's Row slashed by $3m to go at cost price - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
187-191 Hedges Avenue, Mermaid Beach Qld 4218. Picture: Realestate.com.au

A STUNNING beachfront home on the Gold Coast's Millionaire's Row has had its price slashed by a whopping $3 million.
The five bedroom, five bathroom, seven car garage dream home at  in Mermaid Beach was being marketed at $16.995 million by Professionals agent Luke Henderson.
"This home is for sale well below its replacement cost - that is if you could ever again find three adjoining blocks side-by-side on Hedges Avenue.

The beach in front of the property is patrolled by lifesavers. Picture: Realestate.com.au

No expense was spared to create this dream home. Picture: Realestate.com.au

"It was built considering every individual detail, with the finest of quality materials and with the thought that it would never ever be sold - however circumstances have changed and now is your opportunity to secure your dream home without waiting the three years that it took to design and build."
Designed by architect Paul Uhlmann, the property has a whopping 30 metres of direct frontage on the patrolled beach.

A bath with a view. Picture: Realestate.com.au

The ultimate mancave. Picture: Realestate.com.au

Imagine waking up to this. Picture: Realestate.com.au

It has a dream list of features including a massive yard that the size of one whole block of land, a mancave that includes a study, pool table, bar, powder room and massive four-screen television, inground tiled magnesium pool and spa, a lift to three levels and an impressive chef's kitchen.

The home has a magnesium pool. Picture: Realestate.com.au

Perfect spot for a barbecue. Picture: Realestate.com.au

The home was designed by architect Paul Paul Uhlmann. Picture: Realestate.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mermaid Beach Qld 4218</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realestate</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mermaid Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Paul Uhlmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hedges Avenue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millionaire's Row</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Uhlmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast's Millionaire's Row</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
