<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441700304839600</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/what-croc-monster-beast-caught-outback-wrangler/3209498/</url>
  <title>WHAT A CROC: Monster beast caught by outback wrangler</title>
  <content>
AN image of a monster crocodile caught by Outback Wrangler Matt Wright has gone viral, with some animal lovers criticising the use of duct tape to bind the animal's snout shut.

Mr Wright uploaded a snap of the saltie to his Facebook page on Saturday, and it has already attracted more than 4000 likes and hundreds of shares and comments.

WANT MORE?

Many people were quick to point out the thick layers of tape covering the croc's snout and eyes.

Tom Miller estimated it would have taken 10 rolls of duct tape to cover the saltie's mouth.

"Did you get enough tape on him?" Sally-Jo Famlonga said. "Hope that's not staying on for too long poor boy."

Dean Adermann said he could see no reason why the monster was caught in the first place. "Leave the poor animal alone," he said.

Others were quick to jump to Mr Wright's defence.

"It's a crocodile, they've been around since the dinosaurs," Jay Ryan said.

"I'm sure he doesn't mind a bit of tape on his snout."

Rebecca De Vries praised the Wrangler's team for catching the saltie and keeping the community safe.

Andrew Buckley pointed out croc catchers moved on salties so they didn't pose a threat in populated areas, or risk being shot by people.

"Most times these crocs are being relocated as they have clashed with humans/livestock and so if good people don't relocate them, some redneck will just shoot it," he said.

Matt Wright was unable to be reached for comment.

Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
Local legend needs your help
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Fiery larrikin Peter FitzSimons had the audience in stitches.
What The Health slammed by experts
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wrangler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally-Jo Famlonga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outback Wrangler Matt Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Adermann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca De Vries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wright</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
