<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441867808566136</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/07/10/26/isis-teen-arrested</url>
  <title>Iraqi soldiers cheer as German teen arrested for joining Islamic State</title>
  <content>
A German teenager arrested for joining Islamic State has been filmed as cheering Iraqi soldiers jostled her through a crowd, while the 16-year-old wailed despairingly.
German media outlet Bild has published video purportedly showing Linda Wenzel's arrest in Mosul at the end of last month.
Wenzel appears distraught however only screams out once, though she does appear to be holding back tears.
Wenzel's parents have been desperately looking for her since she disappeared from her home town of Pulsnitz, near Dresden, in July last year.
She is suspected of converting to Islam after being groomed by ISIS members on social media.
Dresden prosecutor Lorenz Haase said at the time of the arrest there was a possibility "Linda might be put on trial in Iraq, she might, as a foreigner, be expelled, or because she is a minor reported missing in Germany, she could be handed over to Germany".
According to Iraq's counter-terrorism laws, Wenzel could theoretically face the death penalty, the Associated Press claims, but could not be executed until she reaches age 22.

Related Articles

The report cites Iraqi sources as saying Wenzel had married a Muslim man in Iraq.
Wenzel was arrested by Iraqi forces after she and a group of 20 female ISIS supporters from various countries barricaded themselves inside a tunnel in the ruins of Mosul with guns and explosives, .
German weekly Der Spiegel reports that Wenzel had been detained in Baghdad with three other German women, where they were questioned following the liberation of Mosul.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pulsnitz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dresden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baghdad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraqis</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mosul</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wenzel</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Der Spiegel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Wenzel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bild</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorenz Haase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
