<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441777614251860</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/cricket/england-v-south-africa-moeen-alis-blazing-halfcentury-puts-hosts-on-brink-of-series-victory/news-story/3a6be7220c5c08dabfb5b38b9581abef</url>
  <title>Magic Moeen puts England on the brink of win</title>
  <content>
MOEEN Ali's dashing fifty all but put the fourth Test beyond South Africa's reach as England moved towards a series win at Old Trafford on Sunday.
When rain ended the third's play, England were eight for 224 in their second innings - a lead of 360 runs - with Moeen 67 not out.
South Africa now need to set a new ground record if they are to end this four-match series all square at 2-2. No side has made more in the fourth innings of a Test at Old Trafford to win than England's four for 294 against New Zealand in 2008.
LIVE stream England v South Africa on FOX SPORTS. Get a free 2-week Foxtel Now trial & stream LIVE within minutes.
Off-spinner Moeen has been a thorn in South Africa's side with both bat and ball this series.
This innings meant he'd now scored 200 runs and taken 20 wickets in the series, with Moeen the first England player to perform that 'double' since Andrew Flintoff in the 2005 Ashes.
Moeen made South Africa pay for Dean Elgar dropping him on 15 when a low slip chance off left-arm spinner Keshav Maharaj did not stick. It was a drop that would cost Maharaj in particular, with Moeen hitting him for three resounding sixes.
The second of those, a straight drive that saw Moeen complete a 49-ball fifty, was 'caught' on the England dressing-room balcony by wicketkeeper Jonny Bairstow to the delight of the crowd.
"We needed a bit of momentum and it came off for me," Moeen told Sky Sports. "Sometimes you have to take the odd risk." England are bidding for a first home Test series win over South Africa since 1998, with Root seeking a victory in his first Test series as England captain.
RECORD CHASERS:
SID'S ASHES XI:
South Africa resumed the day on nine for 220 and were soon all out for 226 when Stuart Broad dismissed last man Duanne Olivier.
That gave England a healthy first-innings lead of 136.
Olivier's exit meant James Anderson, England's all-time leading wicket-taker - was denied a maiden five-wicket Test innings haul on his Lancashire home ground.
But figures of four for 38 in 17 overs gave Anderson, who'd struck four times from the newly-named James Anderson End on Saturday, his best innings return in seven Tests at Old Trafford.
South Africa fast bowler Morne Morkel then removed both Alastair Cook (10) and Tom Westley (nine) with the aid of gully catches.
Keaton Jennings, dropped on nought, fell for just 18 when he edged a cut off Kagiso Rabada to first slip Hashim Amla.
It was the latest in a run of low scores - the South Africa-born opener managed just 127 runs in four Tests this series at an average of 15.88 - that have left Jennings at risk of being dropped for the start of England's upcoming three-Test series at home to the West Indies, which precedes an Ashes tour of Australia.
Dawid Malan, out for scores of one and 10 on Test debut during England's 239-run victory in the third Test at The Oval, was also looking to cement his place after falling for 18 in the first innings of this match.

Cricket: England finished at 8/224 on day three with Moeen Ali saving the day with 67 not out.

Ali inspires England
But the Middlesex left-hander, born in London but brought up in South Africa, exited for six - having been dropped on five - when caught via bat and pad at short leg off Maharaj.
Root (49) and Ben Stokes (23), however, then shared a valuable stand of 57. They both fell to paceman Olivier, only playing this match after back injuries ruled out both Vernon Philander and Chris Morris.
Olivier, who took an impressive three for 38 in total, insisted South Africa could yet achieve a remarkable win.
"If we can bowl them out for 380, I still believe it is possible," he said. "England batted really well but we still have a chance.
"It is going to be difficult but it should be - it's Test cricket."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kagiso Rabada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duanne Olivier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Indies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny Bairstow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vernon Philander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middlesex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivier</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hashim Amla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keshav Maharaj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SID'S ASHES XI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawid Malan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moeen 67</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Stokes (23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moeen Ali</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Elgar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maharaj</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lancashire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moeen</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Moeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Westley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Trafford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Flintoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alastair Cook (10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morne Morkel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keaton Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Anderson End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
