<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441090419475872</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836896/man-threatens-to-slit-registrars-throat-in-court/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Wagga man threatens to slit registrars throat in court</title>
  <content>
Wagga Local Court

After spending a night behind bars for allegedly intimidating a manager at a shelter he was banned from - it still wasn't enough to stop this Wagga man. 

Threatening to slit the court registrar's throat as he was refused bail, Jason Maxell Hurst, 48, just didn't know how to stay quiet. 
Slurring at the court registrar to "get on with it" as he read out his offences, the Ashmont man continuously interrupted during his bail application as he sat restlessly in the cells, appearing via video link. 
"All I did was ask to shower that's all I've done - I haven't had a shower in two weeks," Hurst said. 

Hurst's solicitor said corrections had informed him his client would rather sleep in the cells than talk to his lawyer as he addressed the court. 
"In the words of corrections he is a problem child who is not a child your honour," Mr Kennedy said. 
Hurst is facing three charges including intimidation with intent to cause fear, possession of a prohibited drug and possession of equipment to administer a prohibited drug. 

Charges allege the accused was in possession of a cannabis leaf and pipe when police were called to the shelter on August 3. 
Hurst's solicitor submitted just two lines, informing the court the accused was on a number of a good behaviour bonds when he committed the alleged offences. 
Police prosecutor Peter Robertson told the court the offence was what he would call an appalling matter, as the accused continued to shout and interject. 
"Of course you would say that," Hurst said. 

Mr Robertson said he opposed bail as he referred to Hurst's tremendous criminal history. 
"The victim was merely trying to care for vulnerable people and now needs the protection of the court," Mr Robertson said. 

According to police facts tendered to the court, Hurst attended the Riverina shelter for the second time at about 8pm on August 3, after he was asked to leave earlier that day. 
The facts state the manager reminded the accused of the ban, as Hurst told her he would get her and would return when she finished work. 
Wagga registrar Paul Fernon told the court Hurst had not shown why his detention wasn't justified as he refused bail. 

Staff were forced to mute the screen as Hurst erratically continued to scream and threaten the registrar. 

Hurst will next face court on August 7.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hurst</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Robertson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Fernon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Maxell Hurst, 48</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
