<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441047469802402</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/man-shot-by-police-after-hostage-situation-in-grafton/news-story/9c2ac0963c4efbce7c652757d3e8074a</url>
  <title>Man dies after being shot by police</title>
  <content>
A knife-wielding man has died after being shot by police in a stand-off at Grafton yesterday.
A critical incident investigation team has been established to investigate the shooting.
Police said they were called to a house in Turf St after reports of a disturbance about 3.45pm yesterday.
"On arrival officers were allegedly confronted by a man armed with a knife," police said in a statement.
Officers told him to put down the weapon and tried to use a Taser stun gun on him, but it was unsuccessful and police were forced to shoot.
The officers treated the man at the scene until the arrival of NSW Ambulance paramedics.
He was taken to Grafton Base Hospital in a critical condition, before being airlifted to the Gold Coast University Hospital where he died.
Police have appealed for witnesses to come forward or contact CrimeStoppers on 1800 333 000.
The shooting comes more than a week after
Mokmool was shot dead by police after a terrifying stand-off in which he held a bottle to the throat of a florist.
Police have launched a critical incident investigation in relation to the fatal shooting.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton Base Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimestoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mokmool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turf St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
