<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441090419475869</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4836900/injured-woman-found-unconscious-in-the-gutter/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Injured woman found unconscious in the gutter</title>
  <content>
Police are appealing for information after a woman was found unconscious in a gutter with serious injuries on the Central Coast.

About 2.15pm on Sunday the 54-year-old woman was found at the intersection of Fairview and Copnor Avenues, The Entrance.
The woman had head injuries and was taken to Wyong Hospital by ambulance. The woman remains unconscious and police are unable to speak with her to ascertain what happened.
Police from Tuggerah Lakes Local Area Command  are investigating whether her injuries are a result of misadventure or assault.
Officers have been told the woman was seen walking around a car park with a small dog just before she was found unconscious.
At the time she was wearing pyjama pants with 'Batman' on them and ugg boots. She may have been living out of her car, a silver Saab, which was parked in the car park.
Detectives also believe a customer of the nearby bottle shop may have witnessed what happened to the woman and possibly even taken video footage of her.
They are appealing for that person and anyone else who may have information about how the woman came to be injured to come forward.
Call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or use the Crime Stoppers online reporting page:   

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuggerah Lakes Local Area Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Copnor Avenues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairview</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
