<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441738959545732</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/the-magic-number-13-will-be-lucky-for-those-teams-wanting-a-slice-of-finals-action/news-story/d2f5ca883f2aaca4ca22b5fee1cf332e</url>
  <title>The magic number 13 will be lucky for some</title>
  <content>
THIRTEEN wins is the AFL's "magic number" to September action. For the second time in the past three seasons, 13 wins will be needed to qualify for next month's AFL top-eight finals.
And that cut-off point puts St Kilda and Melbourne in a knock-out clash at the MCG on Sunday as the race to September develops a sharp focus on the last two spots in the final eight.
The field for these two spots is now reduced to AFL premiers Western Bulldogs, Essendon, Melbourne, West Coast and St Kilda.
The 11th-ranked Saints (10-9) stayed on the tightrope to September with a dramatic eight-point win against West Coast at Etihad Stadium yesterday - a result that puts the Eagles (10-9) at risk of missing the finals for the first time since 2014.

St Kilda is favoured by history in its match-up with the 10th-placed Melbourne. However, the Saints lost to the Demons for the first time since 2006 in round one by 30 points.
Melbourne's draw - with bottom-10 opponents in St Kilda, Brisbane and Collingwood, all at the MCG - is coupled with the Demons needing to win all three games to reach the magic number of 13 and to qualify for the finals for the first time since 2006.
Same with eighth-ranked Essendon as the Bombers (10-9) can expect to lose to top-ranked Adelaide at Etihad Stadium on Saturday night and then fall short of a top-eight berth even with wins against Gold Coast (away) and Fremantle (home). West Coast should advance to 11 wins on a return to its Subiaco base on Saturday to start as favourites against Carlton.
But finding the 13th wins will be difficult as the Eagles' final two home-and-away games are against top-two contenders GWS (away) and Adelaide (home). The top-eight finals will begin on September 7.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
