<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441953707913265</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/police-hit-stumbling-block-in-donna-steele-investigation/8780458</url>
  <title>Queensland police hit 'investigative block' in Donna Steele homicide probe</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A lack of security footage is proving to be a stumbling block as homicide detectives investigate the suspected murder of a woman in the small Cape York community of Cooktown.
A body, believed to be that of 42-year-old Donna Louise Steele, was found early on Sunday morning in Isabella Creek, at Leggett's Crossing.
The waterway off the Endeavour River is a well-known fishing spot for residents.
Ms Steele had been missing since last Wednesday, and a search involving a rescue helicopter and the SES had not located her.
The body was found about 20 kilometres from Ms Steele's home, and police are gathering statements from residents.
Four crime scenes have been established, including at Ms Steele's house and a nearby property.
Detective Inspector Geoff Marsh said the lack of CCTV cameras in the town was an "investigative block".
"Even at the store, [CCTV] was within the store, there's nothing in the streets," he said.
"Unfortunately we're yet to find that piece of information that'll assist us to get closure."
Specialist police from Brisbane are at the scene and the dive squad is expected to search the waterway later this week.
"The feeling in the community is absolute shock, Cooktown is a small coastal community, very tightknit community, they all know each other," Detective Inspector Marsh said.
"Obviously the story of the missing person was of great alarm to a lot of people, a lot of volunteers came and assisted in the search."
Ms Steele had two young sons, aged eight and 10, who were now being looked after by their father.
"They're obviously being cared for by their father now and we're offering all the support we can now from the Queensland Police perspective," Detective Inspector Marsh said.
"There's nothing to suggest that it's a random attack or a random event ... we're confident that this is a known person to her."
Ms Steele's partner worked outside Cooktown and raised the missing person alarm after returning home on Thursday evening.
"Upon his arrival home obviously the absence of the mother of the children was of grave concern," Detective Inspector Marsh said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooktown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabella Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Louise Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Steele</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leggett's Crossing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Endeavour River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Marsh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Geoff Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
