<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441867808566148</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/a-west-australian-wedding-celebrant-married-a-woman-who-was-comatose/news-story/79258c97848f889128cf7c05c2873a1e</url>
  <title>Celebrant marries comatose bride</title>
  <content>
A WEST Australian marriage celebrant could be banned from marrying couples after she was found to have married a woman who was comatose and unable to say "I do".
Diane Caratozzolo-Waddington, of Perth, married the dying woman and her partner in October 2015. The bride was in the final stages of cancer and was not awake for any of the wedding ceremony, according to a local newspaper .
Ms Caratozzolo-Washington pleaded guilty to purporting to solemnise a marriage when she appeared at the Rockingham Magistrates Court last week.
The court heard at the point the woman was supposed to confirm she took her partner as her lawful husband, Ms Caratozzolo-Washington said: "Oh, she can't answer, but I know she wanted to get married when I saw her before."
It's believed she told the man to put a pen in his unconscious wife's hand and sign an "X" as her signature.
The Weekend Courier reported Ms Caratozzolo-Washington's lawyer told the hearing she had performed more than 300 weddings and always did her best.
The president of the Australian Federation of Civil Celebrants, Anthony Burke, told  he'd never ever heard of a case where a celebrant had married a couple where one of them was not conscious.
Ms Caratozzolo-Washington would now need to wait until the Attorney-General's Department had reviewed the situation - with a possible outcome being could be she is struck off as a celebrant.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockingham Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diane Caratozzolo-Waddington, of Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federation of Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekend Courier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General's Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Caratozzolo-Washington</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
