<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441262218169844</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/angry-port-adelaide-coach-ken-hinkley-rejects-china-theory-we-got-bashed-up-20170806-gxqkh0.html</url>
  <title>Angry Port Adelaide coach Ken Hinkley rejects China theory: 'We got bashed up'</title>
  <content>
Coach Ken Hinkley reacted angrily on Sunday night after his team's record 84-point loss to Adelaide when it was suggested the China connection had taken its toll on Port Adelaide.
He dismissed a growing theory that because the Power travelled to China and had the bye earlier than the other clubs apart from Gold Coast they had become worn out.

Up Next

Bolt defeated by Gatlin in final 100m race

00:23

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Adelaide Crows crush Port Power

The Crows may have failed to hit the mark early on but soon corrected their form to produce their biggest ever margin over port in showdown 43.

Hinkley, who is not one to hide from criticism, said he was not an excuses coach.
"I reckon that would be a really long bow to draw," he said of the early bye. "That would be an insipid response by me to say that was the reason.

"We didn't work hard enough [against Adelaide]. There is a level of work that you have to bring; a level of competitiveness that you have to bring. Don't bring the other fluffy excuses in of you can't back up effort.
"The side we played were a really good side, but were they that much better? Come on, don't give me that."

In an amazing statistic, Adelaide had 50 more inside-50 entries - 81-31. They also had 46 more contested possessions.
"We got bashed up," Hinkley said. "I find it inexcusable to play that poorly when there is a bit to be done.Photo: AAP
"It was a terrible, a really poor performance. We were dominated from the start to the end. It was unacceptable. We got smashed in every area.
"Our form line has been worrying, particularly around the contest. Our ability handle heat hasn't stood up as well as we would like it to. We have enough size in there to do that, so I think we do not have a hardness about us at the moment that is required to play high level football."Photo: AAP
Adelaide coach Don Pyke was particularly pleased about his players' ability to maintain the intensity and pressure around the ball for four quarters.
"That allows you to get the outcome," Pyke said. "We came from the back off a minus-50 contested possession last week; it was a good response.
"Our midfield is an area that has grown. At the start of the year there were questions but they keep on taking on the challenges and they keep getting better and better some of those guys ... they are elevating their game to a really high level and a really high consistent level.
"It's been pleasing to see their growth. They now have a feeling for what they are capable of doing in games of footy and that only helps them."
In a remarkable team performance, ruckman Sam Jacobs was awarded the Showdown Medal. He highlighted a really strong self belief in the group compared with some recent years.
"A lot of guys have now played four, five or six years together and now we have got some real stability," Jacobs said. "We are a really focused group; a really driven group. There is a real rush to get to where we ant to."
Port expects to regain Chad Wingard (ankle) and Matthew Broadbent (ankle) for next Sunday's clash with Collingwood at Adelaide Oval, while Adelaide has concerns for defender David Mackay (corked thigh) for their contest with Essendon at Etihad Stadium on Saturday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinkley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Pyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
