<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441906463272380</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/southeast/elios-osteria-diners-catch-thief-in-attempted-robbery/news-story/7591c07aa38d8dad5ec3e0d2880f1c42</url>
  <title>You wanna pizza this?</title>
  <content>
HUMBLE diners became heroes after they foiled a would-be thief's attempted bag snatch at a suburban pizzeria.
Elio's Osteria owner Paul Campbell said the dinnertime rush was on when a woman's handbag was snatched from an outside table.
"Two tables of people chased him down and stopped him," Mr Campbell said.
The patrons held the alleged offender until police arrived.
He had dropped the handbag and purse, which were found and returned to the owner.
Mr Campbell gifted the woman her dinner and also rewarded the heroes, who he said were regular customers, with pizza.
He said as people became more absorbed by their smartphones, they were losing their sense of community.
"It delights me that a group of people who didn't know each other raced up and rushed to somebody's aid," he said.
"Nobody called for help, it just happened.
"I'd love to say thank you to the people who helped and left our customer with fond memories of our pizza joint in the suburbs."
A Queensland Police Service spokesman confirmed a juvenile stole a woman's handbag at 8.45pm and was chased by diners.
He said the alleged offender would be dealt with under the Youth Justice Act.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elio's Osteria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Campbell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Justice Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
