<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441481261504820</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/why-these-lies-about-the-people-swap/news-story/875f272781996d8699717cee10357849</url>
  <title>WHY THESE LIES ABOUT THE PEOPLE SWAP?</title>
  <content>
A leaked transcript shows Malcolm Turnbull telling Donald Trump that we'd take his unwanted refugees if he took out boat people. So why did Turnbull and other minister keep lying to us about what they denied was a people swap? Check the quotes.

It is not linked to any other resettlement discussions... The announcement today is not connected to any other arrangements.

There is not, and there will be, no people swap.

Speculation that it may be linked to an arrangement with the US or any other country or that this is part of a 'people swap' is false.

No, well again, just to reinforce the Costa Rica arrangement had nothing to do with this deal and it's not a people swap.
There are some countries where you do need to enter into a transactional arrangement where we need to swap this for that or we want this for that. That's not the nature of the relationship with the US.

Please, if we can agree to stick to the deal...
Basically, we are taking people from the previous administration that they were very keen on getting out of the United States. We will take more. We will take anyone that you want us to take.
Aren't voters sick of being lied to?
(Thanks to reader Clinton.)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa Rica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LIES ABOUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PEOPLE SWAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
