<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442078261966500</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/banking-and-finance/cba-says-53506-alleged-late-reports-may-be-one-breach-20170806-gxqlik.html</url>
  <title>CBA says 53,506 alleged late reports may be one breach</title>
  <content>
Commonwealth Bank says a string of failures in its automated reporting system may be only one breach of the law, which would mean any fine facing the bank over allegations it broke anti-money laundering laws would be drastically lower than speculated.
It came as chief executive Ian Narev said the board of directors would take "very serious account" of the latest scandal to hit the bank when it was deciding on executive bonuses for the year, in board meetings on Monday.

Up Next

Dollar commentary turns fanciful

01:45

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

CBA accused of breaching money laundering act

Austrac has launched civil proceedings in the federal court alleging that CBA failed to comply with the law on more than 50,000 occasions.

The country's largest bank is embroiled in a fresh scandal after the financial intelligence agency, .
, and even some possible terrorists, Austrac alleges.

One specific part of the allegations is that CBA did not tell Austrac quickly enough about more than 53,506 cash deposits of more than $10,000, . Banks are required to inform authorities of transactions over $10,000.
With a maximum penalty of $18 million for a late notification, it has been noted in some media reports that 53,506 contraventions of the law, though it has also been reported that such an extraordinary fine is extremely unlikely.

After a sharp drop in CBA shares on Friday, on Monday CBA told the market that media discussion about the potential fines it might face was "speculative", and the outcome would be determined by the court.
"Austrac alleges that approximately 53,000 threshold transaction reports were lodged late," CBA said on Monday.
"However, these alleged contraventions could be considered to arise from a single course of conduct to the extent that they emanated from the same systems error.
"Ultimately, a court will seek to ensure that, overall, any civil penalties are just and appropriate and do not exceed what is proper having regard to the totality of established contraventions."Photo: James Elsby
Importantly, CBA's "error" defence does not diminish the other breaches of the law Austrac is alleging.
In court documents, the regulator alleges CBA breached another part of the law 174 times when it failed to file a "suspicious" matter report with Austrac, and failed to properly monitor a further 71 customers who were at risk of money laundering. 
Ultimately, a court will seek to ensure that, overall, any civil penalties are just and appropriate.
CBA

The bank's statement came as Mr Narev told ABC Radio's AM program the bank had made "mistakes" and there would be accountability.
"If we haven't done a good enough job, we put our hands up, say why, and do a better job and we're doing that," he said.
There is an expectation some of CBA's top managers will have their bonuses cut, at the least, and questions over whether Mr Narev will survive the scandal as CEO.
Mr Narev said the board, chaired by Catherine Livingstone, would meet on Monday to sign off on its annual report ahead of the bank's Wednesday results, which will include determining senior executive bonuses.
"I would expect as they make their way through that, including with my own remuneration, they will take very serious account of this and see what consequences are appropriate," he said.
Mr Narev's pay last year was $12.3 million, making him the highest paid of the big four bank bosses.
Mr Narev, who has led the bank for six years, said whether he stayed in the job was ultimately a matter for the board.
"I'm enjoying my job, I'm very dedicated to it. These parts aren't the most pleasant but they're important and the rest of it's up to the board," Mr Narev said on ABC Radio's AM.
CBA shares were close to unchanged in early trade, down 0.1 per cent, at $80.64.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio's AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Elsby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
