<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442082556933829</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/travel/whale-hits-queensland-boat-passengers-injured/news-story/ffbf5bf47ce1277019f92d1bb372ef60</url>
  <title>Tourists' horror injuries as whale slams boat</title>
  <content>
WARNING: Graphic image.
A WHALE slammed a charter boat in the Whitsundays, sending passengers into the air, knocking two unconscious and leaving others with broken bones.
The five fishing tourists and three crew were on board the A-One Fishing Charters boat when it was struck off the coast of Bowen on Saturday.
Captain Oliver Galea suffered a deep head laceration, while several others suffered broken bones and had to picked up by the RACQ Helicopter.
Mr Galea, 44, told AAP one person suffered a fractured cheek bone, while another had two broken ribs and a third man's nose was broken.
Mr Galea was taken to Proserpine Hospital where he received eight stitches and shared a photo on Facebook of the gaping cut he received after slamming into the hand rail.
He said in "a split second" everyone was on the ground and no one knew the cause of the impact until they saw the whale moving away.
"There was no sign of it. It was a very rare, freak accident," he said.
Whales often came near the boats, but were easily spotted from their blowhole and tended to stay away from the engine noises, he said.
The collision left a dent in the boat and knocked out one of the engines. Despite being an out-of-the-ordinary tourist experience, Mr Galea said everyone was okay.
"We all caught up on Sunday night and we have made good friends from the experience. We are all glad we made it," he said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Fishing Charters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACQ Helicopter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Proserpine Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Galea, 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Galea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Galea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitsundays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
