<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441962297848156</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-07/grey-nomads-gemstone-fossicking-in-outback-central-australia/8737898</url>
  <title>Grey nomads converge in the hunt for outback gems</title>
  <content>
Carol Torney finds it difficult to imagine living in a home, the self-described grey nomad says of living in a van with her husband John.
"We just love it," Mrs Torney said of the months where they fish in the south, whereas in other months they escape to the north to avoid cold weather.

Fossicking has been a life-long passion for Carol Torney.

Fossicking has been a life-long passion for Carol Torney.

ABC Regional: Brett Worthington

Since Mr Torney's retirement, the couple has spent the years since travelling the country with their lives packed into a van.
But for Mrs Torney the highlight of the year is setting up camp in gem fields, a place rich with nostalgia for her.

"My mother was a fossicker so as a child I grew up fossicking crystals and things all over Victoria," she said.

"So obviously as I got older, and got married, I introduced him to fossicking and it's just been going ever since.
"It's a vicious circle," Mr Torney joked.
"You get the fever, they say," Mrs Torney responds.

"I don't call it a fever, I just love doing it," Mr Torney replied.

John Torney washing rocks while fossicking for gemstones in outback Central Australia.

John Torney washing rocks while fossicking for gemstones in outback Central Australia.

ABC Regional: Brett Worthington

The Torneys have set up camp about 140 kilometres north east of Alice Springs in an area known as the Mud Tanks Zircon Fields.
They have brought with them fellow grey nomads Les and Lorri Western, along with son Tony, who they met travelling in northern Australia.
They come to Central Australia because the Westerns wanted to learn how to fossick for gemstones.

"John used to dig holes in coal mines and we're all out here still digging holes," Mrs Torney said.

"Yeah, we retire and what do we do? Go bush and dig holes," Mrs Western responded.
"What else would you do?" Mr Torney replied with a laugh.

Lorri and Les Western sort through rocks looking for gemstones.

Lorri and Les Western sort through rocks looking for gemstones.

ABC Regional: Brett Worthington

The camp is spread between their van and bus, and they spend the mornings in the gem fields digging up rocks which they then sieve into buckets based on their size.
Upon returning to camp, they wash the rocks and sort through the remnants looking for gemstones.
"I'd love to have some made [into jewellery] and used like a family heirloom," Mrs Western said.
But when asked if her children and grandchildren would appreciate the effort needed to find the stones, she was unconvinced.

"Probably not. Because as far as they're concerned, Mum and Dad and Pop and Nan are just out having a good time," she said.

"They have no idea what we go through."

Mrs Western inspects a zircon gemstone with fine tweezers.

Mrs Western inspects a zircon gemstone with fine tweezers.

ABC Regional: Brett Worthington

The Westerns live in Esperance on the south coast of Western Australia.
They travel throughout winter and try to limit how much time they spend at home.
"It's just something to do," Mr Western said.

"My dad died at 66. He had one year of retirement. I've got no intention of doing that.

"You got to get out and do something."

Zircon gemstones Carol and Jim Torney have fossicked across Australia.

Zircon gemstones Carol and Jim Torney have fossicked across Australia.

ABC Regional: Brett Worthington

The couple laughs at the suggestion of missing home.
"Miss home? No way," Mr Western said.
"Dad sent [me] to Perth for high school and it didn't really work out.

"Every weekend we were out in the bush. Once a bush kid, always a bush kid. I hate the cities [and prefer to be] out having a good time."

Self-confessed "grey nomad" John Torney takes a break from washing rocks while fossicking.

Self-confessed "grey nomad" John Torney takes a break from washing rocks while fossicking.

ABC Regional: Brett Worthington

It is a similar sentiment from Mr Torney, who has been retired for 14 years.
"We travel around now and dig gemstones here there and everywhere, wherever we can find them," he said.
"We have a bit of fun while we're doing it [and] a couple of drinks.

"It's magic, we love it. [We're] just on the road all the time and the whole of Australia is our backyard and we don't have to mow it. Someone else does the mowing."

The Torneys and Westerns will next head to Sapphire in central Queensland where they will also dig for gemstones.
"I've heard a lot about these [sapphires]," Mr Western said.
"But I'm starting to think they're a bit like barramundi, I think they're a bit of a myth because I haven't seen them yet."

East Arrernte man Raymond Reiff teaches tourists about gemstone fossicking and Indigenous culture.

East Arrernte man Raymond Reiff teaches tourists about gemstone fossicking and Indigenous culture.

ABC Regional: Brett Worthington

Teaching tourists to fossick and understand Aboriginal culture

Raymond Reiff, an East Arrernte man from Central Australia, teaches tourists how to fossick for gemstones.
He also runs cultural lessons for visitors to gain an understanding about Aboriginal culture.
He smiles when he says that tourists are surprised that the stereotype they have of Aboriginal people does not meet reality.

"They imagine every Aborigine walks around with a digeridoo. But we're desert people, we don't have digeridoo. We just use clapsticks for dancing and music and singing ," Mr Reiff said.

"Through art we show them the meanings, what we paint and the boomerang.
"They sit down nearly all day just watching me cutting out a boomerang with a handsaw.
"They look at it and think it's easy but once they see me do it - it takes a long time - they realise how long it takes."
Mr Reiff laughed when he recounted stories of tourists who expect the boomerang to come back when they throw it.
"If you throw it that far, it's a long walk to go and pick it up," he said.

Indigenous painting on wooden stumps from the area contain references to local culture.

Indigenous painting on wooden stumps from the area contain references to local culture.

ABC Regional: Brett Worthington

Mr Reiff said he hoped when tourists leave they take with them a new-found appreciation for Aboriginal culture in the outback.
"[I hope] they leave with a proper knowledge of Central Australia and the more traditional Aboriginal ways and culture," he said.

"Hopefully what they see here at Gemtree [is that] we are trying to live two ways - the white man way and our way. Hopefully they can see that we can all live and work together as one.

"Hopefully they see the real Australian Aborigines out bush."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mud Tanks Zircon Fields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Western</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Torney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fossicking</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Torney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Aborigine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Arrernte</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Torney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Regional</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torneys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Reiff</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aborigines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raymond Reiff</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Western</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Torney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LORRI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol Torney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gemtree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Worthington</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Western</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorri Western</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sapphire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
