<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441966592815605</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:23</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/kohli-leading-indians-close-to-record/3209530/</url>
  <title>Kohli leading Indians close to record</title>
  <content>
CRICKET: A big win over Sri Lanka in the second Test in Colombo means India is one victory away from equalling the record of consecutive series successes set by Ricky Ponting's Australian between 2005 and 2008.
Virat Kohli's team defeated the hosts by an innings and 53 runs to secure an unbeatable 2-0 lead in the three-match series.
Ravindra Jadeja bagged his ninth five-wicket haul in Test cricket to take the Indians to their eighth Test series in a row - a run that began in Sri Lanka in 2015.
The only team to have won more consecutive series is Australia, which won nine in a row under Ponting.
Coincidentally, it was India that ended Australia's winning streak by taking out the 2008 Border-Gavaskar Trophy at home.
The only other side to have won eight series in a row is England. That run stretched from 1884 to 1890.
The Indians will not get the chance to equal Australia's nine-series run until November-December, when they face Sri Lanka on home soil.
Batting first in the second Test in Colombo, India declared its first innings on nine for 622 and then dismissed Sri Lanka for 183 and enforced the follow-on, commanding a 439-run lead.
Sri Lanka performed better in the second innings but couldn't prevent an innings defeat when they were bowled out for 386 with more than a day to spare.
A breakthrough victory at the CrossFit Games.
In some ways SunCentral is like the Coast's version of the NBN
"I then said, 'Hey Ryan' ... (and he) started to run."
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Fiery larrikin Peter FitzSimons had the audience in stitches.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Ponting's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ravindra Jadeja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ponting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November/December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunCentral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border-Gavaskar Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virat Kohli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kohli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
