<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442000952554425</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/bluescope-steel-shares-are-on-a-tear-2017-8</url>
  <title>BlueScope Steel shares are on a tear</title>
  <content>
Shares in Bluescope Steel jumped in morning trade.

A short time ago, they were up 6.7% to $14.25.

Ord Minnett, in a reporting season review of BlueScope Steel, raised its recommendation to accumulate from hold and the target price to $15 from $13.

The move was driven by Bluescope's cost savings and the potential for further efficiency gains, tax benefits and up to $2 billion in capital management over the next five years.

"The company has $2.5 billion in tax losses which can be used to offset Australian income," says Ord Minnett in a note to clients.

The steel maker's business has been turning around since October 2015 when it announced what it called a game changer agreement with its employees to cut 500 jobs and freeze wages for three years.

The agreement was a significant part of the company's cost cutting targets and kept the Port Kembla steelworks south of Sydney from shutting.

In 2016, BlueScope doubled full year underlying profit to $293.1 million. Sales were up 8% to $9.18 billion and the statutory net profit was up 160% to $353.8 million.

It's due to release its 2017 year results on August 21.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kembla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlueScope Steel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluescope</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord Minnett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
