<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441777614251817</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/morgan-stanleys-three-reasons-to-be-cautious-on-acquisitive-webjet-20170806-gxqlvr</url>
  <title>Morgan Stanley's three reasons to be cautious on acquisitive Webjet</title>
  <content>
As fund managers and analysts re-work the numbers on Webjet following a sizeable acquisition, Morgan Stanley analysts reckon there are good reasons to be cautious. 
Morgan Stanley cut the stock to "underweight" on Monday morning, and told clients there were three issues which made it hard to own the company. 
The issues included:
1. Large acquisition with questions over previous acquisition accounting: Webjet was pursuing the Jac deal while debating with its auditor and seeking opinions from other accounting firms on treatment of a previous deal.

2. Lack of transparency in B2B: WEB provides TTV by brand, but no colour on revenue, costs, or EBITDA. We still don't have an EBITDA figure for Thomas Cook. This deal makes B2B more opaque.

3. Further complications: Jac is a transformational acquisition. We were surprised by language from management like "capacity to pursue further growth opportunities".
Morgan Stanley's warning comes only days after  and funded it with an equity raising. 
The ASX-listed travel company told shareholders the deal would be at least 25 per cent accretive to earnings per share in the 2017 financial year, on a proforma basis before synergies, and was expected to complete by the end of August. 
Its pitch was about creating the No.2 business to business player globally, with contracted hotel relationships increasing from about 10,000 to 17,000. 

The JacTravel acquisition followed Webjet's announcement that it had disagreed with auditor BDO about how to account for another deal; its sourcing partnership with Thomas Cook. 
Webjet has finished the institutional portion of its $165 million rights issue and is due to open the retail offer later this week. New shares were offered at $10 each, which was an 8.6 per cent discount to the theoretical ex-rights price. 
Webjet shares were trading down 8¢ to $12 on Monday morning. 
Morgan Stanley has an $11.35 price target on the stock. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BDO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JacTravel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webjet</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBITDA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Cook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B2B</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
