<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442078261966513</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/what-does-the-cwa-smell-like/8780430</url>
  <title>What does the CWA smell like? Iconic group's essence captured in a bottle for 95th anniversary</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

How would you describe the essence of the County Women's Association?
Is it scones with jam and cream and a freshly baked fruit cake or does it have a more contemporary scent?
This year marks the CWA's 95th anniversary in Queensland, and to celebrate the group will this week launch its own perfume.
Called 1922, it has notes of citrus, lavender, rose and boronia with a base of vanilla and spices.
It will be released on Friday at The Ekka.
The scent was created after Ally Martell, editor of the Queensland CWA's magazine Ruth, interviewed a perfume maker in Brisbane.
"I interviewed Jonathon Midgely at Damask Perfumery and their laboratory is like a wizard den," she said.

"During the conversation I asked him that if he could bottle all the good things about the CWA, what would it smell like?
"He started laughing, but then he said jams, marmalades and then wondered what would women have smelt like in 1922.
"He said, 'We have to add boronia because it smells like the scent of an angel', which the CWA are."
Mr Midgely set about creating the perfume for the group but sadly won't get to see its release.
He died three weeks ago and 1922 was one of the last fragrances he created.
"We were heartbroken at the CWA when he passed as he donated all his time to design and create the scent," Ms Martell told
What does it smell like?

"The perfume has three notes and the top note is citrus, mostly mandarin, and then the florals come through," Ms Martell explained.
"Members of the QCWA have been bottling and boxing 1922 by hand to have it ready for the launch."
The artwork and branding of the bottles was supplied by Michelle Grayson, a Brisbane watercolour artist who specialises in prints of flowers and perfume bottles.
Ms Grayson's art deco font links the perfume to the 1920s era.
She also created an original painting for the QCWA to help launch the scent.

Ms Martell said the perfume was a fitting, feminine way to help the QCWA celebrate all its achievements since it began on August 11, 1922.
"The CWA supports women, families and communities and they stay together as friends forever," she said.
"The biggest branches are in Brisbane; it's not just for country women either ... many have a heart in the country and love the tradition of the CWA."
All money raised from the sale of the perfume will go to the QCWA for future community projects.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CWA's 95</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland CWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>County Women's Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damask Perfumery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ally Martell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Grayson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Grayson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCWA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Midgely</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Martell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Midgely</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CWA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
