<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441962297848197</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/mackays-12-most-wanted-crims-of-the-week/3209512/</url>
  <title>Mackay's 12 most wanted crims of the week</title>
  <content>
A SPATE of crime swept over Mackay last weekend, with everything from robberies to dog baiting and a major drug seizure taking place.

On August 4 police seized a large quantity of the dangerous drug commonly known as fantasy at a mail centre in Mackay.

The drug was in a liquid form and was contained within a total of 90 bottles disguised as cosmetic products.

Police are also amid investigations into a robbery which took place the same day.

Three men broke into the residence about 4.20pm, one armed with a spear gun, and stole a vast range of items from the property.

A 51-year-old man arrived at the address and parked behind the trio's vehicle in the driveway.

One man left the scene on foot, while the other two men exited the dwelling and stole the 51-year-old man's car.

The man threw himself onto the bonnet of his vehicle and it was driven onto the street.

The man fell from the moving vehicle and sustained multiple injuries, he was then transported to Mackay Base Hospital in a stable condition.

The thieves original vehicle was left at the scene.

Investigations are continuing into a suspected dog baiting incident that took place on several streets in Andergrove at the weekend.

Several residents reported their animals becoming sick, one of which had to be put down, after being fed a raw chicken bone.

Some residents reported finding another substance inside the chicken, believed to be causing the animals to become sick.

Multiple dogs were impacted.

Anyone with information about this particular matter contact Mackay Northern Beaches Police Station on 07 49 697 666 or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 any time of the day.

In better news, the same day an honest South Mackay resident was walking along Evan St in South Mackay, on the footpath near the skate-bowl, and happened to stumble across some money on the ground.

It was collected and taken to the Mackay police station and is being treated as found property while police attempt to locate the lawful owner.

Police couldn't nominate the exact amount but said the notes were all the same denomination.

If you believe you are the lawful owner, contact the Mackay Police Station on 07 4968 3444 and refer to police report number QP1701346583.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andergrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Mackay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QP1701346583</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay's 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Base Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Northern Beaches Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evan St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
