<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441962297848123</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:22</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/massive-upgrades-set-for-key-industry-player/3209534/</url>
  <title>Massive upgrades set for key industry player</title>
  <content>
A MAJOR redevelopment is set to breathe new life into a busy Coast funeral parlour.
Partial demolition of two buildings, new connections, a car park redesign and internal building and refurbishment are all proposed for the Drysdale Funerals parlour at National Park Rd, Nambour.
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners InvoCare Australia Pty Ltd reveal the scale of the works.
The internal reconstruction works with additions will create a new, single building, housing a foyer, reception/waiting room, reflection room, storage, office, staff room and amenities, arrangement rooms, customer amenities, reflection lounge, kitchen and chapel.
A new shed replacing the one set for demolition will contain a garage with one car park, storage, coffin lift and cool room.
The existing car park, currently non-compliant with Sunshine Coast Council and Australian standards, would be re-jigged to become compliant, reducing the number of parks from 40 to 34.
Landscaping is proposed to cover 25% of the 2752 sq m site.
InvoCare has operated the funeral home on site for a number of years and the upgrades are proposed in order to keep up with present operational requirements.
The funeral parlour operates during normal business hours and "typically, one or two services would be held per day, where the facility has the capacity to accommodate up to 100 attendees to a service".
Services are normally scheduled for 10am, 12pm or 2pm, and go for about two hours.
InvoCare currently employs six full-time staff at the site.
The proposed development will be a major upgrade for what is a funeral precinct in Nambour, with Gregson and Weight Funeral Directors and crematorium directly across the road from the funeral parlour set for a major facelift.
A breakthrough victory at the CrossFit Games.
In some ways SunCentral is like the Coast's version of the NBN
"I then said, 'Hey Ryan' ... (and he) started to run."
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Fiery larrikin Peter FitzSimons had the audience in stitches.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>InvoCare</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>InvoCare Australia Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drysdale Funerals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunCentral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Park Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weight Funeral Directors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
