<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442082556933885</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/sex/nutritionists-reveal-the-foods-that-can-boost-a-guys-libido/news-story/47bee3b27b2d987c4f6d0cc28ed0c205</url>
  <title>Nutritionists reveal the foods that can boost a guy's libido</title>
  <content>
There are seven foods that can assist a man's libido.

Jennifer NewtonThe Sun

Share

BOOSTING your performance between the sheets not only improves your love life - it can also improve your health.
New research has revealed that men who have sex several times a week can improve their .
But what can men do if their libido is falling flat and getting it on with their partner is the last thing on their mind?
Well, according to nutritionists, what you eat can have a massive affect on your sex life and making simple changes can spice up your relationship.
Charlie Turner and Lee Foster, founders of  have come up with seven foods that can boost your libido. So what are you waiting for, get to the supermarket now!
Dark chocolate
Dark chocolate increases serotonin and dopamine levels in the brain, making us happy and then puts us in the "mood".

Dark chocolate can help increase libido.Source:istock
It also increases blood flow and relaxes blood vessels - sending blood to all the right places.
Nuts

Almonds, Brazil nuts, walnuts, and peanuts are believed to increase libido and reverse impotence in men - they provide the raw material for a man's healthy production of hormones.
Garlic
Garlic might seem like the last thing you want to eat before a night of passion. But it contains high levels of allicin, and increases blood flow. These effects may help men with erectile dysfunction.
Broccoli and celery
These are foods that will improve the essential fuel to spark your sexual appetite and increase libido.

Broccoli helps remove excess oestrogen, and in turn, increases testosterone.Source:istock
For example, celery contains androsterone, an odourless hormone released through male perspiration that acts as a turn-on. Broccoli also helps, removing excess oestrogen, and in turn increasing testosterone.
Fish
Foods high in vitamins B such as fish are major factors in increasing libido. Vitamin B3 is in charge of anaerobic metabolism, which offers sexual energy and raises blood flow to the genitalia and B6 regulates prolactin responsible for levels of sexual enjoyment in men.
Oats
You should never skip breakfast - mainly because oats increase the amount of testosterone available in your bloodstream. Research at the San Francisco Institute for Advanced Study of Human Sexuality found that including oats in your diet improved men's libidos in just 8 weeks.

Oats increase the amount of testosterone available in your bloodstream.Source:istock
Whey protein
You already know that you need protein to build muscle mass, but you may not be aware that consuming protein also helps boost testosterone levels. Protein, rich in whey, is vital for the manufacture testosterone.
Previously, we brought you the story of a depressed  'three times a day'.
We also revealed how some women who have  despite NEVER having sex.
This article was originally published on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer NewtonThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advanced Study of Human</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
