<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441734664578392</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/07/10/21/creepy-video-shows-neighbour-peering-through-mans-bedroom-vent</url>
  <title>Creepy video shows neighbour peering through man's bedroom vent</title>
  <content>
A US man has been filmed crawling through his neighbour's attic and peeping through a vent into their bedroom.

Jerome Kennedy from Pittsburgh told TV station KDKA he first noticed his neighbour Robert Havrilla going into his attic when his 10-month-old daughter was born.

Mr Kennedy said he had a surveillance camera installed last month after he heard someone above his bedroom several times and saw flashlights coming down through his vent.

The bedroom the neighbour was peeping into was the one he shared with his wife and baby daughter.

"The only thing I can assume is he's watching my baby, my wife, or myself," Mr Kennedy said.

The surveillance footage showed Havrilla removing a false attic wall and lying on some planks above his daughter's cot, Mr Kennedy said.

Havrilla appeared in court on Wednesday and waived his right to a preliminary hearing.

His lawyer, Anthony Jackson, said he was successful in having a luring charged dropped.

"I think it will come out soon that he did not have a malicious intent at all. I think it was an innocent situation," Mr Jackson said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havrilla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Havrilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kennedy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KDKA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerome Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pittsburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
