<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441906463272371</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/10/25/foreign-isis-fighters-sneaking-into-syria-arrive-to-rude-awakening-and-chain-of-broken-promises</url>
  <title>Foreign ISIS fighters sneaking into Syria arrive to rude awakening and chain of broken promises</title>
  <content>
Many foreign fighters who defect to Syria to join ISIS are religious novices who often don't even know how to pray in line with Islamic tradition, according to a new report.

A  found foreign jihadists fled Syria "disillusioned and disappointed" after ISIS failed to make good on its promises.

There were personal accounts of inadequate military training camps and religious courses run by "immature" teachers who appeared bereft of in-depth teachings.

Regular salaries, houses, furniture, full time jobs, houses and even wives failed to materialise once fresh recruits had arrived in the self-declared caliphate.

The UN report is the result of direct interviews with 43 ISIS fighters from 12 nationalities who had returned to their homelands or been intercepted attempting to reach Syria.

Foreign fighters seduced by ISIS and the self-styled caliphate are most likely to be young males living in urban centres from disadvantaged economic and educational backgrounds.

However, the report stated many of these would-be fighters lacked "any basic understanding of the true meaning of Jihad or even the Islamic faith".

Related Articles

Most ISIS recruits saw their religion in terms of justice and injustice rather than in terms of piety and spirituality.

Foreign fighters interviewed by the report's authors described poorly run military training camps in Syria that left them hopelessly underprepared for battle.

During a simple two-week course, trainees learned how to shoot without firing bullets, because that would bring about attention from the anti-ISIS coalition.

Most respondents said that "frankly the course prepares you for nothing".

On arrival in Syria, new recruits also undergo a short religious indoctrination course.

These were taught by "immature" teachers who seemed not well versed in religious matters, according to interviewees.

"I began to think about leaving Syria as soon as I arrived," one foreign fighter told interviewers.

"I started to think, could the armed group, with its reputation and might, provide a kind of teaching and teachers as simple as that? I started immediately to question the reputation of the armed group altogether: its purpose; its teachers; its philosophy; everything."

This lack of psychological and physical preparedness for the battlefield and life in the "caliphate" prompted many to defect.

The report also noted defections "were the result of exposure to extreme brutality, disgust over the slave trade, observations of deep hypocrisy - a total mismatch between the words and deeds of IS."

One of Australia's most wanted terrorists, , remains in Turkey eight months after he was arrested in November last year trying to leave ISIS across the Turkish-Syrian border.

In June Prakash begged a Turkish court to not send him back to Australia, but that he instead find a new home in a Muslim country.

He claimed to have made "a mistake" joining ISIS.

ASIO believes about  have travelled to Syria and Iraq to fight for Islamic State.

The report underlined that radicalisation of young men and women begins in the real world, typically arising from a number of repeating triggers.

There is a pattern of a dysfunctional family background, problems at school, unemployment and stigmatisation in the labour market.

These vulnerabilities are likely to be amplified by social networks formed in gathering places such as mosques, prisons, schools, universities, neighbourhoods or the workplace.

Potential jihadists will then seek out further extremist information on the internet, according to the report.

The 58-page UN report downplayed the internet as an aggressive recruitment tool for ISIS. Instead, ISIS propaganda on the internet was a reinforcer of injustices and narratives.

The report acknowledged the small sample size of interviewees, but it nonetheless offers many interesting insights that could benefit governments and policymakers.

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign ISIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June Prakash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish-Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
