<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441141959084365</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/opinion/belle-taylor-its-time-for-ladies-to-take-the-mic/news-story/bd3b7ec8bb020f696a628d1c43d52123</url>
  <title>Women need to speak up more</title>
  <content>
LAST week I joined the end of a really long queue to shuffle into the Discovery Lounge at the State Library to hear the Disrupted Festival of Ideas' keynote speaker, Tara Moss.
Moss - author, journalist, TV presenter and occasional tabloid bait - was a major drawcard at the festival. The Canadian-born author has lived in Australia since 1996, has written nine crime novels, two non-fiction books and is a popular public speaker.
Her talk was focused around her latest book, Speaking Out: A 21st Century Handbook for Women and Girls, which argues that women need to speak up more and participate in public debate. To drive the need for this home, she had statistics flashing up on a screen on stage - showing the staggering inequality between men and women in public life.
Moss seemed to think that these stats were shocking, but sitting in the audience my jaw wasn't dropping. In fact, it all felt a bit like old news.

Yes, we know women are under-represented in public life, that the numbers in Parliament, the media and even in Hollywood movies are grossly uneven. Next you'll be telling me the Pope is Catholic. Frankly, the numbers weren't surprising, but they do raise the question: why?
There was one particular statistic that Moss flashed up on the screen that got me thinking. In mainstream news articles, 76 per cent of quotes from experts were men. Only 24 per cent of expert quotes were from women.
"That can't be right?" was my initial thought. I interview women all the time. I also deal with women a lot at work. Overwhelmingly the number of press secretaries and publicists that I communicate with are women.
But on reflection, I realised when it came down to it, the final voice that ends up in print, is more often than not, male.
One reason for that discrepancy is that there are simply fewer women in senior positions to quote - the reasons for that are varied and complex, but it does go some way to contributing to that 76/24 figure.
I suspect, however, that there is another reason - and it's not as simple as reporters having a bias (conscious or not) for male experts.
Newsrooms are busy places and often a reporter has several stories on the go at any one time. If you are seeking a comment for a story you are looking not only for the best person, but the most accessible.
If the greatest expert in the world agrees to speak to you an hour after deadline, it's not much use. Better off chasing the second best who is going to take your call when you need them to. If you've ever wondered why the same names seem to pop up again and again speaking on any number of issues, it's because those people are willing to talk, under wet cement if need be.
Could there occasionally be a better person to speak on a certain issue? Probably. But newspapers are written by real people who have to work within the laws of time and space. Yes, I know, it's like when the Wizard of Oz pulls back the curtain.
I've worked as a journalist for more than a decade and this I know - men are more willing than women to speak to journalists.
If you call a male doctor, lawyer, academic, sportsman or businessman, they are more likely to take your call than their female counterparts.

Maybe women are wary of journalists, or maybe they are just more measured in their approach. Women are more likely to ask for time to prepare for an interview. Time the reporter often doesn't have.
Women are more likely to ask for written pre-prepared questions, which is not only laboriously time-consuming at both ends, but results in stilted, dull answers.
Obviously this isn't across the board. There are women who will speak. But there are a lot more men who are willing to hold forth.
Why is this the case? I suspect that women are more likely to be told in many subtle and not-so-subtle ways throughout their lives they shouldn't speak out of turn.
Women shouldn't comment on things that they don't know about, whereas plenty of blokes seem to be armchair experts on an awfully wide range of topics. And even if a woman is full bottle on the subject, no one likes a show-off.
Perhaps the hesitation women have in regards to speaking in the public sphere comes from a similar mindset that is behind the widely reported reluctance of women to ask for a pay rise.
The gender pay gap sits stubbornly at about 16 per cent and has hovered around that mark for the past 20 years. This is despite women being just as educated and as qualified and capable as their male counterparts.
A major reason why this pay gap exists isn't because there is a secret conspiracy to pay women less, it's because women are simply less likely than men to ask for more money. Weirdly, many women seem to think hard work will be recognised and rewarded without a song and dance. Men just ask for it.
Moss finished her talk with a call to arms, telling the women in the audience to speak up, even if they were told not to, or their voice was too loud, too annoying or weirdly pitched.
It's time for ladies to take the mic - or just take the call.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moss</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Century Handbook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wizard of Oz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disrupted Festival of Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discovery Lounge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
