<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442091146868537</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/dustys-coffee-date-sets-tongues-wagging</url>
  <title>Dusty's coffee date sets tongues wagging</title>
  <content>
Dustin Martin was spotted meeting with his agent on Monday morning

AFTER another weekend of speculation about Dustin Martin's contract, the Richmond superstar caught up with his agent Ralph Carr on Monday morning.

Contacted by AFL.com.au, Carr trotted out his standard 'nothing to report' line, but clearly things are bubbling along.

The pair was spotted meeting at a South Yarra cafe on Monday morning. 

It follows a weekend in which long-term contracts have been floated, figures of $1.2 million a season have been bandied about, and then more radio buzz of an imminent announcement on Monday.

Martin, a restricted free-agent at season's end, had indicated he wouldn't decide on his future until the Tigers' campaign was over.

However, the goal posts appeared to change last week, when Carr went public saying a decision could be made before the end of the home and away season.

Asked if things were looking more positive in relation to Martin after Sunday's win over Hawthorn, coach Damien Hardwick shrugged his shoulders and grinned, but then said the negotiations were being handled by others.

Whatever the case, everything is pointing to a new deal soon, which would eliminate a massive distraction as the Tigers prepare to embark on a potentially historic finals series from within the top four.

The 26-year-old has had a stellar season for the Tigers, kicking 26 goals, averaging 3.6 tackles a game and being tipped as a Brownlow favourite by many.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ralph Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
