<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441442606798485</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/finals-hypothetical-no-matches-in-melbourne</url>
  <title>Finals hypothetical: No matches in Melbourne?</title>
  <content>
The Crows and Cats would meet at Adelaide Oval in the first week of finals if the eight stayed as it is

IF THE home and away season stopped right now, we'd be set for an historic opening weekend of finals - with no games in Melbourne.

The cities of Sydney and Adelaide would host two games each in an unprecedented scenario that might hurt crowd numbers without a game at the MCG, but would see the code take centre stage in a traditional heartland and an emerging market.

Hypothetically, the first-placed Crows would host the fourth-placed Cats at Adelaide Oval on a Thursday night, in front of a likely sell-out crowd.

The AFL's newest franchise GWS could host the resurgent Tigers at Spotless Stadium in a Friday night blockbuster at Spotless Stadium, which would guarantee mega television ratings in Victoria.

Then, Saturday would loom as elimination day.

The afternoon fixture would most likely feature Port Adelaide and Essendon back at Adelaide Oval, and we'd expect the Saturday night slot to go to the Swans and Bulldogs in a re-match of last year's Grand Final. 

As with last year, this scenario would make a Sunday final unlikely.

While the make-up of the top eight looks set to go down to the wire, the AFL is already in the middle of working out scenarios for the first week of finals actions.

With three weeks to play, West Coast, Melbourne and St Kilda - all outside the eight now - remain in finals contention, equal on 40 points with Bombers, who are in eighth spot.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
