<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441086124508561</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/07/46/marriage-equality-liberal-debate</url>
  <title>Controversial marriage equality bill to be debated by Liberal party room</title>
  <content>
The controversial debate over same-sex marriage will come to a head today as Liberal MPs and Senators face off in a special party room meeting where reformers will push for a free vote in parliament.
Backbencher Dean Smith, who has drafted his own marriage equality bill, said it shouldn't be seen as a vote on Malcolm Turnbull's leadership.
Senator Smith, together with Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans and Warren Entsch, will push for a parliamentary vote on the bill rather than a postal plebiscite after circulating it to members over the weekend.
Four of the five MPs planning to bring the bill to the house did not mention marriage equality in their maiden speech, The Daily Telegraph reports, with Mr Wilson reportedly initially telling people in his constituency of Goldstein during his campaign he will not be a gay rights advocate.
Voters in four of the five rebels' electorates of Brisbane, Goldstein, North Sydney and Leichhardt are strongly supportive of an immediate conscience vote, Fairfax Media reports.
The Marriage Amendment (Definition and Religious Freedoms) Bill allows for two people to marry regardless of their gender, while enshrining protections and exemptions for religious communities.
That includes religious ministers, civil celebrants, and businesses linked to a religious body who refuse to marry same-sex couples.

Related Articles

Senator Smith believes it's the most comprehensive marriage equality bill to go before parliament.
It's expected Labor will also support Senator Smith's bill
Many MPs are also expected to continue their push for a plebiscite, which the coalition promised at the last election but has failed to get through parliament.
Former prime minister Tony Abbott has issued a stern warning to colleagues pushing for a free vote, insisting they are "honour-bound" to oppose it without a plebiscite.
He scolded colleagues who "insist on having public second thoughts about our own policy".
"Keeping faith with the electorate should weigh just as heavily as deeply-held personal belief," he writes in The Australian.
"Like it or not, coalition MPs are honour-bound to oppose same-sex marriage in the absence of a plebiscite that's supported it."
Mr Abbott insists the marriage equality backers hold a minority view within the coalition ahead of what's expected to be a heated special party room meeting on the issue in Canberra on Monday afternoon.
A non-binding postal vote, being touted by cabinet minister Peter Dutton, is thought to also be an option to be floated today.
Legal advice sought by marriage equality advocates suggests, however, that option isn't possible without legislation, which would be unlikely to pass the Senate.
Senator Smith said the issue was bigger than the Liberal Party and did not need to be seen through the prism of leadership.
This is a test for each and every member of the parliamentary Liberal party," he told ABC TV.
The party room was a respectful place and people showed courtesy to one another, he said.
"There is an expectation people put their best foot forward and make the most convincing argument they can."
The bill has the backing of advocates, who believe it's one of the strongest they've seen.
"It is a bill that is designed to pass the Senate," Australian Marriage Equality co-chair Alex Greenwich said.
With AAP

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Religious Freedom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Amendment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldstein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leichhardt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
