<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441700304839597</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/usain-bolt-bristles-at-journalists-question/3209501/</url>
  <title>Usain Bolt bristles at journalist's question</title>
  <content>
ATHLETICS: Usain Bolt was a model of dignity and class as he accepted a crushing defeat in the 100m final at the world championships, but the retiring sprint legend strongly bristled at one question from a journalist.

The Jamaican star, who finished third behind Americans Justin Gatlin and Christian Coleman in his farewell race, interrupted a press conference featuring all three medallists to answer a question directed at Gatlin.

The American winner, who has twice been suspended after testing positive for banned substances, was asked if the lower times at these world championships could be attributed to greater doping control.

The journalist pointed to the number of sub-10 second times at this event (seven), compared to 21 at the 2015 world championships in Beijing.

"Woah woah, what?!" Bolt interjected. "What's she saying? I heard you but I'm saying, 'what?!'

"First of all, I'm sure everybody up here takes that very disrespectfully. We've proved we've worked hard; as I said Justin has done his time over the years and he's proven himself over and over again. I've proven myself over and over again.

"Young kid, just coming in, Coleman, has done great and shown the world he's going to be a great athlete. There's something called injury - and sometimes everything don't go smoothly as you want to. There's negative wind, there's so many different (factors).

"So for you to just directly state something to all three of us like that (slow times may be in relation to tighter doping controls), I take that as disrespectful ... because we've done so many great things throughout the years. Yes, it's slow. But we came out there and put on a good show for everybody so, yeah ... wow."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Justin Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
