<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440914325814658</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/townsville-running-festival-puts-city-on-the-map/news-story/ae69de61faf4a9155acee03a3f39a9e7</url>
  <title>Running festival puts city on the map</title>
  <content>
THOUSANDS of runners beat the sunrise yesterday to pound the pavement in the Townsville Running Festival.
More than 3000 people laced their running shoes for the annual event, which attracted competitors from Japan, Africa and New Zealand.
Along with the running events in Townsville, more than 200,000 Chinese competitors once again signed up for the virtual marathon.
Mayor Jenny Hill hopes to draw more visitors from the Chinese market through the event.
"What a great day, more than 3000 people are here for the Townsville Running Festival, and we've got more than 200,000 people at home somewhere in China on their treadmills doing the virtual marathon," Cr Hill said.
"I hope next year that many more will come out to Townsville to be a part of this fantastic festival and enjoy our stunning weather and scenery along our Pallarenda and Strand beachfronts."
The event drew record crowds cheering on competitors from Pallarenda through to The Strand, including the "Party House", a group of 50 to 60 people who have been meeting at Rowes Bay to cheer on the runners for 14 years.
Festival president Tony Gordon said it was Australia's second oldest racing event and the state's only certified marathon outside the southeast.
"The event attracts national and international visitors to the city," he said. "Year after year this event grows in both competitor numbers and support from the local and regional community."
For full results see page 20 of today's print of digital print edition.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pallarenda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowes Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Jenny Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Running Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Party House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
