<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441949412945897</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/facebook-liking-anti-government-posts-could-cost-public-service/8780660</url>
  <title>Facebook liking anti-government posts banned under new public service policy</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Checking Facebook and liking a post critical of the Government could be enough to see public servants facing disciplinary action, under new guidelines that also say employees may be held accountable for comments other people make on their Facebook pages.
The Australian Public Service Commission's social media guidelines were updated this morning, reinforcing the requirement that public servants appear impartial in their roles.
But the rules' coverage of sending private emails, liking Facebook posts, and failure to delete posts made to a public servant's page have sparked the ire of the public sector union.
A frequently asked questions section of the page outlined the breadth of the updated guidelines.
"If you 'like' something on a social media platform, it will generally be taken to be an endorsement of that material as though you'd created that material yourself," it reads.
"'Sharing' a post has much the same effect.
"Doing nothing about objectionable material that someone else has posted on your page can reasonably be seen in some circumstances as your endorsement of that material."
The guidelines also state criticising parliamentarians on both sides of the aisle could also breach the code.
"Criticising your Minister, or the Prime Minister, is just as risky as criticising your agency," the policies say.
"Equally, criticising your shadow minister, the leader of the Opposition, or the relevant spokesperson from minor parties, is also likely to raise concerns about your impartiality."
Rulebook 'fairly extraordinary': Union

Social media policies are commonplace in many workplaces, and generally prohibit workers from criticising their employer.
The guidelines state that public servants can partake in some political activities, such as sharing petitions, in the right circumstances.
But Community and Public Sector Union secretary Nadine Flood said they were a serious concern.
"If you email your mates something and they put in on social media then your job might be under threat," she said.
"You name it, the Government does something on it - so what are public servants allowed to say? What's left?"
Ms Flood said while many private sector companies had social media policies, the Government's guidelines went too far.
"It is fairly extraordinary," she said.
"It's one thing to say public servants working on a particular government policy shouldn't be publicly criticising that policy.
"It's quite another to say they really have no right to engage on social media on anything that Government might do that could be a community issue."
The Australian Public Service Commissioner has been contacted for comment.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nadine Flood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Public Service Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Sector Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Public Service Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Flood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
