<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441919348174405</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/third-time-lucky-for-tia/3209497/</url>
  <title>BREAKING: Gladstone local crowned fittest woman on earth</title>
  <content>
CROSSFIT: Gladstone's Tia-Clair Toomey is the fittest woman on earth.

After two previous successive runner-up efforts to Iceland's Katrin Tanja Davidsdottir, Clair-Toomey went one better and announced herself as the new Reebok CrossFit Games 2017 world champion.

The event was held in Wisconsin in the US and Toomey's dream was realised after an epic battle with fellow Australian Kara Webb of Brisbane.

Webb had caught up and the final discipline came to the 89 foot lunge with 2 35-pound kettlebells overhead.

MORE | News
>> Region's cancer incidence up to 90% higher than Australia's
>> Calliope workers camp tax 'advantage' under scrutiny

With enormous pressure on Toomey, she was no-repped, but she showed her mental strength.

Toomey, who is also the CrossFit Gladstone trainer with her coach and fiance Shane Orr, and Webb both dived across the line at the same time and the end result was anyone's guess.

CrossFit Games director Dave Castro brought the two Australian women together and after a tense few minutes, he announced Toomey as the winner.

Just six points separated Toomey and Webb at the end of the four-day competition.

"Ten times better. Like 100 times better," Toomey said on the The CrossFit Games site when asked whether it was better than Olympic Games selection.

Close friend and CrossFit Gladstone employee Kristian Brodie, who has been coaching in Toomey's and Orr's absence, said it was like a dream come true.

"I have been friends with them for years and I was just ecstatic and it was extremely nerve-wrecking," Brodie said.

In what seemed like an eternity, Brodie described the final few moments as anxious.

You may also be interested in:
Sport and recreation grants help clubs aim for goals
Foul-mouthed man aggressive with daughter, punches woman in head

"There was a lot of thought going through and when Castro called out her name and pointed to her as the winner, it was just unbelievable," he said.

MORE LATER.
A breakthrough victory at the CrossFit Games.
In some ways SunCentral is like the Coast's version of the NBN
"I then said, 'Hey Ryan' ... (and he) started to run."
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Fiery larrikin Peter FitzSimons had the audience in stitches.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webb</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toomey</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Castro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clair-Toomey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunCentral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Orr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reebok CrossFit Games 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit Gladstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wisconsin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Kara Webb of Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone's Tia-Clair Toomey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristian Brodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit Games</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iceland's Katrin Tanja Davidsdottir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
