<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441786204186549</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/kellyanne-conway-benghazi-trump-jr-russia-meeting-2017-8</url>
  <title>Kellyanne Conway makes mindblowing pivot to Benghazi when grilled about Trump Jr.'s Russia meeting</title>
  <content>
"This Week" host George Stephanopoulos put Kellyanne Conway  Sunday morning when the senior White House adviser tried to change the subject away from President Donald Trump's role in crafting a misleading statement about his son's meeting with a Russian lawyer last year. 

Stephanopoulos pointed out that the White House and Trump's surrogates have given conflicting statements about the level of Trump's involvement in responding to initial reports that Donald Trump Jr. met with the lawyer, Natalia Veselnitskaya, last June, in a meeting that also included then-campaign manager Paul Manafort and senior adviser Jared Kushner. 

When Stephanopoulos pressed her on the discrepancy in the statements, saying the White House "didn't tell the truth," Conway pushed back with an astonishing pivot to the Affordable Care Act, and later to the 2012 Benghazi attacks.

"You know, let's talk about telling the truth," Conway said. "Let's talk about a president looking Americans in the eye, who are still suffering eight years later, who were lied to. If you like your plan, you can keep your plan. If you like your doctor, you can keep your doctor."

Conway then shifted to the Obama administration's response to the 2012 attack on US government buildings in Benghazi, Libya.

"Benghazi happened because of a video. Go tell the families of those four innocent Americans who were slaughtered in Benghazi that that lie mattered."

"Hold on a second," Stephanopoulos interjected. "You're changing the subject." 

"No. No. That is a subject," Conway replied. "Let's talk about credibility that impacts people."

Stephanopoulos said Conway was simply "going back to President Obama and Hillary Clinton," to which she replied that "those were big lies."

When Stephanopoulos continued grilling her on the different responses offered by the Trump administration on Trump Jr.'s statement to The New York Times, Conway did not address the question, and later went on to call the FBI counterintelligence investigation into the Trump campaign's possible collusion with Russia "fabricated." 

Watch the exchange below:

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benghazi</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Affordable Care Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Manafort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellyanne Conway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Jr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalia Veselnitskaya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Stephanopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conway</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanopoulos</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
