<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441399657124805</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/elon-musk-might-be-a-total-jerk-and-build-his-own-hyperloop-system-report/</url>
  <title>Elon Musk Might Be A Total Jerk And Build His Own Hyperloop System: Report</title>
  <content>
Photo via

Remember when Elon Musk claimed he was so busy with space and cars that he was willing to hand over developing a "Hyperloop" vacuum-sealed high speed train to everyone else - and then he went and started a tunnelling company? Well guess what, he might go back and make his own Hyperloop after all.

Elon Musk is probably thinking really hard about what to put in the tunnels he keeps spontaneously digging and proposing . He brought up a way of putting cars in the tunnels (which  itself). Now he wants to dig tunnels for his Hyperloop idea, according to a report from Bloomberg.

It would make sense for him to go back to the companies competing in his Hyperloop competition, considering the amount of resources they have been pouring into getting the vacuum-sealed, super-speedy transport design right. Bloomberg claims he's actually going to be kind of a jerk and not do that, because of course he isn't. From the report:

What a dick move! Hyperloop One is probably the most recognisable of the three startups that spawned off of Musk's original idea, and it's already pretty far along. The company's most recent test was for its transport pod, where it reached 309km/h, with the tepid goal of reaching at least 402km/h in later tests. It's unclear whether Hyperloop One or any other company will actually be able to accomplish speeds in excess of 483km/h safely.

The Bloomberg report accurately points out that Elon Musk getting into the game himself could be very bad news for the companies he inspired to start from nothing. It will be even more difficult to bring workers and investors on board with such a new concept when they are also betting against the industry clout of Elon Musk.

Here's a statement from Boring Co. on the rumoured Musk Hyperloop, via Bloomberg:

I'm not entirely confident that Musk and company will continue to let what is now the competition continue using the name they have trademarked, should one of the other Hyperloop companies manage to beat Musk to the punch in any respect. I'm no lawyer, but there's probably a strong argument to be made on the use of "Hyperloop" as generic language for the type of high-speed travel technology, like "train" or "car." We'll see if it ever has to be argued in court.

There have been previous issues and concerns from all parties involved over Musk's involvement in the development and image of the emerging Hyperloop technologies; Musk is annoyed that he's associated with companies he's not directly involved in, and the companies are frustrated that Musk continues to be the figurehead for the work they're developing.

Perhaps Musk's best solution is to just go ahead and get involved - it's just too bad he's probably going to screw over everything that's been accomplished so far. If you can't disassociate with them, buy them challenge them?

WATCH MORE: Car News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk Might Be A Total Jerk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Car News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boring Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Build His Own Hyperloop System</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyperloop One</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musk Hyperloop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musk</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyperloop</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
