<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441004520129041</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/football/fa-community-shield-arsenal-continue-wembley-fortune-with-penalties-win-over-chelsea/news-story/3e685deeb7f56f61469a9830cae9bb73</url>
  <title>Chelsea see red as Arsenal win Community Shield</title>
  <content>
GOALKEEPER Thibaut Courtois and star signing Alvaro Morata were the Chelsea fall guys as Arsenal won the Community Shield 4-1 on penalties at Wembley.
TRANSFERS:
ROBBIE SLATER:
EPL PREVIEW:
Goals from Chelsea's Victor Moses and Arsenal new boy Sead Kolasinac sent the game to a shootout and with both Courtois and Morata limply squandering their spot-kicks, Arsenal won the trophy for the third time in four years.
Courtois blazed his penalty over the bar before substitute Morata, a $95 million capture from Real Madrid, shot wide, allowing Olivier Giroud to seal victory for Arsenal.
"I'm very happy because we won a trophy we wanted to win and because the quality of the game was very good," said Arsenal manager Arsene Wenger.
"Even when we were 1-0 down, we didn't panic, kept control of our game and came back. The performance is in continuity of what we did at the end of last season."
Arsenal, embarking upon their first season without Champions League football since 1997, have won on their last nine visits to Wembley, a run stretching back to a win over Wigan Athletic in the semi-finals of the FA Cup in 2014.
Wenger, who has already been subjected to a fan invading the pitch in an attempt to abuse him during a pre-season friendly, was quick to call for unity in the stands ahead of Saturday's (EST) Premier League opener against Leicester.
"I would like they stand behind the team as we might go through some very good periods and some not so good periods," he said.
"We want to be united and together throughout the season.
"Every game is a battle in the Premier League, like today. It is a dream to make the fans happy, a difficult dream but we try hard."
Antonio Conte's Chelsea, who begin their Premier League title defence at home to Burnley on Sunday morning (EST), was fuming after the result.
Moses, sent off after receiving a second yellow card for diving as Arsenal stunned Chelsea 2-1 in May's FA Cup final, partially atoned by putting the champions ahead early in the second half.
But after Pedro had been shown a straight red card for an ugly challenge on Mohamed Elneny, Kolasinac headed in an 81st-minute equaliser.
"This is the second game, after the FA Cup, that we finish with 10 men," he said.
"I didn't see the situation. For me for this reason it is very difficult for me to say something about this decision.
"I heard there was clearly a penalty but I did not see. We are working, we are trying to do our best.
"We had a tough pre-season, between the six days until we start the league it is important to be focused on the next game."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPL PREVIEW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Conte's Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsene Wenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May's FA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsenal</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wigan Athletic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kolasinac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wembley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leicester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morata</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alvaro Morata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea's Victor Moses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivier Giroud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sead Kolasinac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtois</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pedro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thibaut Courtois</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Elneny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
