<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441348117516633</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/personal-finance/superannuation-and-smsfs/alternatives-to-family-trusts-20170804-gxplkd</url>
  <title>As family trusts come under threat, what other tax-effective vehicles exist?</title>
  <content>
by
Ben Smythe

With the "politics of envy" in full swing in Australia, tax advisers will no doubt continue to be a profession in demand.
The latest salvo comes from the Labor Party, which  to reduce the attractiveness of income splitting for trusts by imposing a flat 30 per cent tax rate on distributions. If this becomes law, where does this leave us in terms of future tax planning?
Superannuation pensions (up to a balance of $1.6 million) for members over the age of 60 continue to be the "Cayman Islands" of tax planning. For this structure, you will pay a zero rate of tax on income and withdrawals. For a husband and wife this represents $3.2 million in assets, which is not insignificant when you consider the family home is also exempt from capital gains tax. 
The number of self-managed super funds  with more than $3.2 million of pension assets is quite small, and with limits on future contributions now in place, it will difficult for most savers to get close to this level without a significant investment return and/or small business sale.

If you are fortunate enough to accumulate $1.6 million in your super pension account, any further contributions you make to super will be added to your accumulation bucket and taxed at 15 per cent. 

This is still a reasonable concession compared with marginal tax rates, with the main downside being that you can't access super until you meet a so-called condition of release. Provided you are over age 60, you will continue to pay no tax on withdrawals from your super accumulation account on retirement, regardless of the size of your balance. This will no doubt be the next battleground.
If super no longer appeals to you or you are rightfully concerned about future regulatory changes that will affect you in your retirement in 10 or 20 years' time, what other tax-effective vehicles should you be looking at for building wealth?
Trusts represent a "flow through" vehicle whereby the trustee is required to distribute all of the trust's income to beneficiaries every year. 
The "tax effectiveness" of trusts rests with the marginal rate of tax paid by eligible beneficiaries. Because all resident taxpayers have access to the "tax-free threshold" of $18,200 a year, a distribution to an eligible beneficiary who has little or no other income is a useful way to use up their tax-free threshold.

As the Labor Party points out, an eligible beneficiary could well be an 18-year old child who is studying full-time at university. If the rate of tax for all trust distributions was moved to a flat 30 per cent as Labor proposes, it would reduce the tax effectiveness of trusts but would still represent a reasonable arbitrage from the tax marginal rate of tax for high-income earners.
Insurance bonds 

Companies are now taxed based on the size of the company, within the range of 27.5 per cent to 30 per cent a year. Companies have the choice of distributing profits to shareholders, and shareholders then include their dividend in their personal tax return as income. Where the dividend is "franked", shareholders receive a tax credit for the tax paid by the company.
If the shareholder has little or no other income, they could end up paying no tax on the dividend and even receive back a refund of any excess franking credit. When looking at the benefits of a company versus a trust, if trust distributions are taxed at a flat rate of 30 per cent, you are likely to see companies becoming more popular structures for accumulating wealth, because of their ability to retain profits and distribute when they see fit.

One final option worth considering is insurance bonds. These structures were typically ignored by tax advisers because of their fee structures and limited investment options, but the range of products now offered in this space has certainly improved.
Insurance or investment bonds are "tax paid" entities. The tax rate is a flat 30 per cent. However, depending on the investment strategy you use, and the availability of franking credits with that investment strategy, you could reduce this rate down to 21 per cent. The bond structure allows you to build wealth in a tax-friendly environment, and provided you hold the investment for 10 years, there is no tax payable at the end of the period, nor any capital gains tax when you sell down the bond assets to cash after 10 years. 
Tax is certainly a dynamic issue in Australia and despite Treasury's best intentions, complexity is rife when looking at tax planning. While tax should never be the dominant purpose for an investment decision, you definitely need to be aware of the tax implications of any decision you make, and look to avoid having all "your eggs in the one tax basket".
Ben Smythe is the managing director of

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Smythe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cayman Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
