<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441734664578423</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/cigarette-butt-roads-could-help-reduce-pollution-waste/8775566</url>
  <title>From ashtrays to asphalt: Could this be the end of the road for cigarette butts?</title>
  <content>
Melbourne researchers are calling on Australian governments and the construction industry to start putting cigarette butts into the surfaces of roads, to stop their toxic chemicals reaching rivers and oceans.

Cigarette rubbish:

Cigarette filters enter waterways and don't break down
1.2 million tonnes of cigarette waste is produced worldwide each year
Melburnians put 9 million butts into landfill annually
The world's cigarette litter is expected to double by 2025

A research team from RMIT University, led by senior engineering lecturer Abbas Mohajerani, said it had found a way to mix cigarette butts in asphalt to help with road construction.
Testing showed the roads would not only be able to handle heavy traffic but the compound would also reduce heat conduction, which in turn would help reduce the urban heat common in big cities.
Most cigarette butts are not biodegradable and their toxic chemicals are released into the environment.
Around the world, 1.2 million tonnes of cigarette butt waste is created each year. That is expected to increase by more than 50 per cent by 2025 as the world's population grows.
Smokers in Melbourne put about 9 million cigarette butts into landfill each year, .
In Sydney, the city council hands out free canisters for smokers to use as a personal ashtrays to discourage littering.
'We can solve the whole cigarette butt problem'

Dr Mohajerani said the study, published in the journal of Construction and Building Materials, involved the use of bitumen and paraffin wax to prevent chemicals escaping from the cigarette butts.
He said if cigarette butts were used in roads on a large scale in Australia, toxic litter could be dramatically reduced.
"Let's say for example we put 10 to 15 kilograms of cigarette butts in one cubic metre of asphalt concrete, which is 2,200kg, [the cigarette butts] don't change the structure very much," he said.
"But because the volume of asphalt concrete we are producing in Australia and in the world is huge - hundreds of thousands of cubic metres in Australia - if you add just a little bit, we can solve the whole cigarette butt problem."
Dr Mohajerani said bitumen had been used to store nuclear material in France for many years.
"The function of [cigarette] filters is to filter and trap the chemicals. There are over 4,000 chemicals in the smoke of a cigarette and most of them are trapped in the filter, and many of them are carcinogenic," he said.
"We actually saturate and encapsulate the cigarette butt, and we don't use them on the surface of the pavement, we use them in the second layer.
"The encapsulation prevents the leeching of those chemicals. The water cannot reach inside the filters so chemicals cannot escape from the filters."
An earlier study, published in the International Journal of Environment Research and Public Health, found cigarette filters were the single most collected item in beach clean-ups around the world.
It said the butts caused environmental havoc by washing from streets into drains, then making their way into rivers and oceans.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Journal of Environment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbas Mohajerani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Materials</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Mohajerani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melburnians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
