<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441867808566164</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/local-afl/morris-on-monday-overlooking-local-umpire-for-aflnt-promotion-hard-to-fathom/news-story/4580fe149c4ad077242b31dfdc9641d8</url>
  <title>Overlooking local umpire hard to fathom</title>
  <content>
TERRITORY sport always prides itself on local content, from the on-field participants to umpires, administrators and even those people who are not always mentioned in dispatches, the sponsors.
None more so than the difficult and to a large degree, unrecognised, area of field umpiring, which despite former Geelong and West Australian champion Polly Farmer's claim the game does not need them, makes up a big slice of the game's pie.
So it was with a fair degree of surprise that I discovered another southern raider has found their way on to the AFLNT's long staffing list, when a local woman with a long-standing love for the game and deep passion for field umpiring was -overlooked.
This column does not intend to downplay the qualifications or integrity of the successful applicant for what was a vacant umpiring development co-ordinating role.
And there are always two sides to every story, something I'm sure the selection panel of game development manager Jennifer Le Quesan, HR manager Jenny Elliot and umpiring head coach Mark Noonan will remind me of.
For years I have been hearing of plans by Big Brother the AFL to rule Top End football, from chief executive Michael Solomon to the back- room staff and of course, the men and women who blow whistles on matchdays.
My reaction after writing about the Territory game for almost a quarter of a century has been sceptical, for reasons I thought were logical. You need local knowledge and an ability to liaise and communicate with indigenous people.
But it seems the message in this case was loud and clear in the opposite direction - bring in a southerner who can use a computer, speaks well and has sufficient knowledge of umpiring.
Referees for Darwin's own -Sheryle Schmode were not contacted and skills dating back seven years in umpiring, youth development and indigenous mentoring it seems, were considered but not imple-mented.
In this era of women in football, when the national competition is up and running in a big way and proud women like Erin Phillips, Bec Goddard and Daisy Pearce have their names up in lights, an opportunity to raise more awareness in Territory football was missed.
Do we question the professionalism and integrity of the AFLNT in the development side of the game?
Solomon, operations manager Joel Bowden and the AFL's national talent and development manager Adam Davis were presented with a plan to build female and multi-cultural awareness by Schmode, with Davis assisting with some input of his own.
Right now the only senior women's umpire is seriously contemplating giving the game away, a sad endorsement on the otherwise positive steps Territory football has taken towards female participation in the last decade.
"The difficult part is umpiring is something I feel so good about,'' Schmode told this writer. "I come alive when I walk out on the field and off the field where I talk to people about umpiring and what I love doing, but it has now been crushed.''
Michael Solomon is a man of integrity. This writer is convinced an important and permanent role can be found in Top End umpiring for a woman totally committed to her role.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daisy Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bec Goddard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheryle Schmode</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schmode</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Brother</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polly Farmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Le Quesan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Elliot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Solomon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Bowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
