<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441777614251829</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/waterfall-gully-rd-to-get-400000-state-government-upgrade-but-residents-say-more-needed/news-story/30c558788df80f2ac0d98582be3c11c7</url>
  <title>Waterfall Gully Rd upgrade - but more needed</title>
  <content>
WATERFALL Gully Rd will be given a $400,000 upgrade - but residents say it is not enough to fix critical problems with the flood-prone road.
The Transport Department will spend the money to reseal more than half of Waterfall Gully Rd, which suffered significant damage during last September's storms.
But foothills residents are concerned the upgrade will not go far enough and have renewed long-standing calls for urgent work to install kerbs and raise the camber of the road to properly protect their homes from damaging flood events.
Waterfall Gully Residents' Association chairman Peter Moschakis said fixing the road was the only way to properly floodproof the area.
He welcomed a Burnside Council decision last month to spend $570,000 to clear First Creek and Chambers Gully, but said that spending did not go far enough.
"When there is a flood, two-thirds of the water gets carried by the road," Mr Moschakis said.
"The sections of road that are kerbed, the damage is minimal so I think that if you do it right in the first instance you will not have to pay for the damage costs later."
Mr Moschakis said raising the camber of low-lying sections of the road would also help mitigate flood damage.
A Transport Department spokesman said about 2.2km of road from Waterfall Tce would be resurfaced in 2018/19 to improve the condition of the gateway to the popular Mt Lofty walking trail.
The spokesman said the project followed urgent repair work after last September's storms, when First Creek burst through the Chambers Gully entrance and dumped more than 400 tonnes of rock onto Waterfall Gully Rd.
He said residents would be consulted before the plan was finalised, but indicated the upgrade would not include work to create a kerb on a number of unsealed sections of the 4km road.
"That treatment is extremely constrained due to Waterfall Gully Creek running alongside (the road), the close proximity of properties and fences and the steep embankments," he said.
Foothills residents have long called for a complete upgrade of Waterfall Gully Rd, arguing a lack of unbroken kerbs and sealed footpaths has contributed to the flooding of homes during major storms.
The split ownership of the road - the State Government is in charge of its surface and Burnside Council responsible for the footpaths and walkways - has delayed a resolution because the two parties have been unable to agree on, and fund, a permanent fix.
Burnside Council chief executive Paul Deb supported work to resurface Waterfall Gully Rd, but cast doubt over the prospects of installing new kerbs and footpaths.
"Much of Waterfall Gully Rd is not suitable for kerbing, but each area will be considered on its individual merits," Mr Deb said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Deb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Deb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Department</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterfall Gully Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chambers Gully</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gully Residents' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterfall Tce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gully Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Moschakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Lofty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterfall Gully Rd</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnside Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foothills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Moschakis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
