<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441391067190057</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/world/a-british-model-says-she-had-her-wrists-and-ankles-handcuffed-before-being-stuffed-in-bag-by-kidnappers/news-story/60b6561811c60170cec60edd29c6215d</url>
  <title>Model drugged, cuffed and stuffed in bag</title>
  <content>
A BRITISH model who was kidnapped by sex slavers told last night how she was drugged, handcuffed and stuffed in a suitcase.
Mum Chloe Ayling, 20, was driven to a remote farmhouse and held captive for six days after being abducted by masked men.
Chloe, who was lured to Italy by a fake photoshoot, said: "I feared for my life second by second."
Her kidnapper told her he was part of a sinister syndicate called Black Death which sold women as sex slaves.
The terrified mum, 20, was warned she would be auctioned to Arabs on the dark web then fed to tigers when they grew bored.
She is thought to have been drugged with ketamine before being stuffed in a suitcase and held for six days.
Her abduction came after she was lured from England to a bogus fashion shoot in Milan.
Chloe said: "I've been through a terrifying experience. I've feared for my life, second by second, minute by minute, hour by hour."
Recalling how her ordeal started, Chloe said: "When I entered the studio on July 11 I had my iPhone, wallet and wheelie suitcase.
"The door from the adjoining room was closed. Before I could go in someone with black gloves put their hand on my mouth.
"A second person in a balaclava and dark clothes gave me an injection."
"I woke up in a car's boot. My wrists and ankles were handcuffed, and there was adhesive tape on my mouth.
"I was inside a bag and was only able to breathe through a small hole."
The gang drove Chloe two hours to Borgial near Lemie on the French border.
When she woke, she had been stripped to just a pink chenille body and socks.
In the remote farmhouse, tucked away in hills prowled by wolves, the gang outlined her fate.
Chloe said: "The man said that in the past five years he has made more than £11million.
"The girls are destined for Arab countries. At least three a week are sold and when the person gets bored of her he gives her to other people.
"When they're no longer interested they feed her to the tigers."
Polish-born Lukasz Herba, 30, appeared in an Italian court last week for a pre-trial hearing.
Officers are also thought to want to talk to his brother, Mikal Herba, 36, as a witness. The pair share a home in Oldbury, West Mids.
Police say Lukasz Herba demanded £270,000 to stop the auction, hosted on pornographic sites on the dark web.
He later said he would pay most of the ransom if she could find three people to hand over the remaining £38,000.
He was arrested on July 17 after delivering Chloe to the British consulate in Milan. Reports said he took pity on her after she told him she had a two-year-old son.
Chloe was under orders to address her captor as "MD".
A note found on Herba's computer after Chloe was freed bizarrely reads: "You are being released as a huge generosity from Black Death Group."
It says her kidnapping was a mistake and that "our main and very well respected men" insisted on her release.
It ends: "You have also agreed to pay outstanding costs of your release of $50,000 - paid in Bitcoins within one month. Any disobedience will result in your elimination."
Chloe has told police: "I'm scared for my life especially because I've told you these things and he says there are 10,000 members in Europe."
Reports in Italy say Herba took her shopping for shoes. He is said to have told police he has leukaemia, and carried out the kidnapping to pay medical bills.

A post shared by Chloe Ayling (@chloeayling) on

Police believe he previously lured Chloe to Paris for a photoshoot which didn't go ahead and she returned home unharmed.
When he was arrested police found a leaflet illustrated with drawings of Black Death plague doctors from the 1300s.
The only year-round resident of Borgial said Herba had visited the farmhouse over a month ago with large bags.
He used two cars - an English reg Mercedes and a Polish-reg Volvo.
Herba told the farmhouse's owner he was a painter in need of solitude.
UK neighbours of Herba said he was obsessed with computer games, referring to himself as "Vampire Zero God".
They said he sometimes went for walks with a rat on his shoulder. Last night at home in Coulsdon, South London, Chloe said: "I'm incredibly grateful to the Italian and UK authorities for all they have done.
"I have just arrived home after four weeks and haven't had time to collect my thoughts."
Lorenzo Bucossi, of the Milan Flying Squad, said Herba had told Chloe many slaves were destined for the Middle East.
But there was no proof any of his boasts were true.
West Midlands Police said an address in Oldbury was raided on July 18 in connection with the investigation.
and is reprinted with permission
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polish-born Lukasz Herba, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Death</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lemie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Death Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borgial</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lukasz Herba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oldbury</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Midlands Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vampire Zero God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikal Herba, 36</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Ayling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arab</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 11 I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Mids</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polish-reg Volvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorenzo Bucossi, of the Milan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flying Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herba</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Ayling, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coulsdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
