<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441176318823072</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/real-housewives-of-sydney-star-lisa-oldfield-posts-sympathy-shag-selfie-with-husband-david/news-story/81699031c0f56ad64dd27282a80a8a61</url>
  <title>Oldfields post crude 'sympathy shag' selfie</title>
  <content>
CONTROVERSIAL Real Housewives of Sydney star Lisa Oldfield has revealed some major PDA on her social media account overnight.
The 42-year-old, who made headlines after her husband David revealed they had not had sex in a year, uploaded a picture after apparently doing the deed.
It appears the drought is now over with Lisa telling her 30,000 followers on Instagram she gave her former One Nation politician man a "sympathy shag" after his stint on Hell's Kitchen last night.
"Gave the old bloke @davidoldfieldau a #sympathy #shag - we all know my show was better than his @hellskitchenon7 @rhosydney #rhos #hellskitchen," she wrote.
"To be fair, I haven't eaten in a week thanks to #drliu and just wanted something warm inside me."
In March, David confessed he hadn't had sex with wife Lisa in more than a year - but claims when they did "it's pretty wild."
David, now a stay-at-home husband and parent to the couple's two children, Bert, 4, and Harry, 6, told News Corp Australia his 16-year-old marriage was sexless, with Lisa claiming the couple were now in therapy, at the time.
"We make plans to do this sort of thing [have sex], it's hilarious. It's like booking an appointment in the diary. We have in the past year made plans to do it, and then one thing leads to another and something goes wrong and it doesn't happen," he said in March.
But things appear to be looking up for the couple - just last week, David hinted he and Lisa could work together on a reality show
Lisa also wrote in another Instagram post: "When @davidoldfieldau says on @hellskitchenon7 you're not a #workingmum but like a bloke in the 1950s that has a wife that #doeseverything - yeah he does the #nanny the #ridinginstructor and the #cleaner."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Housewives of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry, 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hell's Kitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bert, 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
