<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440918620782036</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/national/rush-hour-stories-you-need-to-know-today/news-story/2d38458b190394e9fb9b3d60106922c3</url>
  <title>RUSH HOUR: Stories you need to know today</title>
  <content>
Live: Rush Hour
Good morning! Things will be tense between factions of the Coalition today, as the party meets to discuss same-sex marriage. Delays are expected in Sydney's south after a crane collapsed on an apartment block at Wolli Creek. And a new study has revealed there's a scientific reason for liking big butts.
6:30am
Why big backsides are healthier
A new study has suggested pear-shaped women are healthier than their busty counterparts, because they're less susceptible to heart attacks, strokes and diabetes.
The research, published in , indicates when fat stored in the lower half of the body it doesn't travel to vital organs like the heart and lungs.
Basically, it means not as much fat is released into the bloodstream, so it doesn't go on to cause as many complications down the track.
The research was conducted at the University of Tubingen, Germany where experts used MRI scans and regular health checks to observe fat distribution.
However, the results do not apply to people who are overweight.
6:05am
Coalition to discuss gay marriage
The Coalition will hold a special party room meeting on same-sex marriage today.
A group of Liberal MPs will pitch a private members' bill as protecting religious freedoms in the hope of satisfying conservative colleagues' concerns about a free vote.
Political experts predict the most likely outcome is a reaffirmation of a plebiscite, which could lead to a postal vote on the issue.
However, the coalition continues to be divided by strong factions, who will go face-to-face
Tension is rising within the party, with the latest Newspoll showing Labor leading the Government 53-47 on a two-party preferred basis.
However, Malcolm Turnbull continues to lead Bill Shorten as preferred prime minister 46 to 31 per cent, according to the latest results.
5:45am
Crane collapse causes delays
Delays are expected in Sydney's south again today after a crane collapsed onto an apartment block at Wolli Creek.
Emergency services were called to Brodie Spark Drive at Wolli Creek just after 9.30am on Sunday, following reports a crane had fallen off one building and crashed into another.
Three people have been treated for minor injuries after the machine fell onto a penthouse apartment, crushing a balcony.
No-one was inside the crane at the time but the two buildings were evacuated, with emergency services creating an exclusion zone.
Fire and Rescue NSW superintendent Josh Turner said four buildings had been evacuated while authorities figure out how to remove the crane.
Train lines and roads in the area have been affected.

At least 150 residents spent the night in temporary accommodation after a crane collapsed into a building.

Residents return home after crane collapse
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tubingen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rush Hour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Spark Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newspolls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rescue NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
