<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442005247521745</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/best-tips-build-wealth-early-retirement-2017-8</url>
  <title>I retired at 52 with a $3 million net worth  --  here are my 10 best tips to build wealth</title>
  <content>
No matter how much you make, you can spend it all. We don't have to look far to find examples. It's almost a cliche that high-income actors and sports stars go bankrupt. People who have made millions somehow spend it all and then some. As a result, they are often left with nothing (or less).

A bit closer to home, you can see this principle play out across our country.

The median American household annual income is . U.S. households median net worth is . This means that over a 40-year period at an 8% return rate, the average American is saving a paltry $US310 a year. What are they doing with all the rest? They are spending it!

On the other hand, those who  do much better.

Assume a family can save $US5k per year (less than 10% of their income). In 40 years at 8% they will have a net worth of $US1.3 million. See what even a little bit of saving can do over a lifetime?

And this doesn't mean you have to save on EVERYTHING, just some things. Enjoy your life by spending on what you want here and there, just keep it in line so you have excess to save and invest. Even 10% will make you wealthy over time.

Personally, I wanted to do better than average and was able to . Others have saved much more. If we can do it, so can you.

There are two major areas to control spending: on the big things, and on the little things.

Big things like homes, cars, extravagant vacations, and the like can bust your budget in a single move. Little things like eating out for lunch regularly, smoking a pack of cigarettes daily, and, dare I say, drinking $US5 cups of coffee several times a day don't seem like much, but they can add up to big dollars over time.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US310</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
