<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441648765231440</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/racing/poor-form-is-perfect-form-for-michael-hickmotts-unbreakable-leading-into-the-darwin-cup/news-story/18ebdc29a570e92c32caec358ff9920c</url>
  <title>Losing habit not a worry for Cup hope</title>
  <content>
POOR form is actually perfect form for Michael Hickmott's Unbreakable leading into the $200,000 Carlton Mid Darwin Cup today.
It would usually sound like twisted logic, but the classy five-year-old's seventh placing behind winner and big Cup hope Royal Request in the Chief Minister's Cup over 1600m on July 15 has Hickmott beaming with confidence.
The three-time Darwin Cup winner and reigning champion studies the form of his horses religiously, and believes Unbreakable's back-of-the-pack finish second-up from a spell last start has him primed for Cup glory.
"His second-up form is horrible," Hickmott admitted of his stayer who will start from barrier nine with 2008 Melbourne Cup winning jockey Blake Shinn aboard.
"Previous to the ROANT Cup (which he won on July 1) he had four second-up runs from a spell and never ran a place, and he replicated that in the Chief Minister's Cup.
"It's always been the plan to run third-up in the Cup. If you look at his form third-up, he's a horse that improves and always goes well.
"Even last prep he ran second at Caulfield (the $60,000 Thomas North Handicap on April 22) third-up from a spell off a disappointing run second-up again."
Having Shinn in the saddle will be a combination punters would find hard to ignore.
"They'll complement each other. Unbreakable is a horse that doesn't need too much assistance," Hickmott said.
"He's a delicate horse, and you know if he'll perform at his best he'll do it pretty much all himself.
"Unbreakable is clearly the classiest horse of the three. His win in the ROANT Cup was breathtaking."
Then there is fellow five-year-old Lieder piloted by two-time Perth Cup winner William Pike from barrier six.
"He (Lieder) is the true handicapper. He sneaks into the field with 54kg," Hickmott said.
"Willie was really keen to ride him. He's such a strong rider and this horse takes a lot of bullying.
"He's quite a relaxed horse through the run. He needs to be told what to do in a race.
"William Pike is a rider who does that, and he'll be in the race at 54kg with a massive chance."
Don't write off Hickmott's seven-year-old Wexford Town from barrier seven, either.
"Wexford Town is a class galloper who's coming back from being in the wilderness," Hickmott said.
"Very good looking horse, has a great deal of stamina and his work has been fantastic.
"If he was to replicate his form running second to Assign at Caulfield three runs ago (the $120,000 Mornington BMW Cup Prelude over 2000m on February 27 last year) he would be more than competitive."
Hickmott lives and breathes horse racing and is right at home in the Top End.
"When it comes to a Darwin Cup there's no stone left unturned," Hickmott said.
"I don't drink or smoke. My adrenalin rush is this. I don't jump out of planes.
"My adrenalin rush is watching people get excited about their horses winning.
"I love to see people enjoying their horses win. There is nothing better in the world."
"(Darwin) was a great place to do an apprenticeship. I had some smart people up here look over my shoulder and teach me a lot of things.
"The Darwin Turf Club, Thoroughbred Racing NT and LJ Hooker when I was working there.
"They all developed me when I came up from when I turned 18 to now having a business where I trade horses overseas."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unbreakable</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Request</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington BMW Cup Prelude</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton Mid Darwin Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hickmott's Unbreakable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Minister's Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas North Handicap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thoroughbred Racing NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hickmott</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Pike</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WEXFORD TOWN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ Hooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Turf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROANT Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Shinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
