<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441824858892661</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/halffinished-house-littered-with-illegally-dumped-rubbish/news-story/e4c6c088cf4288247253d06a83837073</url>
  <title>Dumpers target half-finished house</title>
  <content>
A CRANBOURNE family whose half-finished house was turned into a rubbish dump has praised the community for pitching in to lend a hand.
Steph Widdowson was set to start renting a property in the Bloom estate from her sister-in-law Tash before its builder Ashford Homes - owned by former Family First senator Bob Day - went broke in late 2016.
The empty home became a target for rubbish dumpers and the City of Casey said the family would face a $2000 fine if it was not cleaned up.
They could move the mess to the nature strip and it could be collected as hard rubbish but there was so much they would have had to hire someone to move it themselves.
Taking to a community Facebook page, Ms Widdowson vented her frustration and people rallied around to help, organising a community working bee on the first weekend in August to clean up all the rubbish.
"When I got there I was just stunned at how much garbage there was," she said.
"The majority of it was builder's waste but there were a lot of obvious household garbage, including a microwave, a cabinet and a kid's bike.
"I don't get mad often, I'm very even tempered, but looking at it all made me furious - there was no way my husband could take care of it, even if he brought two friends."
Ms Widdowson, whose family is living in their current property thanks to the kindness of their landlord, said her sister had been struggling to find a builder to finish the home but was still paying the mortgage for it.
For her family, the delay in moving into the area had created other problems.
"We enrolled my daughter in prep for a school we aren't in the zone for," she said.
"It looks like it will be at capacity next year and they won't be taking unzoned children anymore.
"My son Kalel is eight, and he goes to Southern Autistic School in East Bentleigh.
"We are now talking about transitioning him to my daughter's school, but I worry that if we leave it too long, he won't get in if we don't live in the area."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family First</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Bentleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Autistic School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Widdowson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph Widdowson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashford Homes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITY of Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
