<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441305167843313</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/08/37/melbourne-sydney-adelaide-weather-wind-rain-wind</url>
  <title>Blizzard of Oz: Wind and cold to continue this week</title>
  <content>
Damaging winds and chilly temperatures hit parts of Victoria, New South Wales and South Australia at the weekend, and it's not over yet.
While today will bring some reprieve, winds will strengthen in New South Wales from tonight, with coastal areas expected to bear the brunt.
"It was a very windy weekend, and things will act similarly from Wednesday. Wash, rinse, repeat," Weatherzone senior meteorologist Jacob Cronje told 9news.com.au.
"From late Wednesday, winds will strengthen with another front to hit South Australia, and move to eastern parts (of the country) by Friday."
West and central Victoria is also looking likely to be in the firing line for damaging winds.

Hail and thunder are on the horizon today in Melbourne, with winds of up to 30km/h expected.
The city will reach a top of just 12 degrees before conditions clear on Wednesday and Thursday as winds then begin to pick back up.

Related Articles

In Sydney, winds of up to 40km/h are on the horizon this morning with a top of 18 degrees, while Adelaide will have a day of reprieve after a wild weekend of wind and rain. The city will reach 16 degrees.
Localised flooding is still possible for parts of the Adelaide Hills, with a warning for the Upper Onkaparinga River.
Alpine regions received "the best snow of the season" over the weekend, with thousands flocking to the snow to make the most of the conditions. In Victoria, around 80cm of snow fell at Falls Creek and Mt Hotham.

Further snow is expected to fall over the New South Wales and Victorian alps today, with 10-20cm possible for all major resorts, Mr Cronje added.
"Natural snow depths should be around 120-160cm at all major resorts by the end of the day.
"It's a bit of a drier frontal system, and not as moist as the previous system," Mr Cronje said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cronje</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weatherzone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blizzard of Oz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alpine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Hotham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper Onkaparinga River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falls Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Cronje</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
