<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442078261966509</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/ousted-survivor-contestant-reveals-shows-primitive-toilet-provisions/news-story/310aabe226830c8bd8dfd874ab3b00b0</url>
  <title>Ousted Survivor contestant reveals show's primitive toilet provisions</title>
  <content>
Survivor Australia - Tarzan gets voted out
0:30

On Survivor Australia, Tarzan gets voted out. CREDIT: Channel 10

August 6th 2017
15 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Tarzan said Survivor contestants go to the bathroom 'wherever they want'. Eew. Picture: NIGEL WRIGHT.

Share

OUSTED Australian Survivor competitor Mark "Tarzan" Herlaar has lifted the lid on one of the most mysterious elements of the show: Where exactly do the contestants go to the toilet?
Speaking to Kyle and Jackie O on their this morning,claimed he and his fellow contestants were left with rather informal provisions during their time on Samoa.
"There's plenty of coconut trees. It's just ... as it takes you," he said when asked what bathroom facilities were available. "You just go wherever you feel you need to."
"To be honest with you, most of them didn't s**t for three or four days. It's actually not high on your priority list, going to the bathroom," he continued, explaining the limited food on offer tended to slow the body down.

Tensions run high - not least because no-one's done a number two in days. Picture: Nigel WrightSource:Supplied
Herlaar's claims are a direct contradiction to what when we asked him that exact question - at the time, he explained that season one contestants didn't have to make do with a coconut tree to do their business.
"There is a porta-potty near their camp, yes. But that's it, nothing else. I don't think [the porta-potty] is particularly great, let's say that," LaPaglia told us.
"Environmentally, when somewhere like Samoa is kind enough to let us shoot there, we have to treat the place with a certain respect, and leave it as we found it. Sanitation is an issue."
There are three possible explanations here:
1. Tarzan's telling a little white lie;

2. Ten have stripped out the porta-potty budget for season 2 of the show;
3. Poor old Tarzan missed the memo that there was an actual toilet facility on-site and persisted in pooing under a coconut tree while his fellow contestants enjoyed the relative luxury of a porta-potty.
Herlaar may have been reticent to reveal the details of the porta-potty during his media commitments this morning, but he was keen to stress that competing on Survivor is just as tough as it looks. Despite what some viewers may think, crew don't sweep in to offer creature comforts when the cameras are switched off.
"They may as well drop you there and not come back for 55 days - you are doing it hard. There was one occasion I nearly lost it because the night before was horrendous. Cyclonic winds and we would've easily got 200 mill of rain. It's freezing at night, too," he said.
Australian Survivor continues 7:30pm tonight on Ten.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herlaar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaPaglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarzans</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIGEL WRIGHT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel WrightSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Survivor Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
