<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441129074182235</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/national/more-australians-sleeping-rough-than-ever-before-as-homeless-crisis-peaks/news-story/ee49e734624836ec5aef5491217f1c95</url>
  <title>Homeless crisis 'worst in 50 years'</title>
  <content>
MORE Australians are sleeping rough or without a place to call home than ever before according to one of the sector's leading advocates.
Reverend Bill Crews from the Exodous Foundation has been working with the homeless since 1970 and says the current state of the issue is worse than he has seen it in close to 50-years.
"Honestly it's worse than I've ever seen since 1970 and it's getting worse," Rev Crews said.
"There is increasing discrepancy between the rich and the poor ... and there is so much contract work so there are a lot of people who are really underemployed and just aren't able to pay for housing. Domestic violence issues are also on the rise leading to more women and children sleeping in their cars or on the street.
"It's devastating the amount of people we are seeing on the streets. And the problem is no longer confined to the cities. Almost every suburb you go into now you will find someone who is homeless."
The most recent census data on homelessness is yet to be made available, however estimates put the figure up 20 per cent since 2011, with around 23,000 Aussies sleeping rough.
Today News Corp Australia will launch the AskIzzy power card campaign in order to address this worsening issue. Members of the public can purchase a $15 power card for someone in need which charges their phone for four hours and keeps them in touch with services like food and shelter.
is a mobile app and website that allows homeless users to search for vital services in their area.
This year it has had more than 400,000 searches from people sleeping rough.
News Corp Australia can also reveal the federal government will today begin making available $117.2 million in key funding to support more than 700 critical frontline homelessness services.
The money will prioritise services to women and children experiencing domestic violence and young people experiencing homelessness.
More than 105,000 of the 280,000 people who accessed specialist homelessness services in
2015/16 had experienced domestic or family violence.
Assistant Minister for Social Services Zed Seselja conceded the homelessness problem was getting worse.
"We recognise it is a significant and growing problem," Senator Seselja said.
"Clearly the targets that were set to tackle this issue have not been met and we are actively working with the states on how best to resolve this issue."
Senator Seselja denied the federal government was "buck passing" to the states.
"I don't want to be sitting here and blaming this state or that state. But many of these programs are state-run so our job is to ensure there are measurable targets that ensure Commonwealth money is making a difference."
Kids Help line says it has received contacts from an alarming number of kids reaching out to the service saying they are couch surfing and without a home. The service has received 3091 contacts from children and young people where homelessness was a concern from 2014-2016.
To donate to the AskIzzy power card campaign go to the
lanai.scarr@news.com.au

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AskIzzy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exodous Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rev Crews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reverend Bill Crews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Services Zed Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Seselja</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
