<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441605815557908</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-07/judas-pest-management-expanded-to-wild-horses-brumbies-wa/8685068</url>
  <title>'Judas' pest management for wild horses</title>
  <content>
Western Australia is pioneering a method of culling wild horses to stop the destruction of one of Australia's most significant wetlands.
The Fortescue Marsh, about 250 kilometres south of Port Hedland, might occupy some 900 square kilometres, but it is small enough for the estimated 1,000 horses to do damage.
Parks and Wildlife conservation officer, Hamish Robertson, said the Fortescue Marsh needed to be protected from the animals.
"The marsh has a lot of very special plants and animals with high conservation significance," Mr Robertson said.
Aside from their effects on the marsh, wild horses are also known to affect pastoral stations.
Kimberley Pilbara Cattlemen's Association president, David Stoate, said the impact of wild horses could come at a considerable cost to pastoralists, as well as the environment.
"It's a lot of grazing pressure, as well as their affect on water points, water holes, and natural water courses, the affect of them can be quite severe," Mr Stoate said.
Following an aerial survey of the Fortescue Marsh in 2014, which showed tracks across the marsh leading to waterways, heavy erosion and wallowing, caused largely by horses, Western Australia's Parks and Wildlife service .
Using a light tracking collar with VHF and satellite beacons, which pinpoint the horses' locations every two hours, peak activity times, and temperature, Parks and Wildlife was able to find out how far the horses were roaming, and why.
Hamish Robertson said the idea was to eventually install a fence around the marsh, however he believed it was important to first reduce wild horse numbers.
Biblical story of betrayal

The Judas program is a method of reducing feral animal numbers combining the satellite collars and an aerial culling approach.

A team of professional vets, shooters, pilots, and conservation officers are engaged to carry out the Judas program.

A team of professional vets, shooters, pilots, and conservation officers are engaged to carry out the Judas program.

Supplied: Parks and Wildlife Service, Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions, Western Australia

The concept revolves around betrayal, and relies on horses, and other pests such as donkeys and camels, being social animals which will endeavour to find a new herd if they are left alone.
"We fit a [satellite] collar to a horse, and the horse will essentially betray the locations of the other horses, and so we'll go out and remove that impact from the marsh but we'll leave the collared animal out there and she will go and find another group," Hamish Robertson said.
"If you have a needle in a haystack, it's similar to try to find a feral horse in the Pilbara - it's pretty hard, we're talking over a couple of million hectares here - to go and find a feral horse even with a helicopter is quite difficult.
"So if you want to find a needle in a haystack you use a magnet.

"These collars are essentially magnets, bringing us directly to where the collared animal is and the rest of the horses.

"we'll find more than just that one needle, we'll find the other needles we didn't know about, which is the beauty of this approach."
Historically strong opposition

However the culling of wild horses has historically .
Horse activist, Libby Lovegrove, described the Judas program as "cruel" and likened it to the treatment of cattle in Indonesian abattoirs, as shown on the .

"It's just the most senseless thing. [Parks and Wildlife should] just look into it a lot more deeply than just going up in the helicopter and stupidly shooting them all, I mean it's just a really stupid solution," Ms Lovegrove said.

Ms Lovegrove believed Parks and Wildlife should consider re-homing the animals, or making them sterile with a fertility drug.
However Hamish Robertson said research had been done into other methods, and did not believe they were viable.
"The Pilbara's a large landscape, you've got huge travelling distances, lack of refrigeration in most instances ... and they're different than domesticated animals - they can't readily be round up, you can muster horses but it puts them under immense stress.
"[The fertility drug] can work on small populations on a small landscape. We've looked at that and it's not really practical either because you have to re-administer the drug every one to two years to keep it effective.

The 'Judas' horse will likely be a young, healthy filly, who will easily join or build a new herd

The 'Judas' horse will likely be a young, healthy filly, who will easily join or build a new herd

Supplied: Parks and Wildlife Service, Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions, Western Australia

"You've got to come back every two years, re-find the same ones in a vast landscape over 2 million hectares, and do that on a continual basis - that's just not practical at the moment."
Management is key

Equine veterinarian and animal ethics consultant Sheila Greenwell agreed the Judas program would be the most humane method for the region.
"I've seen animals die from water depravation, and I can tell you I'd rather be shot through the head than go that way," Ms Greenwell said.
"Also, when food runs short that leads to lots of fighting."
Ms Greenwell accepted that horse numbers had become uncontrollable in the region and had to be reduced, however she believed the management of numbers in the future was crucial.

"The life of a wild horse isn't how everyone perceives it - galloping in open planes of grassland - it's not.

"It's essentially a continual fight for survival, and when numbers get high and environments get squashed, those issues accelerate.
"It's our responsibility, I feel, to prevent the population getting to that level."
After a small pilot program culling wild horses with the Judas method, Parks and Wildlife was confident it would be successful on a larger scale in the future.
But Hamish Robertson said a fence around the marsh would still be required, in conjunction with aerial culling.
"It can't be [the Judas program] alone, it has to be a number of different approaches," Mr Robertson said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lovegrove</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley Pilbara Cattlemen's Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Hedland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildlife Service</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Greenwell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VHF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia's Parks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libby Lovegrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Robertson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Marsh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Stoate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stoate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheila Greenwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Biodiversity</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Robertson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judas</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
