<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441051764769825</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/theyre-beatable-damien-hardwick-says-richmond-is-ready-to-snap-its-12game-losing-streak-to-geelong/news-story/a79e9653fe6f651ce3791db1b8eb2312</url>
  <title>'They're beatable': Tigers ready for Cats</title>
  <content>
RICHMOND coach Damien Hardwick says the club is embracing the challenge of travelling to Geelong and playing in a match that could define not only the top four, but the top two.
After defeating Hawthorn by 29 points at the MCG on Sunday, Richmond sits third on percentage behind the Giants who have won one less game, but drawn two.
Geelong (12 wins) sits half a game beneath both clubs, while Port Adelaide, Sydney and the Western Bulldogs are nipping at their heels, one and a half games behind.
While Adelaide looks to have claimed top spot and will certainly host a home final after thumping Port Adelaide, it's a battle between GWS, Richmond and Geelong for the other home final within the top four.
Saturday's match between the Cats and Tigers at Skilled Stadium therefore shapes as one of the most crucial games in the run home.
And Richmond believe they are more than up to the challenge, particularly after the Swans provided a blueprint to success on Friday.
"I think we just embrace it. We're enjoying the challenge at the moment, we're enjoying the struggle of the AFL seasons, it has been an incredible season so far," Hardwick said.
"The players have really enjoyed that. It's going to be a big game down the highway, there's no doubt about that.
"It's a big challenge down there, there's no doubt about that. But they are beatable."
While Geelong will relish the inclusion of Brownlow Medal winner Patrick Dangerfield, captain Joel Selwood has been ruled out with an ankle injury.
Power forward Tom Hawkins and depth midfielder Mitch Duncan may also miss the match because of undisciplined acts.
On the flip side, Richmond will more than likely welcome key forward Jack Riewoldt (eye) back.
"It makes me sleep easier," Hardwick said upon hearing Selwood wouldn't play.
"That's disappointing. You want to see the good players play.
"The fact of the matter is we lost Jack for two weeks so sides can win without their best players playing, there's no doubt about that. We've just got to make sure we're ready to go."
Of its last 16 matches at Simonds Stadium, Geelong has only lost matches to the Swans. It has become an impregnable fortress for the club.
What's more, the last time Richmond defeated Geelong was in Round 9, 2006 - more than a decade ago.
But Hardwick said he was undaunted by history.
"Geelong are a good side, they've played some outstanding footy throughout the year," he said.
"It's one of those ones when you go into a hostile environment ... our guys love to travel and play well interstate.
"It's not interstate but it's a journey down there and it's a hostile environment. It's a challenge. But if we play our best footy we're capable of beating most sides."
Dion Prestia, who kicked one goal from 31 touches while also playing a negating role on Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell, told foxfooty.com.au he was equally confident the Tigers could claim another scalp.
"We play Geelong next week so that's a big game to set up the top four," Prestia said.
"We keep showing up every week. We've done it all year besides probably two games. It was always going to happen with a young group, but we keep showing up and getting the job done."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prestia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardwick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dion Prestia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skilled Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong (12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
