<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441863513598775</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/former-mtv-host-maz-comptons-awkward-interview-with-robert-downey-jr/news-story/aed8d7f025d3c337c6542cd246f03d4b</url>
  <title>Former MTV host Maz Compton's awkward interview with Robert Downey Jr</title>
  <content>
Former MTV and radio host Maz Compton has lifted the lid on one particularly awkward moment with Robert Downey Jr.

Share

MAZ Compton has spilled the beans on her most bizarre celebrity interviews during her years as a jetsetting MTV host - including one particularly strange encounter with Robert Downey Jr.
In her soon-to-be-released mini-memoir UnEdited, Compton said she'd been given one-on-one time with the actor as part of an Australian press junket for Iron Man back in 2008.

Robert Downey Jr in Iron Man.Source:News Corp Australia
According to the TV and radio presenter, when she entered the room he immediately reached for "a bottle of pills at his feet" and offered her one, while chatting away to the cameraman about a trip he'd taken to Mexico.
In a bid to "break the ice", Compton asked him if the pills were perhaps for a parasite that he'd picked up on his holiday.
"His mouth dropped open ... The cameraman announced to the room 'rolling when you're ready Maz,' and at that exact moment, RDJ did something bizarre," she explained.
"[He] lifted up his right arm before the first word was out of my mouth. He pointed directly at me and said: 'You're a piece of sh**'.
"I was part in shock, part in fear of responding. I didn't know whether to laugh or leave. I think everyone in the room was waiting for my retort. I stared into his eyes. Without hesitation, I fired back ..."no, you're a piece of sh**."
It was a make-or-break moment, but thankfully, the risky move paid off.
"He laughed - a really friendly and warm laugh - and said, 'Good, I like you. Continue.'"

UnEdited will be released tomorrow, August 8, and will be  and most .

Former MTV and radio host Maz Compton has released a tell-all "mini-memoir".Source:Supplied
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Downey Jr</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTV</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maz Compton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Man.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Compton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
