<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441391067190112</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/08/56/investigation-into-collapsed-sydney-crane</url>
  <title>Investigation into collapsed Sydney crane</title>
  <content>
A crane that collapsed onto an apartment block in Sydney's south has forced more than 160 people out of their homes, with authorities unsure when it will be safe to return.
An investigation into the Sunday morning incident at Wolli Creek is underway as authorities try to piece together what went wrong, with NSW Fire & Rescue Superintendent Josh Turner saying removing the crane will be complicated.
"We have no idea what may have caused it and that is part of an ongoing investigation by SafeWork NSW," he told AAP on Monday.
"The crane has been stabilised so it is safe for workers to start dismantling it."
Police were called to Brodie Spark Drive at 9.30am on Sunday, following reports a crane had fallen off one building and crashed into another.
Images show the crane's tower and arm smashed into the top-floor penthouse apartment, crushing a balcony.
No one was inside the crane at the time of the crash.

Related Articles

Supt Turner said the residents of the 88 units would remain in temporary accommodation until authorities were sure the building was safe.
"We had to isolate the power and gas to the building because we're unsure about the damage at this stage," he said.
"The integrity of the building will be checked and until that's done we can't give a timeline when people will be able to return."
Two people injured in the incident were taken to St George Hospital, with one of them suffering a leg injury, an ambulance spokesman told AAP.
The crash caused disruptions to trains on Sunday on the T2 airport line, but a spokeswoman for the Transport Management Centre said on Monday trains were running as normal with no delays.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rescue Superintendent Josh Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supt Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Spark Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Management Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SafeWork NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
