<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441610110525280</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/world/migrant-crisis/aid-group-accused-of-helping-people-smugglers-suspect-farright-hackers-20170806-gxql2a.html</url>
  <title>Aid group accused of helping people smugglers suspect far-right hackers faked GPS data</title>
  <content>
An aid group whose rescue boat was confiscated for allegedly helping people traffickers in the Mediterranean say their equipment may have been hacked by anti-migrant groups trying to undermine their mission by creating fake evidence of illegal rescues.
A spokesman for Jugend Rettet, whose boat Iuventa was seized by Italian police last week, told Fairfax Media they have done nothing illegal in the complex and dangerous situation off the coast of Libya, where thousands of would-be migrants are putting to sea in unseaworthy boats and dinghies.Photo: ANSA/AP
Julian Pahlke, who is based in Berlin but has been at sea on previous Jugend Rettet rescue missions, said they had received a 450-page document "full of possible evidence" from Italian police, which their lawyers were still combing through.
He was unable to comment on the specific allegations, he said, but his group "clearly deny" any illegal actions.
The accusations are based on the group's encounters with what they call "engine fishers", he said, groups which "belong in the wider sense to the (people) trafficker networks", who turn up during or after a sea rescue and try to collect the boats and engines to take them back to Libya for re-use or to make some money.
Engine fishers were "a pretty big problem", Pahlke said, because they are sometimes armed and have previously attacked NGO and coastguard boats if they tried to destroy migrant boats.

The Iuventa itself was attacked by engine fishers late last year, Pahlke said.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Whenever we are not sure if we can burn and destroy the boat - maybe we are attacked if we do that - we always need to tell our crew to step back, to not provoke them. Our crew is not armed and not protected.Photo: AP
"That's the only weapon we have, to be diplomatic and maybe leave the boat to them."
The Iuventa was seized by police a week ago, after prosecutors in Trapani said they had evidence suggesting the ship was used "to aid and abet illegal immigration".Photo: AP
Trapani prosecutor Ambrogio Cartosio said there were "contacts, meetings, understandings" between the Iuventa and the smugglers, and that migrants were being "handed over" to the Iuventa rather than being rescued.
However he said his "personal conviction" was that the aid group's motive was humanitarian, and it "would be fantasy to say there was a coordinated plan between the NGOs and the Libyan traffickers".Photo: ANSA/AP
The Iuventa was part of a fleet of up to 12 boats crewed by aid groups, who are trying to fill the gap left by what they say are insufficient rescue patrols by Europe's coastguards and navies.
On the weekend Italian media reported that prosecutors were investigating other leading humanitarian organisations - including Medecin Sans Frontieres (Doctors Without Borders) - over their role in rescuing migrants crossing the sea from Africa.Photo: ANSA/AP
In response, MSF said it would cooperate with prosecutors and hoped "any doubts can be dispelled soon to end this trickling of accusations that poisons the atmosphere in an ever gloomier situation".
The allegations against the NGOs include that they have entered Libyan waters to perform 'rescues' of migrants against maritime law.
On Sunday a far-right,  called Defend Europe claimed that Golfo Azurra, a boat run by Spanish NGO "Proactiva Open Arms", had " and took migrants onboard". 
Proactiva founder Oscar Camps - who has met with Pope Francis twice on the issue of immigration -  that this was slander, and accused Defend Europe of falsifying data, posting images of false boat positions, and making "threats by radio".
Earlier he said the group had "disrupted radio" while his group was carrying out a search for migrant boats.
Two weeks ago Camps Tweeted that "our AIS signal has been hacked to show we're in Libyan waters, but we're not", a claim that Italian magazine Famiglia Cristiana said it had verified with technicians from Marine Traffic, the digital hub that collects and publishes navigation data (the AIS signal includes the boat's GPS location).
Asked if Jugend Rettet had been the subject of a similar attack, Pahlke said "it's something that's at least very likely... something we need to consider".
He said his group's "first and most important rule" was not to enter Libyan territorial waters without permission from Rome's coastguard control centre.
Jugent Rettet is now focusing on getting their ship back in their possession and back into the search and rescue zone off the Libyan coast, Pahlke said.
"All the NGOs are still needed down there," he said. "What we are doing is the only possible answer to this misery."
Jugend Rettet translates as "youth rescues" - they are a group of 18-30 year old unpaid European volunteers who "don't want to see anyone dying at the European border because that does not belong to our perception of what Europe should stand for," Pahlke said.
"Our intention is to fill this [search and rescue] gap."
They have rescued around 14,000 people since they started operating a year ago.
"Every boat that's coming is an emergency," Pahlke said. "By the law of the sea if a boat cannot reach a safe port by its own and the situation cannot be improved with what's on board then it's an emergency and we need to rescue them - and that is the situation with all of the boats."
Italy has tried to impose a code of conduct on the NGOs to restrict their work, but some groups including MSF and Jugend Rettet refused to sign. Pahlke said they were willing to keep negotiating over the code, but as it was written it was inconsistent with international law, so they couldn't agree to it.
He also denied the NGO boats were acting as a "pull factor" for migrants and traffickers.
Picking up migrants close to Libya "leads traffickers to force even more migrants on to unseaworthy boats with insufficient water and fuel than in previous years". Fabrice Leggeri, head of the EU's border agency Frontex said in February.
However this view was challenged in March, by two academics from Oxford and UC Berkeley.
They looked at data on rescues and deaths at sea from previous years and  between the number of rescue vessels near Libya and the number of migrants arriving in Italy.
On the other hand there was a strong link between the number of rescue vessels and the number of deaths at sea.
"SAR (search and rescue) operations reduce mortality risks (or conversely, the absence of SAR operations leads to more deaths), and has little or no effect on the number of arrivals," the academics concluded.
Their research supported the NGOs' view that they were not contributing to the crisis by creating a "pull factor" - and they were saving lives.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golfo Azurra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camps Tweeted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Famiglia Cristiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARINE TRAFFIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frontex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope Francis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libya</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANSA/AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar Camps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UC-Berkeley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctors Without Borders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish NGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pahlke</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Proactiva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jugent Rettet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trapani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defend Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medecins Sans Frontieres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Pahlke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jugend Rettet</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Proactiva Open Arms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambrogio Cartosio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iuventa</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fabrice Leggeri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGOs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libyan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
