<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441133369149596</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/teams/port-adelaide/port-adelaide-coach-ken-hinkley-might-find-it-harder-to-change-his-lineup-even-with-a-healthy-list/news-story/07da71eff61544f1950b166abe884e1d</url>
  <title>Depth test for 'embarrassed' Power</title>
  <content>
Port Adelaide might be injury free this week with coach Ken Hinkley optimistic on the recovery of Chad Wingard and Matthew Broadbent from ankle sprains - but this does not guarantee a savage reaction at selection to the Showdown debacle.
Even Hinkley concedes the depth test at Alberton will prevent wholesale changes to deal with the worrying signs from the record 84-point loss to Adelaide in Showdown 43 at Adelaide Oval on Sunday.
"Typically what happens, you end up going away from similar names and bringing back in reasonably similar names," said Hinkley as preparation begins for Sunday's home clash with non-contender Collingwood at Adelaide Oval.

AFL: Listen in to the Port Adelaide Power post match press conference.

Power press conference
This is highlighted by the Power most probably dismissing Karl Amon from the midfield for Brendon AhChee but not a high-profile midfielder after Hinkley excused only Robbie Gray from the Showdown failure. Or small forward Jake Neade earning a recall at the expense of Aaron Young.
"Your depth is exposed now at this time of the year," Hinkley said. "You know your players who you think are possibly capable of helping you out. That's a few in, a few out - that's not wholesale. It can't be wholesale at this stage of the year.
"It's - get back to work, do what you are supposed to do and own your position better. And stand up."
Hinkley is most confident in Wingard, who sprained his left ankle in the third term of the loss to Melbourne at the MCG on July 22. He has missed two games.
"Chad was nearly right to play (in the Showdown)," Hinkley said.
Broadbent has missed four games in the past two months as he struggles to shake off an ankle injury suffered in training in mid-June. The Power continues to insist there is no need for surgery.
"We'll see how he trains," Hinkley said. "It was a bit of bone bruising, but this is not an injury that needs surgery - it needs recovery time. He has played a couple of times when he though the was right and it was the recovery after the performance has been the biggest problem."
michelangelo.rucci@news.com.au
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon AhChee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinkley</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Neade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Amon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
