<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441863513598793</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/expensive-tunnelling-will-be-used-to-build-north-east-link/8780314</url>
  <title>North-East Link: Route, tunnel options released for Melbourne's 'missing' roadway</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Expensive tunnelling will be used to build what has been called Victoria's highest-priority road project, Melbourne's missing North-East Link, regardless of which of four routes is chosen, the State Government says.
Four possible corridors to build a tolled link between Melbourne's Metropolitan Ring Road and the Eastern Freeway, or EastLink, have just been released by the Government.
The North-East Link Authority expects the new link would carry 100,000 vehicles a day.
Some of the route options cut through the marginal Labor held seats of Ivanhoe and Eltham, as well as Opposition Leader Matthew Guy's electorate of Bulleen.
The Government says the link is needed because Melbourne does not have a completed orbital road, which is constraining economic growth.
Twenty per cent of freight in Melbourne goes between the city's north and south-east, clogging Rosanna Road as a result.
Of the four options, route A - an 11-kilometre road and tunnel from Bulleen Road at the Eastern Freeway to Greensborough - has the most positive attributes, according to the authority's early work.
The authority said an above-ground road would cost $200-$300 million per kilometre, and tunnel cost between $800 million-$1 billion per kilometre.
Other corridor options include a 40-kilometre outer loop, and tunnels under Templestowe joining at EastLink.
The designs for the project in each corridor are yet to be finalised but the construction of any road is expected to take five to seven years.
'It has been talked about for too long'

The  and the authority has to choose a preferred corridor by the end of 2017.
Premier .
Mr Andrews said his Government expected to build the link for about $10 billion, but he was unable to say how much each corridor option would cost.
He stressed that Monday's announcement was just to highlight the corridor options.
"You have to think about what the cost is of us not building this," he said.
"It has been talked about for too long."
Ivanhoe MP Anthony Carbines said Rosanna Rd was congested between 5:00am-7:00pm, and that it was a "Berlin Wall" through his community.
"The community are going to support the option that lets them reclaim their streets," Mr Carbines said.
Eltham MP Vicki Ward agreed that the project was about helping the local communities.
"The north-east commutes are too long," Yan Yean MP Danielle Green said.
Information including mail-outs to residents, forums and a website will be set up to explain the four options.
Property acquisitions will be minimised but will occur, the authority said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Matthew Guy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham MP Vicki Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosanna Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulleen Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanhoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Freeway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Metropolitan Ring Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Carbines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanhoe MP Anthony Carbines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yan Yean MP Danielle Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Templestowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East Link</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREENSBOROUGH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East Link Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosanna Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulleen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
