<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441266513137161</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Broker</source>
  <url>http://www.brokernews.com.au/news/breaking-news/io-investors-slugged-with-73-basis-point-rise-239611.aspx</url>
  <title>IO investors slugged with 73 basis point rise</title>
  <content>
The average interest only investment loans with a variable rate have shot up by 73 basis points due to rate movements beginning last November.
These figures, from the latest Reserve Bank of Australia () Statement on Monetary Policy released on Thursday (3 August), reveal this increase was caused by a double whammy of rate rises in November and again in June.
"Since May, most lenders have increased their standard variable reference rates for interest-only loans by around 30 basis points and reduced standard variable rates for principal-and-interest loans to owner-occupiers by around five basis points," the  wrote.
The net effect of these changes alone has increased the outstanding variable rate by around five basis points since May, with a rise of 13 basis points since November.
However, the Reserve Bank also said the increase in the average rate for all outstanding loans is expected to be less than the five and 13 basis point change estimates for three reasons:

It is likely that some existing borrowers will switch their repayment terms from interest only to principal and interest

The lowest advertised variable interest rates for the majors and mid-sized lenders have not increased to the same extent as the reference rates

Interest rates for new fixed rate loans remain below those on maturing loans meaning that borrowers can roll over their loans as they mature for lower rates

The average fixed and variable rates, as well as the associated changes since November, are listed below:
 

 
Interest rate
Change since Nov 2016

Variable P&I rate
 
 

Owner occupier
4.41%
-4 basis points

Investor
4.98%
+29 basis points

Variable IO rate
 
 

Owner occupier
4.98%
+52 basis points

Investor
5.46%
+73 basis points

Fixed P&I rate
 
 

Owner occupier
4.14%
+3 basis points

Investor
4.45%
+20 basis points

Average outstanding rate
4.63%
+13 basis points

The  also flagged a number of uncertainties to watch out for when making housing market predictions in the future.
"The risk of more weakness in apartment prices in some locations where a large amount of supply is coming online remains. This could mean that buildings approved but not commenced do not go ahead, in which case dwelling investment and related household spending would be weaker than expected."
Decreasing house prices could also spell trouble for some apartment developers, the  added.
"Recent state and federal budget measures intended to restrain foreign investment have not yet had time to have had their full effects, which are uncertain; however, the effects are likely to be largest in housing markets where foreign buyers have been most active, particularly inner-city apartments."
Related stories:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday 3 August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nov-2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
