<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441962297848118</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:22</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/man-charged-after-cars-vandalised-with-acid-at-macquarie-university-and-centre-20170807-gxqm9a.html</url>
  <title>Man charged after cars vandalised with acid at Macquarie University and Centre </title>
  <content>
﻿
Police have charged a man over alleged acid attacks on cars parked at a university and a shopping centre in Sydney's north west.
The 53-year-old allegedly poured an acid-like substance on cars at Macquarie University and the Macquarie Centre between February and June.
Officers arrested the man at a home in Ryde and took him to Ryde police station where he was charged with 16 counts of malicious damage.
Examination of the cars found that an acid-like substance had allegedly been poured on them, causing the paint to be stripped from the affected areas.
The man has been granted bail and is scheduled to appear at Burwood Local Court on August 21.

Police were alerted to the alleged vandalism earlier this year after drivers shared their experiences on a Chinese-language forum before setting up a support group on the Chinese social media platform WeChat.
The alleged incidents were reported to Macquarie University and the Macquarie Centre and police from the Ryde Local Area Command commenced an investigation.
A police spokeswoman said a number of cars were allegedly damaged with the substance over a four-month period.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryde Local Area Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WeChat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burwood Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese-language</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
