<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441824858892632</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/nathan-brown-takes-down-a-player-from-every-afl-club/news-story/56f94dc09e3ffba882dd29010a46ca9c</url>
  <title>'With a head like that, I'd take tails'</title>
  <content>
THE great thing about retirement is you can generally say whatever you want about the current crop of stars without worrying about getting punched in the face.
The AFL has cracked down on striking this year but we still reckon former Western Bulldogs and Richmond gun Nathan Brown would be in grave danger if the one-liners he threw out on radio on the weekend were ever uttered on the playing field.
Commentating for Triple M on Sunday, Brown - who retired in 2009 after playing 219 career games - was given the task by his fellow broadcasters of sledging one player from each of the 18 AFL clubs. And didn't he enjoy it.
Here are some of (what we believe are) his best wisecracks. The full list can be found on the .
Carlton: Dale Thomas - "The only man that's paid $47,000 a possession."
Already the victim of a that bagged him for getting dropped to the VFL, former Collingwood golden boy Thomas has struggled with form and injury since joining Carlton in 2014 on a $3.5 million deal.
Collingwood: Chris Mayne - "With a head like that, I'd take tails."
Probably a fair call by Brown based on the photo below.

Melbourne: Clayton Oliver - "Did he sneeze into a Milo tin this morning?"
Every kid who grew up with freckles has been the subject of ridicule at least once.
North Melbourne: Ryan Clarke - "NASA's come calling, they're looking for a new place to land a rocket and your forehead looks great."
We're surprised Brown didn't refer to the ample real estate available on Clarke's noggin as a "fivehead".

Port Adelaide: Tom Jonas - "Old Tommy Jonas has been complaining that commentators don't get his name right. That's because we don't give a s***."
Writing a  has come back to haunt the Port star.
Richmond: Alex Rance - "He met his girlfriend at 16 and he's been with her the whole time, I'd say you've wasted your talents all these years. You're an extremely good looking man, it's a waste."
An All-Australian lock and an objectively good looking rooster to boot, plenty of women would like to get their hands on the Richmond defender.

West Coast: Sam Butler - "You're the only premiership Eagle and no bastard's ever heard of you."
Very harsh for a veteran who has a premiership medal from West Coast's 2006 triumph over Sydney.
Western Bulldogs: Robert Murphy - "I'd be reminding Bob Murphy no matter how many times you watch that vision of yourself on the dais you didn't win a premiership."
Coach Luke Beveridge melted hearts when he gave injured skipper Bob Murphy his premiership medal after the Dogs won the 2016 grand final. But it's impossible to melt hearts made of stone.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Rance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast's 2006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Jonas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Tommy Jonas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Butler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Mayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
