<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441348117516616</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/simon-rodman-believed-to-be-first-australian-with-bionic-ear-to-gain-a-commercial-pilots-licence/news-story/eee982b66a0fed3b4549afc53f79a6eb</url>
  <title>Rodman's career really taking off</title>
  <content>
THE sky is far from the limit for Simon Rodman.
Mr Rodman, 23, is believed to be the first person with a bionic ear in Australia to gain a commercial pilot's -licence.
He achieved the milestone late last month after 250 hours in the air.
"It took a long time and was pretty expensive. It feels good to have got there," Mr Rodman said.
He was first introduced to flying in Year 9 at Mt Eliza's Peninsula Grammar.
"We had six lessons and that's what really kicked things off for me," he said.
Mr Rodman went on to attain his private pilot's licence in 2014, completing most of his training at Tyabb's Peninsula Aero Club.
"Back then I really hadn't thought about flying as a career," he said. "After I got my private licence and spent more time flying, I realised I wanted to do it professionally."
Now that he has qualified for a commercial licence, he is able to look for work in that field. "The next step will be finding a job - that might be a bit harder for me. I'm not sure how potential employers will feel about taking on a pilot with a hearing aid," he said. "I can hear crystal clear with the implant, I've passed the medical and I have been approved by CASA (Civil Aviation Safety Authority).
"It will come down to perceptions, I guess."
Civil Aviation Safety Authority spokesman Peter Gibson said he hadn't heard of an other person with bionic ear in Australia who had obtained a commercial pilot's licence.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Rodman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyabb's Peninsula Aero Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rodman, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civil Aviation Safety Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rodman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CASA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Eliza's Peninsula Grammar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
