<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440871376140944</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/health-and-wellbeing/nutrition/mediterranean-diet-only-works-for-the-wealthy-20170804-gxpnn0.html</url>
  <title>New research suggests the Mediterranean diet only works for the wealthy</title>
  <content>
It is ironic that it was once known as the "". New research has found that the Mediterranean diet works, but only for the wealthy. 
The tiny, volcanic Italian , off the coast of Sicily exemplifies the traditional primarily plant-based diet.Photo: William Meppem
People grow their own vegetables and deliciously ripe fruit including oranges, peaches, figs and apricots. They eat locally caught fish (and eat little red meat), drink wine, eat almonds and pistachios, wholegrain pastas, sourdough breads and flavour dishes with olive oil, capers and fresh herbs as well as some fermented dairy (yoghurt or cheese). 
From obesity and longevity experts to researchers in gut, heart and brain health, the traditional Mediterranean diet is consistently regarded .Photo: Stocksy
For the new study, published in the journal International Journal of Epidemiology, Italian researchers wanted to explore whether the cardiovascular benefits associated with the diet differed across socio-economic groups.
Over a four-year period, they studied 18,000 people looking at how well they adhered to the diet as well as their education levels and earnings.

After adjusting for variables, they found that the diet reduced the risk of heart disease by 15 per cent - but only among those who earned more than about $60,000 a year. There was no reduced risk for those on lower incomes.
On further examination, they discovered that those who earned more tended to eat a greater variety of fruits and vegetables as well as more whole grains and fish but less red meat and dairy. They also tended to choose more organic foods, which contain "concentrations of antioxidants, lower concentrations of cadmium and a lower incidence of pesticide residues". 
"People with high income or higher educational level consumed products richer in antioxidants and polyphenols, and had a greater diversity in fruit and vegetables choice," said researcher Licia Iacoviello. "We have also found a socioeconomic gradient in the consumption of whole-grain products and in the preferred cooking methods. These substantial differences in consuming products belonging to Mediterranean diet lead us to think that quality of foods may be as important for health as quantity and frequency of intake."
Dietitian Melanie McGrice calls the research "fascinating". 
"We've certainly known for a long time that socio-economic status impacts health, and this is another reason for this divide," McGrice says. "I agree that the quality of the food that we eat impacts our health. There's a significant difference in eating a home-grown apple to one that has been kept in cold storage for months." 
 Although these foods are accessible and cheap to grow somewhere like Pantelleria, they are often expensive and less accessible for others.
"It is not uncommon for foods such as oily fish (e.g. salmon), nuts and a variety of nutrient-dense produce to come at a cost, and therefore I am not so surprised at these findings," says dietitian Kara Landau.
While there may be inequality, even within one diet, there are ways people on a tight budget can increase the quality of their diet.  
"I'd recommend growing as many of your own vegies as possible," McGrice suggests. "That gives you access to nutritious, high-quality foods at a comparatively low cost.  Sharing resources is another good trick.  Foods are also cheaper when purchased in bulk, so organise a group with your local friends and share produce."
Landau adds that seasonal produce contains greater nutrients and tends to be more affordable.
"Purchasing communally so that costs are dispersed amongst families but variety is maintained [is another option], as well as selecting nutrient-dense legumes and lentils that are usually more cost effective than other protein sources and also are able to provide beneficial prebiotic fibres, antioxidants and polyphenols."
It's an unfair problem, one the Italian researchers would like health authorities to consider. In the meantime, Landau insists we can minimise the disparity: "There are certainly ways of enhancing the nutrient density of your diet on a budget to mitigate these variances."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pantelleria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melanie McGrice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kara Landau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrice</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sicily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Journal of Epidemiology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Licia Iacoviello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WILLIAM MEPPEM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
