<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441086124508564</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/north-east-link-lungs-versus-lanes-as-residents-rally-against-highway-route-options-20170806-gxqdmu.html</url>
  <title>North East Link: 'lungs' versus lanes as residents rally against highway route options </title>
  <content>
The mayor of a council with large tracts of green-wedge parkland in Melbourne's north-east says his shire and its residents will fight any environmentally destructive route for a highway proposed by the Andrews government through suburbs like Eltham and Warrandyte.
The government is on Monday expected to release route options for its next multi-billion-dollar road project - the North East Link, a six-lane motorway to link the Metropolitan Ring Road in Greensborough to either the Eastern Freeway or EastLink.Photo: Luis Ascui
The road has been discussed for decades, but with no land set aside for it, its likely environmental impacts have seen successive governments put it in the too-hard basket.
Potential routes identified under a new study for the road have price tags ranging from $8 billion to $16 billion - almost triple the cost of any road ever proposed for Melbourne before.Photo: North East Link Authority

MAP: The government in 2009 released the above route options for the road. It is expected to release fresh options on Monday.

The government's North East Link Authority will go to Greensborough on Monday to brief community groups on its engineering assessments.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The government has  indicating the routes being assessed. Geo-technical drilling has been done in suburbs including Greensborough, Ringwood, Warrandyte, Heidelberg, Lilydale, Donvale and Eltham.
Nillumbik Council mayor Peter Clarke said any route that went through Eltham, Warrandyte and areas around Kangaroo Ground should be immediately ruled out.
Roads Minister Luke Donnellan did not rule out going through green-wedge areas when asked about this on Sunday. The government had promised to explore all options for the tollroad, he said. "And that's exactly what we're doing."
Cr Clarke said he had been briefed by government officers that a route for the road through green wedge areas would, as well as having a big environmental impact, cost up to $16 billion. "An open-cut freeway across Melbourne's green wedge would be environmental vandalism," he said.
He said building options that avoided these areas would be "substantially cheaper, approximately half the cost of destroying the green wedge", and would travel largely along existing major routes or power line reserves.
The "missing link" to the north east has been identified as an infrastructure priority: the city's north has seen a massive growth in population, and many roads to the outer suburbs are badly clogged during the morning and afternoon.
One group vowing to fight the road coming through its area is the Eltham Community Action Group. Spokesman John Graves is an engineer who worked for VicRoads for 34 years before retiring in 2012.
Mr Graves, also a former mayor of the Eltham area, said it was crucial no freeway cut through green-wedge areas.
"If the North East Link cuts [through] the green wedge, the pressure on increasing development will be very strong," he said. "In effect the size of the green wedge and its capacity to continue as the 'lungs' of Melbourne would be diminished or destroyed."
A six-lane freeway feeding into the Eltham area's "undulating two-lane roads" would make traffic even worse than its current dire situation, he added. 
Opposition roads spokesman Ryan Smith said the North East Link, while an important project, would place even more traffic onto the Eastern Freeway - making the dumped East West Link tollroad even more crucial.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nillumbik Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham Community Action Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geo-technical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East-West Link</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lilydale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roads Minister Luke Donnellan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Freeway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Ground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Ascui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Graves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrandyte</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East Link</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREENSBOROUGH</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Graves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East Link Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan Ring Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
