<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441696009872245</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/north/teddy-shrine-created-to-mourn-lost-toys-and-prompt-brisbane-city-council-to-fix-pothole-at-deagon/news-story/e449b149d145818de5a0688744859ffd</url>
  <title>Pothole no laughing matter ... or is it?</title>
  <content>
LOOKING at the funny side of life has paid off for these residents.
Tired of a recurring pothole in their street at Deagon, in Brisbane's north, the group took to humour to address the issue.
A "teddy bear shrine" was erected at the corner of Sarah and Bungama streets at Deagon to honour a group of stuffed toys they said had plummeted into hole, never to be seen again.
The concept was that of resident John Wall, who decided humour might catch the attention of Brisbane City Council.
"(It is a) humorous protest by residents to say to council, 'hey come fix this'," Mr Wall said.
He said the 30cm deep hole, which opens directly into a storm water culvert, had been a recurring issue for the past two years.
He said the hole had been repaired last year but returned around Christmas.
Residents had initially placed a traffic cone over the hole to prevent cyclists, skateboarders and cars driving into it.
Not long after, the council placed a removable A-frame over the hole.
Mr Wall said months then passed with no further action, and so the shrine was created.
"(It's a reminder that) things that seem small to them ... are big to us.
"It's quite dangerous," he said.
The stretch of road along Bungamar St makes up part of the Moreton Bay Cycleway.
Resident Linda Harrod-Eagles said the deep hole was dangerous to those who travelled along the cycleway.
"It's clearly a safety risk," Ms Harrod-Eagles said.
Northside Chronicle contacted Brisbane City Council about the situation and a spokesman said the hole would be repaired within the week.
"The hole was created by a damaged stormwater pipe below the road surface," the spokesman said.
"This needed to be repaired before the pothole could be filled."
The spokesman later confirmed the pothole had been repaired.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bungamar St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay Cycleway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deagon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bungama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Harrod-Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chronicle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Harrod-Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
