<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441992362619709</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/network-denies-axing-tim-allens-popular-sitcom-over-trump-support/news-story/a75270ddab5af8ef18402a0231d120e2</url>
  <title>Network denies axing Tim Allen's popular sitcom over Trump support</title>
  <content>
Tim Allen Reveals Why He's Jealous Of Tom Hanks
1:40

Tim Allen is super jealous of Tom Hanks. That is, when it comes to how many lines Hanks has in the 'Toy Story' movies.

November 26th 2014
3 years ago
/video/video.news.com.au/News/

Tim Allen's high-rating sitcom Last Man Standing has been cancelled. Picture: GETTY

AFPAFP

Share

US television network ABC has denied that it cancelled comedian Tim Allen's popular sitcom Last Man Standing due to its conservative politics.
Fans of the show - and Allen himself - were angered when ABC announced in May that one of its most-watched scripted series, a solid ratings draw, was being brought to an end.
Allen's character, an outspoken conservative, echoed the political positions of the 64-year-old actor, a Republican who attended President Donald Trump's inauguration.
The announcement sparked a firestorm of criticism on social media, with Allen tweeting that he had been "stunned and blindsided" by Disney-owned ABC's decision.
Stunned and blindsided by the network I called home for the last six years.
Meanwhile a petition on Change.org that attracted more than 300,000 signatures claimed the comedy was cancelled because it was the only entertainment program that was not constantly shoving "liberal ideals down the throats of the viewers."
"Politics had absolutely nothing to do with it," ABC Entertainment president Channing Dungey told the Television Critics Association press tour in Los Angeles.

Tim Allen and Nancy Travis in a scene from Last Man Standing.Source:Supplied
"We have actors on our shows who have all sorts of political views. Tim Allen is a valuable part of the Disney family and has been for a very long time." She described Last Man Standing as a "high quality show" but added that the network had not been able to find room in the schedules for a seventh season.
A month before the cancellation Allen had spoken about Trump's inauguration on late-night talk show Jimmy Kimmel Live, saying that he was "almost afraid" to say he had been at the event.
"You gotta be real careful around here," . "You get beat up if you don't believe what everybody else believes. This is like '30s Germany."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Man Standing</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Allen Reveals Why He</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney-owned ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jealous Of Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Television Critics Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hanks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Man Standing.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Kimmel Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toy Story</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nancy Travis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Allen</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channing Dungey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFPAFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
