<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440884261043069</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/grant-hackett-enjoys-quiet-night-town/3209451/</url>
  <title>Grant Hackett enjoys 'soft' night on the town</title>
  <content>
OLYMPIC swimming champion Grant Hackett has enjoyed a Gold Coast night out with none of the drama which has plagued him of late.

The trouble-prone three-time Olympic gold medallist, whose most recent meltdown led to his arrest five months ago, seemed back in a good head space at Broadbeach on Saturday night.

He was spotted relaxing with friends at The Star casino complex's Garden Bar around midnight.

Gold Coast teacher Rebecca Lachmund said one of her friends introduced herself to Hackett and his group of "tall swimming mates" before they mingled with his pals at the bar.

"I was a bit starstruck and freaked out a little," she said, but added Hackett and his mates - including fellow Aussie swim stars Cam McEvoy and Ky Hurst - were very easygoing.

"He just seemed like a great guy. He seemed happy, he wasn't drunk, just chilling.

"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."

A fresh and healthy looking Hackett happily posed for snaps.

A friend close to his group later said Hackett was "just on the soft drinks" and had enjoyed heading out with his pals.

It was a far cry from February when arrested at the Gold Coast home of his parents, who were forced to ring police due to concerns about his erratic behaviour.

He was taken into custody but released without charge.

Around that time he publicised a photo of his battered face, and recently revealed to KIIS 1065's Kyle and Jackie O radio show it resulted from an "intervention" by his brother Craig.

"I wasn't in a good space for a couple of months and he came over to my house and I was refusing that help.

"He wanted to come in. I was trying to push him out and we got into a push-and-shove and he whacked me with his weak arm. We were both very regretful of the situation," Hackett told the show in June.

Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
"I then said, 'Hey Ryan' ... (and he) started to run."
Teen suffered head and shoulder injuries from the accident
Crash causes nightmare for Sunday drivers on Bruce Hwy
Upcoming shows target tastes from Shakespeare to Ten Tenors
There's a live music gig to suit all music tastes in our Gig Guide
Get off the couch and get social with our 10 Things To Do
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Fiery larrikin Peter FitzSimons had the audience in stitches.
What The Health slammed by experts
Former newsreader Tracey Spicer bares all for autobiography.
Nearly 4000 people attend concert at stadium
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbeach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Hackett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Lachmund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackett</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Tenors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KIIS 1065</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garden Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ky Hurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
