<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440922915749449</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-league/nathan-brown-challenges-nrl-to-do-the-right-thing-with-clubs-over-salary-cap-20170806-gxqa9c.html</url>
  <title>Brown challenges NRL to 'do the right thing'</title>
  <content>
Outspoken Newcastle coach Nathan Brown has dared the NRL to "do the right thing" and force clubs who have overspent the yet-to-be-confirmed salary cap to shed players. Brown suggests teams who have overspent as a result of uncertainty over the exact cap for next year are just using it as an excuse for their recklessness.
"Everyone got the email saying you have to work off 9.1 million and if you don't it's your responsibility," Brown told Triple M on Sunday. "Some went over it and took a chance ... some like us stayed under it in the hope that players would come along. Let's hope our friends at the NRL hold their nerve and make them go under it and don't allow something like a grandfather rule. Those that put the market into a spin have to pay the price."

Up Next

Bolt defeated by Gatlin in final 100m race

00:23

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Rare two-in-a-row for the Knights

Brock Lamb starred for Newcastle, with fan favourite Nathan Ross failing to finish the game with a suspected fractured back in Round 22 against the New Zealand Warriors.

He confirmed the Knights were 'certainly looking at clubs who are rumoured to be over the cap' in their recruitment plans. "We had some interest in James Graham some time ago but he wanted to stay at Canterbury and they didn't want to let him go. If the NRL do the right thing and make them go under the cap, then they might have to let a player go."
2. When beards were beards
Another week, another non-send-off. Former Australian Test stars Brad Fittler and Andrew Johns used entertaining language in their assessment of whether Newcastle's Chanel Matautia should have been dismissed for clearly tripping Warrior Mason Lino at McDonald Jones Stadium on Saturday.
"We've cleaned up the game so much," Johns said on Channel Nine, "but back when men were men and beards were beards, back in the 1980s you got sent off for that. It's a send-off. Back in the wild west you got sent for that."

Fittler added: "You can't protect yourself from that, you can't protect yourself from a trip. He should be off."

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Discussing the NRL referees' boss, 'Freddie' added: "If Tony Archer gets through this unscathed, he's doing well. I'm not sure how he can get out of this."Photo: AAP
3. The gate of Mt Smart Stadium is this way
Sometimes we get so used to cliches and platitudes in the NRL that we don't recognise a bunch of fantastic quotes when they hit us in the face. Once more, with feeling, these gems from Stephen Kearney on Saturday: "There were some guys out there who were trying really hard, there were some guys that weren't. There was some effort from some individuals but there was some effort from others that would be very questionable. I just don't think we played with enough conviction. The idea is to get some players in there who know that. If individuals aren't getting that done, I'll have to get some new ones in there. There's things that have probably let slip in the last while and that's what happens when you take your eye off the ball. We'll be addressing that."
Taking into account an item in last week's Set Of Six, it seems we can fairly expect some players to be "walked to the front gate" at Mt Smart this week.

Will he or won't he play the World Cup? Brisbane five-eighth Anthony Milford.

4. Milford confusion
It seems that almost every time Anthony Milford gets the ball, a commentator tells us his shoulder "could go at any time" and he  "needs end-of-season surgery". Thus, we assume he is out of the World Cup; it's that old Bennett-Milford-Samoa thing again.
But alas, no, according to Samoa coach Matt Parish. Asked if Milford had advised him of his unavailability, Parish told us by text: "Not at all. He thinks he'll be right. I'll obviously pick him if Australia doesn't."
Are we headed for another showdown over Milford? If he's fit enough to run rampant in a 54-0 victory, he's fit enough for a World Cup. In other news, Paul Gallen on Sports Sunday yesterday on Sonny Bill Williams: "I heard rumours the Roosters, if he was not playing, would name him anyway because of the amount of people he'd bring in, who'd come to the game."
5. Goodwin gone, regardless
South Sydney fans are sad to see winger Bryson Goodwin - scorer of the match-equalling try on Friday - go and some hold out hope that if his intended English club, Leigh, are relegated he might stay. Leigh are currently in The Qualifiers, involving the bottom four clubs in Super League and the top four from the Championship, to determine who goes up in 2018.
"I think they'll be all right," Goodwin told me on Friday night at fulltime. "They've got a really good squad; hopefully they do really well and stay in the Super League." Leigh beat Featherstone 38-12 on Saturday night. Pressed on whether his deal was binding regardless, Goodwin answered: "Yeah, yeah. I'll be still going."
6. Big blow for Scotland
Further evidence that the rugby league Gods move in mysterious ways. Within hours of Scotland naming their World Cup train-on squad, prop Adam Walker tested positive to cocaine and was stood down and teenager Campbell Graham made his debut for South Sydney. Graham has two Scottish parents and was immediately called up.
"It might be a bit early for him - I'll tell him to sit out when they play England," joked Sam Burgess. The youngster had been given the week off training to focus on his trial HSC only to be called up at 11am after a knee injury to Robert Jennings. On a similar theme, did the Sky commentary team really say Rangi Chase's cocaine positive was "a big blow to him"?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Smart Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Milford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rangi Chase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrior Mason Lino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Kearney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Parish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryson Goodwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Gallen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Archer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Smart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonny Bill Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle's Chanel Matautia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Fittler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fittler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett-Milford-Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Set Of Six</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
