<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441395362157445</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/game-of-thrones-historic-parallels-2017-7</url>
  <title>[SPOILERS] 5 times 'Game of Thrones' based schemes, massacres, and battles on real moments in history</title>
  <content>
The Red Wedding  fans, and will likely be remembered as  to ever grace television.

A strikingly similar attack took place in Ireland in 1574.

An Irish chieftain named Sir Brian mac Felim O Neill ruled over the kingdom of Clannabuidhe and had previously been knighted by the English Crown. When he lost the Queen's favour, he began to fight against the English invaders. Eventually, however, he invited Walter Devereux, the Earl of Essex, to his castle to discuss peace terms over a Christmas feast, according to Wayne E. Lee's '.'

At the Earl's signal, Sir Brian, his wife, and the rest of his family were seized, while 200 of their followers were indiscriminately slaughtered.

Sir Brian O Neill and his family were all subsequently executed.

A similar situation occurred in Scotland, during the 1692 Massacre of Glencoe.

Captain Robert Campbell and 120 of his men were given hospitality at Clan MacDonalds' castle. After two weeks, a message arrived ordering Campbell to attack, .

One winter's night, the soldiers played cards with their victims and bid them pleasant dreams, as usual. Then they massacred all the MacDonald men they could find, including the chief.

Another Red Wedding-esque incident -- the similarly-named Black Dinner -- went down in Scotland in 1440. Advisers of the 10-year-old King James II grew concerned that Clan Douglas was growing too bold and powerful, .

These advisers invited the 16-year-old Earl of Douglas and his younger brother to come over to Edinburgh Castle. The king and the Douglases had an enjoyable time. Nothing seemed amiss.

Then, at the end of the dinner, the severed head of a bull -- a symbol of Clan Douglas -- was tossed on the table. Like the 'Rains of Castamere' at the Red Wedding, this was the signal. Much to the young king's horror, his two friends were dragged outside, put through a mock trial, and decapitated.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MacDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPOILERS] 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Devereux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edinburgh Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clan Douglas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Douglases</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earl of Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earl of Essex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clan MacDonalds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Dinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Wedding-esque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Brian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Brian O Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne E. Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rains of Castamere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Wedding</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massacre of Glencoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felim O Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King James II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clannabuidhe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
