<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441438311831093</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/world/strippers-on-good-samaritan-murder-charge/news-story/cbe64033480c9d2667345051d0def310</url>
  <title>Strippers 'shot' good Samaritan</title>
  <content>
FOUR strippers were busted for the slaying of a good Samaritan who helped the dancers change a flat tyre, Missouri police said.
Ralph Cross, 55, was found - shot in the back - inside his home in Wilson City in the far southeast corner of Missouri this past Monday, according to officials, The New York Post reports.
Brittany Curry, 28, Ponesha Taylor, 23, Johniesha Simmons, 19, and Lauteshia Dotson, 23, were all booked on suspicion of first-degree murder, armed criminal action and unlawful use of a weapon.
Cross had purportedly gone so far as to purchase a new tyre for the alleged femme fatales, and let them lounge in his home as he serviced their vehicle.
After killing Cross, the ladies then allegedly camped out in his home - with his decaying body - until the corpse was discovered, said cops.
Curry pulled the trigger on Cross, CBS-affiliate KFVS 12 reported, citing Acting Mississippi County Sheriff Branden Caid. Caid contends the women robbed Cross before killing him, as his pockets had been turned out and his home appeared ransacked.
A witness told cops he saw the victim arguing with three of the women, while the fourth sat in a white vehicle parked just outside his home.
The same, unnamed, witness, said they overheard one of the women Cross was "tripping and do not go back down there," according to the report.
The women later turned themselves in, and are being held without bail. None have admitted to taking part in the crime.
This story appeared in and has been republished with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acting Mississippi County Sheriff Branden Caid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS-affiliate KFVS 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samaritans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brittany Curry, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauteshia Dotson, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ralph Cross, 55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missouri</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ponesha Taylor, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johniesha Simmons, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
