<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441691714904916</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/07/10/08/family-to-sue-after-wheelchair-fell-over</url>
  <title>Family of special needs girl to sue after improperly secured wheelchair fell in bus</title>
  <content>
The family of a special needs girl who fell over in her wheelchair while on a school bus in Georgia, USA is suing the local distract for $17.656 million.
April Moore said her 16-year-old daughter Jonay Owens cut her face when she fells last September on the bus ride home from school, according to reports from US media.
A video captured the moment the student fell, with it taking three minutes before either the bus monitor or driver came to check on her.
Owens reportedly cannot call for help because she is nonverbal. She is also blind and has cerebral palsy.
The family's attorney is alleging the staff did not properly secure her seat.
They have alleged the mother was never directly notified of the incident, with the driver and aide only telling her caregiver of a "minor incident".
"When I saw the video, I broke down in tears knowing my baby needed me and I wasn't there. And for them to just sit and do nothing hurts my heart," the mother said in a statement obtained by .

Related Articles

The statement also announced potential legal action against the school district.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonay Owens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
