<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440879966075697</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/music/audience-member-faints-and-others-walk-out-during-confronting-sydney-play-dry-land/news-story/abfaebdf68efcbf1224ec1e01042c143</url>
  <title>Graphic Sydney play causes fainting, walk outs</title>
  <content>
SYDNEY'S theatre scene is abuzz about Dry Land, a confronting play which some audience members find too intense to endure.
From the new darling of Broadway, US writer Ruby Rae Spiegel, Dry Land which is currently playing at King's Cross Theatre, follows an young aspiring swimmer's unwanted pregnancy.
At this week's Aussie premier one audience member fainted during a scene where a home abortion is acted out, while the lead actor Patricia Pemberton revealed several other people have walked out of the theatre during the confronting scene.
"It is quite intense ... It is a life altering situation at such a young age," Pemberton said.
"I have had a few people saying they felt a little ill from the top of the play does open on a heavy scene.
"We have had a few people who have had to leave."
Despite this, Pemberton, 23, is adamant the play does not intend to shock.
"The play isn't designed to shock the audiences, but I think that does say a lot about society," she said.
Samantha Meacham who plays opposite Pemberton said while the issues are confronting, she felt it was an important story to tell.
"The play deals with a whole lot of issues, a lot of issues about identity with young girls," she said.
"It is definitely tough, but it is important to understand how dire their situation is."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruby Rae Spiegel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pemberton, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pemberton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Pemberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Cross Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dry Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Meacham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
