<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441476966537453</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/teams/tigers/young-fan-left-in-tears-after-meeting-his-nrl-hero-james-tedesco/news-story/afd930bf3afa55ad57677f5855fefdaf</url>
  <title>Boy in tears after encounter with NRL star</title>
  <content>
THIS is the heartwarming story of a young NRL fan, a footy star and his shiny pink boots.
The Tigers may have lost to the Panthers on Sunday afternoon but the emotional reaction from a small fan after meeting his idol, fullback James Tedesco, has won the hearts of league lovers all over.
For Tigers fanatic Ashton, just meeting his hero Tedesco would have been enough to make his dreams come true.
But a generous gesture from the star fullback gave this little supporter a day out at the footy he won't soon forget.
After posing for photos, the Blues number one handed over a pair of personalised pink football boots to Ashton.
The encounter left young Ashton in tears, who was overwhelmed by experience.
Tedesco's boots have become Ashton's most prized possession, even taking them to bed with him.
His family took to social media to thank Tedesco for his kindness and express their gratitude.
"Our little man's face was priceless, the reaction from him and everyone in the moment was all but amazing. Thank you James Tedesco for making my little man's dreams come true".

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tedesco</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Tedesco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
