<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441391067190040</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/markets-live/markets-live-bright-start-ahead-for-asx-20170806-gxqju6.html</url>
  <title>Markets Live: Bright start ahead for ASX</title>
  <content>
More records on Wall St set an upbeat background for investors this week, but the accelerating flow of news from reporting season will ultimately set the tone on the ASX.

The Dow powered higher for an eighth consecutive day on Friday as positive economic news strengthened the US Federal Reserve's bias toward tighter monetary policy and the Trump administration revived chatter about tax reform.

The benchmark 30-member index rose 0.3 per cent, extending its record-setting streak and an advance above the 22,000-point mark.

At home, the August profit reporting season ramps up in the week ahead with around 20 major companies reporting, providing plenty of news for shareholders to chew over. Highlights include hearing implants maker Cochlear on Tuesday, Commonwealth Bank, James Hardie and Carsales on Wednesday, and then on Thursday there are reports from AMP, packaging company Orora and AGL Energy.

"As always, in a low interest rate world dividends will be a key focus," AMP Capital head of investment strategy Shane Oliver said. "But the key to watch will be outlook statements, as the current financial year won't have a repeat of the huge boost in commodity prices to resources profits".

Profits over the 2017 financial year are expected to have jumped by around 18 per cent, driven by a more than doubling in earnings for the listed resources sector as commodity prices rebounded from their 2016 lows. Elsewhere, profit growth remains subdued at around 5.5 per cent, on AMP Capital estimates.

"The challenge is that the good news with regard to strong mining sector profits - owing to last year's iron-ore price surge - appears largely priced in, while non-mining results are likely to be patchy, reflecting subdued growth, a high Australian dollar and intense competition," BetaShares chief economist David Bassanese said.
Good morning and welcome to the Markets Live blog for Monday.

Your editors today are Jens Meyer and Patrick Commins.

This blog is not intended as investment advice.

Fairfax Media with wires.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BetaShares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bassanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markets Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hardie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Commins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP Capital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jens Meyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CarSales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
