<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440871376140968</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/condiment-tray-thief-who-boasted-of-her-crime-on-facebook-named-dumbest-defendant-of-the-day-in-darwin-local-court/news-story/e5cfb726724a6b35edcc2a676531c6d2</url>
  <title>McThief posted crime on Facebook</title>
  <content>
THE "dumbest" defendant of the day in Darwin Local Court stole a condiments tray from McDonald's on Smith St after a night on the sauce with mates, before boasting of her crime on Facebook.
Kyara Blazely, 18, pleaded guilty to a single count of stealing, committed in the early hours of March 26.
Prosecutor Sarah Day said Blazely ordered and paid for a meal at the restaurant but took off with the $72.30 condiment tray.
The theft was caught on security cameras and a staff member from the restaurant came across Blazely's Facebook post - since deleted - showing the tray, with the caption "I stole a tray of sugar from McDonald's".
"At no time did the staff give the defendant permission to steal the condiment tray," Ms Day said.
"It was probably just a mistake, but she obviously regrets it now."
A contrite Blazely returned the ill-gotten condiment tray to the Darwin police station several days later, undamaged, and did not have to pay restitution to the multinational restaurant chain.
The court heard Blazely willingly took part in a police interview, where she fessed up to her crime and identified herself on store security footage.
Judge Elizabeth Morris said to Blazely, "You certainly win the prize for dumbest defendant today, having a photo on Facebook of you and the tray and saying 'I stole a tray'."
A sheepish Blazely, supported in court by a friend, agreed when Ms Morris said, "it was obviously a spur of the moment thing".
Blazely nodded again when asked, "So you'd been out with your friends?"
"It was a really foolish thing to do," Ms Morris said.
"Although the tray was not very expensive it's still something that didn't belong to you."
Ms Morris said Blazely "had the embarrassment ... of going into the police station and fessing up that it was you".
She said Blazely, who had just turned 18, was "not someone who's experienced at this kind of thing" and who had good prospects of rehabilitation.
Blazely walked from court with no conviction but will have to pay a $150 victim impact levy.
Blazely told the court she has been back to McDonald's several times since the theft.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blazely, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McThief</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Elizabeth Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Morris</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blazely's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blazely</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
