<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441863513598816</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/technology/donald-trump-is-broadcasting-his-own-news-bulletin-with-former-cnn-commentator-and-publishing-it-on-facebook/news-story/beae95621fffa184c5994e1ce9a86c16</url>
  <title>'Goodbye America, hello North Korea'</title>
  <content>
DONALD Trump's war on so-called "fake news" has what could be described as its first defector.
Former CNN commentator Kayleigh McEnany quit her role as a talking head on the news network over the weekend and just a day later appeared in her new role delivering the "real news" on Trump's Facebook page.
Fed up with the TV news, the Don is producing his own.
The outspoken Trump supporter teased her new role on Twitter before appearing in the low budget video this morning which was reportedly broadcast from the Trump Tower - prompting some to describe her new role as tantamount to being the president's chief propagandist.
The video starts out by spruiking the economic achievements of the new president - despite his inability to achieve any notable legislative reforms.
"President Trump has clearly steered the economy back in the right direction," Ms McEnany says.
She goes on to detail a new piece of proposed legislation designed to slash legal immigration into the United States called the Reforming American Immigration for Strong Employment (RAISE) Act.
The bill - which was praised by CNN for being a return to a more normal immigration policy following the problematic border wall plan - aims to reduce the number of low-skilled immigrants entering the US and would replace the current employment-based system with a more Australian-style merit based system.
"Americans deserve a raise, and President Trump is finally putting the American worker first," Ms McEnany told viewers. At the time of writing 745,000 people had watched the Facebook clip.
Ms McEnany's former employer, CNN, has borne the brunt of Mr Trump's frequent attacks on the media, along with the likes of the New York Times and Washington Post. In fact the broadcaster's logo was at the centre of  when it appeared in an online gif (later tweeted by the president) in which the CNN logo could be seen getting chock-slammed by Donald Trump during one of his previous appearances on pro-wrestling show WWE.
And the new face of Trump TV didn't miss her chance at taking a dig at the traditional media when signing off from the 90 second clip.
"Thank you for joining us, everybody. I'm Kayleigh McEnany, and that's the real news," she said.
Unsurprisingly, many on social media were quick to raise objections and make comparisons to state controlled media in countries like North Korea.

CNN propped up Kayleigh McEnany only to see her now adding legitimacy to Trump TV. Should've never put such a shameful airhead on the air.

BREAKING NOW: Exclusive footage of Kayleigh McEnany's meteorology internship prior to taking her new position at Trump TV  🇺🇸
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayleigh McEnany</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McEnany</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strong Employment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reforming American Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's TV</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
