<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442293010333892</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-opinion/delay-delay-delay-coalition-tying-itself-in-knots-to-avoid-equality-question-20170807-gxqpy2.html</url>
  <title>Resignation is the honourable course of action for MPs afraid of a marriage debate </title>
  <content>
In most jobs, refusing to undertake a core function for which you were employed - even as conscientious objection - would dissolve the contract. The honourable path is resignation.
But not the pseudo-accountable world of representative politics, where internal loyalties trump responsibility to electors, and where the rules can be sidestepped at one's convenience.

Up Next

Olympic champion Betty Cuthbert dies aged 79

01:16

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Turnbull rallies the troops

PM Malcolm Turnbull has called a special Liberal party meeting to try and settle the divisive issue of same sex marriage.

Take the MPs pleading ignorance of their own family heritage when they signed their nomination forms. Try that with your next tax return.
Yet politicians believe there's one set of rules for the public, and another for them. 

In the same-sex marriage debate, double standards, and double-speak, abound.
Exhibit 1: Recent polling showed marriage equality was a top-order issue for only around 6 per cent of Australians. Conservatives jumped saying it proved government should be focused on the bigger things like energy bills, jobs, stagnant wages.

Yet the same people insist, with born-again zeal, that the plebiscite was central to voters' judgment in 2016 and that therefore, a parliamentary vote would be a fundamental breach of the Coalition's election pitch. This bears little scrutiny. It is far more likely that the only impact from Malcolm Turnbull's craven retention of Tony Abbott's plebiscite fudge was negative, in that it was a vote depressor, helping the Coalition to shed votes and contributing materially to Turnbull's near-death experience.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Voters who would have switched to Labor but for Turnbull's plebiscite promise are a myth.Photo: Andrew Meares
Exhibit 2: The Liberal party room will hold a secret ballot on Monday to decide whether to proceed to a parliamentary debate, and, if not, whether to pursue a supposed "compromise" voluntary mail-in.
Why?
Self-evidently, a non-compulsory, non-binding postal vote, with all the franchise problems it would carry, was expressly not promised in 2016. In material terms, it would constitute a more flagrant departure from the election promise than a parliamentary vote - especially as such a vote has to happen anyway for legislative change. For a start, a key aspect of the plebiscite was that it would happen quickly - causing minimal delay - ie by February 2017. It did not.
And that's before you get to the imminent legal challenge to the mail-in, and the fact that neither side would take its outcome seriously.
So, not only are MPs refusing to conduct a debate in the House of Representatives (to wit: their job), and to be accountable to constituents for their votes at its conclusion, but via the secret ballot, they are now wanting to hide their votes from each other. Such courage.
The expectation for a parliamentary debate is entirely central to Australia's democratic institutional tradition. It should not however, be conflated with the expectation of a positive result.
When reform advocates demand, do you job and vote for marriage equality, what they should say is do your job and debate marriage equality.
The numbers are tight in the Parliament, even if there is a conscience vote. But the proposition that the issue is politically ultra vires - beyond the power of our representatives - is an affront to democracy and should be seen as such by true conservatives.
Nobody's saying how you have to vote, but if you refuse to even discuss it, you should probably resign.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
