<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441777614251849</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/07/10/25/breastfeeding-mum-london-museum-cover-up-apologise</url>
  <title>Breastfeeding mum forced to cover up in museum</title>
  <content>
A prominent London museum has apologised to a mother who was told to cover up while breastfeeding inside the attraction.
Kat Joyce, 37, took to Twitter to vent her frustration at being told to cover her breasts while visiting the Victoria and Albert Museum during National Breastfeeding Week last week,  reported.
"Flashed a nanosecond of nipple while breastfeeding and was asked to cover up in V&A courtyard. Am perplexed," Ms Joyce wrote in a tweet ,which has since been shared thousands of times.
Ms Joyce noted the irony of the request, given the museum's many images and sculptures of naked men and women with exposed nipples.
"I had been attempting to be discreet and to feed under a cardigan, but with a distracted one-year-old it can be challenging. The staff member was friendly and polite, but obviously asking me to cover up was still intrusive, unpleasant and embarrassing for me, as well as obviously ludicrous," she told the BBC.
She shared an image holding her young son standing next to a statue of a woman breastfeeding to highlight the absurdity of the request.
A V&A spokesperson on Twitter said the museum was "investigating" the incident.

Related Articles

"Women are welcome to breastfeed in the museum and we have quiet spaces for those who prefer privacy," the spokesperson said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Museum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Breastfeeding Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Joyce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kat Joyce, 37</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
