<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441227858431108</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/guthrie-says-abc-will-push-racist-plan/news-story/23a588ba258e42eef3c2ef90093e5002</url>
  <title>GUTHRIE SAYS ABC WILL PUSH RACIST PLAN</title>
  <content>
The ABC is meant to be impartial. But ABC boss Michelle Guthrie promises it will be biased and peddle propaganda. 

ABC managing director Michelle Guthrie has announced a policy shift with the national broadcaster supporting the spirit of indigenous recognition proposals in the Uluru Statement from the Heart...
Ms Guthrie told guests at a corporate open-air gala dinner that the ABC would back the constitutional reform push by aggressively targeting more positive depictions of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander life.
She said that "while we have an obligation to tell the difficult stories, we must also tell of the successes ... we must be prepared to make these stories a regular part of our reporting, a central part of our coverage and not simply episodic or tokenistic"...
"The ABC's role is clear... The ABC will support you in what the Uluru Statement from the Heart so movingly described as the need for you to take a rightful place in your own country, to have power over your destiny so your children can flourish and walk in two worlds, their culture a gift to their country.''
Ms Guthrie's declaration [will be followed tonight] by a special edition of ABC TV's Q&A broadcast from the Garma meeting grounds, hosted by the ABC's indigenous affairs editor Stan Grant.
Panel members included Mr Pearson, Indigenous Affairs Minister Nigel Scullion, academic Marcia Langton, Garma festival director Denise Bowden, Yothu Yindi Foundation board member Djapirri Mumungirritj and Nyamba Buru Yawaru chief executive Peter Yu.
This is frightening.
The nation's biggest news outlet - state-funded - will be campaigning for a proposal to divide us by race, and lock that division in our constitution for generations. This is not merely a massive distraction from the true problems devastating Aboriginal communities. It is also dangerous - not just because it will push us towards forms of apartheid, but because it locks in a victim culture and a dependency that will doom generations of Aboriginal children.
And we already see what the Guthrie decree means. Tonight's Q&A panel is hosted by an activist and locks out sceptics from the discussion.
All this has happened under the Turnbull Government's watch. In fact, the Government appointed a good mate of the Prime Minister as chairman - a man whose first announcement was to declare the ABC free of bias.
This will have grace political consequences for the Liberals. The ABC will campaign hard on yet another ideological issue that won't just split Australia but the Liberal party.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Djapirri Mumungirritj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Yu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Affairs Minister Nigel Scullion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nyamba Buru Yawaru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yothu Yindi Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Guthrie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denise Bowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guthrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV's Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GUTHRIE SAYS ABC WILL PUSH RACIST PLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcia Langton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Guthrie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru Statement</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
