<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651440918620782076</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/hawthorn-east-speed-bump-bungle-leads-to-drivers-using-wrong-side-of-the-road/news-story/3f884ca25fcc1826ed993c31689549d9</url>
  <title>Speed bump causes road madness</title>
  <content>
MOTORISTS are driving on the wrong side of the road to avoid newly installed speed bumps on a Melbourne street, which the council has admitted are not working.
The new-look speed cushions were installed in Anderson Rd in Hawthorn East earlier this year, replacing old ones, but people living nearby say they are causing more issues than they are solving.
Laurie Doolan said his family had been against the new-look speed bumps before they were installed and now the situation along the street had become worse.
He said repeated attempts to get Boroondara Council to fix it had come up empty.
Council environment and infrastructure director Bruce Dobson said there had been some unforeseen issues with the speed bumps which the council would now need to fix.
"Some drivers have entered the traffic lane on the opposite side of the road to avoid a speed cushion," Mr Dobson said.
"This speed cushion needs to be moved to address this and we will do that."
Dr Doolan said the new speed bumps had turned the once-quiet street into a speedway.
"The way the four-wheel-drives come rattling down the road, it's only a matter of time before someone is killed.
"We've got two schools at the end of the road and in the morning it's like Russian roulette.
"When you're backing out of your driveway, you always look left, but now we have to look right to make sure there's no-one flying down the wrong side of the road."
He said the council had been told before the work was done that there would be problems.
Mr Dobson said the original speed humps were in poor condition, didn't meet current design standards and created access issues for large vehicles such as waste trucks.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Dobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anderson Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Doolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Doolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dobson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boroondara Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
