<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442215700921573</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/aussie-trengove-happy-with-fairytale-finish/3209559/</url>
  <title>Aussie Trengove happy with 'fairytale finish'</title>
  <content>
JESS Trengove had the number nine in her head all week leading up the world championships marathon.
This was the ninth marathon of her career and her brother, Jack, the former Melbourne captain, wears No.9 in the AFL.
So it made sense in her mind that she'd become the first Australian woman to register a top 10 placing at the world titles and finish . . . ninth.
"This is my ninth marathon and I had a little thing about number nine, it's my brother's footy number," Trengove said.
"My coach Adam (Didyk) wrote me a little letter before the race saying I think there is something special about this number nine thing so run proud out there knowing it's your brother's footy number.
"And then to finish ninth, it's a fairytale."
Trengove, who finished 11th at the 2013 Moscow world championships, was at the front of the leading pack at the 35km mark but dropped back slightly over the next five kilometres.
She then pulled back ground over the final couple of kilometres, crossing the line in 2 hours 28 minutes 59 seconds.
Bahrain's Rose Chelimo took gold in 2hr27.11sec after kicking back over the last few hundred metres from Kenya's two-time champion Edna Kiplagat with American Amy Cragg grabbing the bronze medal.

Trengove, who set her personal best at the London Marathon in April, wasn't originally going to return for the world championships but was happy she changed her mind.
"I crossed the line in the London Marathon in April thinking I was probably going to focus on another major later in the year, but I crossed the line and thought I love this city and I love running for my country," she said.
"I just had this urge to run for Australia again this year, my body felt all right so we were like, it's 15 weeks let's do it, and I am so grateful we made that decision.
"This was the first marathon race where I felt I could respond to the surges and be in control.
"One of my proudest moments in the race was just before half-way and the pack started getting away from me, a few people were out there and I heard them yelling out you that I had to stay with that pack.
"I had to push a bit more than I would like to at that point to get back on them but it was the best thing I did because once you're moving with that pack it's a lot easier, you go with the flow.
"If I didn't push beyond my comfort zone at that point it could have been a very different race."
Trengove, who won the bronze medal at the 2014 Commonwealth Games in Glasgow, is focused on emulating her hero Kerryn McCann's famous 2006 victory from Melbourne on the Gold Coast next year.
"I'm incredibly excited about April 2018," she said.
"The Gold Coast is going to be very special for our country."
Sinead Diver, 40, was the next Australian home in 20th position (2:33.26sec) with Milly Clark coming 24th (2:35.27sec).
In the men's race the first Australian over the line was Jack Colreavy in 45th (2:21.44sec) with Brad Milosevic next in 60th (2:25.14sec) while Josh Harris didn't finish.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Milosevic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Amy Cragg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trengove</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerryn McCann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edna Kiplagat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Didyk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Marathon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milly Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sinead Diver, 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glasgow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bahrain's Rose Chelimo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Colreavy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
