<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441777614251808</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/movies/a-rare-breed-more-femaleled-films-but-still-not-enough-says-screen-australia-20170806-gxql40.html</url>
  <title>More women are making movies in Australia, but it's still nowhere near enough, says agency</title>
  <content>
The gender balance in Australian filmmaking is shifting but still has a long way to go, according to new figures released by Screen Australia.
The number of female-led films receiving production funding from the agency has increased by 77 per cent in just two years, up from 22 per cent of all projects in 2014-15 to 39 per cent in 2016-17. 

Up Next
Australian Survivor 2017:
Tarzan moves on

01:20

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Gender Matters funding recipients announced

The fifty-eight recipients of Screen Australiaas Gender Matters initiative will share in a combined funding pool of over $3 million to address gender imbalance in the industry.

That is still short, however, of the 50 per cent split set by Screen Australia as a target (but not as a quota) when .
"This data stands as a reminder that just because gender equality in the screen industry has been a point of discussion doesn't mean that it's translating into action industry-wide, particularly in feature film," said Fiona Cameron, the agency's chief operating officer. "Whilst we are getting close to gender parity across the titles that receive our production funding, the results are uneven, with the television and online sectors continuing to do the heavy lifting."Photo: Steven Siewert SWS
A female-led team is defined as having women in at least 50 per cent of the key creative roles - writer, director, producer and antagonist (lead character). Thus, for instance, a project written by a man and directed by a man could still qualify if it were about a woman and produced by a woman.
The analysis produced by Screen Australia covers film, television, documentary and multiplatform (predominantly web series) production, and shows that across the board 48 per cent of projects that received production investment met the criteria last financial year.

TV fared best, with 67 per cent of productions that received SA funding meeting the 50 per cent female target. Documentary was at 43 per cent and multiplatform at 52 per cent.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In announcing  - a suite of initiatives and funding designed to elicit more female-led projects - in 2015, Screen Australia revealed analysis covering the years 1970 to 2015 that showed only 30 per cent of producers working in film, 16 per cent of directors and 21 per cent of writers were female.
The figures weren't merely historic, either. Identifying as currently active - which meant they had had at least one credit in the preceding five years - the numbers were remarkably similar: 32 per cent of producers, 16 per cent of directors and 23 per cent of writers were female.
This is despite the fact that close to half of graduates from the country's film schools in each of those areas are female.
Tackling this gender imbalance isn't merely being driven by a desire to do the right thing. It also makes good business sense. Women make up close to half the cinema audience, and more than half in the 50+ age range.
This is why Screen Australia claims it has wide-ranging support for its push to get more women telling stories.
"We know feature film as an art form needs attention," said Joanna Werner, chair of the Gender Matters taskforce. "We know not enough female writers and directors are working. These are lost opportunities, culturally and commercially.
Added Cameron: "The whole industry is along for the ride in recognition of the overriding commercial imperative." 
Facebook:  
Twitter: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Siewert SWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Screen Australiaa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarzans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gender Matters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanna Werner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Screen Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
