<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441833448827365</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/signalised-crossing-will-be-installed-at-hornibrook-esplanade-clontarf/news-story/dc8714c6207fa541ba7ce0ea69242b03</url>
  <title>Hornibrook Esplanade crossing gets nod</title>
  <content>
RETIRED  forensic crash investigator- Michael Flannery is relieved his calls for action have been heard with the State Government revealing- plans to install a signalised crossing on a busy stretch of road at Clontarf-.
State Labor MP for Redcliffe- Yvette D'Ath announced- last week the crossing would be placed on Hornibrook Esplanade between- Roland and Young streets.
It is understood the department- of main roads will consult with residents and business owners as it completes design work this financial year.
The commitment follows a story in the Redcliffe & Bayside Herald in May in which Mr Flannery said he feared someone would be killed trying to cross the stretch of road after he witnessed many near misses.
"Everyone was hopeful we'd be able to get a (pedestrian) refuge but a signalised crossing is even better," Mr Flannery said.
He said with a refuge, pedestrians would have had to decide when it was safe to cross and signalised crossing removed the guesswork.
Mrs D'Ath said the department had conducted an assessment of pedestrian and vehicular traffic in the area.
"There are limited crossing points along this section of Hornibrook Esplanade and a strong desire from pedestrians to cross this busy road," Mrs D'Ath said.
A safer form of crossing would particularly benefit children, the elderly and people with a disability.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hornibrook Esplanade</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayside Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs D</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Flannery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redcliffe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Flannery</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ath</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yvette D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Labor MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clontarf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
