<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441047469802429</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/east-hills/its-that-time-of-year-where-camellias-put-on-bloomin-great-show-in-our-burbs/news-story/bc8eeb85ab852734393f033e8bce6fed</url>
  <title>Camellias put on bloomin' great show in our 'burbs</title>
  <content>
FOR Philip Hough, tending to his camellias is an escape from the world around him.
"If the world is pissing you off, there's nothing better than to get out in the garden, breathe some fresh air and connect with nature," Mr Hough says.
And his great gardening love is Camellias - which are now blooming across Adelaide.
Do you grow camellia's? What's you secret to beautiful blooms? Leave a comment below
As president of Camellias South Australia, he will join thousands of fellow enthusiasts as they descend on Carrick Hill this weekend for the annual camellia show (August 12 and 13).
With dozens of camellia bushes at his Myrtle Bank home, Mr Hough describes his hobby as a "keen interest".
"It probably goes back to the first house my wife and I bought at Lower Mitcham many, many years ago," he says.
"That had a couple of mature camellias and my late father was a very keen gardener."
The event, which runs over two days, draws an average crowd of 2500 people.
"I reckon it's a mixed bunch," Mr Hough says.
"You get your keen gardeners, because we do sell camellia plants, and you get just a broad spectrum of the community from young people to old people interested in looking at good-quality blooms."
There will be plants for sale and plenty of advice for people looking to join the ranks of camellia growers.
And Mr Hough says the flowers will be just as pretty as the surrounds.
"I think Carrick Hill is one of the best kept secrets in SA."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrick Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myrtle Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Mitcham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camellias South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Hough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camellia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hough</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
