<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442159866345864</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/australian-tiaclair-toomey-wins-2017-crossfit-games-to-be-crowned-fittest-woman-on-earth/news-story/188476dfc892012f9512ce2bb7e09a8c</url>
  <title>Aussie crowned world's fittest woman</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN Tia-Clair Toomey has won the CrossFit Games at her third attempt to be declared the fittest woman on earth.
The 24-year-old Queensland's emotional victory in Madison, Wisconsin came after she finished runner-up in 2015 and 2016.
Toomey, also a weightlifter who , finished the gruelling four-day event on 994 points to sneak home ahead of compatriot Kara Webb.
Annie Thorisdottir of Iceland was third.
Toomey opened the Games with an impressive showing in the Run Swim Run - a 500 metre swim, sandwiched between a pair of 1.5 mile runs - winning that event to sit atop the leaderboard after the first workout.
After admirable finishes in several of the following events, Toomey got the best of her compatriot Webb to win the Muscle-Up Clean Ladder workout. Toomey's eighth place finish in the Fibonacci Final - the last workout of the tournament - was enough to see her earn the tight, two-point edge over Webb.
"I have phenomenal athletes to compete against," Toomey said after being named the victor.
"Ever since I started CrossFit, Kara Webb and Annie (Thorisdottir) were everything. So just to be right next to me on the floor... I'm a bit overwhelmed....it's just so nice."
The CrossFit Games, regarded as one of the toughest sporting events on the planet, test competitors' strength, speed and endurance in a.
Defending champion Matt Fraser of the US retained the men's title with the most dominant performance in the event's history.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Run Swim Run</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fibonacci Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kara Webb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annie Thorisdottir of Iceland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thorisdottir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toomey</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Fraser of the US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIAN Tia-Clair Toomey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wisconsin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muscle-Up Clean Ladder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit Games</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
