<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441996657587084</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/berwick-teacher-greg-morrell-who-groomed-a-student-for-sex-and-touched-her-buttocks-will-be-rehabilitated-in-community/news-story/27c4d72945cd96b5709cd3fb815a563c</url>
  <title>Teacher who abused girl escapes jail term</title>
  <content>
A FORMER Berwick teacher who groomed a student for sex has escaped jail.
Gregory Morrell, 42, from Narre Warren South, pleaded guilty to grooming the 14-year-old girl in 2016 and 2017, and to one indecent act where he placed his hands on her buttocks in 2016.
Morrell will serve a 24-month community corrections order and spend the next eight years on the sex offenders register for his crimes, which left his victim feeling "worthless".
He was sentenced on Friday.
Victoria Police prosecutor Leading Senior Constable Jo Daley said the girl, then at Beaconhills College, had come to Morrell for help with maths before Morrell sent her a series of emails, texts and snapchats.
Sen-Constable Daley read text messages sent between the two including one from her that said "you should have pressed against me more" and one from him that said "you should have used your hands too".
The girl later sent a text message saying, "I thought I could do this but it turns out I can't".
Sen-Constable Daley read a statement from the girl that described the effect the abuse had on her - including suicidal thoughts, self-harm, alcohol abuse, and self-hatred - and said the abuse could have escalated if the girl hadn't told him to stop.
"I have lost my innocence and that is something I will never regain," the statement said.
"He destroyed my self-esteem, my self-worth, and now I see myself as worthless."
Morrell's defence lawyer James Mortley said Morrell admitted hugging the girl and other students.
He said Morrell had lost his career for his crime and was now working as a landscaper.
He said he was not allowed to see his own children unsupervised.
Mr Mortley presented a psychiatric report from a forensic psychologist Pamela Matthews that found Morrell did not have pedophilic tendencies.
"The impact on him has been profound," he said.
"He allowed a fantasy to cloud his judgment and took advantage of a 14-year-old student in his care."
Magistrate Peter Reardon said children under the age of 16 cannot consent because of their age and teenagers were particularly impressionable.
He said Morrell was eligible to a discount in his sentence because he spared his victim a trial by pleading guilty.
"You abused the trust of a young girl ... this conduct should be denounced by the court.
"You are a married man with children yourself - you might have reflected how you would be feeling if you sent your children to school to have them exposed to such a situation."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregory Morrell, 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leading Senior Constable Jo Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pamela Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaconhills College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narre Warren South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen-Constable Daley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Peter Reardon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Mortley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mortley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FORMER Berwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morrell</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
