<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441227858431092</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/mornington-peninsula-shire-council-to-vote-on-getting-the-ball-rolling-on-a-pool-at-rosebud/news-story/0d4a73ccec229e84f7befef8321c00b0</url>
  <title>Dipping a toe in the water with pool plan</title>
  <content>
The push for a pool is paying off with the council set to vote on the next step.
Councillors are tomorrow night expected to consider a recommendation from officers to start work on a business case for the project.
Southern Aquatic Centre Action Group convener Betty Preston was "thrilled".
"I know there's a long way to go, but we only ramped up our push for the pool in February so to have got to this point in six months is great," she said.
Ms Preston has been lobbying for a southern peninsula aquatic centre for more than 20 years.
The pool project stalled in 2014 after a plan to build it on the Rosebud foreshore was scrapped.
"I took a breather after that, it had taken so much out of me," Ms Preston said.
She resumed her campaign earlier this year.
"There was a new council and the timing was right," she said.
A Planning for Rosebud Aquatic Centre report that will be discussed at tonight's meeting recommends council-owned land adjoining the municipal offices in Besgrove St as the preferred site for the pool.
The proposed business case would investigate three options for the aquatic centre.
It would look at either a 25m indoor pool or 50m indoor pool or 50m outdoor pool.
All options include a 'learn to swim' pool, warm water hydrotherapy pool and spa, wellness centre with steam and sauna rooms, aquaplay/splash deck, changerooms and spectator seating.
The business case would also explore opportunities for renewable energy and the possibility of including a gym or other program spaces to reduce operating costs.
According to the report, the estimated cost of an aquatic centre ranges from $28.4 million to $30.7 million depending on the chosen option.
If councillors vote in favour of proceeding with a business case, it would completed by the end of 2017.
Once complete the business case and the three concept plans would be put on the council website for two months for community comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Preston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Preston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud Aquatic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Aquatic Centre Action Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Besgrove St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
