<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442250060660439</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/elisabeth-steicke-exwife-of-millionaire-gambler-urged-to-mediate-dispute-over-yet-another-unpaid-legal-bill/news-story/5039ffedf50d44bb634a8a8da665d9a5</url>
  <title>'Be sensible and mediate', judge tells gambler's ex-wife</title>
  <content>
A MILLIONAIRE gambler's ex-wife has been urged to "be sensible" and mediate a dispute over yet another legal bill - or risk seeing the $300,000 she purportedly owes multiply.
Last week, the Supreme Court ordered Elisabeth Steicke pay an Adelaide lawyer more than $89,000 after she unsuccessfully challenged its $20,000 bill.
On Monday, Judge Graham Dart warned Ms Steicke was headed down the same path in her battle with Pederick Lawyers, who claims she owes a debt of $300,000.
"One thing we've never done, in all of these numerous matters of Ms Steicke's, is mediation ... we really need to get everyone in a room and see if we can't sort this out," he said.
"Last week she turned a $20,000 debt into an $89,000 judgment, and we shouldn't have to do that again - it's just not sensible.
"The parties have different views but, if approached with a proper view, you might get a commercial result ... there's got to be a better way than being adversarial."
Ms Steicke and her former husband David - a member of the billion-dollar Punters Club gambling syndicate - remain in dispute over property and assets.
Between them, they have a amassed a legal bill in excess of $40 million.
For seven years, Ms Steicke has fought multiple separate actions against firms that have represented her.
She has to date hired 20 different firms, fired 19 of them, and accused several of overcharging and leaving her with just $5.25 to contest the dispute.
On Monday, the court heard Pederick performed $3 million worth of work for Ms Steicke, of which $300,000 remains outstanding.
Judge Dart was told the firm had filed separate proceedings against her and her ex-husband, to take possession of property held in their joint names, to satisfy $120,000 of that debt.
Peter Heinrich, for Ms Steicke, said that other case made mediation "difficult" for his client, who maintained she had been unfairly billed "tens of thousands of dollars".
Judge Dart ordered both Mr Heinrich and counsel for Pederick speak to their clients with a view to arranging a mediation conference.
He adjourned the case for two weeks.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Dart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pederick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Heinrich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pederick Lawyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Graham Dart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elisabeth Steicke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punters Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Steicke</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Heinrich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
