<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441309462810637</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/dubai-floating-seahorse-underwater-homes-2017-8</url>
  <title>These ultra-luxurious underwater homes are being built in Dubai</title>
  <content>
In the clear-blue waters off the coast of Dubai lies a chain of islands known as The Heart of Europe. They're manmade reconstructions of actual European nations, just on a smaller scale - part of  known as "The World."

Richard Branson, fittingly, owns the island representing Great Britain.

The Heart of Europe rolled out its first $US2.8 million floating home, the aptly named "," in early 2016. Since then, development firm Kleindienst has been rolling out even larger homes that will cost .

Keep scrolling to see the gorgeous renderings.

Kleindienst Group

The first models went on sale in 2015, before any Seahorses were even completed. Kleindienst told Business Insider it sold approximately 60 Seahorses in 2015.

Kleindienst Group

From the home, residents will be able to see actual seahorses dance through the Arabian Gulf -- the animal's natural habitat.

Kleindienst Group

If you want to take a swim, a convenient step-ladder offers a safe entry and exit. Or you could just dive right in.

Kleindienst

It's not exactly the most accessible way to get to and from home, but once they're out there, they can cross between the islands via floating jetties.

Kleindienst Group

Kleindienst also hopes it can make some headway in restoring the endangered seahorse population in the area.

'We will create an artificial coral reef beneath the luxury retreats which will be a protected area in which seahorses can safely live and breed,' Kleindienst said at an unveiling even in May 2015.

Kleindienst Group

The Signature Edition will have four designated bedrooms and several rooms that can transform into sleeping quarters, meaning the Seahorse can accommodate up to eight adults and eight children, according to Kleindienst.

Kleindienst Group

Kleindienst Group

Below the water's surface there are actually two bedrooms, one bathroom, and a viewing area for the coral garden.

Kleindienst Group

Kleindienst Group

Kleindienst Group

Kleindienst Group

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kleindienst</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arabian Gulf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Signature Edition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Branson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heart of Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kleindienst Group</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
