<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651441051764769832</docid>
  <date>06/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/telling-jews-they-are-too-dangerous-as-neighbours/news-story/d708cc9f96fd5e57cc049ad074191275</url>
  <title>TELLING JEWS THEY ARE TOO DANGEROUS AS NEIGHBOURS</title>
  <content>
Australia is shamed. A NSW court last week banned construction of a synagogue at Bondi, to save locals from getting accidentally hurt if the Jews are shot or bombed.
After this decision by the Land and Environment Court, what next? Send Jews back to the ghettos to keep us safe?
What a victory for the jihadists trying to kill them.
This disgrace started when the Friends of Refugees from Eastern Europe decided to build a synagogue on tennis courts at Wellington St, Bondi.
Waverley Council, which ironically includes several Jews, resisted, worried at first by a design with apartments at the back.
That design was then modified; a planned blast wall - a defence against car bombs - was made smaller and less obtrusive.
And when Waverley Council still failed to approve the project, FREE appealed to the Land and Environment Court.
The council now claims it was the court alone that rejected the appeal, on the grounds of the danger to the neighbours.
But Commissioner Graham Brown made clear in his findings that the council's barrister had queried the "suitability of the site having regard to impact on safety and security 'of future users of the synagogue, nearby residents, motorists and pedestrians'."
(.)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waverley Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friends of Refugees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jews</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Graham Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JEWS THEY ARE TOO DANGEROUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
