<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442297305301253</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/game-of-thrones-who-might-live-and-die-on-season-7-episode-4-2017-8</url>
  <title>THE ODDS: Who will probably survive 'Game of Thrones' this week, and who could die</title>
  <content>
In this shortened, seven-episode season of "Game of Thrones," basically anyone can be killed - and at any time.

So to prepare you (and ourselves) for this intense season, which is already filled with deaths three episodes in, we put together a list of all the characters still alive, their chances of dying this week, and in the season generally.

We'll update each character's risk of death percentage every week, depending on what happens as the story progresses.

Season seven episode four, "The Spoils of War" airs Sunday night on HBO.

Here's who will live and who will die this week on "Game of Thrones:"

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 100%. Jon Snow isn't looking forward to the inevitable battle with the White Walkers, but he is just dandy in Dragonstone yet again this week.

Chance of survival this season: 90%. He's already died before and his life could be saved again.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 100%. She is Daenerys of the House Targaryen, the First of Her Name, The Unburnt, Queen of the Andals, the Rhoynar and the First Men, Queen of Meereen, Khaleesi of the Great Grass Sea, Protector of the Realm, Lady Regnant of the Seven Kingdoms, Breaker of Chains and Mother of Dragons. She is perfectly fine and there's nothing to worry about for now.

Chance of survival this season: 99%. All men must die, but Daenerys Stormborn is not a man.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode:100%. Turns out getting wrongfully accused of murder and having to escape execution is the best thing that has ever happened to this guy.

Chance of survival this season: 75%. Tyrion is at a huge risk being in Westeros. And Dragonstone is too close to King's Landing for comfort. But the chances that we will see his death on the show are very slim. He's one of the people to root for and it's unlikely that George R.R. Martin will let the writers kill off his favourite character.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 100%. He's probably sticking around, especially since we already suffered an entire season without him.

Chance of survival this season: 80%. The Hound's scenes in the season premiere proved that his story is moving forward in a way that makes his character more important than ever. He will be an essential figure in the battles to come, and the end of the series as a whole.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 100%. This week Sam is fine, unless scooping maester poop. The Citadel is safe from any surprise attacks.

Chance of survival this season: 88%. Sam will probably survive the series unless he catches Jorah Mormont's greyscale and can't seem to cure himself.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 100%. Gilly is fine!

Chance of survival this season: 60%. Due to their discovery of dragonglass in Dragonstone, Gilly and Sam likely won't stick around Oldtown for the whole season -- he's got important things to do and they go everywhere together, which could be her ultimate downfall.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 95%. From the looks of the episode four teaser, Arya makes it close enough to Winterfell to see it. But will she actually make it there after all this time? Most likely. But this show can be cruel.

Chance of survival this season: 75%. Arya will likely survive the season and the series, but her mission puts her at a big risk.

Macall B. Polay/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 95%. Davos should be fine this week in Dragonstone, along with his king Jon Snow.

Chance of survival this season: 40%. Of any of these people, Davos probably deserves life the most. But the closer Davos gets to Jon Snow and ruling, the more danger he's in. But he has stuck around for a reason: He's a skilled fighter with a pirate background, and is a useful asset when it comes to giving a king really good advice.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 95%. There's no way she's going this soon. With Euron, the Iron Bank and Randyll Tarly on her side, she's got things under control. But definitely not for long.

Chance of survival this season: 50%. If she doesn't die by the end of season seven, she will die in season eight.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 90%. Tycho -- who is new to the odds list this week! -- should be just fine. Unless he suddenly betrays Cersei. But he's too smart to do that while he's in King's Landing.

Chance of survival this season: 80%. The biggest threat to his life is Cersei.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 90%. Qyburn is as safe as he is creepy this week.

Chance of survival this season: 20%. Being Team Cersei makes him really vulnerable: Arya will kill anyone who gets in her way of murdering the queen, especially a creepy maester who's not even a maester.

HBPO

Chance of survival this episode: 90%. From trailer footage we know that Beric and crew will be fighting the White Walkers, so he'll be around for a few more episodes or more.

Chance of survival this season: 50%. If he does die, Thoros of Myr will bring him back. But if Thoros of Myr dies, then Beric will stay dead.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 90%. From trailer footage we know that Thoros, the Hound, Beric, and crew will be fighting the White Walkers, so he'll stick around.

Chance of survival this season: 50%. Thoros has made it this far, so he's survived for a reason. Thoros could die fighting the White Walkers, which would be bad for his buddy Beric, who isn't as good at staying alive.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 90%. This week, Varys will probably just chill at Dragonstone and feed information to Daenerys.

Chance of survival this season: 65%. Varys is too cool and smart to die, but it's possible. If there's any danger, he'll sense it and find a good place to hide. Being on Team Daenerys certainly helps his chances, since someone will need to be alive to serve as Master of Spies if she wins the game of thrones.

Macall B Polay/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 90%. She is close and important to Daenerys, which puts her at a huge risk. And this is 'Game of Thrones,' so that romantic scene with Grey Worm in 'Stormborn' probably means one (or both) of them is doomed.

Chance of survival this season: 40%. More like Missan-die. She is usually at her queen's side, which makes her relatively safe from threats. But with Euron Greyjoy out there and allied to Cersei, anyone on Team Daenerys needs to look out. And Missandei can't translate her way out of combat.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 90%. He'll probably crush some people this week with his bare hands, but The Mountain will not be crushed . . . yet.

Chance of survival this season: 20%. He's got a lot of enemies. He's strong, but he is also basically a zombie, so he has to have some kind of weaknesses that makes him easy (for Arya) to kill.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 90%. Last week, we found out that Jorah's already cured of greyscale thanks to Sam's apparently very rare ability to follow directions. This week, he'll probably be on a mission to reunite with his Khaleesi.

Chance of survival this season: 60%. There's still a chance he could die fighting for his Khaleesi.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 85%. Like everyone else in Winterfell, Sansa will be really cold. But she's got Brienne protecting her, and Littlefinger is too obsessed with how much she looks like her mum to harm her. As lady of Winterfell, Sansa could be the one in charge of harming people this week, more specifically Littlefinger.

Chance of survival this season: 70%. Sansa will probably survive the season, and hopefully the series. She's learned a lot from Cersei and Littlefinger and her enemies, so she could outwit them all.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 80%. He's in Winterfell now, and creepier than ever. Maybe even creepier than Littlefinger. Of all the Starks, he's the most vulnerable right now and could be a target for Littlefinger since he knows a lot of things to use against him.

Chance of survival this season: 60%. He's one of the last remaining Starks and he has magical powers so he should be fine, but his inability to walk and lack of Hodor don't give him any advantages.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 80%. It looks like he's headed into a battle that he cannot win with dragons, so he could die. But from what we've seen in season seven so far, his journey isn't close to over. So chances are he makes it through the week.

Chance of survival this season: 60%. Jaime's survival depends on which side he chooses in the end. Because if he sticks with Cersei, he'll probably die. We'd bet on him turning on her at some point.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 80%. Littlefinger is a threat to all in Winterfell this week, but Brienne could slice him like butter.

Chance of survival this season: 65%. Won't be surprising at all if she makes it, just delightful. Brienne is one of the few characters who deserves to make it to the, what we assume to be happy, end. But she does fight for a living, so she's always at risk.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 80%. We assume he'll arrive on the shores of Dragonstone this week with the leftover Greyjoys Euron didn't take with him in his attack.

Chance of survival this season: 30%. We're hoping Theon gets more time to be Theon and make it to the final season, but he could sacrifice himself to make up for abandoning his sister during Euron's attack and/or for betraying the Starks.

helen sloan hbo photo 7

Chance of survival this episode: 80%. This week, he'll continue his training with Brienne and maybe help her take on any threats to Sansa and the Stark children.

Chance of survival this season: 50%. Pod has spent his entire tenure on the show surrounded by the best Westeros has to offer: Tyrion, Bronn, and Brienne. With folks like that he has to be brilliant at this point, and every season he debuts a special skill, from pleasing the ladies to combat. We're just waiting for his shining moment, though there's a chance he could die in battle.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 80%. As the last Baratheon left alive, Gendry is definitely coming back to the show. If he doesn't show up in this episode, he simply needs more time to row.

Chance of survival this season: 30%. Or maybe he will win the game of thrones? But probably not. Gendry is not safe until Cersei is gone.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 75%. More Leather Euron, please! This week, his biggest threat is dragon breath.

Chance of survival this season: 18%. He has way more enemies than he has friends. And even his new ally Cersei is more of a frenemy.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 75%. Old Mellie leaves Westeros for Volantis in last week's episode. She's been such an important character in this show, so she'll be back.

Chance of survival this season: 30%. She is really old and she's still on Arya's kill list. Without Stannis, Davos, and Jon Snow on her side, she doesn't have many allies. But there's a chance that we won't see her again until season eight.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 70%. Lyanna has a lot more Northern men to put to shame before her time on this show is over. But this week, Littlefinger is a threat to all in Winterfell.

Chance of survival this season: 50%. If the writers kill her, they are monsters and we will never watch this show again, ever. But she has expressed interest in going into battle for House Mormont, so she's definitely not safe.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 70%. Where is this guy, anyway? We probably won't see him this week, but he'll show up again eventually. After all, he is the Stark children's uncle.

Chance of survival this season: 50%. He's never been the brightest, and we actually have no idea where he is right now. For all we know, he could be rotting in a dungeon in Riverrun: there wouldn't be any more food brought to him, since Arya wiped out all the Freys.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 65%. Littlefinger is a threat to all in Winterfell, and Meera will defend Bran even if it means giving her life.

Chance of survival this season: 30%. Meera has sacrificed her life to help Bran for the past few seasons, and by the end of season seven that sacrifice could turn literal.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 60%. The White Walkers are getting closer and closer to the Jon Snow loyalist and the Wall with every passing breath.

Chance of survival this season: 12%. Unfortunately, Edd and a lot of the men of the Night's Watch will probably die fighting the White Walkers.

Chance of survival this episode: 45%. He led the Unsullied into a trap at the Lannister's home of Casterly Rock, and they're pretty much surrounded. Hopefully Daenerys can come to their rescue, with the help of her dragons.

Chance of survival this season: 20%. He's a soldier and will do anything for Daenerys. His life is always at risk, but he's made it this far because he (and all the Unsullied) are really, really good at what they do.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 40%. With a battle that probably involves dragons coming up his life is at a risk -- unless he can convince Jaime to surrender and have a reunion with his old pal Tyrion.

Chance of survival this season: 20%. Bronn's chances of survival depend on where his loyalties lie.

HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 30%. In the season premiere, Tormund announced that he and the Wildlings are going to Eastwatch-by-the-Sea, one of the castles along the Wall. Their goal? Prevent a White Walker invasion. We're a little worried about this beloved character because judging from the glimpse of the Walkers, they're gonna be tough to beat.

Chance of survival this this season: 2%. He's survived a lot of battles and he'll literally rip the throats out of his enemies using his teeth. So there's a very small chance he'll survive, but he's headed to one of the most dangerous places in Westeros right now and will likely stay there (because he will die there).

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 30%. Yara could die at the hands of Cersei, but chances are Euron will leaves Yara for himself. He's murdered his brother, so he could kill his niece without batting an eye.

Chance of survival this season: 5%. Euron isn't a forgiving man.

Macall B. Polay/ HBO

Chance of survival this episode:25%. He is possibly headed into a battle that includes a fire breathing dragon, so he's at a risk this week. For betraying Olenna Tyrell, the house he's sworn to as a lord in The Reach, he deserves a painful death.

Chance of survival this season: 10%. He deserves to die, but we're also hoping he reunites with his son, Sam, to see how brilliant he is before his time on the show is over.

Helen Sloan/HBO

Chance of survival this episode: 20%. Bran Stark, who arrived in Winterfell last week probably knows the truth about his betrayal of Ned Stark and Littlefinger blatantly lied to Sansa and Jon about this. There will be trouble in Winterfell, and Littlefinger is surrounded by Stark family members and loyalists. He also definitely can't hold his own against Brienne of Tarth.

Chance of survival this season: 10%. He's Littlefinger and he's survived this long, so his chances of sticking around are likely. But not high anymore. But Brandon Stark probably knows the truth about his betrayal of Ned Stark and Littlefinger blatantly lied to Sansa and Jon about this.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euron Greyjoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euron</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volantis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stannis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBPO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grass Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qyburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tycho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhoynar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casterly Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baratheon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned Stark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Sloan/HBO</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Night's Watch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thoros</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Mormont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Cersei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hound</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missan-die</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mellie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildlings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen of Meereen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Men</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterfell</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen of the Andals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greyjoys Euron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spoils of War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jorah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys of the House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Protector of the Realm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George R.R. Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stormborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Targaryen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Regnant of the Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davos</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arya</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missandei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thoros of Myr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey Worm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragonstone</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gendry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meera</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master of Spies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tormund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macall B. Polay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother of Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Littlefinger</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brienne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jorah Mormont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randyll Tarly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unburnt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oldtown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brienne of Tarth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandon Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First of Her</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaleesi of the Great</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macall B. Polay/HBO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citadel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Walkers</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leather Euron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaleesi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Daenerys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys Stormborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverrun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unsullied</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
