<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442507758701752</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/demons-great-garry-lyon-slams-melbourne-for-its-lack-of-resistance-during-loss-to-gws-giants/news-story/68c50ec14105d94d37cdf5541d642537</url>
  <title>'Almost without a whimper': Club great slams Dees</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE great Garry Lyon has slammed the Demons for a lack of intensity in their loss to GWS on Saturday.
The Demons conceded eight straight goals - after booting the opening three majors - and never clawed their way back into the game, going on to lose by 32 points.
Lyon said the showing was simply unacceptable, given the club's finals chances are in the balance.
"I didn't think there was sufficient intensity for a side who were playing for their very existence in terms of a finals position - a side who dropped a game to North Melbourne previously," Lyon said on SEN Breakfast.
"You would expect a response against a team without their three most talented players (Jeremy Cameron, Toby Greene and Jonathon Patton).
"Everything had fallen into perfect order for Melbourne to think, right they kicked the first three goals of the game into a six goal breeze, in the blink of an eye.
"In effect they were plus six goals, and they conceded the next ten."
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 20 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
The Demons were thumped around the clearances all day, and while the Giants' scoring rate slowed, their defensive work was enough to keep Melbourne from threatening.
The loss to the Giants - the Demons' fourth defeat in six games - leaves Melbourne sitting in 10th on percentage, with 10 wins from 19 games.
Lyon said he was particularly surprised by the Demons' failure to put a player behind the ball as the Giants surged with a heavy wind at their backs.
"There was no defiance from Melbourne they just let it happen," he said.
"I was waiting for the backstop, I was waiting for the one behind.
"That was a response that was not expected from a side that has threatened all year to make a charge into a finals group and have a big impact, and they can miss (the finals) altogether.
"It looked to be almost without a whimper, especially in the first half."
To guarantee a finals place, Melbourne could have to win all three of its remaining games.
The Demons face the in-form Saints in a must-win clash at the MCG on Sunday, then finish the home and away season with home games against Brisbane and Collingwood.
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 20 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
