<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442374614713856</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-woman-accused-of-actewagl-fraud-charged-with-fresh-offence-20170807-gxqn9r.html</url>
  <title>New charge for Canberra woman accused of ActewAGL fraud</title>
  <content>
A Canberra woman charged with stealing thousands from ActewAGL customers faced court on Monday charged with a fresh offence.
Jessica Kate Anderson, 29, was working as a contractor at the energy company when it's alleged she and a co-accused, Taylor Jade Geoghegan, 20, found accounts in credit before transferring the money to bank accounts belonging to Ms Anderson.
It's alleged more than $13,000 was taken this way.
Court documents tendered on another occasion suggest the pair had quit their jobs working the telephones at ActewAGL and on the same day booked flights for a Las Vegas holiday.
Both women were arrested but have since been released on bail.
Ms Anderson, of Gungahlin, is charged with 15 counts of fraud, while Ms Geoghegan, of Theodore, is charged with 15 counts of being knowingly involved in the fraud.
On Monday in the ACT Magistrates Court Ms Anderson was also charged with intentionally providing misleading information.
The court heard no further details of the alleged offence.
The case is next due in court on August 21, when Magistrate Peter Morrison said the woman would be expected to enter pleas.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Kate Anderson, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Peter Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Geoghegan, of Theodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Anderson, of Gungahlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ActewAGL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Jade Geoghegan, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Magistrates Court Ms Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
