<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442357434844501</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:54</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/a-crackdown-on-foreign-investment-has-raised-genuine-fear-in-torontos-housing-market-2017-8</url>
  <title>A crackdown on foreign investment has raised 'genuine fear' in Toronto's housing market</title>
  <content>
The red-hot housing market in Toronto, Canada has come to a screaming halt

It follows a period of rapid growth, which had analysts concerned about speculative market conditions led by activity in apartments.

This chart from the Toronto Real Estate Board (TREB) shows the recent sharp fall in the rate of annual price growth:

Although it has the data to do so, the TREB doesn't publish median house prices, only the average price.

The annual growth rates of Toronto property markets peaked at a huge 30% in April, when the average selling price in the greater Toronto area hit $CAD920,761 ($AUD917,723) according to the TREB.

That's when the Province of Ontario stepped in, announcing a "Fair Housing Plan" on April 20 which included a 15% levy on overseas borrowers.

Since then, a degree of fear has gripped investors with prices falling by 4.6% in July from June.

In addition, sales volume have crashed as investors shift to the sidelines in droves.

Although summer can be a quieter period for transactions, total sales volume fell by 40.4% in July from the same time last year.

Total price falls since April 20 are now up to around 19%, to an average price of $CAD746,218 ($AUD743,756). On the strength of Toronto's housing market over recent years, annual growth in July was still positive at around 5%.

Turning to the Australian market, the NSW government also put foreign investors in its sights in June this year,  The measures came into effect on July 1.

That follows the  Also at that time, Victoria trebled its land tax surcharge on "absentee landholders" from 0.5% to 1.5%.

Data from NAB released in July  just prior to the implementation of the latest surcharge increases.

Although not as drastic as Toronto's 15% levy, it will be interesting to note how those measures impact the

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD743,756</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto Real Estate Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TREB</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAD746,218</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Housing Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto's 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Province of Ontario</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 20</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAD920,761</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD917,723</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
