<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442383204648596</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/nsw-police-defend-officers-after-mans-death-at-grafton-20170807-gxqra3.html</url>
  <title>NSW Police defend officers after man's death at Grafton </title>
  <content>
The tactical response from police officers confronted with a knife-wielding man who was shot in northern NSW before dying in hospital followed "textbook" procedure, police say.
after responding to reports of a disturbance at a Grafton unit on Sunday afternoon.

Up Next

Crane collapse bars residents from returning

01:39

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Man shot by police in Grafton dies

A knife-wielding man who was shot by police during a confrontation in Grafton in northern NSW has died in hospital. Vision courtesy Seven News.

"Both taser and OC spray were deployed prior to police having to shoot the individual," NSW Police Assistant Commissioner Northern Region Max Mitchell said on Monday.
Residents nearby the Turf Street unit heard police yelling at the man to "drop the knife".

Two constables and a sergeant first used a Taser and OC spray on the man, who was known to police, before he was eventually shot.
The man, whose age has not yet been released, was treated at the scene and flown to Gold Coast hospital in a critical condition. He died overnight.

"It's an unfortunate situation and from what I've been briefed on, police have undertaken their tactical options textbook," Mr Mitchell told reporters in Newcastle.
One resident said he heard the drama unfolding before seeing an officer pointing his gun at the offender.Photo: Seven News
"There was another one over the road with his gun pointed straight at me and the culprit right in between us," the resident, who didn't want to be named, told AAP.
"I leapt up, shut the door and got my head down.
"A gun can go where it's not supposed to go, so I put two walls between me and the police."
The officers were still yelling for the man to drop the weapon after two shots rang out, the resident said.
Mr Mitchell said he was unaware whether residents could have been at risk, but a critical incident investigation would examine all aspects of the shooting.
"They're the type of issues that police will call upon," he said.
"If there were any witnesses who are able to come forward and provide a statement, it's most important," he said.
The officers involved were in shock, Mr Mitchell added.
"My understanding is they are as well as what could be expected," he said.
"No police officer wants to shoot an individual.
"It is traumatic."
AAP 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turf Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mitchell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Assistant Commissioner Northern Region Max Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
