<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442421859354804</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/more-sports/australias-golden-girl-of-athletics-was-ahead-of-her-time-as-modern-results-show/news-story/0b82ea98a241702a6efc2cfe92fb3d0a</url>
  <title>A timely reminder how good Betty Cuthbert was</title>
  <content>
CALL it a tribute of sorts to Betty Cuthbert and a timely reminder on the day before she died of how far ahead of her time she was.
Cuthbert's winning time in the 400m at the 1964 Tokyo Olympics, 52.01 seconds, was the exact time which qualified the last of the women from the heats of the 400m at the world championships currently being held in London.
Her winning time 53 years ago was faster than the victorious time in the 2017 Australian championships 400m final and faster than Aussie Morgan Mitchell could manage (52.22) in being run out in the heats of the 400m in London on the weekend.
Cuthbert's death in Perth was confirmed on Monday. She was 79.
The four-time Olympic gold medallist so often seemed to be left out of discussions whenever someone tried to untangle who deserved to be Australia's greatest athlete or sportswoman.
But Cuthbert's feat in winning a gold medal at the Olympics at 100m, 200m and 400m resonates down the ages.
Unwilling in the past few decades to put herself out there for comment on the Olympic issues of the day and content to live a quiet life after being diagnosed with multiple sclerosis in 1969, Cuthbert was a shy, smiling figure from a gentler time when sport was all about performance.
One of only two Australians to win an Olympic 100m track title - Marjorie Jackson Nelson was the first in 1952 - Cuthbert was added to the international athletics hall of fame in 2012.
Australia's Olympic athletics successes in the 1950s and 1960s came in eras when doping and sports science were not as prominent as they became. But many from the era say it was all the result of hard training not always undertaken by our best modern track athletes.
Australia's foremost Olympics historian, the late Harry Gordon, wrote that Cuthbert regarded her 1964 gold medal as "a far greater triumph than any of her three in 1956''.
Cuthbert had won the 100m and 200m double at the 1956 Melbourne Olympics when aged 18 and was also a member of Australia's winning 4x100m relay team.
Prevented by injury from competing at the 1960 Rome Olympic Games, she retired but came back to tailor a training preparation aimed at the 400m, which had been added to the Tokyo Olympics program.
"I once as asked Betty how she would like to be remembered and she said, 'I never want to be forgotten','' said Australian teammate Marlene Mathews, who finished third behind Cuthbert in the 100m and 200m at the 1956 Olympics.
"I have never met anyone that had such great faith and determination. It was this faith that kept her going for so long and through the most difficult times.''
In 2000, Cuthbert was pushed in a wheelchair by multiple Olympic medallist Raelene Boyle on a leg of the Sydney Games torch relay.
They were part of a chain commemorating 100 years of female competition at the Olympic Games in which the flame was also carried by Dawn Fraser, Shirley Strickland de la Hunty, Shane Gould and Debbie Flintoff-King.
They brought the Olympic flame to Cathy Freeman, the last recipient, who lit the cauldron.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuthbert</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raelene Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Morgan Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawn Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shirley Strickland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marjorie Jackson Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlene Mathews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Gould</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debbie Flintoff-King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
