<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442378909681249</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/politics/asylum-seeker-found-dead-in-manus-island-transit-facility/news-story/76115a8f589bb0c27628f307b3fcdc9a</url>
  <title>Asylum seeker found dead in Manus Island transit facility</title>
  <content>
Sanitation Services Cut Off Inside Manus Island Compound Set to be Demolished, Refugees Claim. Credit - Anonymous via Storyful
0:37

Protests inside Australia's offshore detention centre on Manus Island were triggered on August 1 after essential services such as power and sanitation were cut off in alleged move to coerce residents to vacate the compound. Residents of the Foxtrot compound inside the Manus Island Regional Processing Centre have faced increasing pressure from centre management to relocate before its planned closure on October 31. Refugees and activists claimed that operators switched off power and water to the facility, in a bid to hasten its departure so the compound could be demolished. As well as power and water, refugees said sanitation and cleaning services have ceased, leading to overflowing bins. A letter sent out to detainees from centre management said residents are "personally liable for any risk associated with residing or entering Foxtrox compound." Foxtrot is one of many compounds being occupied by the 800-plus refugees and asylum seekers who have been denied entry to Australia. Residents fear that if PNG Immigration and the Australian Border Force are able to successfully force residents out, then the Mike, Oscar, and Delta compounds would also be vulnerable. Although Papua New Guinea authorities have organised alternative accommodation in East Lorengau, a settlement in the Manus township, Foxtrot residents have expressed concerns for their safety - especially after three men were allegedly attacked with machetes and left seriously injured over the weekend. Credit: Anonymous via Storyful

August 2nd 2017
5 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

An Iranian man, who was seeking asylum in Australia, has taken his own life on Manus Island. Picture: Brian Cassey

Kevin Nguyen, Claire BickersNews Corp Australia Network

Share

AN asylum seeker on Manus Island has been found dead.
It's understood the Iranian man, who was seeking asylum in Australia, took his own life.
The Department of Immigration and Border Protection has yet to confirm the incident but Sky News reports the man was found dead in a new transit facility on the island.
It's understood he had suffered from mental health issues.
Refugees and asylum seekers inside the centre confirmed the incident to News Corp.
It's understood the man's family has not yet been informed.
Immigration Minister Peter Dutton has been contacted for comment.
Refugees waiting for resettlement in the United States were told to move to the transit centre last month as preparations begin for the main detention centre to shut down by October.

An Iranian man, who was seeking asylum in Australia, has taken his own life on Manus Island. Picture: Brian CasseySource:News Corp Australia
Their re-settlement has been at the centre of a leaked phone call from the White House between President Donald Trump and Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull.

During the heated January 28 phone call, revealed in full by the Washington Post on Friday last week, Mr Turnbull corralled the new president into endorsing the refugee deal.
The prime minister assured Mr Trump the United States was not obliged to accept a single refugee, needing only to process those held in detention to honour the bargain.
Mr Turnbull admitted Australia would rather take some of America's most "unattractive guys" rather than a Nobel Peace Prize winner who came by boat. The president praised Mr Turnbull for being "worse than I am" on rejecting refugees, but bemoaned the agreement.
Mr Trump described the agreement as "a horrible deal, a disgusting deal" which would make him look like a "dope" and a weak and ineffective leader. The agreement, struck with the Obama administration, involved the US accepting up to 1250 refugees held on Manus Island and Nauru, in return for Australia taking asylum seekers from Central America.
More than 1600 refugees have expressed interest in the US resettlement deal, which is expected to offer about 1200 places.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Nguyen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island Regional Processing Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Cassey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Border Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire BickersNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian CasseySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Lorengau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Cut Off Inside Manus Island Compound Set</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtrox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nobel Peace Prize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
