<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442507758701776</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/world/pressure-builds-on-netanyahu-as-former-staffer-agrees-to-testify-in-graft-probe-20170806-gxqlzl.html</url>
  <title>Pressure builds on Netanyahu as former staffer agrees to testify in graft probe </title>
  <content>
Jerusalem: Political cartoons depict flames licking at the foundations of the fortresslike household of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. Commentators say the noose is tightening around his neck.
For months, Netanyahu has been under investigation in two separate, leak-ridden graft cases involving illicit gifts from wealthy friends and back-room dealings with a local newspaper magnate in a bid for favourable coverage. The latest blow came just before the weekend, when the Israeli police signed a state's witness deal with Ari Harow, Netanyahu's former chief of staff and once one of his closest confidants.Photo: AP
A day earlier, in a legal document pertaining to the negotiations with Harow, the police said in writing, for the first time, that Netanyahu was suspected of bribery, as well as fraud and breach of trust.
In light of these developments, analysts say, it appears likely that Israel's longest-serving prime minister after David Ben-Gurion will ultimately face charges, injecting his fourth term with a new level of turbulence and intrigue. The question now, his critics say, is how long he can stave off what they view as his looming political demise.

"Ari Harow signed a state's witness agreement because he has something to tell," Sima Kadmon, a prominent political columnist, wrote in the Yedioth Ahronoth newspaper on Sunday. If the authorities were prepared to let Harow, who was facing trial in a case involving his private business interests, off so lightly with six months' community service and a fine, Kadmon said, "then Netanyahu is already a dead man walking."
Earlier reports from Israel by police conducting the investigation. Police wish to ask questions over gift giving to Mr Netanyahu's family by friends such as Mr Packer and Hollywood tycoon Arnon Milchan. 
Any actual indictment could still be many months off, and most analysts, including Kadmon, doubt that Netanyahu, a political survivor who has vehemently denied any wrongdoing, will be going anywhere soon.
Under Israeli law, a prime minister does not have to resign even if convicted, said Professor Barak Medina, an expert in constitutional law at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem. If the police recommended filing charges, the state prosecutor and attorney general would still have to agree, after granting the prime minister a hearing. There is no precedent in Israel for a sitting prime minister being charged.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Still, if the police were to recommend serious charges, like bribery, against Netanyahu, it would be "hard to survive," Medina said, because the political and public pressure would grow.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hebrew University of Jerusalem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yedioth Ahronoth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerusalem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ari Harow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Ben Gurion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kadmon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netanyahu</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Barak Medina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Netanyahu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sima Kadmon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnon Milchan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
