<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442460514060908</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/chris-judd-column-tackling-the-hard-questions-on-tackling-20170807-gxqrjn.html</url>
  <title>Chris Judd column: Tackling the hard questions on tackling</title>
  <content>
Of all the skills that have improved at AFL level over the last decade, tackling is the one that stands out the most.
The attention tackling was given during the week was often no more than a pre-game reminder at the turn of the millennium, however today it's considered every bit as important as kicking and handballing. There are specialist coaches employed by various clubs, and it's reviewed by the coaches just as diligently as any other skill.

Up Next

Dockers end their losing streak

01:30

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 20

It's all about the six pointers; Hannebery through traffic kicks a ripper, Coniglio has a claim to GOTY in Canberra, McDonald-Tipungwuti nutmegs Petrevski-Seton at the G, Billings clutch kick against West Coast and Eddie Betts is back from surgery to work his usual magic from the pocket.

One of the consequences of the improvement in tackling execution has been that some people feel the game's not as skilful as it was a decade ago. My firm belief is that were today's players given the same amount of time to make decisions as their predecessors then a steady improvement in skill level around the ground would be clear to see. The quick handballs in close that teams like Sydney and the Western Bulldogs use to evade tackle pressure has been an unforeseen benefit of better tackling skills in the AFL.
There have, however, been some unfortunate consequences from clubs' increased focus on tackling. Namely, the number of players getting knocked out after being tackled to the ground and having their head contact the playing surface, often while their arms are pinned.Photo: AAP
The two most recent examples to come under scrutiny have been Patty Dangerfield's tackle on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer and on Saturday night, Brodie Grundy's tackle on the Kangaroos' Ben Brown.
Both these tackles saw the recipients suffer concussion, after they were driven into the ground. But they were different examples to the dangerous tackles of the last couple of years where players were almost picked up and slung around into the turf. In both cases Brown and Kreuzer had some momentum moving forward and it's reasonable to assume the tacklers were trying to turn them so as not to give away a free kick for in the back.

There is a duty of care explicit today that the tackler, particularly if the arms are pinned, doesn't use excessive force causing the head to contact the ground. This all sounds completely reasonable on paper, but when you're tackling a professional athlete who weighs 100 kilograms, if you don't put as much force as you possibly can into the tackle, he is usually able to stay on his feet and still dispose of the football, or worse still evade the tackle all together.
Currently, if there haven't been two distinct actions like the sling tackle, and if the player being tackled already has forward momentum, it doesn't feel fair that the tackler be held to account for consequences that can't be easily predicted. But on the other hand, in a game where head high contact is forbidden, it doesn't seem fair that players be carried off on a stretcher after having their arms pinned in a tackle as they're forced to ground. Therein lies the conundrum for the AFL.Photo: AAP
There must be an acceptance that in a contact sport occasionally there will be concussions caused by accidental incidents. Dangerfield's suspension for his tackle of Kreuzer wasn't a malicious act, he wouldn't have intended to cause harm to Kreuzer and he was tackling a much bigger man so it is natural that he applied a significant amount of force to ensure the tackle stuck.
The ramifications for Dangerfield's suspension were significant, he missed an important game against Sydney and is now out of the running for the Brownlow. However, those ramifications aren't nearly as significant as those experienced by players who retire after multiple concussions and face the potential risk of long-term health consequences.
As the player who is being tackled can't modify their behaviour to reduce these risks (they're already trying to avoid being knocked out) the only person the AFL can target to modify behaviour and in turn reduce the risks of head trauma is the tackler.
You feel for the players, who are under pressure from their clubs and supporters to tackle with intensity but are now forced to ensure there's not enough vigour in the tackle for opponents to hurt themselves. In time, tackling techniques will modify and improve again, but you get  the feeling there'll be a few more unlucky players serving suspensions along the way.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patty Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Photos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Judd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
