<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442344549942303</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/amazons-australian-launch-everything-we-know-so-far/</url>
  <title>Amazon's Australian Launch: Everything We Know So Far</title>
  <content>
Amazon is  - which means you will soon be able to buy everything from food to electronics without paying those exorbitant international shipping fees. Here's everything we know about Amazon's arrival Down Under so far.

When is Amazon coming to Australia?

Amazon Australia's launch date remains shrouded in mystery. However, all signs point towards .

Where will Amazon operate from?

As reported last week, Amazon will kick off its local presence with . The flagship facility will be located in the Pellicano's M2 Industry Park, providing easy access to the South Gippsland Highway, Monash Highway and Eastlink.

How many products will Amazon sell?

Amazon's  has promised "hundreds of thousands of products". However, it's not entirely clear whether this number relates to individual product types or total available stock across all categories. The latter seems more likely, but we're pretty sure the selection will be pretty big regardless.

What kind of products will Amazon sell?

Amazon is keeping tight-lipped on precisely what it will actually be selling in Australia.  reckons it will start with books, electronics and clothing.

Food delivery also appears to be a priority, with Amazon's former global logistics senior manager, Brittain Ladd . This is backed up by  who is currently currently director of consumables for Amazon Germany.

How fast will products be delivered?

Speed is . If it can beat local retailers on delivery time as well as price, the battle is basically over.

According to Ladd, Amazon will be launching an Australian version of its premium Prime Now service, which provides faster shipping to members alongside other perks. Amazon has also promised "fast delivery" as one of its core strategies.

There's still no word on whether Amazon will be bringing in its own courier service or relying on third parties for delivery. Either way, its entry Down Under is sure to put existing supply chains and logistics providers .

Where curious to hear what your thoughts are on Amazon's imminent launch down under. What are you most excited about? Tell us in the poll below!

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LADD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pellicano's M2 Industry Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon's Australian Launch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Gippsland Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everything We Know So Far</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brittain Ladd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
