<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442417564387416</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/antipokies-group-wants-whitehorses-leading-pokie-venue-to-be-closed-after-punters-pour-in-almost-16-million/news-story/19fc6a33bd15fb5d6b2715b4701a0795</url>
  <title>Calls for pokie venue to be shut down</title>
  <content>
A LEADING anti-pokies group has called for The Chase Hotel to close down its pokies after it was revealed almost $16 million was poured into its machines in a year.
Data from the Victorian Commission for Gambling and Liquor Regulation showed The Chase Hotel was the twelfth most lucrative pokies venue in the state out of 502 venues.
It has prompted the Alliance for Gambling Reform director Tom Costello to take a swipe at the "strong link" between lucrative pokies venues and their proximity to major shopping centres.
He said The Chase Hotel was on the top floor of the Forest Hill Chase shopping centre, which covered more than 63,000 square metres and generated sales in excess of $300 million a year.
"The owner of Forest Hill Chase, US private equity firm Blackstone, should think about buying The Chase Hotel and closing down the pokies which are taking money out of the pockets of shoppers," Mr Costello said.
In the past financial year, punters spent $15,978,991 on the The Chase's 90 pokie machines.
Mr Costello said pokies venues inside shopping centres like The Chase and the Epping Plaza Hotel are "something planners should never have allowed".
"This confirms once again that pokies venues are extra dangerous when they are located near major shopping centres," Mr Costello said.
The Chase Hotel opened in 1995 after a long community campaign against it, spearheaded by former anti-gambling group Salt Shakers, was unsuccessful.
In a 1998 report Salt Shakers noted pokies located near shopping centres were "totally unacceptable" as "the person shopping with housekeeping money is at greater risk when the gaming venue is situated near the shops". Almost $53 million was spent on 431 pokie machines in Whitehorse in the past financial year - or about $145,000 a day.
According to the Alliance for Gambling Reform, of which Whitehorse is a supporter, the losses equated to approximately $389 for every adult in the municipality.
Punters tipped in $10,441,769 at the Burvale Hotel, followed by $8,843,662 at Box Hill RSL sub-branch, $7,775,997 at the Blackburn Hotel, $6,767,848 at the Mitcham Hotel and $3,076,022 at the Box Hill Golf Club.
If you or someone you know has a gambling problem, visit gamblinghelponline.org.au or phone 1800 858 858.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liquor Regulation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gambling Reform</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chase's 90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackburn Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chase Hotel</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forest Hill Chase</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epping Plaza Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Costello</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burvale Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Shaker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitcham Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehorse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
