<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442469103995640</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/13/11/sydney-tent-city-back-and-forth-continues</url>
  <title>Sydney tent city back-and-forth continues</title>
  <content>
A federal Labor senator has criticised the NSW top cop for his comments about Sydney's tent city in Martin Place as the war of words continues between all sides and tiers of government.
Federal opposition spokesman for homelessness Doug Cameron took aim at the NSW Police Chief Mick Fuller for his comments on the makeshift camp.
"Commissioner Fuller summed up the awful situation in Martin Place with all the nuance and appreciation of a complex social problem you might expect of a career policeman," Senator Cameron said in a speech at the launch of National Homelessness week on Monday.
Mr Fuller on Friday added his voice to those of Social Housing Minister Pru Goward urging Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore to "step up" and resolve the issue after a meeting at Sydney Town Hall.
"At the end of the day council has the power to remove their property. If you don't have a bed, if you don't have a tent it will be very difficult to stay there long term," Mr Fuller told reporters.
Senator Cameron questioned why the NSW Police Commissioner was commenting.
"I'm sure Mr Fuller is a very fine police officer with a distinguished record of service, but why would we seek his advice - why would he even offer it - on a complex social problem that is clearly beyond his area of expertise."

Related Articles

Senator Cameron also criticised the level of discussion around homelessness in Australia.
"It would seem the reason is because it is almost impossible to have a public discussion about high visibility homelessness other than as a municipal hygiene problem or a law and order problem or a problem of homeless peoples' own making," he said.
He said that one of the main causes of homelessness was the same housing market dysfunction that was hurting first home buyers.
Meanwhile NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian warned on Monday that if City of Sydney did not remove the camp, the government would intervene.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Homelessness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fuller</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Chief Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cameron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Housing Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doug Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
