<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442426154322149</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/rising-star-re-signs-for-titans/3209581/</url>
  <title>Rising star re-signs for Titans</title>
  <content>
THE Titans have scored a retention coup by signing rising star Morgan Boyle for a further three seasons, locking the hulking forward up until the end of 2020.
Boyle, who joined the Gold Coast from Canberra last year as part of their under-20 program, made his NRL debut in Round 6 against his old club and has played 12 games this year despite being on a second-tier deal.
The 197cm, 100kg second-rower's improvement has been exponential and the Titans were desperate to extend his contract.
They had to fight significant interest from several clubs though, including the Wests Tigers, who were understood to have been chasing the 21-year-old as late as last week before he signed with the Titans.
Boyle is understood to have signed a significantly upgraded three-year deal.
Boyle is the latest part of the puzzle for the Titans, who have several members of their pack locked up until at least 2019, including Ryan James, Jarrod Wallace, Kevin Proctor and Nathan Peats.
Fellow young gun Max King extended his deal with the Titans to the end of 2019.
The Titans are also expected to announce the signatures of forwards Jai Arrow and Brenton Lawrence in the coming days.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boyle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jai Arrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Peats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brenton Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Proctor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
