<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442421859354809</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/albert-park-stunner-soars-while-first-timers-buy-along-the-bay/news-story/57d85561b47731b1d677e2138d856363</url>
  <title>Albert Park stunner soars while first timers buy along the bay - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, sold for $5 million under the hammer.

STRONG demand in the premium market saw an Albert Park stunner surge to a top price, while first-home buyers were out in force along the bay.
The modernised Art Deco property at notched one of the weekend's loftiest prices when it sold for $5 million, while first timers won the keys at auctions in Parkdale and Frankston.
They were among 907 auctions across Melbourne last week, with CoreLogic recording a preliminary clearance rate of 75.7 per cent.
RELATED:
RELATED:

Demand was strong demand in Albert Park's premium market.

Two families fought it out for the three-bedroom Herbert St property, which had a reserve price of $4.6 million, according to Hocking Stuart, Albert Park, director David Wood.
"The two competing parties were families from Brighton and Balwyn, with the keys going to the bidder from Balwyn," he said.
Mr Wood said the strong outcome was a partially the result of pent up demand at the top end of the market.
"There is serious demand in that $5 million to $10 million range in both Albert Park and Middle Park," he said.
"These properties are tightly held, with only half a dozen hitting the market every year, so when they do come up they are always well received."

, sold to a first-home buyer for $660,000.

At the other end of the scale, a first-home buyer won the keys to a Parkdale villa unit when it sold for $660,000 under the hammer.
The property at , was called on the market at $600,000, according to Advantage Property Consulting director Frank Valentic.
"Villas are the jewel of the apartment market," he said. "The offer a bit of land and single level living."

The open-plan kitchen, meals and living room in the Parkdale unit.

Mr Valentic said two bidders, both first-home buyers, contested the auction, held by Hocking Stuart, Mentone.
"We have seen a definite come back from first-home buyers," Mr Valentic said.
"There are out and about at a lot of auctions. Investors have ducked for cover with changes from banks and laws."

, sold under the hammer for $735,000.

First-home buyers were also out in force further down the bay where a four-bedroom house at , sold for $735,000.
Mr Valentic said the Frankston market was going from strength to strength, having undergone a 30 per cent lift in house prices this year.
"Houses are going up $10,000 a month," he said.
"It's pretty hard for first-home buyers to save that each month for a deposit."

The property was offered to Advantage Property Consulting for $680,000 earlier this year.

Interestingly, Mr Valentic said Advantage Property Consulting was offered the property at the start of the year for $680,000, but they didn't have a buyer at the time.
He said the auction result meant the house had grown $55,000 in value in six months.
"The market is moving like a freight train," Mr Valentic said.
"I would encourage first-home buyers to push themselves because it's not going to get any cheaper."
O'Brien, Chelsea, sold the property.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balwyn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkdale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Park</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Deco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herbert St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAVID WOOD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advantage Property Consulting</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Valentic</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mentone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hocking Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Valentic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
