<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442417564387436</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/british-model-home-after-milan-kidnapping/news-story/587835eef4369e9d65b27f1d2508b76c</url>
  <title>British model home after Milan kidnapping</title>
  <content>
A 20-year-old British model who was allegedly kidnapped in Milan and detained for six days while her captor tried to sell her on an online auction site has reportedly returned to the UK.
The woman, named in reports as Chloe Ayling, was attacked on July 11 by two men as she attended an arranged photo shoot.
She is believed to have been drugged and transported in a bag to Borgial, an isolated village near Turin, before being released on July 17, Italian police said.
According to reports, Ms Ayling arrived back at her home in Coulsdon, south London, on Sunday, where she said she feared for her life during the "terrifying experience".
A Polish man, who lives in Britain, was arrested on July 18 on suspicion of kidnap and extortion, state police said.
Officials have released a mugshot of the suspect, named as 30-year-old Lukasz Pawel Herba.
The National Crime Agency (NCA) said it has been assisting with the investigation.
"The NCA and the East Midlands Special Operations Unit (Emsou) have been working closely with the Italian authorities since the kidnap was reported," a spokesman said.
"A house in the Oldbury area linked to Lukasz Pawel Herba was searched on July 18 by Emsou officers with assistance from West Midlands Police.
"Computer equipment seized is being forensically examined."
It's alleged the men tried to sell Ayling online for more than $US300,000 ($A377,670) and demanded the model's agent pay to secure her safe release.
She was kept handcuffed to furniture but was freed after six days and taken to the British consulate in Milan, despite the ransom not being paid, police said.
It has been reported the captor demanded 50,000 pounds upon her release and threatened to kill her if she told police about the incident.
Milan police officer Lorenzo Bucossi told reporters the group the suspect was allegedly working for offered "mercenary services" on the dark web.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ayling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borgial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oldbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Midlands Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Midlands Special Operations Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMSOU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Ayling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Crime Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lukasz Pawel Herba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorenzo Bucossi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coulsdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$300,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
