<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442301600268621</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/cricket/indias-ravindra-jadeja-suspended-for-one-test-after-dangerous-throw-against-sri-lanka/news-story/978979d57735f215c2a9fd92d8810e56</url>
  <title>India's matchwinner picks up one-Test ban</title>
  <content>
INDIA spinner Ravindra Jadeja has been suspended for the third and final Test against Sri Lanka after accumulating six demerit points over a 24-month period.
Jadeja was named man-of-the-match for the second Test after scoring 70 with the bat in the first innings and picking up five wickets in Sri Lanka's final innings to lead India to a series-clinching victory in Colombo.
The 28-year-old had entered the match with three demerit points that he picked up for running down the middle of the pitch while batting during the Indore Test against New Zealand in October 2016.

Cricket: Ravi Jadeja has been rubbed out of the Third Test between Sri Lanka and India.

Jadeja suspended for throw
LIVE stream Sri Lanka v India on FOX SPORTS. Get a free 2-week Foxtel Now trial & stream LIVE within minutes.
RECORD CHASERS:
OLD TRAFFORD:
He was handed a further three demerit points in the second Test against Sri Lanka for an incident on Saturday when he fielded the ball off his own bowling and threw it back at batsman Malinda Pushpakumara, who had not left his crease.
The ICC said that Jadeja breached article 2.2.8 of the player's code of conduct which prohibits "throwing a ball (or any other item of cricket equipment such as a water bottle) at or near a player... in an inappropriate and/or dangerous manner during an International Match".
He was fined 50 per cent of his match fee, the ICC added.
ICC rules state that crossing the four demerit points threshold results in two suspension points.
The ICC said that two suspension points equate to a ban from one test or two ODIs or two T20Is, whatever comes first.
As such, Jadeja will miss the third Test that will take place from August 12-16. The sport's governing body said that Jadeja had admitted to the offence and accepted the sanction and therefore, there was no need for a formal hearing.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malinda Pushpakumara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indore Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ravi Jadeja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ravindra Jadeja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ODIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jadeja</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Match</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Third Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T20Is</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trafford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
