<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442421859354760</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/poker-machines-losing-their-shine-as-spending-drops-to-10year-low-in-moreland/news-story/44fa00a66015d403a916872e7722cb72</url>
  <title>Tide turning on pokies in Moreland</title>
  <content>
ACTIVE anti-pokies campaigning has been credited for slowly turning the tide on pokies losses in Moreland.
Latest Victorian Commission for Gambling and Liquor Regulation figures show that pokies losses for Moreland, while still among the worst 25 per cent across the state, are the lowest they have been for ten years.
In Moreland gamblers lost $61.6 million over the 2016/17 financial year, down $10.2 million from the 2006/07 losses of $71.8 million.

Less people are playing but the ones that play are losing a lot more. - Gabi Byrne, Free Yourself Program director
Moreland Mayor Helen Davidson said the council was actively informing the community about the harm caused by poker machines in recent years and had taken a stand through the planning scheme to prevent and increase in the number of machines in the municipality.
"We are a proud and leading partner in the Alliance for Gambling Reform and believe we are making a real difference not just locally but at a state and national level." Cr Davidson said.
Gabi Byrne, the director of Free Yourself Program, a self-help group for problem gamblers, said the alliance's "The Pokies Play You" campaign last year and screenings of the anti-pokies documentary Ka-Ching! Pokie Nation  had contributed to the growing insight into the harmful nature of the pokies gambling industry.
●
But Ms Byrne said while overall losses were down in Moreland, the harm from pokies was still felt intensely by addicted patrons.
"Less people are playing but the ones that play are losing a lot more," Ms Byrne said.
She said many young people were gambling via other avenues such as online sports betting but the majority of problem gamblers she saw were still addicted pokies players.
One recent client, a single mother with two children, was struggling to keep a roof over her head after re-mortgaging her home twice to play pokies.
She said people should have as much empathy for pokies addicts as drug addicts as the chemical release in the brain from playing pokies affected gamblers in a similar way to cocaine and other drugs.
Meanwhile, Moreland Council's Supreme Court appeal against an increase in the number of pokie machines at the Glenroy RSL will be going ahead on October 10.
The RSL is seeking an extra 10 machines to add to 40 already on site.
●
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liquor Regulation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Byrne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gambling Reform</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ka-ching</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland Council's Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenroy RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pokies Play You</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Free Yourself Program</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland Mayor Helen Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabi Byrne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
