<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442301600268667</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/debris-hurtles-towards-motorists-in-terrifying-mot/3209568/</url>
  <title>Debris hurtles towards motorists in terrifying motorway moment</title>
  <content>
TERRIFYING dash cam footage has captured the moment debris was sent hurtling into the path of oncoming traffic on the Sunshine Motorway.

Rick Piccinich uploaded the harrowing footage to Dash Cam Owners Australia on Friday, as he headed southbound just past the Mudjimba exit.

Mr Piccinich explained how he helped avoid a disastrous crash, by "following protocol".

"I... instinctively activated my hazard lights in a nanosecond," he said.

"I checked my rear vision mirror, noticed the vehicle behind me getting closer and then observe and react to the obstacles which were now clearly visible ahead to him and other drivers.

"I have observed many times now where this action had averted collision/s with vehicles and every time this happens, risk of injury is dramatically reduced.

"Hasn't seemed to (have) caught on yet, but surely hope it does for everyone's safety."

The footage appears to show a work van and white hatchback avoiding debris flicked up off the road which looks to have come from a caravan pulled up on the shoulder of the motorway further ahead.

The van passes over some of the debris which flies through the air past Mr Piccinich's car.

Heavy rain misses most of Coast
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
A breakthrough victory at the CrossFit Games.
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dash Cam Owners Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Piccinich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Piccinich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mudjimba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
