<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442550708375156</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/craigieburn-man-torn-over-christian-values-while-competing-on-australian-survivor/news-story/fb4f5c3d8a2b5ea74d9809ec5b3908b8</url>
  <title>Stepping out of comfort zone for Survivor</title>
  <content>
JERICHO Malabonga thought a childhood spent outdoors would help prepare him for the toughest game on TV.
But the Craigieburn man admits he was well out of his element on the new series of Australian Survivor.
For 55 days, 24 contestants will endure a climate of torrential rain and extreme humidity in Samoa to outwit, outplay and outlast each other in a bid to take home $500,000.
Mr Malabonga, a flight attendant, said it was the hardest physical and mental challenge he had faced.
"Being a Kiwi, we love camping outdoors and we are use to doing things rough but not this rough, "he said.
"I went there with nothing more than the clothes off my back. It was as raw and real as you will get and absolutely brutal."
Mr Malabonga said he was also torn at times when it came to his Christian values.
"I wanted to be myself but at the same time play a really strong, social and strategic game," he said.
"I hold dear my principles and values but you are in game where people are deceiving and lying to you."
Mr Malabonga, a fan of the show, said despite the harsh conditions the experience had been life-changing.
"I love the game and the social component of it and I've grown a lot as person through the whole process," he said.
Survivor airs on Channel 10 Sunday-Tuesday from 7.30pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JERICHO Malabonga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigieburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Malabonga</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10 Sunday-Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
