<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442859946024309</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/man-injured-on-coast-work-site-to-be-airlifted-to-/3209593/</url>
  <title>UPDATE: Man injured on Coast work site airlifted to hospital</title>
  <content>
UPDATE: A 42-YEAR-OLD man injured by an excavator wasn't meant to be working today, his colleague has said.

James McKenzie was seriously injured by a three-tonne excavator at a building site on Riverstone Ct, Noosaville just before 1pm today.

Colleague Cole Parker said Mr McKenzie was called in to help on site by the advice of a fellow tradesman working on the building.

"He wasn't meant to be here today, he was meant to be on a day off," Mr Parker said.

"Now this has happened to him and he wasn't meant to be here. It's no good. He's ended up all mangled in the excavator. We don't know what's going to happen to him.

"He was a good guy."

Mr Parker said work has stopped on site and will remain closed until further notice while workplace health and safety assesses the situation.

"We've got to shut down, we'll have workplace health and safety here soon," Mr Parker said.

Mr Parker said the Life Flight helicopter couldn't land safely near the site.

Ambulances transported Mr McKenzie to Noosa Hospital where the Life Flight helicopter landed and took off on the helipad. 

UPDATE: PARAMEDICS treating a man injured by an excavator will meet a rescue helicopter at Noosa Hospital.

The man in his 40s is currently being transported to the chopper in an ambulance.

He is suffering from leg fractures and a hip injury and will be taken to a hospital in Brisbane.

EARLIER: A MAN injured on a Coast construction site will be airlifted to hospital.

Ambulance crews are currently on scene at a Riverstone Ct, Tewantin address with man, in his 40s, who is suffering leg fractures and a hip injury.

Reports indicate he was injured by an excavator.

A Queensland Ambulance spokesperson said it was likely the man would be airlifted to a Brisbane hospital.

BREAKING: PARAMEDICS have rushed to a construction site after a man was reportedly injured by a piece of machinery.

Emergency services were called to a Riverstone Ct address in Tewantin about 12.50pm and one ambulance crew is currently on scene.

The man is currently being assessed for injuries.

More to come.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverstone Ct</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Parker</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McKenzie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YEAR-OLD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cole Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Flight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
