<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442683852362941</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/lifestyle/liberal-party-mps-to-debate-samesex-marriage-free-vote-in-party-room-meeting/news-story/205ed73cbc3d188e48c01f2bc5608a2f</url>
  <title>Liberals' fake display of business-as-usual</title>
  <content>
A TENSE special meeting of Liberal MPs on same-sex marriage this afternoon will have to be monitored from a distance.
Sergeant-at-Arms James Catchpole has declined to relax rules which keep news cameras and reporters well back from the meeting room and the comings and goings of those attending about 4pm today.
In fact, the entire day has been planned as an attempt to display business-as-usual, despite the obvious fact the events surrounding it are unprecedented.
There will be close attention paid to body language as Liberal MPs - from same-sex marriage opponent Tony Abbott to supporter Trent Zimmerman - join Senate colleagues including critic Eric Abetz and rebel Dean Smith.
But the debate won't start there.
Cabinet met this morning to establish what will be taken to the special meeting and the prospect is for a return to attempts to pass legislation for a national ballot - a plebiscite - on the issue.
Parliament rejected the idea last November but a section of the Liberal Party argues it was an election policy and cannot be abandoned without betraying voters.
One point to be discussed is the strong possibility the Parliament will again reject the ballot. There also will be discussion of a compromise ballot through the mail system, as proposed by Immigration Minister Peter Dutton.
The options backed by Cabinet will also have to be endorsed by the backbench at the meeting this afternoon.
At the meeting, West Australian Senator Dean Smith, a gay man, will call for a free vote on a bill for marriage equality he has drawn up and distributed to colleagues.
"I will respect the decision of my colleagues if they choose to continue with a plebiscite position, but I will use my privileges as a backbench senator to introduce my bill to the Senate this week," Senator Smith has said.
However, the proposed changes to the Marriage Act would most likely be introduced in the House of Representatives, which has greater authority than the Senate.
Senator Smith will not be alone in urging a conscience vote. Others include at least five MPs who have supported him - Victorian Tim Wilson, Trent Zimmerman and John Alexander of NSW and Trevor Evans and Warren Entsch of Queensland.
Those calling for a reboot of the plebiscite policy will include Mr Abbott and Craig Kelly of NSW, Mr Abetz of Tasmania and Zed Seselja of the ACT.
Whatever comes from that meeting will be further discussed tomorrow at the joint-party meeting with the Nationals which is the usual start of a sitting week.
Whether the $160 million plebiscite plan gets up or is shelved, its backers will argue it was the fairest way to settle the matter, and will accuse opponents, including the Labor Opposition, of scuttling the best chance for marriage equality.
If the postal ballot is approved, it I'll be condemned as an expensive - estimates range from $40 million to $100 million - voluntary opinion poll which would not bind MPs to the result and would be vulnerable to tampering and delivery mix-ups.
Labor would be drawn into the tension should a Liberal in the House of Representatives introduce Senator Smith's bill there.
Labor MPs have been told they must vote for a suspension of standing orders to allow the introduction of the Smith bill. But they would have a free vote on the bill itself should it proceed.
There could be MPs on both sides who cross the floor to vote against their parties on same-sex marriage.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abetz of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zed Seselja of the ACT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Alexander of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Kelly of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant-at-Arms James Catchpole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
