<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442722507069160</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/bush-beat-exraider-tom-learoydlahrs-making-invaluable-impact-at-north-tamworth/news-story/bf3bb9e31ea7414472dd6a2c9ccbc06a</url>
  <title>Ex-Raider propels North Tamworth league</title>
  <content>
FORMER NRL forward Tom Learoyd-Lahrs isn't playing for North Tamworth this season but he is still having a profound impact on the club.
After guiding his hometown Bears to the Group 4 premiership last year, Learoyd-Lahrs has turned his attention to coaching the under 14s team.
The ex-Canberra, Brisbane and Melbourne big man has also helped out with the first grade side, while he was a trainer for the Group 4 under 14 and 15s at the CRL Country Championships in Cessnock in July.
Learoyd-Lahrs has also presented welfare and education sessions with ex-NRL star and proud Dubbo product Andrew Ryan to all of the Northern Pool teams.
North Tamworth president Brad McManus says Learoyd-Lahrs' contribution has been invaluable.
"Tom is helping out and doing what he needs to do," McManus said.
"It is good to have him around the club. When he speaks, everyone listens."
North Tamworth moved a step closer to their fourth consecutive minor premiership with a comprehensive 44-18 victory over Gunnedah on Sunday.
The Bears have been hit hard with injuries this season, but they remain on top of the table thanks to the rise of a few rookies.
McManus believes the younger players have breathed life into North Tamworth this season.
"We've had six under 18s starting in first grade, but they are all good kids," he said.
"You have to look where the club is going to sit in the next four or five years.
"By the time they get to 21, they will be really good first grade footballers and that's if they don't move on and go elsewhere."
GORRELL TO RETIRE

AFTER more than 16 seasons and four clubs, Queanbeyan Kangaroos captain-coach Aaron Gorrell will hang up the boots at the end of the season.
Gorrell, 36, never thought his career would last this long due to a raft of injuries.
But the lure of reaching 100th first grade games for the Kangaroos was enough motivation for the ex-Broncos and Dragons hooker to keep playing.
"I'll play 100 games next weekend, but I didn't think I'd get there," Gorrell said.
"I wasn't going to go around again this year, but the club raised that record and I thought I could get there as long as I remained injury free.
"But this will definitely be my last year and hopefully we can go through to the grand final." The Queanbeyan Kangaroos are in second position with two rounds remaining in the regular season.
COUNTRY'S REAL HEROES

FORGET the on-field action - Country Rugby League wouldn't function without the game's countless volunteers.
The CRL honoured the hard work of many people at the Volunteer and Club of the Year awards in Sydney on Saturday night.
The Volunteer of the Year was awarded to Jeanette Hillier from the Glen Innes Magpies. Jeanette was nominated for her continued service to the game over the past 30 years, including positions in administration, coaching and refereeing while continuously serving as a Sports Trainer since 1992.
Jeanette is the current President of Group 19 Junior Rugby League and successfully combines this role with her position as Referees Coordinator for Glen Innes Junior Rugby League.
In the other awards, Susan Moodie from Western Suburbs Newcastle Schoolboys won the Women in League Achievement award, while the Carbonne United Roos claimed the Club of the Year.
NEXT GENERATION NRL STARS

Laurie Daley's hometown Junee played host to the next wave of future NRL stars at the 74th annual Riverina Schoolboys Carnival over the weekend.
Over 125 Country Rugby League club teams participated across 15 fields from the under 7s through to the under 14s on Saturday.
The Riverina League Tag Carnival will be contested on Sunday with over 40 teams and 61 games played. The CRL are well represented at the carnival with ex-NRL prop Roy Asotasi and Jillaroo Maddie Studdon present as NRL Ambassadors.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gorrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Innes Junior Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan Kangaroos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junior Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GORRELL TO RETIRE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referees Coordinator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club of the Year</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Tamworth</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverina Schoolboys Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carbonne United Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Pool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Rugby League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League Achievement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Learoyd-Lahrs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McManus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jillaroo Maddie Studdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Learoyd-Lahrs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeanette</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gorrell, 36</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GENERATION NRL STARS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volunteer of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Moodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverina League Tag Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REAL HEROES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Suburbs Newcastle Schoolboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gunnedah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Innes Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-Raider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Trainer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeanette Hillier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Asotasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRL Country Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Gorrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL Ambassadors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
