<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442808406416108</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/power-tool-theft-thieves-take-5000-worth-of-tools-from-outside-tradies-aspendale-gardens-home/news-story/6c34b81ee6035454564e7ec825e7c829</url>
  <title>$5000 tools gone in 60 seconds</title>
  <content>
SECURITY cameras have captured the moment thieves broke into a tradie's ute and stole about $5000 worth of power tools and test equipment.
The theft occurred in the early hours of this morning but victim Pete Boardman, director of PBE Electrical Group, only noticed the damage to the car as he left home to do the school drop-off.
Mr Boardman said he didn't hear a thing when the thieves targeted his car, parked outside his home on Sanctuary Place, Aspendale Gardens.

He believes they struck about 1.50am and may have been casing nearby streets before spotting his ute.
Mr Boardman said he had locked his car, including the back tray, but the thieves had broken the lock and took off with a kit bag containing power tools and some test equipment.
He has contacted police and will make a statement later this afternoon, but has already posted photos and CCTV footage on Facebook.
The businessman said he feels thankful the security cameras outside his home had captured the break-in.
"I'm encouraging all my neighbours to get CCTV now," Mr Boardman said.
"If we all have this security, we have more of a chance of catching the thieves.
"I've got a fleet of cars and they've been knocked over before, but never mine and never out the front of my place."
If you heard or saw anything suspicious in that area overnight, phone Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Boardman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete Boardman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PBE Electrical Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanctuary Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aspendale Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
