<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442821291318219</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:42</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/eltham-cfa-volunteers-say-working-relationship-with-career-fireys-has-broken-down/news-story/c629972ed550962c762e30a7ec656e33</url>
  <title>Fireys break ranks over 'toxic' split</title>
  <content>
A SPLINTER group of Eltham CFA volunteers says their relationship with career firefighters is so toxic they can no longer work or train with them.
Thirteen veteran Eltham volunteers have written to CFA chief officer Steve Warrington and Emergency Services Minister James Merlino saying "tensions between staff and volunteers have been increasing".
HAVE YOUR SAY: What do you think of the row? Tell us below.
They said that what used to be a "productive and harmonious environment is now substantially less".
"Some staff are refusing to interact with volunteers at all, either in a training capacity or even when simply on station, despite the best efforts of volunteers," the volunteers wrote.
The group says the entire Eltham brigade agreed it would be better if the volunteer fighters moved back to their old base.
They're urging the State Government and Nillumbik Mayor Peter Clarke to urgently stop the sale of their old station, saying they can no longer share their new $10.5 million station with career fireys.
The Eltham CFA moved from their old premises at 909 Main Rd to their new 24-hour station on Brougham St in late2015.
It's staffed by 30 career firefighters and 30 volunteers.
The State Government was set to sell the old site and approached Nillumbik Council to gauge its interest, according to Cr Clarke.
But the 13 volunteers say Eltham CFA members want to return to their old station if the Andrews Government merges paid and volunteer firefighters.
Integrated stations such as at Eltham are set to have CFA volunteers and the new Fire Rescue Victoria staff under the one roof under a proposed new law.
The letter, seen by the Leader, said it was agreed during a July brigade meeting of both paid and unpaid firefighters that if the new law went through, they will be left with an "unsustainable working environment."
"The former station could again be made a functional fire station with minimal requirements for facilities upgrades," the letter said.
The letter, though signed by just 13 members, says it reflects the views of all CFA volunteer firefighters at the station.
Cr Clarke said the council hoped to buy the station but would not step in the way of the volunteer firefighters.
He said the building could be used as council offices or public space, but no decision had been made.
A spokesman for Mr Merlino's office said no decision had been made on the sale of the old Eltham CFA building and the government was waiting on the findings of the select committee set up to consider submissions on the plan to merge fire services.
The committee's findings will be tabled in Parliament by tomorrow.
Eltham officer-in-charge Paul Elso told the Diamond Valley Leader, through CFA Media, that: "Whether you're a career or volunteer firefighter, our job is to protect our community. It's what we're doing today and what we're doing tomorrow."
CFA Media has been contacted for comment.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFA Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Rescue Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nillumbik Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Elso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Clarke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond Valley Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Services Minister James Merlino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham CFA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nillumbik Mayor Peter Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fireys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Warrington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brougham St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merlino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
