<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442722507069129</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/technology/social-media/twitter/twitter-bets-future-on-premium-video-despite-losing-nfl-rights-20170727-gxkg63</url>
  <title>Twitter bets future on premium video despite losing NFL rights</title>
  <content>
One of Twitter's top executives has brushed off the loss of broadcast rights for America's National Football League to tech rival Amazon, and said an increased focus on live video streaming services will be central to the company's latest push towards profitability.
Twitter's chief operating officer Anthony Noto, who also serves as its chief financial officer, said Thursday Night Football had been just the beginning of its live video strategy and that it has gone on a content binge. In the second quarter of 2017 it signed 40 new partnerships.
The former chief financial officer of the NFL and Goldman Sachs global co-head of technology, media and telecommunications investment banking, told The Australian Financial Review that while the NFL loss was a blow, it had a much broader plan for live broadcasting and now has deals with more than 200 content providers.
"We think it's always important to make sure we're with our advertisers and remind them of some important elements when they invest in Twitter," Mr Noto said.

"We have a very differentiated ability to do advertising with video - premium branded video."

The company streamed more than 1200 hours of live premium video in the second quarter, hitting 55 million unique viewers, up 22 per cent compared with the first quarter.
Twitter has content deals with the Women's National Basketball Association, Major League Baseball, PGA Tour, Bloomberg, BuzzFeed and more.
"We're trying to build an impactful company that maximises shareholder value. We're on a path to be able to achieve GAAP profitability at a specific revenue," Mr Noto said, but would not specify what that revenue number was.
Engagement with ads increases

Encouragingly for Twitter, which reported its second quarter financial results last week, engagement with ads has grown 95 per cent over the last year.
Unfortunately the loss-making company is facing challenges. Advertising revenue fell 8 per cent to $489 million in the second quarter, compared with a year earlier. Overall revenue was better than expected at $574 million. The company reported a loss in the quarter of $US116 million.
Twitter's total monthly active users (MAUs) were stagnant at 328 million over the three months to the end of June. However, it reported 12 per cent growth in daily active users.
RBC Capital Markets analyst Mark Mahaney said the monthly MAUs were an unexpectedly bad surprise, particularly in the light of recent product improvements and the widespread publicity the platform has enjoyed with the constant use by US President Donald Trump.

He said Google and Facebook were still taking massive chunks of the online advertising market and that Twitter was suffering in comparison to its larger rivals.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$116</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAUs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America's National Football League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Noto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League Baseball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PGA Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GAAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BuzzFeed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Noto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's National Basketball Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Mahaney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday Night Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBC Capital Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
