<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442898600730416</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/markets/wary-fundies-split-on-cbas-prospects-as-traders-wade-in-20170807-gxqpuy.html</url>
  <title>Wary fundies split on CBA's prospects as traders wade in</title>
  <content>
While short-term traders seemed to think enough damage had been done to Commonwealth Bank on Monday, fund managers are wary of buying the dip and say serious headwinds are facing Australia's largest bank.
Commonwealth Bank shares rose 1.1 per cent on Monday afternoon, clawing back some of the losses made last week when it fell 4.6 per cent.Photo: Louie Douvis
Allegations that Australia's largest bank had  thousands of large deposits that may have facilitated money laundering and terrorism spooked investors on Friday who wiped more than $5 billion off the company's market cap.
Fund managers are also suggesting that sustained brand damage, process remediation costs, a possible management re-shuffle, increased regulatory oversight and the looming threat of a Royal Commission into the banking sector are all cause to avoid the stock.
"While we're not exactly selling out of the banks here, it's not cheap enough to look attractive," says David Sokulsky, chief investment officer at Crestone Wealth Management.
"How much exposure do you want to have in some over the most over-leveraged businesses in the most over-valued market? Combine that with the regulatory versus policy risks and we're better off in offshore banks."

Speculation that CBA may be forced to pay an enormous fine  late last week, but the prospect of increased political and regulatory intervention is the biggest drag on sentiment toward the stock.
Morgan Stanley has an underweight position on Australia's largest bank and equity analyst Richard Wiles told clients on Monday that CBA is vulnerable to a de-rating as its earnings per share and dividend growth prospects decline and its return on equity gap to its peers narrows.
The firm has a price target of $72 on the stock, which is currently trading at $81.62.
Commonwealth Bank has long enjoyed a price-to-earnings premium, but some argue it already underperforms compared to the other major lenders in Australia.
"CBA probably doesn't deserve that premium anymore," said Omkar Joshi, portfolio manager at Regal Funds Management.
"And the whole risk of changes in regulations has now increased, so I wouldn't be buying CBA."
But not everyone feels as negative about the stock's prospects.
Anton Tagliaferro, investment director at Investors Mutual, said he did not think the scandal embroiling CBA would have a long term impact on the bank.
"I think it's just a storm in a tea cup. The CBA's a bank with a trillion dollar loan book, they have hundreds of millions of transactions a year going through the bank, and these things will happen from time to time," said Mr Tagliaferro.
While conceding the allegations were "concerning" and not positive news in the short term, he said it needed to be put in perspective given the size of the bank.
Investors Mutual has an "underweight" position on banks, but he signalled it viewed the recent dip in CBA as a buying opportunity.
"We're still a bit cautious [on the banks] although we hold CBA and we're happy to buy some when people are dumping them on insignificant news."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crestone Wealth Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omkar Joshi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Wiles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tagliaferro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Sokulsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regal Funds Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anton Tagliaferro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investors Mutual</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
