<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442692442297693</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/pressure-rising-on-suns-ahead-of-qclash/3209630/</url>
  <title>Pressure rising on Suns ahead of QClash</title>
  <content>
AFL: The Brisbane Lions plan to heap more pressure on the embattled Gold Coast Suns when the two go head to head in Saturday's QClash at the Gabba.
While the Lions are anchored to the bottom of the ladder, it is the Suns that are feeling the most heat, with coach Rodney Eade in the firing line come season's end.
The Suns are 15th following a five-match losing streak and suffering a seventh straight season of missing finals.
The football department is currently under review.
"I guess when you can cause any disruption or you can do anything to another club, it's a nice thing to play for, it creates motivation within the group," Lions captain Dayne Beams said.
The Lions ensured the Suns made the worst possible start to the season when they jumped them in the first quarter of their round one contest.
They kicked seven unanswered goals before holding on to win by two points.
As well as kicking the Suns while they're down, the Lions are determined to record another victory and give themselves a chance of getting off the bottom.
They have avoided the wooden spoon the past two years, but are still four points behind Carlton and North Melbourne
"We haven't won enough games to get ourselves off the bottom, but that's our aim until the end of the year," Beams added.
"We see the next three games (Gold Coast, Melbourne, North Melbourne) as winnable.
"That's our mission as a group to jump off the bottom of the ladder, it starts this week.
"(There's) no better feeling than to beat the Gold Coast, and hopefully North have a loss and we can jump off.
"Often the last three rounds, in our positon, can drag out a bit.
"We're really looking forward to finishing the season strong."
Brisbane holds an 8-5 win-loss record over the Gold Coast in QClash games.
Suns ruckman Dan Currie said the club had not forgotten the disastrous opening-term ambush that led to Brisbane's Round 1 win at Metricon Stadium.
It sucked the life out of a promising Suns preseason that brought so much hope and left the club chasing to even up the win-loss column - that now sits at 6-13 - from the outset.
"It was certainly not a good start to the year with the way we lost that one and the first quarter," Currie, who came into the side on Saturday for the injured Jarrod Witts, said.
"Until now we have had to focus on other opponents week-to-week but no doubt we will get a stern reminder of that this week.
"We will be carrying that in and we will be trying to redeem that performance from Round 1."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Round 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Currie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QClash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metricon Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Witts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Beams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday's QClash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
