<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442812701383500</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4838868/today-show-hosts-make-acting-debut-in-sharknado-5/?cs=2372</url>
  <title>Today Show hosts make acting debut in Sharknado 5</title>
  <content>
TodayShow hosts Karl Stefanovic and Lisa Wilkinson have made their Hollywood acting debut in the latest instalment of the popular Sharknado franchise.

Unfortunately, they didn't make it out alive.
The duo featured heavily in Sharknado 5: Global Swarming, playing themselves as tornadoes of sharks attacked Sydney Harbour.
And while their acting gig wasn't exactly a stretch, cynical viewers would be be forgiven for urging them to keep their day jobs.
While Wilkinson deadpanned with all the professionalism of her morning gig, Stefanovicl made the most of the cameo.
"Gale and strong wind warnings have been issued for the Sydney area; winds are currently at 50 knots an hour. You're gonna wanna hold on to your budgie smugglers," he exclaimed in one scene, no doubt in a bit of improv.
"We advise Australian residents: you better run, you better take cover," the two cringingly warned, quoting that old hit from Men At Work.
The cameo also had Stefanovic and Wilkinson throwing to "live" images of the Sydney Opera House, which "transformed" Optimus Prime-style, as it defended itself from an approaching sharknado.
"This isn't just an opera house... It's a battle station," one character exclaimed, as the landmark - armed by none other than Olivia Newton-John and daughter Chloe Lattanzi - spread its famous sails into shields and fired lasers at the ensuing threat.
Alas, its beams couldn't protect the Today hosts, with the sharknado reaching Nine's studios in Willoughby (presumably). In the end, they were swallowed up by flying sharks, but not before showcasing their best horror victim faces.

The film, broadcast up against Game of Thrones in the United States, was trending on social media today, taking a bit of online chatter away from Starks' family drama.
Locally, viewers offered their sympathies to Wilkinson - less so to Stefanovic.

We can safely assume Stefanovic and Wilkinson will be back at work on Tuesday morning.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Lattanzi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TODAYshow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Stefanovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Wilkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Newton-John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilkinson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Men At Work</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefanovicl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willoughby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharknado 5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefanovic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharknado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Optimus Prime-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
