<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442640902689367</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/do-cbas-austrac-woes-show-that-australias-banks-are-too-big-to-manage-20170807-gxqmar</url>
  <title>Do CBA's AUSTRAC woes show that Australia's banks are too big to manage?</title>
  <content>
The four pillars policy that protects the major banks from takeover also ensures that when something small goes wrong at any one institution it can grow exponentially and cause multiple regulatory and reputational problems.
In the wake of the AUSTRAC civil action against it is worth asking if the banks have become too big to manage and regulate.
Are they so large and complex that managers can no longer stay on top of their sprawling operations?  impossible in complex processes?
Do the regulators have the appropriate tools to pull such large institutions into line?

It is already clear the CBA case has exposed weaknesses in AUSTRAC's powers. The only way it could seek a financial penalty against CBA was to take court action which involved a 580 page statement of claim and attached appendices.

The AUSTRAC  about suspicious deposits from both AUSTRAC and the Australian Federal Police.
CBA is the largest bank in Australia. That means it is involved in one or both sides of at least half of every financial transaction that occurs.
It is at the forefront of digital banking. .
The root cause of the AUSTRAC case against CBA goes back to a small software coding error made in 2012, according to CBA chief executive Ian Narev.

He says this single software coding mistake triggered the bank's failure to report 53,000 cash deposits in excess of $10,000 to AUSTRAC between 2012 and 2105.
To emphasis the relative scale of the original mistake, Narev says the aggregate number of transactions not reported to AUSTRAC by CBA was 0.35 per cent of the volume of all transactions over the three year period.
Narev described this as "entirely immaterial" when placed in the context of the total volume of transactions.
He said in an The Australian Financial Review that being big brought with it certain risks in relation to operations and management.

"When you're a big institution, mistakes can have a big impact," he said.
Narev said the coding error was part of an upgrade to the software that sent reports automatically to AUSTRAC.
"So, this is an example of what I say when you make a mistake - and you're an institution of our size - that kind of mistake has a big impact and and that is, you know, something we've got to realise," he said.
Once CBA knew of the coding problem Narev says it did a "full root cause analysis" in August 2015. But fixing the broader problems raised by the coding error is not yet complete.

"I'd say in 2015 - that mid of 2015 - is an important time more broadly for the organisation because you know what the world's moving on, we're doing a lot in technology, the criminal element is becoming more sophisticated, we need to take a very deep and broad review of this whole area, upgrade capability, get different people in and from that point of time we really start that," he said.
"And by the way, given an organisation of our size and scale we're still in the middle of it. You know it takes a long time.
"But this is where we talk about we've already spent $230 million and we going to spend another hundred this year. It really triggered a sense of the world's moving really quickly and we need to move faster to do our job."
Once again, there is evidence that being big brings with it unique issues. When a problem occurs it can expose multiple failings that can take years to resolve at enormous expense.

AUSTRAC, of course, goes far beyond one coding error. The regulator claimed that, even before the software problem became known, CBA didn't carry out money laundering and terrorism financing risk assessments and nor did it conduct risk assessments in response to the exponential rise in cash deposits.
AUSTRAC also claimed that CBA didn't respond properly to alerts raised by the internal transaction monitoring system and didn't review its risk assessment response to matters identified by law enforcement authorities.
It would seem the CBA case reveals the extent to which a large regulated institution can allegedly ignore its obligations to the regulator.
Narev says CBA never took its obligations to AUSTRAC for granted and even to this day it remains in constant contact with AUSTRAC to assist in the fight against money laundering and financing terrorism.
But the regulator was slow to move to seek financial penalties. Also, .
Narev says CBA is fighting the AUSTRAC civil proceedings because there are significant areas where there are going to be differences, of either facts or the underlying motivations behind the facts.
"In doing that we are going to show we've made some mistakes and, because we are an organisation as big as we are, those mistakes can have big consequences.
"But that we come at all of our obligations in good faith, with a high sense of... of the importance of it."

Overseas, the response to compliance failures at banks was to significantly beef up the powers of regulators and impose upon banks increased reporting obligations.
This may happen here. Richard Wiles, a banking analyst at Morgan Stanley, is concerned that the AUSTRAC case against CBA will result in significantly higher costs for process and system remediation and greater oversight of CBA by the Australian Prudential Regulation Authority.
One problem with this response is that the impact of the solution can be worse than the problem being solved.
For example, banks in the United States now have to submit to the US Federal Reserve Board an annual comprehensive capital analysis and review. The one prepared this year by Morgan Stanley was 44,999 pages long.
Morgan Stanley CEO James Gorman told Chanticleer that this sort of regulation was "a level of complexity which is not related to what goes on in the real world".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA's AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prudential Regulation Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Wiles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Federal Reserve Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanticleer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narev</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley CEO James Gorman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
